<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Medscape – Archives Health News</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/index/list_13470_0</link><description>Flux personnalisé des archives Medscape Health News</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 10:11:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SGLT2 Inhibitors Reduce Portal Hypertension From Cirrhosis</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/sglt2-inhibitors-reduce-portal-hypertension-cirrhosis-2025a1000au0</link><description>Key outcomes of all-cause mortality and portal hypertension complications are improved with SGLT2inhibitors, new research shows. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Infant Colic May Predict Later Risk for Atopic Disease</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/infant-colic-may-predict-later-risk-atopic-disease-2025a1000atu</link><description>Having infant colic is associated with an increased risk for atopic conditions and respiratory illnesses throughout adolescence, new research shows. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Can Sharing a Kiss Lead to Gluten Transfer?</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/can-sharing-kiss-lead-gluten-transfer-2025a1000ass</link><description>Cross-contact with gluten is minimal for patients with celiac after sharing a kiss with someone who just ate food containing the wheat-based protein. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bone Marrow Lesions Linked to Ligament Lesions in Hand OA</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/bone-marrow-lesions-linked-collateral-ligament-lesions-2025a1000aey</link><description>Bone marrow lesions are less common but strongly associated with the more prevalent collateral ligament lesions in patients with hand osteoarthritis. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape News UK&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Do PARPi Increase Blood Cancer Risk in Ovarian Cancer?</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/do-poly-adp-ribose-polymerase-inhibitors-increase-risk-blood-2025a1000aar</link><description>A real-world analysis suggests a low incidence of secondary myelodysplastic syndrome and acute myeloid leukaemia in patients with advanced ovarian cancer on PARP inhibitor maintenance therapy. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape News UK&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HPV Vaccine Post-Surgery Cuts Viral Persistence</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/hpv-vaccine-post-surgery-cuts-viral-persistence-2025a1000a7h</link><description>The administration of the HPV nonavalent vaccine after surgical treatment leads to a substantial reduction in HPV recurrence among women with HPV-related cervical lesions. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape News UK&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Target for Fat-Burning Drugs Discovered in Mice Study</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/new-target-fat-burning-drugs-discovered-mice-study-2025a1000aub</link><description>Animal studies have established the previously unknown role of a protein that helps activate brown fat, a tissue that can boost metabolism and improve glucose tolerance. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Predicting Glycemic Responses Using Noninvasive Data</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/predicting-glycemic-responses-using-noninvasive-data-2025a1000au4</link><description>Predicting glycemic responses to food using limited data could allow for personalized nutrition planning for individuals with type 1 or type 2 diabetes without reliance on costly, invasive tests. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Single Antiplatelet After TAVR Lowers Risk</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/single-antiplatelet-after-tavr-lowers-risk-2025a1000auc</link><description>New findings from real-world experience support the shift in practice to single antiplatelet therapy after transcatheter aortic valve replacement. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>What Do We Know About the Causes of Autism?</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/what-do-we-know-about-causes-autism-2025a1000aug</link><description>Scientists who have dedicated their careers to studying autism remain highly skeptical that a definitive answer to what causes autism can be reached within a few short months — if at all. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>FDA Okays DHE Nasal Spray for Acute Migraine</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/fda-okays-dihydroergotamine-nasal-spray-acute-migraine-2025a1000auy</link><description>Atzumi combines a proprietary advanced powder and device technology to simplify nasal delivery of dihydroergotamine for acute treatment of migraine. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Safety Questions Over Mechanical Circulatory Support</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/new-safety-questions-over-mechanical-circulatory-support-2025a1000avo</link><description>Specialists are debating the best approach in cardiogenic shock after a new analysis of data comparing Impella with intra-aortic balloon pump has pointed to safety issues. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Subtyping Thyroid Function Testing Halved Positive Diagnoses</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/subtyping-thyroid-function-testing-halved-persons-eligible-l-2025a1000at3</link><description>The study challenged a ‘one-size-fits-all’ approach to defining thyroid function reference intervals. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 05 2025)</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Do Mammograms Improve Breast Cancer Outcomes in Older Women?</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/do-mammograms-improve-breast-cancer-outcomes-older-women-2025a1000avv</link><description>Prior screening mammography is associated with earlier stage at breast cancer diagnosis and lower breast cancer mortality risk in women aged 70 years or older with screen-detected breast cancers. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 06 2025)</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Are US Doctors Ready if Measles Becomes Endemic Again?</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/are-us-doctors-ready-if-measles-becomes-endemic-again-2025a1000awd</link><description>A new modeling study offers a stark look at caseloads in the next two decades if current trends hold. Can the nation’s healthcare system handle the strain? (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 06 2025)</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Early Osteoarthritis Needs Better Definition(s)</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/early-osteoarthritis-needs-better-definition-s-aid-2025a1000awk</link><description>‘The only way that we can really clarify which definition, or maybe definitions, are the most useful is for us to really systematically evaluate many of them,’ said Grace Hsiao-Wei Lo, MD, MS. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 06 2025)</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Henipavirus Detected in Alabama</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/new-henipavirus-detected-alabama-2025a1000aw2</link><description>Camp Hill virus surfaces in North America — efforts intensify to assess risks, track its spread, and define its potential health threat. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 06 2025)</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ctDNA Positivity in CRC Links to Chemotherapy Response</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/ctdna-positivity-colorectal-cancer-links-chemotherapy-2025a1000avz</link><description>Patients with CRC who test positive for ctDNA following curative resection show poorer disease-free survival but a greater response to chemotherapy than those who test negative. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 06 2025)</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Obesity Care Roadblocks: Insurers vs Clinical Guidelines</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/insurance-barriers-obesity-care-physicians-navigate-complex-2025a1000awp</link><description>Physicians describe common prior authorization challenges when treating patients for obesity and share strategies to overcome denials. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 06 2025)</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Novel Shoes May Cut Low Back Pain, Delay Knee Arthroplasty</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/novel-shoe-intervention-may-cut-low-back-pain-delay-knee-2025a1000awu</link><description>Two studies show that wearers of a foot-worn, home-based biomechanical intervention could reduce low back pain and risk for total knee replacement surgery in comparison with physical therapy. (&lt;em&gt;Medscape Medical News&lt;/em&gt;, May 06 2025)</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>