<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:41:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vaping trends shift as UK ban drives switch from disposable to reusable devices</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250421/Vaping-trends-shift-as-UK-ban-drives-switch-from-disposable-to-reusable-devices.aspx</link><description>British disposable vape ban announcement in 2024 led to a decline in e-cigarette use rates, with users switching to refillable devices. A study tracked these changes, highlighting the influence of policy on health decisions. Since 2021, youth vaping surged due to disposable vapes' appeal, prompting UK bans in 2025. Manufacturers now offer reusable alternatives. Findings suggest a shift away from disposables, indicating potential declines in vape usage. Policies play a crucial role in curbing vaping trends. Researchers analyzed data from the Smoking Toolkit Study, revealing a shift towards refillable devices post-ban. The move towards sustainability in vaping indicates positive environmental impacts but may not drastically reduce overall vaping rates. (Published on April 22, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #62 | UNSMOKE THE WORLD | Inside PMI’s Mission to End Cigarettes</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-62-unsmoke-the-world-inside-pmis-mission-to-end-cigarettes/</link><description>In 2016, PMI pledged to transition the company away from cigarette sales - and almost ten years later, they've made progress towards their promise. But instead of celebrating as 40% of PMI's business goes smoke-free, many in tobacco control would rather stand in the way. Why is that? And can anything be done to change their minds? (Published on April 22, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Arkansas Registry Law Includes U.S. Personal Possession Ban</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/8397/arkansas-registry-law-includes-personal-possession-ban/</link><description>Arkansas passed its PMTA registry law, banning some vaping products with unclear e-liquids requirements. The law requires products to meet specific criteria and be listed in the directory by Sept. 1, 2025. It exempts open-system devices with replaceable batteries but not products with built-in batteries. Violators face penalties, and packaging restrictions target child-appealing designs. Arkansas restricts personal possession and importation of unregistered products. This law is only the second in the U.S. to ban personal possession of vaping products. More states are introducing PMTA registry bills in 2025, following Mississippi's lead. Consumer advocacy groups are mobilizing against these bills across the country. (Published on April 22, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>Why Is Tobacco Control Not Getting Behind ZYN?</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/why-is-tobacco-control-not-getting-behind-zyn/</link><description>Tobacco control opposes nicotine pouches due to concerns about targeting children, but Philip Morris International's ZYN adopts responsible marketing practices, emphasizing safety for adult users. ZYN's strategy excludes influencers and celebrities, ensuring age-appropriate marketing. Although some critics suggest youth targeting through flavors and colors, ZYN's subdued branding defies this narrative. Grassroots enthusiasm and organic content differentiate ZYN's marketing approach, diverging from typical influencer strategies. Despite stringent age-gating measures and limited ad platforms, skepticism persists. The tension reflects broader societal mistrust and bias. ZYN's efforts to prevent underage use receive scrutiny from tobacco control, hinting at underlying motives in the anti-smoking agenda. (Published on April 22, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>Increased risk of COPD observed in individuals using e-cigarette: Study</title><link>https://medicaldialogues.in/pulmonology/news/increased-risk-of-copd-observed-in-individuals-using-e-cigarette-study-146545</link><description>A study linked electronic cigarette use to a higher risk of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). E-cigarettes simulate traditional cigarettes and may worsen respiratory conditions, affecting the efficacy of CPAP treatment for sleep apnea. The meta-analysis included 7 observational studies with over 35 million individuals, showing a 1.50-fold increased risk of COPD among e-cigarette users compared to non-users. Prospective cohort and cross-sectional studies revealed a 52% to 55% greater risk of COPD among e-cigarette users. This research highlights the potential negative impact of e-cigarette use on respiratory health, with implications for COPD prevention and management. (Published on April 22, 2025bymedicaldialogues.in)</description></item><item><title>Appealing flavors may help make e-cigarettes more addictive, research suggests</title><link>https://www.upi.com/Health_News/2025/04/22/flavored-vaping-addiction/5981744917254/</link><description>Vaping addiction is mainly due to nicotine in e-cigarettes, not the flavors. However, flavors like menthol can increase usage frequency, especially among young people. Research shows that sweet flavors attract youth to vaping, contributing to nicotine dependence. Efforts have been made to regulate vaping products due to health concerns and their appeal to teens. The FDA oversees restrictions on sales and bans flavored products. Despite regulations, flavored e-cigarettes remain popular among teens. Manufacturers must consider the appeal of their products in addressing addiction issues and promoting public health. (Published on April 22, 2025byupi.com)</description></item></channel></rss>