<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 13:33:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Are heated tobacco products a new health risk?</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20250501-the-truth-about-heated-tobacco</link><description>The text discusses the growing popularity of heated tobacco products like IQOS and their potential health risks. Tobacco companies claim these products are less harmful than cigarettes, but experts warn of health concerns, marketing to youth, and lack of long-term research. Studies show heated tobacco can lead to smoking, emissions may contain harmful chemicals, and dual use may increase health risks. Public health officials urge caution, as these products could encourage more tobacco consumption. Concerns also arise about the marketing tactics targeting young people. Research suggests heated tobacco may not be a safe alternative to smoking. Vigilance is key as these products enter the market. (Published on May 05, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>E-cigarettes, heated tobacco, nicotine pouches effective for quitting smoking – report</title><link>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/2057724/e-cigarettes-heated-tobacco-nicotine-pouches-effective-for-quitting-smoking-report</link><description>Harm-reduction tools like e-cigarettes, heated tobacco, and nicotine pouches help smokers quit effectively, as reported by the World Vapers Alliance (WVA). Scientific studies support that e-cigarettes are at least 95% less harmful than traditional cigarettes. The WVA emphasizes that transitioning to these alternatives can reduce exposure to harmful substances, potentially lowering cancer risk. The WVA advocates for the acceptance of harm reduction strategies by the World Health Organization to aid in smoking cessation. This evidence-based approach has proven successful in countries like Sweden, the UK, and New Zealand. Vaping has been found to be twice as effective as nicotine replacement therapies in quitting smoking. Policymakers are urged to consider a variety of harm-reduction tools to reduce smoking-related diseases and improve public health outcomes. (Published on May 05, 2025byinquirer.net)</description></item></channel></rss>