<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 13:04:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Greece Considers Ban on Flavored E-Cigarettes</title><link>https://greekcitytimes.com/2025/04/25/greece-considers-ban-on-flavored-e-cigarettes/</link><description>Greece's conservative government plans to ban flavored alternative tobacco products, excluding natural tobacco and mint. The legislation aims to restrict minors' access to alcohol and tobacco, eliminating popular flavors appealing to youth and potentially affecting 10,000 employees. The bill, nearing completion, faces challenges, like needing EU approval and criticism for possibly restricting adult consumers. Despite the high smoking rate, analysts support the focus on limiting underage access. The move aligns with ongoing EU discussions on revising tobacco laws amid the rise of alternative products like e-cigarettes and heated tobacco. (Published on April 25, 2025bygreekcitytimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Stricter controls better than total ban on vape products, says expert</title><link>https://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2025/04/24/stricter-controls-better-than-total-ban-on-vape-products-says-expert</link><description>Deputy inspector Ayob Khan Mydin Pitchay revealed students as young as 13 using drug-laced vape. Public health expert Dr. Sharifa Ezat Wan Puteh suggests controlling high-risk vape products instead of banning them. She advocates for regulations allowing safer options for smokers. Dr. Lee Boon Chye emphasizes reducing youth appeal towards vapes by limiting nicotine and removing fruity flavors. Both experts agree banning vapes is not the ideal solution. They propose regulating vape liquid content and tightening import controls to tackle the issue effectively. (Published on April 25, 2025byfreemalaysiatoday.com)</description></item><item><title>The public health playbook</title><link>https://thecritic.co.uk/the-public-health-playbook/</link><description>The British Medical Journal (BMJ) has revealed that outdoor advertising companies are using tactics similar to those of the tobacco industry to oppose local councils’ attempts to ban junk food ads on bus shelters and billboards. An investigation by Sophie Borland, a former Daily Mail health editor, found that these companies have been lobbying against policies that could harm their business. Borland sent Freedom of Information requests to 52 of England’s 317 local authorities and uncovered evidence of attempts by the advertising industry to influence policy in eight of them. Sources suggest that the actual number could be even higher. (Published on April 25, 2025bythecritic.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Beneficial and Harmful Tobacco-Use Transitions Associated With ENDS in the U.S.</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S074937972500025X</link><description>This study analyzed U.S. data to assess transitions in tobacco use related to ENDS (e-cigarettes). While 2.1 million people made beneficial transitions from combustible tobacco to ENDS or quit with ENDS support, 4.6 million made harmful transitions, including nonusers starting ENDS or ENDS users switching to combustible tobacco. Overall, harmful transitions outnumbered beneficial ones by more than 2 to 1. However, with proper regulation, ENDS could provide net public health benefits. (Published on April 25, 2025bysciencedirect.com)</description></item><item><title>HK seeks to ban e-cigarettes in public in April 2026</title><link>https://hongkongfp.com/2025/04/25/hong-kong-seeks-to-ban-e-cigarettes-in-public-in-april-2026/</link><description>Hong Kong plans to ban e-cigarettes and smoking in public places by April 2026. The Tobacco Control Legislation (Amendment) Bill 2025 introduces fines of HK$3,000 for violators. The bill also includes expanding no-smoking areas and doubling fines for smoking violations. Flavoured tobacco sales will be phased out by the second quarter of 2027. Stricter measures on illegal cigarettes include labeling requirements for every pack sold. The proposal aims to deter smoking among youth. Additionally, providing smoking products to minors will result in fines up to HK$25,000. The government's goal is to enhance public health and reduce smoking prevalence. (Published on April 25, 2025byhongkongfp.com)</description></item><item><title>Ban on flavored heated tobacco products in Estonia does not cover vaping</title><link>https://news.err.ee/1609674845/ban-on-flavored-heated-tobacco-products-in-estonia-does-not-cover-vaping</link><description>The Riigikogu passed a law enforcing an EU directive banning flavored heated tobacco products next year to deter smoking, especially among the youth. Vaping products with high nicotine content and flavors remain exempt. Legislators are considering future regulations on vaping. A school principal supports the ban on heated tobacco products due to teenage vaping. Studies show an increase in youth vaping, with strong support for an e-cigarette ban. Vaping is popular among teens, posing health risks and challenges for enforcement. Legislation banning flavored e-cigarettes is in place. Despite concerns, enforcement and regulations on vaping remain a future consideration. (Published on April 25, 2025byerr.ee)</description></item><item><title>Vaping News Dr Jackson Discusses Research</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-04-23_dr-jackson-discusses-research.html</link><description>Dr. Sarah Jackson discussed new research showing that the UK government's plan to ban disposable vapes has slowed the rise in vaping, especially among young adults. The study found two main changes since the January 2024 announcement: the growth in vaping rates has stalled, and more vapers are switching to reusable devices. Dr. Jackson noted that the popularity of disposables had driven a sharp increase in youth vaping since 2021, but the new policy appears to be influencing behavior even before taking effect. (Published on April 25, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>