<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 15:31:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HK seeks to ban e-cigarettes in public in April 2026</title><link>https://hongkongfp.com/2025/04/25/hong-kong-seeks-to-ban-e-cigarettes-in-public-in-april-2026/</link><description>Hong Kong plans to ban e-cigarettes and smoking in public places by April 2026. The Tobacco Control Legislation (Amendment) Bill 2025 introduces fines of HK$3,000 for violators. The bill also includes expanding no-smoking areas and doubling fines for smoking violations. Flavoured tobacco sales will be phased out by the second quarter of 2027. Stricter measures on illegal cigarettes include labeling requirements for every pack sold. The proposal aims to deter smoking among youth. Additionally, providing smoking products to minors will result in fines up to HK$25,000. The government's goal is to enhance public health and reduce smoking prevalence. (Published on April 25, 2025byhongkongfp.com)</description></item><item><title>Ban on flavored heated tobacco products in Estonia does not cover vaping</title><link>https://news.err.ee/1609674845/ban-on-flavored-heated-tobacco-products-in-estonia-does-not-cover-vaping</link><description>The Riigikogu passed a law enforcing an EU directive banning flavored heated tobacco products next year to deter smoking, especially among the youth. Vaping products with high nicotine content and flavors remain exempt. Legislators are considering future regulations on vaping. A school principal supports the ban on heated tobacco products due to teenage vaping. Studies show an increase in youth vaping, with strong support for an e-cigarette ban. Vaping is popular among teens, posing health risks and challenges for enforcement. Legislation banning flavored e-cigarettes is in place. Despite concerns, enforcement and regulations on vaping remain a future consideration. (Published on April 25, 2025byerr.ee)</description></item><item><title>Vaping News Dr Jackson Discusses Research</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-04-23_dr-jackson-discusses-research.html</link><description>Dr. Sarah Jackson discussed new research showing that the UK government's plan to ban disposable vapes has slowed the rise in vaping, especially among young adults. The study found two main changes since the January 2024 announcement: the growth in vaping rates has stalled, and more vapers are switching to reusable devices. Dr. Jackson noted that the popularity of disposables had driven a sharp increase in youth vaping since 2021, but the new policy appears to be influencing behavior even before taking effect. (Published on April 25, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>