<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 06:34:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN Insights #6 | GFN SCIENCE SPECIAL: The physics of vaporisation in e-cigarettes | Featuring Roberto Sussman</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-insights-6-gfn-science-special-the-physics-of-vaporisation-in-e-cigarettes-featuring-roberto-sussman/</link><description>In the third episode of our science special, Roberto Sussman looks at the thermal processes that take place in vaporisation, and the impact different solvents have on the vaporisation temperature of e-liquids. (Published on April 30, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Use of nicotine pouches increasing significantly among US teens, survey reveals</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-04-nicotine-pouches-significantly-teens-survey.html</link><description>The USC study reveals a nearly doubled usage of nicotine pouches among U.S. high school students in 2023-2024. Concerns rise over their popularity linked to confidence and masculinity on social media, prompting calls for regulation by organizations like the FDA. Data shows an increase in teens using both pouches and e-cigarettes. Demographics indicate higher usage among males, non-Hispanic whites, and those in rural areas, highlighting the need for tailored prevention strategies. Risks include nicotine addiction and potential health effects on brain development. Monitoring trends and tailored prevention approaches are essential to address this growing issue. Regulatory policies and prevention efforts, especially for high-risk groups, are crucial. (Published on April 30, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Emissions from conventional and electronic waterpipes relative to cigarettes and a heated tobacco product</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-90721-w</link><description>The study compared aerosol yields from conventional and electronic waterpipes, HTPs, and cigarettes. Conventional waterpipes may expose users to lower levels of harmful substances than cigarettes. Different charcoals or a heating device can reduce exposure. Electronic waterpipes showed significant reductions in toxicants. Findings align with existing literature, suggesting lower exposure with waterpipes compared to cigarettes. Emissions analysis corrects misconceptions about waterpipe nicotine content. Real-world use patterns impact exposure. Overall, exposure to harmful substances is lower with waterpipes and electronic devices compared to cigarettes. Innovative heating methods can further reduce toxicant exposure in waterpipes. Study limitations include standardized testing and assumptions on consumption patterns. In conclusion, waterpipes emit fewer toxins than cigarettes, with potential for decreased exposure through modifications. (Published on April 30, 2025bynature.com)</description></item><item><title>Electronic cigarettes to be completely banned in Uzbekistan</title><link>https://qalampir.uz/en/news/uzbekistonda-elektron-sigaretalar-butunlay-tak-ik-lanadi-118230</link><description>The Senate of the Oliy Majlis in Uzbekistan approved a law banning electronic cigarettes to combat the rising illegal circulation of such products. The law aims to promote a healthy lifestyle, especially among youth, by reinforcing regulations on tobacco and nicotine-related items. It includes penalties for illegal activities and exempts individuals who report violations. Similar laws have been enacted in neighboring countries like Kazakhstan and Kyrgyzstan. The legislation aligns with efforts to protect public health, the national gene pool, and the environment from harmful tobacco products. The law was proposed in January 2024 and passed in April. (Published on April 30, 2025byqalampir.uz)</description></item><item><title>Well, That’s One Way to Address America’s Vaping Problem</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2025/04/vapes-china-tariffs-trump/682647/</link><description>The text discusses the popularity of flavored vapes, particularly the "Miami Mint" flavor, and the regulatory challenges they face. Chinese-made vapes, like many illicit products, are now subject to a 170% tariff due to Trump's trade war. The changing landscape may impact prices and affect consumer behavior. Despite health concerns, vapes can help smokers transition away from cigarettes. Legal vape options face competition from illegal counterparts with more variety and nicotine content. The tariffs could potentially benefit legal vape companies and deter underage vaping, despite drawbacks. Ultimately, the tariffs may offer a solution to the unregulated vaping market. (Published on April 30, 2025bytheatlantic.com)</description></item><item><title>The World Health Organization Has Failed the World on Tobacco Harm Reduction</title><link>https://www.protectingtaxpayers.org/e-cigarettes/the-world-health-organization-has-failed-the-world-on-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>The Taxpayers Protection Alliance discussed WHO's failures in tobacco control during a webinar marking the 20th anniversary of the FCTC. TPA criticized WHO for ignoring harm reduction benefits and advocating prohibition policies, leading to a growing black market for tobacco harm reduction products. The organization's reluctance to adapt to modern science and real-world solutions jeopardizes its credibility. TPA aims to hold WHO accountable through their Good COP/Bad COP campaign, urging the organization to prioritize public health over outdated policies. The webinar highlighted the urgent need for WHO reform and recognition of safer alternatives like vaping and heated tobacco products. (Published on April 30, 2025byprotectingtaxpayers.org)</description></item><item><title>Higher cigarette taxes could save thousands of children's lives</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250429/Higher-cigarette-taxes-could-save-thousands-of-childrens-lives.aspx</link><description>A study by Karolinska Institutet suggests higher cigarette taxes in low and middle-income countries could reduce child mortality, benefiting the poorest children. The research indicates that implementing WHO's recommended 75% tax could have potentially saved over 280,000 children's lives. The study analyzed data from 94 countries between 2008-2020, showing how increased cigarette taxes can improve child survival across all socioeconomic groups. Lead author Olivia Bannon emphasizes the importance of raising cigarette taxes to protect children's health, particularly in vulnerable populations. The study highlights the need to combat tobacco industry interference to implement effective tobacco control policies globally. (Published on May 01, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>Spanish watchdog demands evidence to justify vape and nicotine pouch rules</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/spanish-watchdog-demands-evidence-to-justify-vape-and-nicotine-pouch-rules/</link><description>The Spanish watchdog questions Ministry of Health's vaping restrictions, demanding more evidence. Spain plans to ban vape flavors, except tobacco, and limit nicotine pouches to 0.99mg. The decree faces scrutiny for affecting market competition. Health Ministry claims flavors attract non-smokers. Manufacturers have 10 months to comply with new regulations. High court overturns Barcelona beach vaping ban, citing lack of power. Spain's excise duty on smoke-free products may impact lower-income groups. Concerns arise that strict regulations could reverse declining smoking rates. (Published on May 01, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item></channel></rss>