<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 04:28:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Don’t Let History Repeat: Greece Warned Against Flavour Ban Mistake</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/04/29/dont-let-history-repeat-greece-warned-against-flavour-ban-mistake/</link><description>Consumer groups and vaping advocates in Europe oppose Greece's plan to ban flavoured e-cigarettes, fearing it will harm harm reduction efforts. They argue that flavours help smokers switch to safer options and caution against unintended consequences seen in Denmark. The ban risks driving former smokers back to cigarettes and the black market. Data shows adult vapers prefer flavoured products. Experts recommend science-based regulations that protect public health while supporting harm reduction. In Denmark, a ban on vape flavours unintentionally increased youth use and spurred illegal sales. Critics warn against over-regulation and point to Sweden's harm reduction success. Research confirms flavoured vapes aid smoking cessation. Advocates call for evidence-based policies to safeguard gains in public health. (Published on May 01, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>Study: Nicotine pouch use nearly doubles among U.S. high school students</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250430/Study-Nicotine-pouch-use-nearly-doubles-among-US-high-school-students.aspx</link><description>Nicotine pouch use doubled among U.S. high school students from 2023 to 2024, with 5.4% reporting usage. This emerging trend raises concerns, mirroring the past rise of flavored e-cigarettes. The FDA's decision to allow marketing of Zyn pouches to adults is controversial, given their popularity among teens. Research shows a demographic pattern favoring white males in rural areas. Both nicotine pouch and e-cigarette use increased in 2024, with more teens engaging in dual use. Long-term health effects are uncertain, but addiction risks persist. Preventative measures and regulation are crucial to address this public health issue. Tracking trends and evaluating policies are essential for targeted prevention strategies. (Published on May 01, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>Philip Morris International U.S. CEO: Nicotine has "cognitive benefits"</title><link>https://www.axios.com/2025/04/30/trump-zyn-rfk-jr-nicotine</link><description>The CEO of Philip Morris International’s U.S. business claims nicotine is misunderstood and offers cognitive benefits, arguing that regulators should support smoking alternatives. This comes as PMI pushes to end cigarette sales. With Robert F. Kennedy Jr. now leading the Department of Health and Human Services, there may be major changes in tobacco regulation. Meanwhile, PMI's nicotine pouch brand Zyn is seeing rapid growth in the U.S., with shipments in the Americas up nearly 54% in Q1 2025. Smoke-free products now make up 42% of PMI's revenue, compared to 25% a year ago. Although PMI still earns most of its revenue from smokers, that could soon shift due to Zyn’s rising popularity. (Published on May 01, 2025byaxios.com)</description></item></channel></rss>