<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 04:29:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Are heated tobacco products a new health risk?</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20250501-the-truth-about-heated-tobacco</link><description>The text discusses the growing popularity of heated tobacco products like IQOS and their potential health risks. Tobacco companies claim these products are less harmful than cigarettes, but experts warn of health concerns, marketing to youth, and lack of long-term research. Studies show heated tobacco can lead to smoking, emissions may contain harmful chemicals, and dual use may increase health risks. Public health officials urge caution, as these products could encourage more tobacco consumption. Concerns also arise about the marketing tactics targeting young people. Research suggests heated tobacco may not be a safe alternative to smoking. Vigilance is key as these products enter the market. (Published on May 05, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>E-cigarettes, heated tobacco, nicotine pouches effective for quitting smoking – report</title><link>https://newsinfo.inquirer.net/2057724/e-cigarettes-heated-tobacco-nicotine-pouches-effective-for-quitting-smoking-report</link><description>Harm-reduction tools like e-cigarettes, heated tobacco, and nicotine pouches help smokers quit effectively, as reported by the World Vapers Alliance (WVA). Scientific studies support that e-cigarettes are at least 95% less harmful than traditional cigarettes. The WVA emphasizes that transitioning to these alternatives can reduce exposure to harmful substances, potentially lowering cancer risk. The WVA advocates for the acceptance of harm reduction strategies by the World Health Organization to aid in smoking cessation. This evidence-based approach has proven successful in countries like Sweden, the UK, and New Zealand. Vaping has been found to be twice as effective as nicotine replacement therapies in quitting smoking. Policymakers are urged to consider a variety of harm-reduction tools to reduce smoking-related diseases and improve public health outcomes. (Published on May 05, 2025byinquirer.net)</description></item><item><title>Federal Judge Grants Injunction, Blocks Iowa PMTA Registry For Now</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/8405/federal-judge-grants-injunction-blocks-iowa-registry-for-now/</link><description>A federal judge in Iowa blocked the enforcement of the state's PMTA registry law due to a lawsuit by the vaping industry. Judge Rose cited the Supremacy Clause, stating it violates federal authority. The law was halted until the court resolves the case. The Vapor Technology Association is challenging a similar law in North Carolina. The Iowa ruling could impact other states with PMTA laws. (Published on May 05, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #63 | TAX TRAP | How Safer Nicotine Products Get Treated Like Tobacco</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-63/</link><description>New research reveals governments are taxing safer nicotine products like cigarettes, sabotaging tobacco harm reduction and blocking smokers from switching. Correcting these policies could accelerate global declines in smoking. (Published on May 05, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>The UK’s Impending Disposable Vapes Ban Looks Unenforceable</title><link>https://filtermag.org/uk-disposable-vapes-ban-unenforceable/</link><description>The UK faces challenges with the upcoming ban on single-use vapes in June, as warnings from various groups indicate a potential surge in the illicit vapes market. Experts criticize the government for being ill-prepared, with concerns ranging from vapers switching back to cigarettes to inadequate enforcement resources. The ban may lead to a boost in the unregulated vapes market, risking harm to consumers. Despite initial reservations, some organizations now cautiously support the ban. However, fears of a thriving black market, criminal enterprises, and violence have emerged. Research shows mixed impacts on vaping behavior, with uncertainty about the ban's overall effectiveness in reducing vaping rates or promoting smoking cessation. (Published on May 05, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>OLDCORN: Australia’s tobacco tax fiasco offers Canada a smoking hot warning</title><link>https://www.westernstandard.news/canadian/oldcorn-australias-tobacco-tax-fiasco-offers-canada-a-smoking-hot-warning/64501</link><description>Australia's tobacco excise revenue plummeted to $7.4 billion AUD this year from $16.3 billion AUD in 2019‑20, despite high taxes. Smokers turned to cheaper contraband due to tax hikes, leading to a 50% revenue drop in five years. Canadian authorities should pay attention as they increase taxes and regulations, resulting in a rise in vape store robberies across the country. (Published on May 05, 2025bywesternstandard.news)</description></item></channel></rss>