<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 10:26:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>VIDEO: Alarm over health risks of nicotine pouches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/alarm-over-health-risks-of-nicotine-pouches/105231264</link><description>Griffith Social Marketing Research Fellow James Duel says the dissolvable pouches, known as Zyn, 'snus' or 'zins' are being aimed at young people. (Published on April 29, 2025byabc.net.au)</description></item><item><title>The WHO's Failure to Protect Health: A TPA Webinar</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ba1WElqd2aI</link><description>In this webinar leading up to the World Health Organization's COP11 conference, TPA's Martin Cullip and David Williams sit down with subject-matter experts Roger Bate and Clive Bates to discuss how the WHO has not been living up to its ultimate mission of protecting public health. (Published on April 29, 2025byyoutube.com)</description></item><item><title>The fightback begins: Sweden seeks to block Spanish pouch ban</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/the-fightback-begins-sweden-seeks-to-block-spanish-pouch-ban/</link><description>The Swedish government plans to challenge Spain’s proposed ban on nicotine pouches at the EU level by submitting a Detailed Opinion to delay implementation. Sweden argues that pouches should be allowed where smoking is permitted. France has a similar ban, but with even stricter penalties. Although Sweden is exempt from the EU's ban on tobacco-containing snus, this exemption does not apply to nicotine pouches. The Minister assured that Sweden will oppose any EU-wide ban on pouches as long as their government is in power. (Published on April 29, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Sociedad La evidencia científica que podría transformar las políticas contra el tabaquismo en Europa</title><link>https://www.elplural.com/sociedad/evidencia-cientifica-transformar-politicas-tabaquismo-europa_350907102</link><description>The fight against smoking has long been a public health priority, and recent policy successes are evident. However, a new study led by a researcher from Linköping University challenges conventional views on nicotine and suggests a need to rethink health policies in Europe. With over 30 years of research experience in obesity, diabetes, and nicotine, the author emphasizes the importance of distinguishing between tobacco smoke and nicotine itself. The study focused on the effects of snus, a smokeless tobacco product legal in Sweden but banned elsewhere in Europe. Controlled experiments with medical students showed that snus caused only a slight increase in blood pressure—similar to a cup of coffee—indicating that nicotine alone may not pose the same cardiovascular risks as tobacco smoke. (Published on April 29, 2025byelplural.com)</description></item><item><title>Family Tragedy Spurs One Man’s Drive to Cut Smoking in South Africa</title><link>https://filtermag.org/south-africa-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>Kurt Yeo co-founded Vaping Saved My Life to promote tobacco harm reduction in South Africa. He switched from cigarettes to vapes after his father's smoking-related death and now advocates full-time. Yeo's VSML educates the public and challenges misinformation about vaping. Despite government opposition, he highlights how vaping can help combat smoking. Yeo's advocacy includes hosting a podcast, conducting surveys, and engaging with policymakers. South Africa faces challenges like the illicit cigarette trade and expensive smoking cessation aids. Yeo believes nicotine pouches could be a practical harm reduction solution. Policy changes aim to discourage vaping, but Yeo continues to fight for access to safer nicotine products to combat smoking rates. (Published on April 29, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>​Pouches gain popularity amid shifts in tobacco use</title><link>https://www.royalgazette.com/local-business/business/article/20250429/pouches-gain-popularity-amid-shifts-in-tobacco-use/</link><description>Nicotine pouches are becoming popular in Bermuda as a cleaner alternative to smoking and vaping, especially among younger consumers. These pouches release synthetic or tobacco-derived nicotine without tobacco leaves, appealing to users seeking a smoke-free option. The global nicotine pouch market is growing, with recent FDA approval in the US and success in Europe. Despite challenges like rising tariffs, interest in zero-nicotine options is on the rise. The pouches are gaining attention for potential health benefits, including research linking nicotine to improved cognitive function. The trend towards alternative tobacco products is expected to continue based on consumer health trends. (Published on April 29, 2025byroyalgazette.com)</description></item></channel></rss>