<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 19:26:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Four sentenced for smuggling tobacco, on-selling cigarettes from Gisborne restaurant</title><link>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/national/558879/four-sentenced-for-smuggling-tobacco-on-selling-cigarettes-from-gisborne-restaurant</link><description>Four individuals involved in an illegal tobacco importing scheme in Gisborne were sentenced. Two men received home detention for defrauding Customs revenue and other charges, while an older couple was fined and ordered to pay court costs for their lesser roles. Customs discovered undeclared cigarettes and loose tobacco disguised as Chinese tea in airmail packages, totaling 306,200 cigarettes and 110kg of tobacco. The operation involved selling the goods in a restaurant. Customs' investigations led to the discovery of cash and tobacco products, resulting in charges under the Customs and Excise Act 2018. Customs Officer Bevan Cameron highlighted the significant duty evasion and fraud involved. (Published on April 23, 2025byrnz.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>Greece Set to Ban Teen-Friendly Flavoured E-Cigarettes</title><link>https://greekreporter.com/2025/04/23/greece-set-ban-teen-friendly-flavored-e-cigarettes/</link><description>Greece is preparing a bill to ban all flavoured e-cigarettes and alternative tobacco products, aiming to make their sale out-of-reach for Greek teenagers. Under the draft law, flavours like biscuit, chocolate, watermelon, fruit and even whiskey, which are particularly popular among both teenagers and adults, would be pulled off the market, with only tobacco and mint flavours spared. The e-cigarette sector in Greece employs about 10,000 people, including 2,000 specialized retailers. (Published on April 23, 2025bygreekreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Many young people want to quit vaping. A new study says medication can help</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/04/23/quitting-vaping-e-cigarettes-varenicline-chantix-young-adults/</link><description>Sarah Todd resumed reporting in January 2025 after working as an assignment editor at STAT from October 2022. A recent study at Massachusetts General Hospital found that young e-cigarette users who took varenicline with counseling were more successful in quitting vaping compared to those on a placebo. The research, authored by Eden Evins, highlights the effectiveness of this approach for controlling nicotine cravings among youth. This could lead to a significant shift in how healthcare providers address nicotine addiction in young people, as varenicline has shown promise as a treatment option. Vaping remains a concern among adolescents and young adults due to its addictive nature and health risks associated with nicotine exposure. (Published on April 23, 2025bystatnews.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Insights #5 | GFN SCIENCE SPECIAL: Back to the fundamentals | Episode 2 | Featuring Roberto Sussman</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-insights-5/</link><description>In the second part of our science special, Roberto Sussman takes us through the fundamental physics of vape aerosols to help explain the difference between cigarette smoke and e-cigarette vapor! (Published on April 23, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Latest CDC Data Confirms E-Cigarette Use Correlates with Declines in Smoking</title><link>https://www.realclearhealth.com/articles/2025/04/23/latest_cdc_data_confirms_e-cigarette_use_correlates_with_declines_in_smoking_1105928.html</link><description>The latest CDC report shows adult smoking at its lowest in 60 years. Yet, concerns shift to rising e-cigarette use, despite many using them to quit smoking. Misinformation surrounds tobacco harm reduction products, with the CDC downplaying e-cigarettes' harm reduction potential. Policies backed by Bloomberg are pushed, despite their misleading labeling of e-cigarettes as tobacco products. E-cigarettes are proven to be significantly less harmful than cigarettes. The CDC's skepticism towards e-cigarettes contrasts with their effectiveness in smoking cessation. The influence of Michael Bloomberg on public health policies raises questions of objectivity. Despite opposition, harm reduction efforts are reducing smoking rates, especially through e-cigarettes. (Published on April 23, 2025byrealclearhealth.com)</description></item><item><title>Michael Bloomberg Won His Vietnam War on Vaping</title><link>https://filtermag.org/michael-bloomberg-vietnam-vape-ban/</link><description>Vietnam battles a significant smoking issue, with over 100,000 deaths annually. Despite economic growth, per capita income remains low. The country recently banned nicotine vapes, potentially due to protecting the government-owned tobacco industry and influenced by misinformation. The ban could lead to thriving illicit markets, while ignoring evidence that vaping bans may increase smoking rates. Contrary to facts, various organizations, including Bloomberg Philanthropies and the WHO, support the ban. The UK’s success with reducing smoking using alternative nicotine products is overlooked. Proponents argue for safer options, highlighting that bans may harm public health. (Published on April 23, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item></channel></rss>