<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 09:35:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Terengganu enforces ban on e-cigarettes, vapes starting Aug 1</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/news/nation/2025/04/24/terengganu-enforces-ban-on-e-cigarettes-vapes-starting-aug-1#goog_rewarded</link><description>Terengganu will ban e-cigarettes and vapes sales starting August 1, following a state government decision on April 23. The ban includes advertising and revoking business licenses, with penalties for non-compliance. The government aims to protect public health, especially of the youth, from the negative effects of these products. Further measures will be taken to enforce the ban effectively, including penalties for violators and no acceptance of sponsorship from vape producers. Additionally, support will be provided to employees in the vape industry for transitioning to other sustainable job opportunities through entrepreneurship courses. (Published on April 24, 2025bythestar.com.my)</description></item><item><title>New Zealand Researcher Claims that Using E-Cigarettes Coats the Lungs With Oil</title><link>https://tobaccoanalysis.blogspot.com/2025/04/new-zealand-researcher-claims-that.html</link><description>An electronic cigarette researcher from Auckland University's Bio Engineering Institute is telling the public that when people use e-cigarettes, their lungs become coated with oil, leading to inflammation that eventually causes lung disease. According to an article in RNZ, the professor is quoted as stating: "Every time you vape, some of that will stay inside your lungs, so the e-liquids that are in vapes are sort of quite an oily substance. There'll be a lining of this oil that will stay inside your lungs and actually one of the things that is designed to get rid of that is the process of inflammation. It's when you have this inflammation occurring many times a day over many years, which is what leads to disease and tissue breakdown." (Published on April 24, 2025byblogspot.com)</description></item><item><title>Smoking cessation drug varenicline helps young adults quit vaping, clinical trial reveals</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-04-cessation-drug-varenicline-young-adults.html</link><description>Teens and young adults who used varenicline had over three times the success rate quitting vaping compared to those receiving counseling only, as per a Mass General Brigham study published in JAMA. Varenicline, proven effective for smoking cessation in adults, showed no participants returning to cigarettes. The study highlights the importance of medication in aiding young nicotine addicts, with varenicline offering a safe and effective solution for 16-to-25-year-olds looking to quit vaping. Research on alternative therapies and younger age groups is warranted. In addressing adolescent vaping addiction, varenicline emerged as a successful treatment avenue with no reported safety concerns. (Published on April 24, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>A Cup of Tea With My Anti-Vaping Neighbor</title><link>https://filtermag.org/cup-tea-anti-vaping-neighbor/</link><description>Sarah, a neighbor in rural Wales, and I have a unique friendship despite our differences. She's skeptical about vaping and disapproves of nicotine vapes, even after quitting smoking. Her main source is the Daily Mail, which paints vaping negatively. I, on the other hand, advocate for tobacco harm reduction, highlighting vaping's benefits. Sarah's personal experiences shape her views, and she believes in quitting cold turkey over vaping. While she supports individual choices, she prefers willpower for quitting. To reconsider her stance on vaping, she would require extensive long-term research. Our contrasting perspectives create engaging discussions over tea and cake. (Published on April 24, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Letitia James’ morally confused attack on the vaping industry</title><link>https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2025/apr/23/letitia-james-morally-confused-attack-vaping-industry/</link><description>The author criticizes what they see as moral confusion on the political left. They highlight the irony of exposing young teens to drag shows while shielding college-aged adults from conservative ideas. This perceived reversal of priorities also appears in attitudes toward vaping. Although the author doesn’t support vaping, they note it is less harmful than smoking cigarettes or marijuana and is often used by hardworking individuals as a step away from smoking. This contradiction further illustrates, in their view, how backward Democratic values have become. (Published on April 24, 2025bywashingtontimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Spain risks undoing smoking success with vape ban, report warns</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/spain-risks-undoing-smoking-success-with-vape-ban-report-warns/</link><description>Spain's smoking rates dropped last year, but new restrictions on vapes and nicotine alternatives may reverse this progress. Proposed regulations include an excise duty and flavor bans, limiting nicotine strength, and hindering access. Unlike Spain, Sweden has successfully reduced smoking rates by embracing safer alternatives. Spain risks missing an opportunity for positive change by imposing stringent limitations that contradict successful strategies. The country has struggled with high smoking rates, leading to numerous tobacco-related deaths. Learning from Sweden's success could be key to further reducing smoking rates in Spain. (Published on April 24, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item></channel></rss>