<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 10:42:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vaping trends shift as UK ban drives switch from disposable to reusable devices</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250421/Vaping-trends-shift-as-UK-ban-drives-switch-from-disposable-to-reusable-devices.aspx</link><description>British disposable vape ban announcement in 2024 led to a decline in e-cigarette use rates, with users switching to refillable devices. A study tracked these changes, highlighting the influence of policy on health decisions. Since 2021, youth vaping surged due to disposable vapes' appeal, prompting UK bans in 2025. Manufacturers now offer reusable alternatives. Findings suggest a shift away from disposables, indicating potential declines in vape usage. Policies play a crucial role in curbing vaping trends. Researchers analyzed data from the Smoking Toolkit Study, revealing a shift towards refillable devices post-ban. The move towards sustainability in vaping indicates positive environmental impacts but may not drastically reduce overall vaping rates. (Published on April 22, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #62 | UNSMOKE THE WORLD | Inside PMI’s Mission to End Cigarettes</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-62-unsmoke-the-world-inside-pmis-mission-to-end-cigarettes/</link><description>In 2016, PMI pledged to transition the company away from cigarette sales - and almost ten years later, they've made progress towards their promise. But instead of celebrating as 40% of PMI's business goes smoke-free, many in tobacco control would rather stand in the way. Why is that? And can anything be done to change their minds? (Published on April 22, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>