<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 16:30:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>​Pouches gain popularity amid shifts in tobacco use</title><link>https://www.royalgazette.com/local-business/business/article/20250429/pouches-gain-popularity-amid-shifts-in-tobacco-use/</link><description>Nicotine pouches are becoming popular in Bermuda as a cleaner alternative to smoking and vaping, especially among younger consumers. These pouches release synthetic or tobacco-derived nicotine without tobacco leaves, appealing to users seeking a smoke-free option. The global nicotine pouch market is growing, with recent FDA approval in the US and success in Europe. Despite challenges like rising tariffs, interest in zero-nicotine options is on the rise. The pouches are gaining attention for potential health benefits, including research linking nicotine to improved cognitive function. The trend towards alternative tobacco products is expected to continue based on consumer health trends. (Published on April 29, 2025byroyalgazette.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Insights #6 | GFN SCIENCE SPECIAL: The physics of vaporisation in e-cigarettes | Featuring Roberto Sussman</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-insights-6-gfn-science-special-the-physics-of-vaporisation-in-e-cigarettes-featuring-roberto-sussman/</link><description>In the third episode of our science special, Roberto Sussman looks at the thermal processes that take place in vaporisation, and the impact different solvents have on the vaporisation temperature of e-liquids. (Published on April 30, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>