<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 11:18:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>We know how to end smoking</title><link>https://medium.com/the-great-vape-debate/we-know-how-to-end-smoking-8024451e7a5b</link><description>Governments, WHO, and public interest groups obstruct the shift from deadly combustible cigarettes to safer alternatives like e-cigarettes. The transition, progressing rapidly in countries like Sweden and Japan, offers hope in ending smoking. Despite the reduced harm of new nicotine products, efforts to accelerate the switch face resistance. Influential bodies like WHO and nonprofits like Campaign for Tobacco Free Kids oppose e-cigarettes. Supported by Bloomberg, they hinder progress in low- and middle-income countries by advocating against safer options. (Published on May 02, 2025bymedium.com)</description></item><item><title>Vape Bans Averted in TN and ND—Just Not for Public Health Reasons</title><link>https://filtermag.org/vape-bans-averted-in-tn-and-nd-just-not-for-public-health-reasons/</link><description>State-level PMTA registry bills have posed a threat to vaping by potentially banning most products tied to FDA approval. Some states already shut down vape shops, limiting harm reduction options. Despite concerns, Tennessee and North Dakota revised their bills, shifting focus to US-made products. North Dakota abandoned its proposal due to advocacy efforts, emphasizing American-made items. Fear-based policymaking and misinformation still influence decisions, impacting harm reduction progress. The political shift reflects trade interests more than public health. However, the compromised bills in Tennessee and North Dakota preserve access to nicotine alternatives, pending Governor Lee's approval. Challenges persist for over 650,000 adult vapers in these states amidst ongoing regulatory uncertainties. (Published on May 02, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item></channel></rss>