<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 12:53:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Conservatives to end pharmacy only rule for nicotine pouches, ‘freedom of choice’</title><link>https://www.westernstandard.news/canadian/conservatives-to-end-pharmacy-only-rule-for-nicotine-pouches-freedom-of-choice/64318</link><description>A Conservative government plans to allow smokers to purchase nicotine pouches at corner stores and gas stations, overturning the Liberal policy of restricting sales to pharmacies under the Food and Drugs Act. The Conservatives emphasize freedom of choice for adults and access to less harmful alternatives for those trying to quit smoking. Currently, Health Canada has licensed Zonnic as a nicotine pouch for smoking cessation. (Published on April 28, 2025bywesternstandard.news)</description></item><item><title>Free vape kits boost quit rate among smokers, report finds</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/free-vape-kits-boost-quit-rate-among-smokers-report-finds/</link><description>A report reveals that distributing free vapes in Calderdale, UK, increased successful quit rates from 64% to 75%. Yorkshire Cancer Research funded the trial, showing vapes as effective in aiding cessation. Yorkshire Smokefree Calderdale now offers vape kits alongside other support services. Of the 1,110 participants, 77% using vapes or NRT quit successfully after four weeks. Vapes were preferred over other methods, especially by women and those aged 55-59, and proved cost-effective. The trial positively impacted disadvantaged communities, with 82% finding the offer of a vape device encouraging. Similar schemes in the UK have also led to successful vaping transitions among smokers. (Published on April 28, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>BAT to stop selling vape products from 3Q25</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/business/business-news/2025/04/28/bat-to-stop-selling-vape-products-from-3q25</link><description>British American Tobacco (M) Bhd will discontinue its VUSE e-cigarette range in Malaysia by the third quarter of 2025 to comply with new regulations under Act 852, effective from Oct 1, 2025. The company anticipates minimal financial impact for the year ending Dec 31, 2025. BAT will assess its VUSE products commercially and prioritize combustible value growth while managing operational risks. (Published on April 28, 2025bythestar.com.my)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco use in Alaska continues to decline, though rates still above US averages</title><link>https://alaskabeacon.com/2025/04/28/tobacco-use-in-alaska-continues-to-decline-though-rates-still-above-u-s-averages/</link><description>Smoking rates in Alaska have steadily declined over the past decades, according to a new report from the state's Department of Health. Adult smoking dropped from 28% in the 1990s to 16% in 2023, with significant decreases also among Alaska Native adults. Despite this progress, about one in four adults still used tobacco or nicotine products in 2023. Among youth, both cigarette and e-cigarette use have also fallen, showing the success of public health campaigns. (Published on April 28, 2025byalaskabeacon.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #149 | VIETNAM'S VAPE BAN EXPOSED | Featuring Will Godfrey</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-149/</link><description>In this episode Will Godfrey highlights the interconnected links between Vietnam's recent vape ban and the influence of Bloomberg-funded entities, and how the well-funded opposition to tobacco harm reduction influences vape restrictions across the globe. (Published on April 28, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>What are ‘penjamins’? Disguised cannabis vapes are gaining popularity among young people</title><link>https://theconversation.com/what-are-penjamins-disguised-cannabis-vapes-are-gaining-popularity-among-young-people-254572</link><description>Cannabis vaping has become popular in Australia, particularly among young people using discreet devices like "penjamins" to vape cannabis oil. While cannabis vapes are illegal in Australia, illicit products are still available. The practice poses health risks, with high THC concentrations potentially leading to addiction, psychosis, and respiratory problems. Solvents and additives in cannabis vapes can also cause severe lung injuries. Comparing the risks of cannabis and nicotine vapes is complex, as both have different health implications, especially for young users. (Published on April 28, 2025bytheconversation.com)</description></item><item><title>VIDEO: Alarm over health risks of nicotine pouches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/alarm-over-health-risks-of-nicotine-pouches/105231264</link><description>Griffith Social Marketing Research Fellow James Duel says the dissolvable pouches, known as Zyn, 'snus' or 'zins' are being aimed at young people. (Published on April 29, 2025byabc.net.au)</description></item><item><title>The WHO's Failure to Protect Health: A TPA Webinar</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ba1WElqd2aI</link><description>In this webinar leading up to the World Health Organization's COP11 conference, TPA's Martin Cullip and David Williams sit down with subject-matter experts Roger Bate and Clive Bates to discuss how the WHO has not been living up to its ultimate mission of protecting public health. (Published on April 29, 2025byyoutube.com)</description></item><item><title>The fightback begins: Sweden seeks to block Spanish pouch ban</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/the-fightback-begins-sweden-seeks-to-block-spanish-pouch-ban/</link><description>The Swedish government plans to challenge Spain’s proposed ban on nicotine pouches at the EU level by submitting a Detailed Opinion to delay implementation. Sweden argues that pouches should be allowed where smoking is permitted. France has a similar ban, but with even stricter penalties. Although Sweden is exempt from the EU's ban on tobacco-containing snus, this exemption does not apply to nicotine pouches. The Minister assured that Sweden will oppose any EU-wide ban on pouches as long as their government is in power. (Published on April 29, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Sociedad La evidencia científica que podría transformar las políticas contra el tabaquismo en Europa</title><link>https://www.elplural.com/sociedad/evidencia-cientifica-transformar-politicas-tabaquismo-europa_350907102</link><description>The fight against smoking has long been a public health priority, and recent policy successes are evident. However, a new study led by a researcher from Linköping University challenges conventional views on nicotine and suggests a need to rethink health policies in Europe. With over 30 years of research experience in obesity, diabetes, and nicotine, the author emphasizes the importance of distinguishing between tobacco smoke and nicotine itself. The study focused on the effects of snus, a smokeless tobacco product legal in Sweden but banned elsewhere in Europe. Controlled experiments with medical students showed that snus caused only a slight increase in blood pressure—similar to a cup of coffee—indicating that nicotine alone may not pose the same cardiovascular risks as tobacco smoke. (Published on April 29, 2025byelplural.com)</description></item></channel></rss>