<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 22:37:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Survey of Current Tobacco and Nicotine Product Users to Identify Barriers to Quitting Smoking in Germany</title><link>https://www.cureus.com/articles/348098-a-survey-of-current-tobacco-and-nicotine-product-users-to-identify-barriers-to-quitting-smoking-in-germany?score_article=true#!/</link><description>Smoking rates remain high in Germany despite the well-known serious health risks. This survey assessed motivation to stop smoking in Germany and barriers to quitting smoking or switching to two types of smoke-free products (SFPs): e-cigarettes (E-cigs) and heated tobacco products (HTPs). (Published on April 17, 2025bycureus.com)</description></item><item><title>Greece: Flavour Ban Threatens Public Health Progress</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/greece-flavour-ban-threatens-public-health-progress/</link><description>Consumer advocates and vaping organizations warn against Greece's proposed ban on vape flavors, fearing it will reverse progress in reducing smoking rates. The ban could push adults back to smoking or the black market, ignoring evidence that flavors help smokers quit. Advocates urge policymakers to prioritize harm reduction, engage with experts, and consider evidence-based regulations to protect youth without penalizing adult smokers. (Published on April 17, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Why CDC cuts are being called ‘the greatest gift to tobacco industry in the last half-century’</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/04/14/cdc-closing-office-smoking-health-called-gift-to-big-tobacco-by-former-osh-director/</link><description>Terrie Hall, a former smoker, appeared in anti-smoking ads despite battling cancer. The campaign, run by the CDC, helped millions quit smoking. Following recent closures at the Office on Smoking and Health (OSH), funded by the CDC, concerns arise about the future of tobacco control efforts. Former employees fear a setback in progress, potentially leading to increased smoking rates. With the shutdown of OSH and changes at the FDA's Center for Tobacco Products, monitoring of tobacco trends and regulations is at risk. The move coincides with a positive climate for the tobacco industry, raising worries about public health consequences amidst reduced federal support for anti-smoking initiatives. (Published on April 17, 2025bystatnews.com)</description></item><item><title>Lunch Hour Ep. 131 - Guy Bentley</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gzDOkwK44XM</link><description>In this episode of The Lunch Hour with Andrew Langer, we're joined by Guy Bentley, Director of Consumer Freedom Research at the Reason Foundation. From the moral panic over vaping and the myth of “no safe level” of alcohol, to the creeping hand of public health regulation, Guy makes the case for evidence-based policy and the preservation of individual liberty. (Published on April 17, 2025byyoutube.com)</description></item><item><title>Danish flavour ban fail: nicotine restrictions backfire</title><link>https://snusforumet.se/en/danish-flavour-ban-fail-nicotine-restrictions-backfire/</link><description>Danish vaping restrictions, including a flavour ban, have not curbed youth vaping, with usage almost doubling in two years. Banned flavours are still popular, revealing the limited effectiveness of such bans. A Danish Health Authority report shows a shift from smoking to vaping, especially among young adults. Illegal markets for banned vape flavours are thriving, highlighting the failure of overregulation. Concerns are raised over proposed stricter regulations, with calls to learn from Swedish harm reduction policies. Despite intentions to reduce youth vaping, the Danish flavour ban is deemed unsuccessful, prompting reevaluation of current and future regulations by industry experts. (Published on April 17, 2025bysnusforumet.se)</description></item><item><title>Gen Zyn: Nicotine Pouches Help Curb Youth Smoking Rates</title><link>https://reason.com/2025/04/15/gen-zyn-nicotine-pouches-help-curb-youth-smoking-rates/</link><description>Young adults are increasingly turning to Zyn oral nicotine pouches over e-cigarettes, with rising popularity and positive impacts on smoking rates. These pouches provide a discreet and varied nicotine experience, appealing to a diverse audience including women and athletes. Despite concerns from some policymakers, Zyn offers a safer alternative to traditional tobacco products. Caution is advised to avoid potential side effects of overuse. Regulators should recognize and support the benefits of these products in reducing smoking rates, rather than restricting access. (Published on April 17, 2025byreason.com)</description></item></channel></rss>