<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 15:39:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Greece Set to Ban Teen-Friendly Flavoured E-Cigarettes</title><link>https://greekreporter.com/2025/04/23/greece-set-ban-teen-friendly-flavored-e-cigarettes/</link><description>Greece is preparing a bill to ban all flavoured e-cigarettes and alternative tobacco products, aiming to make their sale out-of-reach for Greek teenagers. Under the draft law, flavours like biscuit, chocolate, watermelon, fruit and even whiskey, which are particularly popular among both teenagers and adults, would be pulled off the market, with only tobacco and mint flavours spared. The e-cigarette sector in Greece employs about 10,000 people, including 2,000 specialized retailers. (Published on April 23, 2025bygreekreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Four sentenced for smuggling tobacco, on-selling cigarettes from Gisborne restaurant</title><link>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/national/558879/four-sentenced-for-smuggling-tobacco-on-selling-cigarettes-from-gisborne-restaurant</link><description>Four individuals involved in an illegal tobacco importing scheme in Gisborne were sentenced. Two men received home detention for defrauding Customs revenue and other charges, while an older couple was fined and ordered to pay court costs for their lesser roles. Customs discovered undeclared cigarettes and loose tobacco disguised as Chinese tea in airmail packages, totaling 306,200 cigarettes and 110kg of tobacco. The operation involved selling the goods in a restaurant. Customs' investigations led to the discovery of cash and tobacco products, resulting in charges under the Customs and Excise Act 2018. Customs Officer Bevan Cameron highlighted the significant duty evasion and fraud involved. (Published on April 23, 2025byrnz.co.nz)</description></item></channel></rss>