<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 15:35:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Cup of Tea With My Anti-Vaping Neighbor</title><link>https://filtermag.org/cup-tea-anti-vaping-neighbor/</link><description>Sarah, a neighbor in rural Wales, and I have a unique friendship despite our differences. She's skeptical about vaping and disapproves of nicotine vapes, even after quitting smoking. Her main source is the Daily Mail, which paints vaping negatively. I, on the other hand, advocate for tobacco harm reduction, highlighting vaping's benefits. Sarah's personal experiences shape her views, and she believes in quitting cold turkey over vaping. While she supports individual choices, she prefers willpower for quitting. To reconsider her stance on vaping, she would require extensive long-term research. Our contrasting perspectives create engaging discussions over tea and cake. (Published on April 24, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Letitia James’ morally confused attack on the vaping industry</title><link>https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2025/apr/23/letitia-james-morally-confused-attack-vaping-industry/</link><description>The author criticizes what they see as moral confusion on the political left. They highlight the irony of exposing young teens to drag shows while shielding college-aged adults from conservative ideas. This perceived reversal of priorities also appears in attitudes toward vaping. Although the author doesn’t support vaping, they note it is less harmful than smoking cigarettes or marijuana and is often used by hardworking individuals as a step away from smoking. This contradiction further illustrates, in their view, how backward Democratic values have become. (Published on April 24, 2025bywashingtontimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Spain risks undoing smoking success with vape ban, report warns</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/spain-risks-undoing-smoking-success-with-vape-ban-report-warns/</link><description>Spain's smoking rates dropped last year, but new restrictions on vapes and nicotine alternatives may reverse this progress. Proposed regulations include an excise duty and flavor bans, limiting nicotine strength, and hindering access. Unlike Spain, Sweden has successfully reduced smoking rates by embracing safer alternatives. Spain risks missing an opportunity for positive change by imposing stringent limitations that contradict successful strategies. The country has struggled with high smoking rates, leading to numerous tobacco-related deaths. Learning from Sweden's success could be key to further reducing smoking rates in Spain. (Published on April 24, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Greece Considers Ban on Flavored E-Cigarettes</title><link>https://greekcitytimes.com/2025/04/25/greece-considers-ban-on-flavored-e-cigarettes/</link><description>Greece's conservative government plans to ban flavored alternative tobacco products, excluding natural tobacco and mint. The legislation aims to restrict minors' access to alcohol and tobacco, eliminating popular flavors appealing to youth and potentially affecting 10,000 employees. The bill, nearing completion, faces challenges, like needing EU approval and criticism for possibly restricting adult consumers. Despite the high smoking rate, analysts support the focus on limiting underage access. The move aligns with ongoing EU discussions on revising tobacco laws amid the rise of alternative products like e-cigarettes and heated tobacco. (Published on April 25, 2025bygreekcitytimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Stricter controls better than total ban on vape products, says expert</title><link>https://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2025/04/24/stricter-controls-better-than-total-ban-on-vape-products-says-expert</link><description>Deputy inspector Ayob Khan Mydin Pitchay revealed students as young as 13 using drug-laced vape. Public health expert Dr. Sharifa Ezat Wan Puteh suggests controlling high-risk vape products instead of banning them. She advocates for regulations allowing safer options for smokers. Dr. Lee Boon Chye emphasizes reducing youth appeal towards vapes by limiting nicotine and removing fruity flavors. Both experts agree banning vapes is not the ideal solution. They propose regulating vape liquid content and tightening import controls to tackle the issue effectively. (Published on April 25, 2025byfreemalaysiatoday.com)</description></item><item><title>The public health playbook</title><link>https://thecritic.co.uk/the-public-health-playbook/</link><description>The British Medical Journal (BMJ) has revealed that outdoor advertising companies are using tactics similar to those of the tobacco industry to oppose local councils’ attempts to ban junk food ads on bus shelters and billboards. An investigation by Sophie Borland, a former Daily Mail health editor, found that these companies have been lobbying against policies that could harm their business. Borland sent Freedom of Information requests to 52 of England’s 317 local authorities and uncovered evidence of attempts by the advertising industry to influence policy in eight of them. Sources suggest that the actual number could be even higher. (Published on April 25, 2025bythecritic.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Beneficial and Harmful Tobacco-Use Transitions Associated With ENDS in the U.S.</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S074937972500025X</link><description>This study analyzed U.S. data to assess transitions in tobacco use related to ENDS (e-cigarettes). While 2.1 million people made beneficial transitions from combustible tobacco to ENDS or quit with ENDS support, 4.6 million made harmful transitions, including nonusers starting ENDS or ENDS users switching to combustible tobacco. Overall, harmful transitions outnumbered beneficial ones by more than 2 to 1. However, with proper regulation, ENDS could provide net public health benefits. (Published on April 25, 2025bysciencedirect.com)</description></item><item><title>HK seeks to ban e-cigarettes in public in April 2026</title><link>https://hongkongfp.com/2025/04/25/hong-kong-seeks-to-ban-e-cigarettes-in-public-in-april-2026/</link><description>Hong Kong plans to ban e-cigarettes and smoking in public places by April 2026. The Tobacco Control Legislation (Amendment) Bill 2025 introduces fines of HK$3,000 for violators. The bill also includes expanding no-smoking areas and doubling fines for smoking violations. Flavoured tobacco sales will be phased out by the second quarter of 2027. Stricter measures on illegal cigarettes include labeling requirements for every pack sold. The proposal aims to deter smoking among youth. Additionally, providing smoking products to minors will result in fines up to HK$25,000. The government's goal is to enhance public health and reduce smoking prevalence. (Published on April 25, 2025byhongkongfp.com)</description></item></channel></rss>