<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 16:30:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Missouri to research viability of issuing more adult-use marijuana licenses</title><link>https://mjbizdaily.com/research-firms-compete-to-study-missouri-adult-use-marijuana-market-licensing/</link><description>Three research firms — Cannabis Public Policy Consulting (New York), Capital Consulting Services (St. Louis), and Whitney Economics (Oregon) — are competing to study Missouri’s cannabis market. The goal is to help the state decide whether to issue more adult-use marijuana business licenses. All firms agree that Missouri’s recreational cannabis market, launched in 2022, has been a success. Experts say the success is largely due to the state issuing only the minimum number of licenses allowed by its constitution. (Published on May 02, 2025bymjbizdaily.com)</description></item><item><title>Swedish Government: Absurd Pouch Restrictions Restrict Free Movement of Goods in the EU</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/swedish-government-absurd-pouch-restrictions-restrict-free-movement-of-goods-in-the-eu/</link><description>EU governments are imposing stricter regulations on nicotine pouches, with Spain proposing a 0.99 mg limit, potentially hampering free movement of goods. Sweden challenges this move, citing EU laws. Precedents like the Cassis de Dijon case and the German Beer Purity Law indicate that such restrictions may violate EU trade laws. Spain's proposal lacks scientific basis, leaning towards de facto bans. The arbitrary limit may face legal obstacles based on past rulings, emphasizing EU principles on free trade. The EU must intervene to ensure fair market access and support safer alternatives for smokers in Spain. (Published on May 02, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine Patch for Long COVID or Alzheimer’s? Why Nicotine?</title><link>https://www.peoplespharmacy.com/articles/nicotine-patch-for-alzheimers-could-nicotine-help-you-remember</link><description>For decades, nicotine has been viewed primarily as a harmful and addictive substance — the main reason people become hooked on cigarettes and other tobacco products. Humans have used tobacco for over 12,000 years, whether by smoking, chewing, or sniffing it. In more recent years, pharmaceutical companies have developed nicotine patches, gums, and lozenges to help people quit smoking — all available without a prescription. However, new research is beginning to challenge this one-sided view. Scientists are now exploring whether nicotine might also offer potential therapeutic benefits. Some studies suggest it could help people suffering from long COVID or Alzheimer’s disease. This emerging perspective could change how we understand and use nicotine in modern medicine. (Published on May 02, 2025bypeoplespharmacy.com)</description></item><item><title>We know how to end smoking</title><link>https://medium.com/the-great-vape-debate/we-know-how-to-end-smoking-8024451e7a5b</link><description>Governments, WHO, and public interest groups obstruct the shift from deadly combustible cigarettes to safer alternatives like e-cigarettes. The transition, progressing rapidly in countries like Sweden and Japan, offers hope in ending smoking. Despite the reduced harm of new nicotine products, efforts to accelerate the switch face resistance. Influential bodies like WHO and nonprofits like Campaign for Tobacco Free Kids oppose e-cigarettes. Supported by Bloomberg, they hinder progress in low- and middle-income countries by advocating against safer options. (Published on May 02, 2025bymedium.com)</description></item><item><title>Vape Bans Averted in TN and ND—Just Not for Public Health Reasons</title><link>https://filtermag.org/vape-bans-averted-in-tn-and-nd-just-not-for-public-health-reasons/</link><description>State-level PMTA registry bills have posed a threat to vaping by potentially banning most products tied to FDA approval. Some states already shut down vape shops, limiting harm reduction options. Despite concerns, Tennessee and North Dakota revised their bills, shifting focus to US-made products. North Dakota abandoned its proposal due to advocacy efforts, emphasizing American-made items. Fear-based policymaking and misinformation still influence decisions, impacting harm reduction progress. The political shift reflects trade interests more than public health. However, the compromised bills in Tennessee and North Dakota preserve access to nicotine alternatives, pending Governor Lee's approval. Challenges persist for over 650,000 adult vapers in these states amidst ongoing regulatory uncertainties. (Published on May 02, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item></channel></rss>