<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 17:32:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN Insights #5 | GFN SCIENCE SPECIAL: Back to the fundamentals | Episode 2 | Featuring Roberto Sussman</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-insights-5/</link><description>In the second part of our science special, Roberto Sussman takes us through the fundamental physics of vape aerosols to help explain the difference between cigarette smoke and e-cigarette vapor! (Published on April 23, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Latest CDC Data Confirms E-Cigarette Use Correlates with Declines in Smoking</title><link>https://www.realclearhealth.com/articles/2025/04/23/latest_cdc_data_confirms_e-cigarette_use_correlates_with_declines_in_smoking_1105928.html</link><description>The latest CDC report shows adult smoking at its lowest in 60 years. Yet, concerns shift to rising e-cigarette use, despite many using them to quit smoking. Misinformation surrounds tobacco harm reduction products, with the CDC downplaying e-cigarettes' harm reduction potential. Policies backed by Bloomberg are pushed, despite their misleading labeling of e-cigarettes as tobacco products. E-cigarettes are proven to be significantly less harmful than cigarettes. The CDC's skepticism towards e-cigarettes contrasts with their effectiveness in smoking cessation. The influence of Michael Bloomberg on public health policies raises questions of objectivity. Despite opposition, harm reduction efforts are reducing smoking rates, especially through e-cigarettes. (Published on April 23, 2025byrealclearhealth.com)</description></item><item><title>Michael Bloomberg Won His Vietnam War on Vaping</title><link>https://filtermag.org/michael-bloomberg-vietnam-vape-ban/</link><description>Vietnam battles a significant smoking issue, with over 100,000 deaths annually. Despite economic growth, per capita income remains low. The country recently banned nicotine vapes, potentially due to protecting the government-owned tobacco industry and influenced by misinformation. The ban could lead to thriving illicit markets, while ignoring evidence that vaping bans may increase smoking rates. Contrary to facts, various organizations, including Bloomberg Philanthropies and the WHO, support the ban. The UK’s success with reducing smoking using alternative nicotine products is overlooked. Proponents argue for safer options, highlighting that bans may harm public health. (Published on April 23, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Terengganu enforces ban on e-cigarettes, vapes starting Aug 1</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/news/nation/2025/04/24/terengganu-enforces-ban-on-e-cigarettes-vapes-starting-aug-1#goog_rewarded</link><description>Terengganu will ban e-cigarettes and vapes sales starting August 1, following a state government decision on April 23. The ban includes advertising and revoking business licenses, with penalties for non-compliance. The government aims to protect public health, especially of the youth, from the negative effects of these products. Further measures will be taken to enforce the ban effectively, including penalties for violators and no acceptance of sponsorship from vape producers. Additionally, support will be provided to employees in the vape industry for transitioning to other sustainable job opportunities through entrepreneurship courses. (Published on April 24, 2025bythestar.com.my)</description></item><item><title>New Zealand Researcher Claims that Using E-Cigarettes Coats the Lungs With Oil</title><link>https://tobaccoanalysis.blogspot.com/2025/04/new-zealand-researcher-claims-that.html</link><description>An electronic cigarette researcher from Auckland University's Bio Engineering Institute is telling the public that when people use e-cigarettes, their lungs become coated with oil, leading to inflammation that eventually causes lung disease. According to an article in RNZ, the professor is quoted as stating: "Every time you vape, some of that will stay inside your lungs, so the e-liquids that are in vapes are sort of quite an oily substance. There'll be a lining of this oil that will stay inside your lungs and actually one of the things that is designed to get rid of that is the process of inflammation. It's when you have this inflammation occurring many times a day over many years, which is what leads to disease and tissue breakdown." (Published on April 24, 2025byblogspot.com)</description></item><item><title>Smoking cessation drug varenicline helps young adults quit vaping, clinical trial reveals</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-04-cessation-drug-varenicline-young-adults.html</link><description>Teens and young adults who used varenicline had over three times the success rate quitting vaping compared to those receiving counseling only, as per a Mass General Brigham study published in JAMA. Varenicline, proven effective for smoking cessation in adults, showed no participants returning to cigarettes. The study highlights the importance of medication in aiding young nicotine addicts, with varenicline offering a safe and effective solution for 16-to-25-year-olds looking to quit vaping. Research on alternative therapies and younger age groups is warranted. In addressing adolescent vaping addiction, varenicline emerged as a successful treatment avenue with no reported safety concerns. (Published on April 24, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>A Cup of Tea With My Anti-Vaping Neighbor</title><link>https://filtermag.org/cup-tea-anti-vaping-neighbor/</link><description>Sarah, a neighbor in rural Wales, and I have a unique friendship despite our differences. She's skeptical about vaping and disapproves of nicotine vapes, even after quitting smoking. Her main source is the Daily Mail, which paints vaping negatively. I, on the other hand, advocate for tobacco harm reduction, highlighting vaping's benefits. Sarah's personal experiences shape her views, and she believes in quitting cold turkey over vaping. While she supports individual choices, she prefers willpower for quitting. To reconsider her stance on vaping, she would require extensive long-term research. Our contrasting perspectives create engaging discussions over tea and cake. (Published on April 24, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Letitia James’ morally confused attack on the vaping industry</title><link>https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2025/apr/23/letitia-james-morally-confused-attack-vaping-industry/</link><description>The author criticizes what they see as moral confusion on the political left. They highlight the irony of exposing young teens to drag shows while shielding college-aged adults from conservative ideas. This perceived reversal of priorities also appears in attitudes toward vaping. Although the author doesn’t support vaping, they note it is less harmful than smoking cigarettes or marijuana and is often used by hardworking individuals as a step away from smoking. This contradiction further illustrates, in their view, how backward Democratic values have become. (Published on April 24, 2025bywashingtontimes.com)</description></item></channel></rss>