<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 07:26:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Smoking/vaping combo poses health risks, research suggests</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-04-smokingvaping-combo-poses-health.html#google_vignette</link><description>A new study warns against the misconception that switching between cigarettes and vape pens reduces cancer risk. Dual users of both have similar exposure to nicotine and carcinogens as exclusive cigarette smokers. Tobacco cessation programs are urged as a safer alternative, as dual-use is deemed ineffective for health protection. Clinicians are advised to promote awareness on the risks of dual-use, emphasizing the importance of evidence-based cessation programs. Stronger FDA regulation of tobacco products, including illegal ones, is recommended to safeguard public health. The research underscores the need to prioritize tobacco prevention and cessation efforts. (Published on April 18, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Smoking – not nicotine – is the primary cause of cancer, says leading French oncologist</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/smoking-not-nicotine-is-the-primary-cause-of-cancer-says-leading-french-oncologist/</link><description>Leading French oncologist Dr. David Khayat highlighted that nicotine alternatives like vapes do not cause cancer, as carcinogens in tobacco come from combustion. He stated that products like vapes reduce harmful substances and should be used more to aid smoking cessation, with harm reduction being crucial. Khayat emphasized the importance of regulatory frameworks balancing access and preventing youth uptake of these alternatives. With smoking causing eight million global deaths yearly, he urged smokers to consider safer alternatives. Khayat's views align with a cardiologist's stance on nicotine's non-carcinogenic and non-heart-disease-causing properties, pointing towards tobacco harm reduction discussions at an upcoming WHO conference. (Published on April 18, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Guest Editorial: What a Former FDA Insider Gets Wrong About Vaping</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/8395/guest-editorial-what-a-former-fda-insider-gets-wrong-about-vaping/</link><description>David Oliveira, a former FDA official, criticizes mismanagement under Brian King and FDA's focus on optics over public health. He opposes the Biden Administration's menthol cigarette ban as pushing people to the black market. Oliveira calls for aggressive enforcement against flavored disposables, targeting unauthorized vape shops to combat vaping, particularly criticizing Chinese manufacturers and obscure product flavors. (Published on April 18, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>Health warnings as high-strength illicit nicotine pouches flood the UK</title><link>https://www.itv.com/news/2025-04-17/health-warnings-as-high-strength-illicit-nicotine-pouches-flood-the-uk</link><description>Illicit nicotine pouches are flooding the UK, posing health risks, especially to children. These legal products, initially designed to help adults quit smoking, are unregulated and can be highly potent. Trading Standards reported a 112% increase in seizures, with over 8,000 confiscated in a year. Nicotine pouches are popular among teenagers due to their flavors and packaging but can lead to nicotine poisoning. Experts suggest regulating their nicotine content to protect public health. Concerns include accidental ingestion by children, addiction, and adverse effects on mental health. Legislation aims to prevent sales to minors and curb appealing branding, but calls for further restrictions persist. (Published on April 18, 2025byitv.com)</description></item><item><title>Australia’s growing vaping black market offers a regulatory warning Europe must heed</title><link>https://eu-policies.com/news/australias-growing-vaping-black-market-offers-a-regulatory-warning-europe-must-heed/</link><description>Released in late March, Australia’s latest federal budget reveals a striking trend: tobacco excise tax revenue has nearly halved since 2019, with projected losses reaching A$10 billion (€5.6 billion) by 2029. Local media investigations over the past month have linked this growing budget deficit to the country’s booming tobacco and nicotine black markets, driven in large part by organised crime. Experts warn that this surge in illicit trade is an unintended consequence of Canberra’s overly restrictive vaping policies. (Published on April 18, 2025byeu-policies.com)</description></item><item><title>Health Ministry gives three months to take Tobacco Sales License</title><link>https://edition.mv/news/40616?ref=home-latest</link><description>The Ministry of Health is now accepting applications for the Tobacco Sales License, required under the Tobacco Control Act's recent amendment. A valid license from the Health Ministry is necessary for wholesale and retail sellers of tobacco products. Applications must be submitted within three months via the OneGov portal. Four licenses are needed for tobacco sales, each with a five-year validity and specific fees. Renewal applications should be made 60 days before the license expires. The fees range from MVR 5,000 for wholesale and retail to MVR 10,000 for import and re-export. Violations can result in fines from MVR 1,000 to MVR 1,000,000 and license revocation. (Published on April 18, 2025byedition.mv)</description></item></channel></rss>