<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 13:32:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Family Tragedy Spurs One Man’s Drive to Cut Smoking in South Africa</title><link>https://filtermag.org/south-africa-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>Kurt Yeo co-founded Vaping Saved My Life to promote tobacco harm reduction in South Africa. He switched from cigarettes to vapes after his father's smoking-related death and now advocates full-time. Yeo's VSML educates the public and challenges misinformation about vaping. Despite government opposition, he highlights how vaping can help combat smoking. Yeo's advocacy includes hosting a podcast, conducting surveys, and engaging with policymakers. South Africa faces challenges like the illicit cigarette trade and expensive smoking cessation aids. Yeo believes nicotine pouches could be a practical harm reduction solution. Policy changes aim to discourage vaping, but Yeo continues to fight for access to safer nicotine products to combat smoking rates. (Published on April 29, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>​Pouches gain popularity amid shifts in tobacco use</title><link>https://www.royalgazette.com/local-business/business/article/20250429/pouches-gain-popularity-amid-shifts-in-tobacco-use/</link><description>Nicotine pouches are becoming popular in Bermuda as a cleaner alternative to smoking and vaping, especially among younger consumers. These pouches release synthetic or tobacco-derived nicotine without tobacco leaves, appealing to users seeking a smoke-free option. The global nicotine pouch market is growing, with recent FDA approval in the US and success in Europe. Despite challenges like rising tariffs, interest in zero-nicotine options is on the rise. The pouches are gaining attention for potential health benefits, including research linking nicotine to improved cognitive function. The trend towards alternative tobacco products is expected to continue based on consumer health trends. (Published on April 29, 2025byroyalgazette.com)</description></item></channel></rss>