<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 12:25:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Swedish experience drives smoke-free future in Asia</title><link>https://scandasia.com/swedish-experience-drives-smoke-free-future-in-asia/</link><description>Sweden's successful move towards becoming smoke-free is influencing Asia, particularly the Philippines, where Japan Tobacco International (JTI) introduced nicotine pouches. With only 5.4% daily smokers in Sweden, the country attributes this to strict regulations and alternative options. JTI's Nordic Spirit, produced in Sweden, has gained popularity in the Philippines. JTI focuses on former smokers in Sweden, with positive results. The Philippines' familiarity with oral products made Nordic Spirit well-received. JTI tailored the product for the local market with affordable pricing. This initiative competes with other similar products, signaling a potential shift in global tobacco trends and a new direction for Asian markets. (Published on August 25, 2025byscandasia.com)</description></item><item><title>Time to get real on taxing cigarettes and restricting vapes</title><link>https://johnmenadue.com/post/2025/08/time-to-get-real-on-taxing-cigarettes-and-restricting-vapes/</link><description>Australia has the world's priciest cigarettes due to a 340% excise increase over 20 years. However, this led to a rise in illegal cigarette consumption. Economist Chris Richardson estimates a yearly $10 billion loss in government revenue. Vaping restrictions and high tobacco prices fuel a violent black market, contrasting with New Zealand's successful vape policies. Political parties overlook this issue while tobacco companies shift to safer products. Australia debates harm reduction, lacking evidence against vaping's benefits. Following New Zealand's lead could curb the black market. (Published on August 25, 2025byjohnmenadue.com)</description></item></channel></rss>