<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 06:18:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Uzbekistan enacts ban on electronic cigarettes and nicotine devices</title><link>https://www.trend.az/business/4123132.html</link><description>Uzbekistan has criminalized the circulation of electronic cigarettes and related products under recent amendments to the Law. Offenders face fines, corrective labor, restriction of liberty, or imprisonment. Those reporting violations are exempt from liability. The draft law on this matter was approved by the Senate in April. (Published on November 28, 2025bytrend.az)</description></item><item><title>WHO urges Vietnam to add e-cigarettes, heated tobacco to banned investment list</title><link>https://news.tuoitre.vn/who-urges-vietnam-to-add-e-cigarettes-heated-tobacco-to-banned-investment-list-103251127163912011.htm</link><description>The WHO is calling on Vietnam to explicitly add e-cigarettes and heated tobacco products to its banned investment list. Although a nationwide ban on their production, trade, import, and use is set to take effect in 2025, the products are still widely available. WHO warns that failing to include them in the Investment Law may leave loopholes for companies to continue producing or exporting them. The organization also points to hospital data showing a significant decrease in related emergency cases after the ban, arguing this strengthens the case for stricter legal measures. (Published on November 28, 2025bytuoitre.vn)</description></item><item><title>Government urged to drop plans to tax zero-nicotine vape products</title><link>https://www.conveniencestore.co.uk/news/government-urged-to-drop-plans-to-tax-zero-nicotine-vape-products/712448.article#toggle</link><description>ECigone opposes the Vaping Products Duty (VPD) taxing zero-nicotine vapes, arguing it hinders smoking cessation efforts. Set to start on October 1, 2026, the £2.20 per 10mls tax will apply regardless of nicotine content. Founder Shane Margereson believes taxing all vapes equally discourages smokers from decreasing nicotine levels and manufacturers from producing zero-nicotine options, slowing harm reduction and quitting progress. Requesting policymakers to exempt 0mg vapes from taxation, he emphasizes the need for strategic regulation that supports smoking cessation. Margereson suggests a minor adjustment in tax policy could greatly benefit public health. (Published on November 28, 2025byconveniencestore.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Why New Zealand failed to reach its Smokefree 2025 target</title><link>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/thedetail/580243/why-new-zealand-failed-to-reach-its-smokefree-2025-target</link><description>New Zealand is struggling to meet its Smokefree 2025 target as smoking rates decline unevenly among different demographics. Despite progress, deep inequities persist, particularly affecting Māori and Pasifika populations. Political changes and the repeal of key tobacco control measures have hindered achieving the goal. Experts suggest shifting the aim to Smokefree 2030 and expanding regulations to include nicotine-free products. However, government policies are not keeping pace with new, addictive tobacco industry products targeting youth. Maintaining the focus on reducing smoking rates, reinstating scrapped measures, and implementing stricter regulations are crucial steps towards a smoke-free future. (Published on November 28, 2025byrnz.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>Sweden's experience in innovative alternatives opens doors to a smoke-free future</title><link>https://gulfnews.com/world/swedens-experience-in-innovative-alternatives-opens-doors-to-a-smoke-free-future-1.500351968</link><description>Sweden's harm reduction strategy led to a 55% decrease in smoking rates, 38% less tobacco-related male deaths, and 41% lower lung cancer rates. The country's unique approach includes promoting less harmful alternatives like nicotine pouches, resulting in 18% usage. Over two decades, a gradual decline in smoking was achieved through awareness campaigns and product availability. Sweden's pioneering model aims for a smoke-free future, with less than 5% of adults smoking. This strategy, based on societal awareness and alternatives rather than bans, could serve as a replicable example for other countries. The focus on harm reduction and public empowerment highlights a practical approach to reducing smoking-related risks globally. (Published on November 28, 2025bygulfnews.com)</description></item></channel></rss>