<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 12:27:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Lives of People Who Use Nicotine Are Not an “Endgame”</title><link>https://filtermag.org/nicotine-tobacco-endgame-human-rights/</link><description>Public health's essence is safeguarding lives with dignity, not a battle. The idea of an "endgame" in tobacco control debates questions the goal—lives saved or nicotine eradicated. Human rights underline health access for all, including informed choices such as safer smoking alternatives. The endgame narrative, meant for industry, could harm individuals and deepen health disparities. It promotes harsh measures, sidelines affected communities, and overlooks harm reduction strategies. A rights-based, humane approach focuses on saving lives and upholding autonomy. Words matter in shaping policies; cooperation should triumph over conquest in public health. Respecting human rights leads to genuine progress on Human Rights Day. (Published on December 11, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #167 | WHY MORE COUNTRIES ARE FIGHTING FOR TOBACCO HARM REDUCTION?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-167-why-more-countries-are-fighting-for-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>Join GFN.TV and Michael Landl from the World Vapers Alliance as they break down COP11’s impact on tobacco harm reduction. Discover how countries challenged WHO recommendations, delayed restrictive measures, and pushed for evidence-based policies. Learn what this means for EU regulations, harm reduction strategies, and the global fight for safer nicotine alternatives. (Published on December 11, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Industry leaders warn EU over sweeping tobacco tax hikes</title><link>https://brusselssignal.eu/2025/12/industry-leaders-warn-eu-over-sweeping-tobacco-tax-hikes/</link><description>International tobacco companies are cautioning against proposed excise-duty increases by the European Commission, fearing detrimental impacts on the tobacco industry and minimal public health benefits. The companies argue that treating all tobacco products equally could harm competitiveness, innovation, and employment. The Commission aims to update the Tobacco Excise Directive, increasing taxes on various tobacco and nicotine products. Supporters believe unified taxation will deter exploitative pricing and improve public health. Opponents warn of potential drawbacks, such as increased illicit trade and negative effects on lower-income consumers and national revenues. The reform also raises concerns about infringing on national fiscal sovereignty. The debate highlights divisions within the EU, with some governments advocating for aggressive tax hikes. (Published on December 11, 2025bybrusselssignal.eu)</description></item><item><title>Concerns raised over UK Tobacco and Vapes Bill</title><link>https://www.jamesevans.wales/news/concerns-raised-over-uk-tobacco-and-vapes-bill</link><description>The Tobacco and Vapes Bill, presented in November 2024, aims to regulate tobacco and vape products by restricting sales to individuals born after 1 January 2009, implementing licensing for retailers, and controlling advertising. The bill also covers smoke-free, vape-free, and heated tobacco-free areas. Additionally, the Welsh Parliament is involved in the legislative consent process for this bill, allowing Senedd Members to provide input. (Published on December 11, 2025byjamesevans.wales)</description></item><item><title>Dual use of cigarettes and vapes can reduce risks of smoking and help smokers quit, study finds</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-12-dual-cigarettes-vapes-smokers.html</link><description>A study by Queen Mary University London reveals that smokers who dual-use cigarettes and e-cigarettes might reduce harmful chemical intake and increase chances of quitting. Dual-users who didn't quit entirely managed to reduce smoking rates and toxic intake. Results suggest e-cigarettes lower smoking urges compared to nicotine replacement therapy. Participants shifting to nicotine-free e-liquids highlights a gradual quitting approach. Tobacco-flavored e-liquids were less popular for quitting. The study emphasizes the harm-reduction potential of dual use. Ultimately, quitting smoking significantly benefits health. The study's findings emphasize the positive impact of dual-use patterns on smoking cessation. (Published on December 11, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Progress &amp; Peril | A.G. Miller Scores Smoking, Vaping &amp; Public Health | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/progress-peril-a-g-miller-scores-smoking-vaping-public-health-regwatch/</link><description>Tom Miller has shaped American tobacco policy for more than 40 years. As the longest-serving attorney general in U.S. history and a principal architect of the Master Settlement Agreement, Miller has spent decades fighting Big Tobacco and advancing public health. Now, in Part 2 of a two-part RegWatch and GFN.TV special, he brings his unmatched authority to the most contentious issues in U.S. nicotine regulation. (Published on December 11, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>From Smoking to Snus and Pouches: The Nordic Blueprint Saving Millions of Lives</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/12/11/from-smoking-to-snus-and-pouches-the-nordic-blueprint-saving-millions-of-lives/</link><description>Nordic countries have effectively reduced smoking rates by offering safer nicotine alternatives like snus, pouches, vapes, and heated tobacco, leading to a significant decline in smoking. Available data shows that these alternatives do not lead to increased smoking rates. However, Denmark's recent tax proposal on these products contradicts the success of harm reduction strategies, risking a return to smoking. The success in Nordic countries highlights that harm reduction works when affordable alternatives are accessible, contrasting with punitive measures. The EU faces a choice between following evidence-based policies that promote harm reduction or hindering progress by restricting access to safer alternatives. (Published on December 12, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item></channel></rss>