<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 01:00:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From Smoking to Snus and Pouches: The Nordic Blueprint Saving Millions of Lives</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/12/11/from-smoking-to-snus-and-pouches-the-nordic-blueprint-saving-millions-of-lives/</link><description>Nordic countries have effectively reduced smoking rates by offering safer nicotine alternatives like snus, pouches, vapes, and heated tobacco, leading to a significant decline in smoking. Available data shows that these alternatives do not lead to increased smoking rates. However, Denmark's recent tax proposal on these products contradicts the success of harm reduction strategies, risking a return to smoking. The success in Nordic countries highlights that harm reduction works when affordable alternatives are accessible, contrasting with punitive measures. The EU faces a choice between following evidence-based policies that promote harm reduction or hindering progress by restricting access to safer alternatives. (Published on December 12, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>How misinformation may be fuelling teen vaping</title><link>https://theconversation.com/how-misinformation-may-be-fuelling-teen-vaping-269476</link><description>Vaping among teens poses global health issues with dependence rising. In the UK, students need medical help due to in-class vaping. In the Netherlands, teens wake at night to vape, showing nicotine addiction. A NZ case with a damaged lung from vaping raises harm concerns. Originally seen as a safer option, vaping is now a youth culture staple, influenced by social trends. Misinformation, psychology, and social proof drive vaping's popularity despite health risks. Changing beliefs through media literacy, engaging content, and highlighting costs can curb vaping's appeal and combat misleading narratives, addressing the root psychological and social factors driving the vaping epidemic. (Published on December 12, 2025bytheconversation.com)</description></item><item><title>WHO welcomes Việt Nam’s strong stance on banned e-cigarettes, heated tobacco products</title><link>https://vietnamnews.vn/society/1731737/who-welcomes-viet-nam-s-strong-stance-on-banned-e-cigarettes-heated-tobacco-products.html</link><description>The World Health Organisation praises Vietnam's National Assembly for banning e-cigarettes and heated tobacco products to protect public health. The decision, made a year ago and reinforced this week, aims to safeguard young people from the harmful effects of nicotine on brain development and long-term health risks. The WHO emphasizes that allowing any loopholes in the ban would undermine its effectiveness. Dr. Angela Pratt highlights the importance of upholding the ban to prioritize health over short-term economic gains. Restrictions on investment and commercial activities related to these products are crucial to enforcing the ban effectively. (Published on December 12, 2025byvietnamnews.vn)</description></item><item><title>Anurag Thakur urges Speaker to act against Trinamool member over using e-cigarette in LS chamber</title><link>https://www.thestatesman.com/india/anurag-thakur-urges-speaker-to-act-against-trinamool-member-over-using-e-cigarette-in-ls-chamber-1503524771.html/amp</link><description>Former Union Minister and BJP MP Anurag Singh Thakur filed a complaint to Lok Sabha Speaker Om Birla, alleging that an AITMC MP used an electronic cigarette inside the Lok Sabha chamber. Thakur said the act was witnessed by several members and reported to the Chair during Question Hour. In his letter, he described the incident as a serious violation of parliamentary rules and relevant laws. (Published on December 12, 2025bythestatesman.com)</description></item><item><title>Mexico threatens eight years of jail in crackdown on vape sales</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/mexico-threatens-eight-years-jail-crackdown-vape-sales-2025-12-11/</link><description>Mexico’s Senate has approved major legal reforms that introduce harsh penalties—up to eight years in prison and fines of up to 226,000 pesos—for producing or selling vapes and e-cigarettes. The pro-government majority passed the changes to the General Health Law, and the bill now only needs President Claudia Sheinbaum’s signature, which she is expected to give. Critics argue the measures are excessively restrictive. (Published on December 12, 2025byreuters.com)</description></item><item><title>Black market cigarettes more prevalent than legal in Australia</title><link>https://www.1news.co.nz/2025/12/12/black-market-cigarettes-more-prevalent-than-legal-in-australia/</link><description>Over half of cigarettes bought in Australia are from the black market, costing taxpayers up to AU$11.8 billion yearly and impacting public health and safety. The illicit tobacco trade undermines efforts to reduce smoking rates, with the black market share estimated at 55-60%. The high excise rates led to this surge, with legitimate packs now over AU$40 while illicit packs go for less than AU$15. Lowering excise rates could increase revenue but risks health consequences, emphasizing the need for stronger enforcement. Shuhyta advocates against excise reduction, urging smokers to choose legal options to combat the illicit market and its associated risks. (Published on December 12, 2025by1news.co.nz)</description></item></channel></rss>