<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 06:19:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Polish president sparks controversy over snus use at UN summit</title><link>https://www.polskieradio.pl/395/7789/Artykul/3583604,polish-president-sparks-controversy-over-snus-use-at-un-summit</link><description>The incident involving Polish President Nawrocki placing a nicotine pouch in his mouth was captured during a UN ceremony. Critics highlighted the irony of him opposing health education while using tobacco products. The president had previously withdrawn his son from health classes, causing debate. Education Minister Nowacka stressed the importance of teaching addiction prevention and healthy habits in schools. Poland sees around 67,000 smoking-related deaths annually, equivalent to a medium-sized city population, emphasizing the detrimental impact of tobacco use. This incident raises questions about public health, education, and the president's stance on these issues. (Published on September 24, 2025bypolskieradio.pl)</description></item><item><title>Things You Need to Know Before Buyimg Disposable Vapes</title><link>https://www.digitaljournal.com/pr/news/binary-news-network/things-need-know-buyimg-disposable-1434789996.html</link><description>Vaping introduced disposable vapes like the popular RAZ, known for its strong flavor and ease of use. When buying, check authenticity, nicotine content, flavors, battery life, and legal regulations. RAZ offers flavors like Blue Raz, Clear Diamond, and Ruby Raz. These disposables are pre-filled, pre-charged gadgets offering a convenient vaping experience without the hassle of traditional mods. Consider your preferences and local laws before enjoying these flavorful options. Some models are rechargeable, and puff counts vary. (Published on September 24, 2025bydigitaljournal.com)</description></item><item><title>Will gov’t push to label e-cigarettes raise tobacco prices?</title><link>https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/amp/economy/20250924/will-govt-push-to-label-e-cigarettes-raise-tobacco-prices</link><description>The government is considering raising cigarette prices to generate more tax revenue, including imposing a new tax on synthetic nicotine used in e-cigarettes. The proposed amendment expands the definition of tobacco to include synthetic nicotine. Experts believe this move is a strategy to gauge public sentiment before potentially increasing cigarette prices. If approved, the government could gain 930 billion won annually from the tax on synthetic nicotine and over 9 trillion won from higher cigarette prices. The country's cigarette prices are lower than the OECD average, making a price hike a possible solution to revenue shortfalls. The government aims to reach its annual tax revenue target by adjusting tobacco taxes. (Published on September 24, 2025bykoreatimes.co.kr)</description></item><item><title>Dorset stop smoking services offer varenicline and cytisine</title><link>https://www.dorsetecho.co.uk/news/25487750.dorset-stop-smoking-services-offer-varenicline-cytisine/</link><description>Varenicline and cytisine, free on prescription, aid in quitting smoking by reducing cravings and withdrawal symptoms. Approved by the MHRA, they enhance the success of quitting and are available in Dorset and Bournemouth, supporting the goal of a smokefree generation by 2030. Personalized consultations with pharmacists and regular check-ins provide valuable support. Councillors highlight the benefits of these medicines, especially for those who struggled to quit before, emphasizing the importance of taking the first step towards a smoke-free life. Local stop smoking services now offer a wider range of tools, increasing the chances of success in quitting smoking. (Published on September 24, 2025bydorsetecho.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>The Safer Nicotine Revolution: Global Lessons, Healthier Futures</title><link>https://www.smokefreesweden.org/safer-nicotine-revolution.pdf</link><description>The passage highlights that, despite decades of work and major financial investment, smoking continues to kill over 7 million people worldwide each year, and progress in reducing it has stalled in many countries. It argues that current methods are clearly insufficient, and a new strategy is urgently needed. The report suggests that embracing safer nicotine alternatives (SNAs) offers a practical and evidence-based solution, leading to sharp declines in smoking, improved public health, and reduced healthcare expenses. (Published on September 24, 2025bysmokefreesweden.org)</description></item><item><title>Spanish Anti-Tobacco Bill Slammed</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-09-17_spanish-anti-tobacco-bill-slammed.html</link><description>The World Vapers' Alliance has criticized Spain’s new Anti-Tobacco Bill for treating all alternative nicotine products the same as traditional cigarettes. The bill extends smoking bans to vaping, heated tobacco, and nicotine pouches in places like terraces, beaches, stadiums, universities, bus stops, and some private vehicles, despite evidence that these products are significantly less harmful. The Alliance called the bill “shocking,” arguing it ignores scientific evidence and international examples, such as Sweden and the UK, where harm reduction strategies have helped lower smoking rates. (Published on September 24, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #10 | Armenia’s THR Challenge | Satenik Muradyan on Fighting Misinformation and Youth Perception</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-10/</link><description>Armenian doctor Satenik Muradyan explains why education is key to tobacco harm reduction, revealing that over 80% of physicians in Armenia lack smoking-cessation training, how misconceptions about tar vs. nicotine fuel resistance, divided youth attitudes toward safer nicotine products, and why step-by-step, evidence-based communication works - insights shared at GFN on overcoming deeply rooted misinformation. (Published on September 24, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>