<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 20:20:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Is the tide turning on vapes?</title><link>https://ajp.com.au/news/is-the-tide-turning-on-vapes/</link><description>Pharmacy ordering company Pharmx has noted a significant increase in demand for nicotine vapes, with a nearly 500% rise in revenue from vapes in the third quarter compared to the same period last year. Availability of nicotine vapes is highlighted as a driving factor in the surge. (Published on May 09, 2025byajp.com.au)</description></item><item><title>Baltimore accuses Zyn nicotine pouch owners of targeting children with deceptive marketing</title><link>https://www.cbsnews.com/baltimore/news/maryland-zyn-nicotine-pouches-flavors-deceptive-marketing/</link><description>Baltimore accuses Zyn nicotine pouch owners, including Philip Morris and Swedish Match, of targeting children with deceptive marketing, violating consumer protection laws. Mayor Scott criticizes the companies for prioritizing profits over public health, particularly children's well-being. Lawsuit alleges fake advertising, enticing youth with promotions and offers. Zyn pouches are nicotine products placed between lip and gums, gaining popularity among the youth for flavors like cinnamon and mint. Concerns include addiction, mental health issues, and oral health risks. FDA approved 20 flavors in January, but health experts urge caution. (Published on May 09, 2025bycbsnews.com)</description></item><item><title>Iraq Moves to Ban E-Cigarettes Amid Alarming Rise in Youth Use, Health Official Warns</title><link>https://www.kurdistan24.net/index.php/en/story/839016/iraq-moves-to-ban-e-cigarettes-amid-alarming-rise-in-youth-use-health-official-warns</link><description>Iraq’s Ministry of Health plans to implement a nationwide ban on the import, sale, and use of e-cigarettes due to rising health concerns and increased use among youth. Dr. Wasim Kilani announced that a new law, the "Law for Protection from the Harmful Effects of Tobacco," will soon be passed, including penalties and enforcement measures. He noted that one in five Iraqis smokes and that smoking is among the top ten causes of death in the country. (Published on May 09, 2025bykurdistan24.net)</description></item><item><title>Opinion: Puritanism on nicotine is another thing Carney should axe</title><link>https://financialpost.com/opinion/puritanism-nicotine-carney-should-axe</link><description>During the federal election campaign, Prime Minister Mark Carney’s past roles drew some attention, but his position on the board of Bloomberg Philanthropies did not—though it should have. Bloomberg Philanthropies has spent $1.58 billion since 2005 opposing tobacco harm reduction, favoring strict anti-nicotine policies over more pragmatic approaches. (Published on May 09, 2025byfinancialpost.com)</description></item><item><title>EU neighbours slam Spain’s pouch ban plan</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/eu-neighbours-slam-spains-pouch-ban-plan/</link><description>Spain faces obstacles in banning nicotine pouches and most vapes as six EU nations present objections, triggering a three-month standstill period for Spain to address concerns on the proposed legislation. If issues are not resolved, implementation may be delayed or blocked. Concerns mainly revolve around EU market rules and the perceived disproportionate limits on nicotine pouches. Spain must either defend the legislation's impact on the internal market or revise it by July 28th to satisfy dissenting countries. The objections are uncommon, with objections typically being minimal in the EU. (Published on May 09, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Government must distinguish between smoking and harm reduction tools, warns expert</title><link>https://www.talkingretail.com/news/industry-news/government-must-distinguish-between-smoking-and-harm-reduction-tools-warns-expert-08-05-2025/</link><description>Tomas Hammargren from bioceramic nicotine pouch brand KLAR stresses the importance of distinguishing smoking cessation products from those targeting youth. He supports harm reduction through safer nicotine alternatives, like nicotine pouches, to reduce health risks. Referencing Sweden's successful harm reduction model, he advocates for responsible regulations to prevent youth uptake and aid adult smokers. Hammargren urges policymakers to prioritize harm reduction and provide diverse, safer options for informed health choices, combating the appeal of youth-targeted products with harmful practices. (Published on May 09, 2025bytalkingretail.com)</description></item><item><title>Truth Interrupted | Public Health Insider Speaks Out About the War On Nicotine | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/truth-interrupted-public-health-insider-speaks-out-about-the-war-on-nicotine-regwatch/</link><description>In a recent episode ofRegWatch, Dr. Jeff Willett—a longtime tobacco control expert—criticizes parts of the movement for ignoring the reduced risks of non-combustible nicotine products. He warns against equating nicotine with smoking-related harms and highlights how Master Settlement Agreement funds are being misused. Willett, now with Global Action to End Smoking, calls for a more honest, science-based approach to harm reduction. (Published on May 09, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>