<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 12:26:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Flavour Bans Cut Youth Vaping – But Slow Cigarette Smoking Decline, Study Finds</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/flavour-bans-cut-youth-vaping-but-slow-cigarette-smoking-decline-study-finds</link><description>Banning flavoured vapes can reduce vaping among young people, but may also slow progress in cutting cigarette smoking rates, according to a new study. (Published on August 11, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Pouches Close Sweden’s Tobacco Harm Reduction Gender Gap</title><link>https://filtermag.org/nicotine-pouches-sweden-gender-gap</link><description>Sweden’s use of the oral tobacco product snus has led it towards becoming the world’s first “smoke-free” country (defined as an overall smoking rate below 5 percent). But modern nicotine pouches are accelerating this progress—with women leading the way, highlights a new report. (Published on August 11, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Minister Praised by Experts</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-08-06_minister-praised-by-experts.html</link><description>International tobacco harm reduction experts at Smoke Free Sweden have applauded Casey Costello, New Zealand’s associate minister of health, for her staunch defence of safer nicotine alternatives that have brought her country to the brink of official ‘smoke-free’ status. (Published on August 11, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>New Zealand Nears Smoke-Free Status—Thanks to Vaping and Common Sense</title><link>https://mipod.com/blogs/mipodblog/new-zealand-nears-smoke-free-status-thanks-to-vaping-and-common-sense</link><description>While some countries are still battling over bans, taxes, and talking points, New Zealand is quietly on the brink of achieving something extraordinary: becoming one of the first truly smoke-free nations. And they didn’t do it with slogans or scare tactics—they did it with science, compassion, and harm reduction. (Published on August 11, 2025bymipod.com)</description></item><item><title>Does Trump Intend to Keep His Promise to Save Vaping?</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/8433/does-trump-intend-to-keep-his-promise-to-save-vaping</link><description>Recent comments from Trump administration health officials have added to confusion over President Trump’s policy on vaping and nicotine. While Health and Human Services (HHS) Secretary Robert F. Kennedy Jr. this week promised “fast-tracked approvals" of vaping products, his subordinate leading the FDA has shown no apparent interest in carrying out such a plan, and urged that the FDA’s war against “illegal products” be expanded to vape shops. (Published on August 11, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item></channel></rss>