<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 15:20:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The effects of vaping on your body just one hour after first puff</title><link>https://www.dailyrecord.co.uk/lifestyle/effects-vaping-your-body-just-35264494</link><description>Vaping, even just one hour after the first puff, can lead to immediate effects such as increased heart rate and blood pressure, along with potential lung irritation. Disposable vapes will soon be banned in the UK, with concerns about their impact on health. While vaping may have fewer harmful chemicals than traditional smoking, it still poses risks like chronic lung damage. The long-term effects of vaping are still being studied, but evidence suggests it could lead to reduced lung function and skin issues over time. Traditional smoking has more immediate negative impacts, including cardiovascular strain and lung damage. (Published on May 21, 2025bydailyrecord.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Tectonic Shift | Consumers Leave Tobacco Control Behind | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/tectonic-shift-consumers-leave-tobacco-control-behind-regwatch/</link><description>Over the past decade, tobacco control has waged war on vaping. They have demonized, taxed, restricted, and banned safer nicotine products. They’ve misrepresented science and misinformed the public, all in a misguided effort to eliminate nicotine use entirely. But U.S. consumers aren’t buying it. They’re rejecting the panic, sidestepping the bans, and switching to nicotine vapes by the millions.  According to Goldman Sachs, sales of smoke-free nicotine products will overtake combustible cigarettes in the U.S. this year. It’s a seismic shift in the nicotine market, and yet public health remains silent. Joining RegWatch to break down this realignment is Dr. Charles Gardner, a key figure in tobacco harm reduction and a relentless advocate for evidence-based public health. Gardner says the age of smoking is ending and almost nobody knows it. (Published on May 21, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>‘Vape products should be taxed higher than cigarettes’</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/business/2025/05/20/2444291/vape-products-should-be-taxed-higher-cigarettes</link><description>The government discussed taxing vape products higher than cigarettes due to increasing youth consumption. BIR suggested different tax rates for vapes to prevent revenue loss. Concerns over vape use by adolescents were raised, with a 40% increase since 2021. Measures like excise stamps were implemented to regulate vape products. Senate deliberations include proposals to amend tobacco excise taxes to address illicit trade. PMFTC recommended an odd-even tax scheme for tobacco products to enhance revenue. Enforcement against illicit trade is considered crucial over tax adjustments. The aim is to balance tax rates while combating illegal activities in the industry. (Published on May 21, 2025byphilstar.com)</description></item><item><title>Poland’s parliament approves ban on selling vapes to minors</title><link>https://tvpworld.com/86834937/polands-lower-house-of-parliament-approves-ban-on-selling-vapes-to-minors</link><description>Poland’s lower house of parliament has approved a bill banning the sale of all types of vapes to minors, including disposable and reusable e-cigarettes, regardless of nicotine content. The bill, which received strong support with 417 votes in favor, now moves to the Senate and, if approved, will go to the president for signing. This ban is part of wider reforms to Poland’s tobacco and vaping laws, aiming to better protect young people from nicotine addiction and related health risks, as previous legislation did not address newer nicotine products. (Published on May 22, 2025bytvpworld.com)</description></item><item><title>The WHO Doesn’t Deserve a Raise—Patients Do</title><link>https://consumerchoicecenter.org/the-who-doesnt-deserve-a-raise-patients-do/</link><description>The World Health Organization (WHO) plans to raise assessed contributions by 20%, equating to an extra $120 million yearly. Despite strains on global healthcare, the WHO diverts funds into unrestricted areas instead of vital programs like polio eradication. The organization's top-heavy structure allows excessive spending, including lavish staff benefits. The WHO's move towards unaccountable core funding shifts focus from critical health initiatives to administrative expansion. To improve transparency, trim senior compensations, and prioritize patient care, national governments must demand reforms before approving contribution hikes. The WHO should prioritize patient needs over bureaucracy. (Published on May 22, 2025byconsumerchoicecenter.org)</description></item><item><title>Hungary Should Call Out the WHO’s Harm Reduction Hypocrisy at COP11</title><link>https://www.thr101.org/post/hungary-should-call-out-the-who-s-harm-reduction-hypocrisy-at-cop11</link><description>Despite joining the FCTC in 2004, Hungary has only seen a slight decrease in smoking rates over two decades. Recent adoption of harm reduction products like heated tobacco has led to significant reductions in cigarette consumption. The WHO's skepticism despite scientific evidence hinders progress. Illicit cigarette trade is growing due to bans on flavored HTPs. Hungary needs to consider the efficacy of harm reduction at COP11 to address the limitations of traditional anti-smoking policies. (Published on May 22, 2025bythr101.org)</description></item><item><title>What Happens in the Real World When Flavors Are Banned in Nicotine Products?</title><link>https://www.fdli.org/2025/05/what-happens-in-the-real-world-when-flavors-are-banned-in-nicotine-products/</link><description>Recent regulatory activities in the nicotine industry involve the withdrawal of a proposed menthol ban on cigarettes in the U.S. and FDA's approval of ZYN nicotine pouch products. Proposals hint at limiting nicotine levels and antagonizing flavors. Regulatory policies seek good intentions but may raise smoking rates and create black markets. U.S. regulations delay reduced-risk products, favoring large companies. Flavors aid smoking cessation, especially with adult smokers. Bans can boost cigarette sales and illicit markets, endangering public health. The focus should be on evidence-based regulations allowing flavored options for adult smokers while curbing youth access. The goal is to reduce smoking-related harm through pragmatic approaches. (Published on May 22, 2025byfdli.org)</description></item></channel></rss>