<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 12:26:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Experts concerned over health effects of high-dose nicotine pouches as sales soar in UK</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/nov/12/experts-concerned-health-effects-high-dose-nicotine-pouches-sales</link><description>Colorful nicotine pouches are the tobacco industry's latest product, marketed as "tobacco-free" but filled with nicotine for a discreet buzz. Despite potential benefits for smokers trying to quit, concerns about addiction and health risks persist. Sales are rising, appealing to younger age groups with revamped marketing. Growing awareness among youth highlights accessibility and potential health issues, with worries about transitioning to more harmful products. The high nicotine content, addictive nature, and unknown long-term effects raise red flags, especially for developing brains. Regulations aim to curb underage use and limit flavors, acknowledging reduced harm compared to smoking but emphasizing the need for caution in preventing non-smokers from starting. (Published on November 12, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Scottish teens report adverse health effects from unregulated nicotine pouch use</title><link>https://www.thepharmacist.co.uk/in-practice/scottish-teens-report-adverse-health-effects-from-unregulated-nicotine-pouch-use/</link><description>Teenagers in Scotland are trying unregulated nicotine pouches, experiencing issues like sickness and gum pain, per a study by ScotCen. These pouches, legal since 2019 and available to under-18s, are widely known among pupils as 'snus' or 'upper deckies'. While some believe them safer than smoking or vaping, adverse effects like gum pain and fainting were reported. School staff lack awareness of pouch use. Researchers advocate for stronger regulations and public health messaging. The UK government plans to license vape sellers in England and Wales. Research efforts are ongoing to assess the impact of nicotine products on youth health. (Published on November 12, 2025bythepharmacist.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Committee Debates Vape Bill</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-11-10_committee-debates-vape-bill.html</link><description>The Tobacco and Vapes Bill has moved to the Grand Committee stage in the House of Lords – and voices of reason are few and far between. Lord Murray of Blidworth introduced a long list of amendments and, in doing so, took aim at the government and Action On Smoking and Health for ignoring the inevitable consequences of implementing bans. (Published on November 12, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Inside fight against black market cigarette trade as cops tackle network of shops illegally flogging fags for £5 a pack</title><link>https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/37288685/fight-against-black-market-cigarette-trade/</link><description>Police find illegal cigarettes hidden under shelves during a search, leading to an ongoing issue costing the UK government £2.2 billion yearly. A recent operation in Blackburn seized £200,000 worth of illicit tobacco. The underground trade is associated with organized crime and counterfeit products, posing health risks due to non-compliance with UK regulations. The National Crime Agency crackdown reveals the alarming scale of illicit trade, involving small businesses and migrant networks. Experts warn of low risks and high profits driving criminals to this market. The public's demand for cheaper cigarettes fuels the illegal trade, with weak penalties failing to deter offenders. Recommendations include tougher measures to combat the growing illicit tobacco market linked to serious organized crime. (Published on November 12, 2025bythesun.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #162 | Clive Bates Exposes Flaws in Global Tobacco Policy and Harm Reduction Debate</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-162-clive-bates-exposes-flaws-in-global-tobacco-policy-and-harm-reduction-debate/</link><description>As the WHO FCTC COP11 conference approaches, Joanna Junak speaks with tobacco policy expert Clive Bates on GFN News about the growing divide between science and ideology in global tobacco control. Bates warns that prohibitionist approaches risk fueling black markets and ignoring proven harm reduction strategies. Watch now to hear his call for a new evidence-based direction in nicotine and tobacco regulation. (Published on November 12, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Thailand Launching Another Crackdown</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-11-11_thailand-launching-another-crackdown.html</link><description>Thailand has announced that it is launching yet another crackdown on vapes and vaping as a consumer organisation states it risks causing a public health disaster. Amid fear of user rates rising from 80,000 to 400,000, the government is amending its legislation from…err…banning the sale and use of vapes to be a comprehensive…err… ban on the sale and use of vapes. (Published on November 12, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>GOOD COP RISING | Fighting the WHO’s War on Safer Nicotine | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/good-cop-rising-fighting-the-whos-war-on-safer-nicotine-regwatch/</link><description>As WHO F.C.T.C. delegates meet behind closed doors in Geneva for COP 11, the Taxpayers Protection Alliance is hosting GOOD COP 2.0—the Conference of the People—a public, science-based counter-conference defending tobacco harm reduction and consumer choice. Joining RegWatch is David Williams, TPA President and founder of GOOD COP, who shares the personal story behind his mission, his critique of the WHO’s “phony science,” and his warning that Bloomberg-funded prohibitionism is costing lives. (Published on November 12, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>