<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 06:21:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Health ministry mulls total vape ban</title><link>https://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2025/07/28/health-ministry-mulls-total-vape-ban</link><description>The health ministry is considering a total ban on vape and electronic cigarettes, pending careful planning and coordination with key agencies. A special committee is assessing regulatory measures and potential impacts, prioritizing public health. The ministry will collaborate with various authorities to refine the proposed approach before deciding on implementing the ban. Any ban will be evidence-based and guided by the committee's recommendations. (Published on July 28, 2025byfreemalaysiatoday.com)</description></item><item><title>Smoke signals: from Charli xcx’s nuptials to The Bear, cigarettes are everywhere</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jul/25/from-charli-xcxs-nuptials-to-the-bear-cigarettes-smoking-everywhere</link><description>Modern weddings are swapping chocolates for cigarettes as party favors. Influencers like Charli xcx and Mary-Kate Olsen set the trend, embracing a rebellious, nostalgic vibe. Expensive but popular, cigarettes are making a comeback in weddings and fashion events. Despite health risks, smoking culture resurges in pop culture and films. Generational factors contribute to this revival, reflecting a desire for freedom and non-conformity. The trend extends beyond weddings, with sales of smoking-related items increasing. influencers and celebrities are seen smoking, normalizing the habit. Whether a short-lived fad or a lasting trend, cigarettes are becoming a symbol of defiance and individuality in social settings. (Published on July 28, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Cannabis Use Sparks Concerns After Over 72,000 Prescriptions Dispensed</title><link>https://cityhub.com.au/cannabis-use-sparks-concerns-after-over-72000-prescriptions-dispensed/</link><description>The unsafe handling of medical cannabis prescriptions by Australian doctors, notably the Montu Group, has raised concerns due to dispensing 72,000 prescriptions to over 10,000 patients in two years. Allegations of unethical practices and aggressive telehealth appointments have led to industry calls for stricter regulations. Despite denial and claims of inaccurate figures, Montu faces scrutiny over potential profiteering and unethical prescription practices. The Health Minister is pushing for improved standards in cannabis prescriptions. Additionally, concerns over misleading advertising and patient vulnerability have emerged. Legal actions are being pursued against Montu for illegal advertising, while the company faces unfair dismissal claims. Government investigations aim to enhance regulations in the medical cannabis industry. (Published on July 28, 2025bycityhub.com.au)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #3 | Exploring the LATAM Perspective</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-3-exploring-the-latam-perspective/</link><description>In this GFN Voices episode, advocates from across Latin America and the Spanish-speaking world joined us at #GFN25 to highlight the regional complexities that need to be overcome, and the ways the THR community is coming together to do just that. (Published on July 28, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Top 10 African cities where people indirectly smoke the most cigarettes</title><link>https://africa.businessinsider.com/local/lifestyle/top-10-african-cities-where-people-indirectly-smoke-the-most-cigarettes/nw51xht</link><description>Fossil fuel-powered engines in cars, factories, and homes are major contributors to air pollution. Fine particulate matter (PM2.5) from these sources poses health risks and leads to millions of premature deaths globally. Indoor and outdoor air pollution is a serious issue affecting ecosystems, health, and climate. HouseFresh's report emphasizes the harmful impact of toxic pollutants in the air and compares air pollution exposure to smoking. Despite natural factors like dust storms and wildfires, human activities significantly worsen air quality. It's crucial to address these concerns to safeguard human health and the environment. (Published on July 28, 2025bybusinessinsider.com)</description></item></channel></rss>