<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 01:04:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Britain will follow Australia into a crime storm with the Tobacco and Vapes bill</title><link>https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2025/07/08/tobacco-vapes-nicotine-health-ban-australia-crime-illegal/</link><description>Australia’s harsh anti-tobacco and anti-vape policies have fueled violent turf wars, with over 230 arson attacks as gangs fight over the black market. The UK may be heading down the same path: illegal vapes and cigarettes are widely sold, taxes are high, and the upcoming Tobacco and Vapes Bill will ban tobacco for future adults, restrict vape flavours, and raise e-cigarette costs—moves likely to boost black market activity. (Published on July 08, 2025bytelegraph.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Quitting the quit-aid: people trying to stop vaping nicotine need more support – here are some strategies to help</title><link>https://theconversation.com/quitting-the-quit-aid-people-trying-to-stop-vaping-nicotine-need-more-support-here-are-some-strategies-to-help-259899</link><description>New Zealand promotes vaping to aid smoking cessation, with a study revealing challenges faced by vapers trying to quit. More than 1,000 surveyed individuals highlighted dependence on vapes, motivating factors to quit, and strategies used for cessation. Factors like health concerns and social influences contribute to relapse triggers, echoing smoking cessation challenges. Support resembling smoking cessation methods is crucial, suggesting tailored approaches for different demographics. While vaping initially served as a smoking substitute, it's now a standalone habit for some. A clinical trial focusing on vaping cessation is underway, emphasizing the need for dedicated support in addressing nicotine addiction. (Published on July 08, 2025bytheconversation.com)</description></item></channel></rss>