<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:56:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The opposition to tackling cigarette smoking</title><link>https://skipscorner.substack.com/p/the-opposition-to-tackling-cigarette</link><description>David T. Sweanor discusses the historical opposition faced in efforts to combat cigarette smoking and improve public health. He highlights ongoing barriers hindering the adoption of safer alternatives to smoking, such as misinformation campaigns and regulatory obstacles. Sweanor emphasizes missed opportunities for a potential market transformation away from lethal cigarettes, despite the clear health benefits. He also criticizes the resistance from various anti-tobacco groups towards embracing advances in tobacco harm reduction. Sweanor concludes by underscoring the immense potential for positive change in public health outcomes if these barriers were overcome. (Published on October 09, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Restoring Confidence in Public Health</title><link>https://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMp2511772</link><description>The text describes the crisis in public health in the United States. Six main factors are identified — complacency, commitment, commercialism, complexity, communication, and comportment. It is explained that misinformation, lack of trust, and weakened social responsibility threaten progress in public health. Education, clear communication, and ethical leadership are presented as key to restoring confidence and improving health outcomes. (Published on October 09, 2025bynejm.org)</description></item><item><title>Sweden moves to stop nicotine pouches meeting the fate of snus</title><link>https://www.euractiv.com/news/sweden-moves-to-stop-nicotine-pouches-meeting-the-fate-of-snus/</link><description>Sweden has sent official letters to several EU countries protesting their bans on nicotine pouches. The Swedish government argues that such bans violate the EU’s principle of free movement of goods. Nicotine pouches, similar to traditional Swedish snus but without tobacco, have become popular since 2014, especially among young people. While snus is banned in the EU except in Sweden, more countries — including Belgium, France, the Netherlands, and Spain — are now banning or restricting nicotine pouches, raising tensions between Sweden and other EU members. (Published on October 09, 2025byeuractiv.com)</description></item><item><title>Clive Bates: WHO Using Tobacco’s History to Poison Good Science</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/10/08/clive-bates-who-using-tobaccos-history-to-poison-good-science/</link><description>Clive Bates urged a global reset in tobacco control policies at the GTNF, stating current approaches fail to address rising smoking-related deaths. He emphasized the need to embrace harm reduction strategies, criticizing the WHO's dismissal of reduced-risk products. Bates advocated for promoting alternatives like vaping and snus, highlighting Sweden's success. He condemned anti-industry bias within the FCTC, noting the need for collaboration. Bates called for a shift towards safer nicotine products and informed consumer choices to reduce smoking rates and save lives. (Published on October 09, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Ireland Taxes Eliquid</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-10-07_ireland-taxes-eliquid.html</link><description>Ireland’s Department of Finance has introduced a tax on e-liquids, called the E-liquid Products Tax (EPT), effective 1 November 2025. The tax targets suppliers at the first point of supply, who must register with Revenue and self-assess the duty. The government says the measure aims to protect public health and curb vaping, especially among young people. While EU-wide rules on vaping taxation are under review, Ireland and other countries are implementing domestic taxes in the meantime. (Published on October 09, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Exclusive: EU’s Leaked COP11 Position Signals Harsh Crackdown on Safer Nicotine Products</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/exclusive-eus-leaked-cop11-position-signals-harsh-crackdown-on-safer-nicotine-products/</link><description>A leaked EU document reveals plans to regulate or ban non-smoked nicotine products like vaping devices and heated tobacco as potential public health threats. The EU dismisses harm reduction, focusing on strict regulations and possible bans on these products to protect youth and the environment. Critics warn this approach may increase cigarette use. The document signifies a shift from previous openness to harm reduction. By equating all nicotine use with smoking, the policy could inadvertently protect cigarettes. The EU's stance risks ignoring real-world data supporting harm reduction strategies. The proposed regulations could hinder safer alternatives, encouraging continued cigarette use, despite evidence of reduced smoking rates in countries with legal non-smoked nicotine products. (Published on October 09, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item></channel></rss>