<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 12:26:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GOOD COP 2.0 | Day 2 of 5 | RegWatch (Live)</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/good-cop-2-0-day-2-of-5-regwatch-live/</link><description>DAY #2 | Live from Geneva, Switzerland – RegWatch special coverage of the Taxpayers Protection Alliance’s Good COP 2.0, the tobacco harm reduction counter-conference to the World Health Organization’s COP 11. (Published on November 18, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>COP11 Day 1: The Echo Chamber Effect</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/cop11-day-1-the-echo-chamber-effect/</link><description>COP11 opened with familiar praises for stringent restrictions on nicotine products, neglecting actual evidence. The World Health Organization's decisions at COP11 lack transparency and focus excessively on bans rather than effective measures. Embracing harm reduction over prohibition has significantly lowered smoking rates in some countries. While many nations advocate for harsh restrictions, New Zealand and Serbia stand out by advocating harm reduction and evidence-based policies. These voices challenge the prevailing narrative and emphasize the importance of data-driven decision-making. Despite existing success stories, the influence of donors aligned with prohibition continues to dominate the conversation at COP11, limiting progress towards more effective solutions. (Published on November 18, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>EU split at WHO meeting seen as test for upcoming tobacco fight at home</title><link>https://www.euractiv.com/news/eu-split-at-who-meeting-seen-as-test-for-upcoming-tobacco-fight-at-home/</link><description>The European Union’s lack of unity during a crucial WHO meeting on tobacco bans has served as a “testing ground” ahead of an upcoming debate on the EU’s own tobacco rules, an EU diplomat said. For the first time, the EU will remain silent during discussions at the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control, taking place on 17–22 November in Geneva. The meeting will focus on strict global measures against tobacco, including new products such as e-cigarettes, heated tobacco, and nicotine pouches. Overall, EU member states agreed on the need for stricter rules for both traditional tobacco and emerging nicotine-based products. (Published on November 18, 2025byeuractiv.com)</description></item><item><title>Mapping Bloomberg's Billions Against Tobacco Harm Reduction</title><link>https://www.thefirebreak.org/p/mapping-bloombergs-billions-against</link><description>Michael Bloomberg's foundation funds NGOs to control global health policy, specifically targeting tobacco harm reduction tools like vaping. By investing billions in activist groups, health NGOs, and the WHO, Bloomberg influences public health decisions globally. These organizations, dubbed "Bloomberg Babies," push his anti-nicotine agenda. The network includes groups like the Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids, Corporate Accountability International, and Vital Strategies. This concentrated control raises concerns over transparency, tax avoidance, and bias in public health discourse. Despite hefty funding, the effectiveness of Bloomberg's anti-tobacco campaigns is questioned, with criticism of hindering harm reduction efforts and promoting questionable policies. (Published on November 18, 2025bythefirebreak.org)</description></item><item><title>Majority of smokers believe e-cigarettes are as dangerous as cigarettes - ”A lie that costs lives”</title><link>https://www.vejpkollen.se/en/2025/11/majoriteten-tror-att-e-cigaretter-ar-lika-farliga-som-cigaretter-en-logn-som-kostar-liv/</link><description>Smokers increasingly think vaping is as harmful as smoking, despite evidence showing it's far less risky. Misinformation perpetuates this belief, impacting public health. Misconceptions arise from the misrepresentation of vaping in the media, promoting fear over facts. Negative perceptions are reinforced by international campaigns funded by Michael Bloomberg. As smokers remain misinformed, the missed opportunity for harm reduction is highlighted, with vaping offering a significantly safer alternative to tobacco. Public trust in science communication is crucial in dispelling myths and promoting informed choices. (Published on November 18, 2025byvejpkollen.se)</description></item></channel></rss>