<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 12:28:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Unforgiving Logic | The Crusade That Forgot Its Cause | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/unforgiving-logic-the-crusade-that-forgot-its-cause-regwatch/</link><description>Tobacco control is all virtue, no restraint. And when it deploys power, it does so as if it holds absolute moral authority: unquestionable, unforgiving, and unshakably certain of its final destination. It doesn’t ask “Does this reduce harm?” In this RegWatch public statement, we expose the divide between tobacco harm reduction and the ideology driving tobacco control. Moral absolutism rooted in resentment, not science, has shaped a global war on safer nicotine products that smears vaping, discredits researchers, and marginalizes anyone who refuses to walk the path of abstinence. (Published on July 29, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>Disposable ban fails to stick as quarter of UK retailers break the law</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/disposable-ban-fails-to-stick-as-quarter-of-uk-retailers-break-the-law/</link><description>According to Haypp, 23% of UK vape retailers are illegally selling disposable vapes following the ban. Mystery shoppers found violations in various UK cities, with London and Glasgow having the most offenders. Retailers used tactics like selling by the box or accepting cash only to make illegal sales. Concerningly, even high-street stores with online profiles were involved. The company suspects the actual number of violators to be higher. This mirrors the situation in Australia, where a similar ban led to a thriving black market. Haypp suggests stricter inspections and consumer education to ensure compliance with the ban and promote safer alternatives. (Published on July 30, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Unified front pushed vs smoking among WV youth</title><link>https://www.panaynews.net/unified-front-pushed-vs-smoking-among-wv-youth/</link><description>The Department of Health in Western Visayas is escalating efforts to combat the growing use of e-cigarettes among youths, collaborating with schools and local governments to enforce anti-smoking and anti-vaping measures. They are alarmed by the appeal of flavored e-cigarettes and aggressive marketing targeting young people. Both smoking and vaping pose health risks, including chronic lung problems and addiction. Efforts involve strict enforcement of national laws and initiatives like the MPOWER strategy. DOH-6 also leads the Tobacco Control Leadership program to empower local leaders. Recognizing municipalities with smoke-free environments, they emphasize the importance of collective action from schools, communities, and government for effective tobacco control. (Published on July 30, 2025bypanaynews.net)</description></item><item><title>Teenagers who vape are smoking at 1970s levels</title><link>https://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/2025/07/30/vaping-children-similar-1970s-smoking-cigarettes/</link><description>Teenagers who vape are smoking cigarettes at 1970s levels, raising concerns about a tobacco addiction gateway. Among vapers, one third also smoke, a ratio seen in 1974. E-cigarette use hampers the decline in nicotine use, and research suggests vaping leads to smoking. Despite bans, 1 in 3 teens have tried vaping by age 15, and e-cigarette use among 11- to 15-year-olds has doubled. Disposable vapes were banned to prevent youth nicotine addiction. Vapers can get hooked quickly, affecting concentration and causing fatigue, stress, and anxiety. Those who vape are more likely to smoke cigarettes, emphasizing the need to address this trend. (Published on July 30, 2025bytelegraph.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Australia’s war on nicotine is failing. A smarter strategy is needed</title><link>https://www.crikey.com.au/2025/07/30/nicotine-tobacco-cigarettes-harm-reduction-vaping/</link><description>Alarming Roy Morgan data reveals rising smoking and vaping rates in Australia post-2024 vaping crackdown. Excessive regulations and high taxes on tobacco have backfired, fueling a dangerous black market. Illicit tobacco and vapes are widely available, leading to criminal activities and endangering communities. Australia's punitive measures have failed to curb illegal trade, contrasting with successful harm reduction policies in countries like New Zealand. Urgent reform is needed to establish a regulated market for safer nicotine products, reduce tobacco excise, and involve consumers in policymaking. Embracing harm reduction can accelerate the decline in smoking rates and combat the growing black market, safeguarding public health and reducing crime. (Published on July 30, 2025bycrikey.com.au)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco use in WA's Kimberley remains high as Australian smoking rate drops below 10pc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-30/one-in-three-people-still-smoking-in-wa-kimberley-region/105490556</link><description>Smoking rates in Australia have reached historic lows, with fewer than 10% of people smoking nationally in 2022–23. However, in Western Australia's remote Kimberley region, about one in three people still smoke regularly. Broome resident Spencer Lim Joon, who quit last year after 40 years of smoking, shared how family health struggles and witnessing the fatal effects of smoking motivated him to stop. (Published on July 30, 2025byabc.net.au)</description></item><item><title>#GFN25 Commentary Team hosted by Harry Shapiro</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn25-commentary-team-1/</link><description> (Published on July 30, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>