<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:55:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The impact of vaping behavior on functional changes within the subgingival microbiome</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-17121-y</link><description>Participants aged 18-35, including ENDS users and controls, underwent saliva and subgingival plaque collection. Periodontal screening was conducted using CPITN. Saliva was collected after rinsing with water. Puffing behavior was assessed, and VOC emissions were analyzed. Subgingival plaque samples were collected following HMP protocols. DNA isolation, amplicon sequencing, and taxonomic annotation were performed. Microbiome analysis included diversity assessment and beta diversity using Bray-Curtis distances. Functional profiling was done using Tax4Fun2. Salivary metabolomics were analyzed, and microbiome-metabolome functional connections explored. Network integration analysis using xMWAS was conducted. Statistical analyses were adjusted for demographic factors. The study aimed to understand oral microbiome responses to ENDS use and associated metabolomic changes. (Published on October 02, 2025bynature.com)</description></item><item><title>Can E-Cigarettes Raise Prediabetes Risk?</title><link>https://www.rttnews.com/amp/3579098/can-e-cigarettes-raise-prediabetes-risk.aspx</link><description>A study led by Sulakshan Neupane at the University of Georgia, based on over 1.2 million CDC survey responses, found that exclusive e-cigarette users were 7% more likely to develop prediabetes compared to non-smokers, equal to about 7,000 additional cases per million users. Traditional smokers had a 15% higher risk, while dual users faced a 28% higher risk. Neupane warned that although e-cigarettes are marketed as a safer alternative, they may still contribute to long-term health problems such as prediabetes and diabetes. (Published on October 02, 2025byrttnews.com)</description></item><item><title>WHO Closing Off Oversight</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-09-30_who-closing-off-oversight.html</link><description>The Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA) has criticized the World Health Organization’s Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (WHO FCTC) for making public registration for its COP11 conference in Geneva nearly impossible. Executive Coordinator Nancy Loucas called the process an "insane system" designed to exclude legitimate stakeholders. Requirements such as detailed documents, letters of intent, and CVs create unnecessary obstacles, while the applicant declaration effectively bars consumer advocacy groups. Loucas argues this reflects a long-standing pattern of exclusion within the WHO FCTC process. (Published on October 02, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Trump promised to ‘save vaping’ – now industry says DOJ raids could wipe it out</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/trump-promised-to-save-vaping-now-industry-says-doj-raids-could-wipe-it-out/</link><description>The seizure of vaping products by federal authorities raises concerns for U.S. manufacturers, contradicting Trump's support for the industry. The Vapor Technology Association revealed that many seized products were American-made. The industry employs over 90,000 workers but faces regulatory challenges. Vaping, deemed less harmful than smoking, helps adults quit cigarettes. Critics question the FDA's focus on vaping over traditional tobacco products. Amid calls for clear guidelines and support for harm reduction, the industry struggles with limited FDA approvals. The crackdown and lack of regulation hinder American companies, despite the potential for domestic growth. (Published on October 02, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>FDA’s Cigarette Labeling Regulations Vacated by Georgia Judge</title><link>https://news.bloomberglaw.com/litigation/fdas-cigarette-labeling-regulations-vacated-by-georgia-judge</link><description>Philip Morris USA Inc. successfully challenged FDA rules on cigarette labeling and advertising in court, citing the agency's failure to disclose important data during the rulemaking process. The judge ruled in favor of the plaintiffs, including cigarette manufacturers and retailers, stating that the FDA's lack of transparency prejudiced their participation in the process. The FDA's attempt to enhance public understanding of smoking risks through new warning labels was supported by the judge, who found the agency's approach compliant with legal requirements. The case highlights legal battles over tobacco regulation and the balance between public health communication and industry interests. (Published on October 02, 2025bybloomberglaw.com)</description></item><item><title>Shaping Vaping Podcast</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/live/NfycccxA_Zo</link><description>The report "Regulating the Tobacco and Nicotine Market in the American Public Interest: A Reform Agenda for the FDA" emphasizes that safer alternatives to cigarettes—such as vapes, pouches, and heated tobacco—are being restricted by the FDA’s approval process, which has fueled the growth of an unregulated black market. (Published on October 02, 2025byyoutube.com)</description></item><item><title>Public Health Has Turned Into Public Harassment</title><link>https://dcjournal.com/public-health-has-turned-into-public-harassment/</link><description>Governments originally implemented smoking bans to protect individuals from secondhand smoke exposure, claiming health concerns. However, recent proposals to also ban vaping and nicotine pouches in public spaces suggest a hidden agenda of stigmatizing nicotine users. Despite lacking evidence of harm to bystanders, governments are enforcing unjust restrictions on these products. The comparison between cigarette smoke and e-cigarette vapor highlights the minimal risk posed by vapor. Policies should be evidence-based and respect personal liberties, rather than imposing unwarranted bans driven by moral panic. The true intention behind smoking bans seems to be controlling and marginalizing certain groups, rather than safeguarding public health. (Published on October 02, 2025bydcjournal.com)</description></item></channel></rss>