<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:58:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The State of Academic Research on Nicotine, Part 2</title><link>https://arielleselyaphd.substack.com/p/the-state-of-academic-research-on-1ce</link><description>The text discusses academia's issues with biased research on nicotine/tobacco due to funding pressures and incentives that prioritize grant funding over quality. The system is unsustainable, favoring quantity over quality in publications and research that aligns with funding agency priorities. Pressure to secure NIH grants leads researchers to conform to agency views, hindering unbiased research. The oversaturation of PhDs exacerbates competition for academic positions, perpetuating a cycle of grant dependence. The focus on grant funding also compromises teaching quality and hampers diverse research perspectives. Future posts will explore solutions to address these systemic challenges in academia. (Published on August 21, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Misleading by design: experts slam Daily Mail for exaggerating youth vaping harms</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/misleading-by-design-experts-slam-daily-mail-for-exaggerating-youth-vaping-harms/</link><description>Experts criticized a Daily Mail article labeling vapes as harmful to youth as misleading. The research cited lacks evidence of causation, purposefully excludes benefits, and relies on low-quality data. The umbrella review of reviews on youth vaping connected it to smoking and health issues but didn't prove causation. Claims of vaping leading to smoking were disputed, with smoking rates among youth decreasing as vaping rose. Concerns about asthma effects were uncertain. The EVALI outbreak was linked to illicit THC, not nicotine e-liquids. Experts suggest caution with youth vaping while avoiding broad conclusions about adult harm reduction based on this limited review. Media misrepresentation undermines harm reduction efforts. (Published on August 21, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>No ban on vape for now to avoid legal issues, says health minister</title><link>https://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2025/08/21/govt-cant-suddenly-ban-vape-says-health-minister</link><description>Health Minister Dzulkefly Ahmad is preparing a report for the Cabinet on the timing and process of imposing a potential vape ban to prevent legal challenges. The government currently refrains from banning vapes and e-cigarettes to avoid complications after legally registering and regulating the industry under Act 852. Dzulkefly noted that a sudden ban could lead to legal issues due to the expectation set by the existing regulations. While considering a complete ban, factors like legal implications, enforcement, and public health are being evaluated. Some states have already prohibited vape sales. (Published on August 21, 2025byfreemalaysiatoday.com)</description></item><item><title>Tennessee Harm Reductionist Faces Charges for Drug Checking</title><link>https://filtermag.org/tennessee-harm-reductionist-arrested-drug-checking/</link><description>Dr. Paige Lemen, a harm reductionist and Tennessee researcher, was arrested while transporting a drug sample for testing. Suffering from an illness, she failed a sobriety test and faced multiple charges including intent to sell drugs. Police seized her lab equipment, medications, and mocked her during the arrest. Despite paying bail, her community work was hindered by increased police surveillance. The case highlights legal uncertainties around harm reduction practices. Lemen aims to prove her innocence in court but fears the outcome's impact on future drug checking cases. She stresses the importance of understanding and supporting harm reduction efforts. (Published on August 21, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item></channel></rss>