<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 01:02:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>To Bring Tobacco Harm Reduction to Prisons, We Need Outside Allies</title><link>https://filtermag.org/tobacco-harm-reduction-prisons-need-allies/</link><description>Harm reduction efforts outside prison can target weak policies for positive outcomes. Advocates suggest addressing vulnerable prison policies related to smoking to save lives and costs in Washington State. Selling nicotine vapes in prisons can promote safer habits and fund essential services. However, achieving policy change requires external support due to restrictions on inmate advocacy. Involving prisoners in harm reduction initiatives is crucial, but often overlooked. Collaboration between inmates and external stakeholders, such as researchers and advocacy groups, is needed to push for vaping policies in prisons. Inclusion of prisoners in harm reduction discussions and initiatives is essential for effective and just policy change. (Published on June 10, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>EU should not copy France’s failed public health strategy</title><link>https://www.europeaninterest.eu/eu-should-not-copy-frances-failed-public-health-strategy/</link><description>France's anti-tobacco policy, with high taxes and bans on safer quitting tools, is ineffective. Around 75,000 people annually die due to tobacco, costing €150 billion. The policy lacks public trust, pushing 1 in 4 French to buy cigarettes illegally. This distrust stems from taxes seen as money grabs. France needs harm reduction programs, truthful messaging, and evaluation beyond tax gains. Hoekstra's EU-wide tax proposal risks expanding failed policies. Sensible changes are necessary to combat smoking effectively. France must shift from punitive measures to supportive strategies promoting healthier choices for smokers. (Published on June 10, 2025byeuropeaninterest.eu)</description></item><item><title>Puffs, Pods, Pouches: Which Nicotine Trend Worries Experts?</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/puffs-pods-pouches-which-nicotine-trend-worries-experts-2025a1000fhw</link><description>CHC Mont Legia welcomed Adrien Meunier, a clinical nurse tobacco specialist, on World No Tobacco Day to discuss the effectiveness of next-generation nicotine products in smoking cessation. Meunier clarified that nicotine itself is not a primary cause of fatal diseases, emphasizing the harm from toxic substances in cigarette smoke. He highlighted the drawbacks of box mod e-cigarettes and recommended pod-based e-cigarettes for smoking cessation, along with a gradual reduction strategy. Meunier also raised concerns about the popularity of puffs among youth and the risks associated with heated tobacco devices and nicotine pouches. Additionally, he warned about new addictive synthetic nicotine molecules entering the market. (Published on June 10, 2025bymedscape.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #156 | Is this the key to reducing smoking rates in Mexico?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-156/</link><description>Despite rising smoking rates Mexico still heavily restricts access to safer nicotine products, leaving few options for Mexico's. But could healthcare professionals be the key to stem Mexico's smoking dilemma? Marcela Madrazo joins us to highlight this alternative approach to THR in Mexico. (Published on June 10, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Bulgaria’s blanket ban on vapes awaits Brussels approval</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/bulgarias-blanket-ban-on-vapes-awaits-brussels-approval/</link><description>Bulgaria is considering a full ban on all vapes pending approval from Brussels, sparking concerns among harm reduction advocates. The legislation, backed by 197 MPs, also targets energy drinks marketed to minors. Lead sponsor Professor Kostadin Angelov suggests the ban may focus on disposable vapes for quicker implementation due to regulatory obstacles. The European Commission must be notified due to potential trade impacts. Smoke Free Sweden opposes the ban, cautioning against hindering tobacco harm reduction efforts in Europe, as it may push ex-smokers back to smoking. (Published on June 10, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Vaping growth falters as Big Tobacco hunts for lifeline</title><link>https://www.ft.com/content/53213912-ca54-4c79-b302-b1e0f6480f28</link><description>Sales growth of e-cigarettes is slowing down in both the US and UK, raising doubts about earlier predictions that vaping would overtake smoking and support the tobacco industry. British American Tobacco expects a mid-teens percentage decline in global vape sales in the first half of the year. In the US, regulated e-cigarette sales have dropped almost every month for the past two years, while in the UK, vaping rates have stagnated. (Published on June 10, 2025byft.com)</description></item><item><title>E-Cigarettes and Tooth Decay: New Research Reveals Hidden Dental Problems</title><link>https://www.fingerlakes1.com/2025/06/10/e-cigarettes-and-tooth-decay-new-research-reveals-hidden-dental-problems/</link><description>Vaping is linked to severe cavities in young adults, creating unique oral health problems by promoting bacteria growth, compromising antioxidant defences, and intensifying inflammation. Unique cavity locations, youth usage patterns, and plummeting dental implant success rates pose additional risks. Strategies to minimize damage include immediate post-vaping brushing, more frequent dental cleanings, strategic hydration, and selecting products with fewer additives. Dental professionals advise ongoing care and caution for vapers. (Published on June 10, 2025byfingerlakes1.com)</description></item></channel></rss>