<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 12:26:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Flavored vapes under fire: Czechia clamps down on e-cigarettes</title><link>https://www.expats.cz/czech-news/article/flavored-vapes-under-fire-czechia-clamps-down-on-e-cigarettes</link><description>The Czech Ministry of Health plans to ban candy-like flavors in e-cigarettes, such as cotton candy, marshmallow, and donut, to curb vaping among children and teens. The new amendment aims to make vaping less attractive to young people. Although e-cigarette sales to minors are already illegal, government data shows that many stores do not enforce age restrictions, with over half of teenagers saying they can easily buy e-cigarette cartridges. The ban will not apply to all flavors. (Published on July 07, 2025byexpats.cz)</description></item><item><title>Vaping versus smoking’s impact on male fertility</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250706/Vaping-versus-smokinge28099s-impact-on-male-fertility.aspx</link><description>Male partners in IVF couples who switched from smoking to vaping experienced improved sperm quality and decreased miscarriage rates, according to a study on E-cigarette versus traditional cigarette use. While vaping showed benefits, experts caution about the risks for hopeful parents. The study compared sperm parameters and IVF outcomes between E-cigarette and cigarette users, revealing fewer miscarriages and increased live-birth rates among vapers. Despite the improvements, established predictors like FSH levels remained crucial. Researchers stress that vaping does not guarantee success, advocating for further research on E-cigarette risks and fertility counseling. Lifestyle choices continue to impact assisted reproduction outcomes, emphasizing the importance of quitting smoking for prospective parents. (Published on July 07, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>Northampton shop gives up licence over illicit cigarettes</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/clyxdn07vxmo</link><description>Viva Mini Market voluntarily surrendered its alcohol license after police found over 600 packets of illegal cigarettes and tobacco in a nearby car’s boot linked to the shop in Northampton. West Northamptonshire Council heard allegations of illicit sales. The license surrender followed the discovery of illegal vapes and tobacco at the store. The police seized the illicit goods from a blue BMW near the shop. The committee adjourned as the license had already been given up before the meeting. The store can reapply for a new license to sell alcohol if desired. Police and the former license holder did not attend the hearing. (Published on July 07, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>THERE'S NOTHING MORE IMPORTANT IN THE TOBACCO HARM REDUCTION FIELD!</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/theres-nothing-more-important-in-the-tobacco-harm-reduction-field/</link><description>Watch Will Godfrey’s post-#GFN25 reaction, where he underscores the critical importance of effective communication in advancing the conversation around safer nicotine products. His reflections highlight how clear, evidence-based messaging can help shift public perception, inform policy, and support harm reduction efforts on a global scale. (Published on July 07, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>