<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 16:21:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #63 | TAX TRAP | How Safer Nicotine Products Get Treated Like Tobacco</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-63/</link><description>New research reveals governments are taxing safer nicotine products like cigarettes, sabotaging tobacco harm reduction and blocking smokers from switching. Correcting these policies could accelerate global declines in smoking. (Published on May 05, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>The UK’s Impending Disposable Vapes Ban Looks Unenforceable</title><link>https://filtermag.org/uk-disposable-vapes-ban-unenforceable/</link><description>The UK faces challenges with the upcoming ban on single-use vapes in June, as warnings from various groups indicate a potential surge in the illicit vapes market. Experts criticize the government for being ill-prepared, with concerns ranging from vapers switching back to cigarettes to inadequate enforcement resources. The ban may lead to a boost in the unregulated vapes market, risking harm to consumers. Despite initial reservations, some organizations now cautiously support the ban. However, fears of a thriving black market, criminal enterprises, and violence have emerged. Research shows mixed impacts on vaping behavior, with uncertainty about the ban's overall effectiveness in reducing vaping rates or promoting smoking cessation. (Published on May 05, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>OLDCORN: Australia’s tobacco tax fiasco offers Canada a smoking hot warning</title><link>https://www.westernstandard.news/canadian/oldcorn-australias-tobacco-tax-fiasco-offers-canada-a-smoking-hot-warning/64501</link><description>Australia's tobacco excise revenue plummeted to $7.4 billion AUD this year from $16.3 billion AUD in 2019‑20, despite high taxes. Smokers turned to cheaper contraband due to tax hikes, leading to a 50% revenue drop in five years. Canadian authorities should pay attention as they increase taxes and regulations, resulting in a rise in vape store robberies across the country. (Published on May 05, 2025bywesternstandard.news)</description></item><item><title>CAPHRA calls for risk-proportionate taxation on Safer Nicotine Products across Asia Pacific</title><link>https://www.aliveadvocacymovement.com/post/caphra-calls-for-risk-proportionate-taxation-on-safer-nicotine-products-across-asia-pacific</link><description>The Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA) emphasizes the need for risk-proportionate taxation on safer nicotine products in the Asia Pacific region. Existing tax systems, borrowed from Western models, are hindering tobacco harm reduction efforts. CAPHRA warns that high taxes on these products hinder adult smokers from choosing healthier alternatives and protect the cigarette trade. The organization urges governments to tailor taxation to reflect risks accurately, citing successful examples in Japan, the Philippines, and New Zealand. CAPHRA stresses the importance of aligning tax policies with scientific evidence to empower individuals to make informed health choices and avoid creating black markets. (Published on May 06, 2025byaliveadvocacymovement.com)</description></item><item><title>Shifting nicotine product preferences observed in US high school students</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-05-shifting-nicotine-product-high-school.html</link><description>A study reveals the increased use of non-tobacco nicotine products among U.S. adolescents, with a rise in dual use of nicotine pouches and e-cigarettes while exclusive e-cigarette use declines. Nicotine pouches, introduced as socially acceptable and less harmful, have gained popularity, particularly among male students and rural youth. The study calls for increased surveillance and regulation to address the growing trend. Overall, there was a shift in nicotine delivery products, emphasizing the need for comprehensive monitoring and prevention strategies to tackle adolescent nicotine use. The research underscores the importance of understanding and addressing changing patterns in youth nicotine consumption. (Published on May 06, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Ex-FDA Tobacco Head Brian King Joins Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids</title><link>https://filtermag.org/fda-brian-king-campaign-tobacco-free-kids/</link><description>Dr. Brian King, ousted from the FDA's tobacco center, now joins Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids, sparking debate about his stance on harm reduction. Former FDA officials' diverse career paths raise questions about their prior views on nicotine products and any potential conflicts of interest. King, known for authorizing vaping products, faces scrutiny for prioritizing youth prevention over harm reduction. Tobacco harm reduction advocates express frustration with the slow progress in regulating reduced-risk products. While King's move to CTFK is seen as controversial, some hope for a shift towards balanced regulation. The industry's ties to public health groups and conflicting viewpoints on harm reduction remain points of interest. (Published on May 06, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Belgium launches next 'buddy' campaign to help friends quit smoking together</title><link>https://www.brusselstimes.com/1561349/belgium-launches-next-buddy-campaign-to-help-friends-quit-smoking-together</link><description>Belgium's Foundation Against Cancer launches the 'Buddy Deal' campaign for the fourth year, promoting quitting smoking with a friend following concerns about e-cigarette addiction. The initiative led by actor Mathias Vergels aims to combat anxiety and depression caused by smoking. The campaign encourages participants to join online for support, offering distractions and events. E-cigarettes are also targeted, as bans on disposable vapes and displays are implemented. The initiative emphasizes the importance of health-conscious quitting and mental well-being. (Published on May 06, 2025bybrusselstimes.com)</description></item></channel></rss>