<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:24:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Alberta students, doctors want federal ban on flavoured e-cigarettes, nicotine pouches</title><link>https://globalnews.ca/news/11480062/alberta-students-doctors-federal-ban-e-cigarettes-vaping/</link><description>Albertan groups are urging federal health ministers to ban all flavored e-cigarettes and nicotine pouches in Canada to deter youth vaping. Despite promises since 2021, the government has not implemented the ban. Concerns are raised about the popularity of vaping among students, prompting advocacy groups like SAAVE and Action on Smoking and Health to seek direct discussions with ministers at the upcoming meeting in Calgary. The focus is on protecting young Canadians from the allure of flavored vaping products. (Published on October 16, 2025byglobalnews.ca)</description></item><item><title>Assessment of the prevalence, knowledge, and perceptions of e-cigarette use among the Palestinian community: a cross-sectional study</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-20132-4</link><description>The study examined Palestinian perceptions of e-cigarette use, finding 19.4% usage with more males than females. Peer influence plays a key role, while e-cigarettes are more prevalent among 26-35 age group and city residents. Knowledge level affected usage, with discrepancies on safety perception and effectiveness for smoking cessation. Concerns were raised about addiction and health impact, suggesting the need for regulation. Socioeconomic factors and lifestyle behaviors were not fully explored. The study had limitations, including sampling bias and not considering confounding factors. Further research is needed to understand the relationship between e-cigarette use, socioeconomic status, and lifestyle behaviors. (Published on October 17, 2025bynature.com)</description></item><item><title>#GFN25 Panel Discussion | Who else should be in the room?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn25-panel-discussion-5/</link><description>Extending THR into other disciplines and communities, is essential. Obvious targets are in the fields of drug use and mental health - evidence is clear concerning levels of smoking and associated health risks - but there is need to engage more widely. The panel addressed the barriers to extending reach, including how can we dispel myths and tackle miscommunication? What role does the media have in the process? Who are the key opinion leaders and groups, what are the initial steps in reaching out and how can we support ongoing dialogue? (Published on October 17, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco use falls in Southeast Asia but the fight isn't over</title><link>https://www.dw.com/en/tobacco-use-falls-in-southeast-asia-but-the-fight-isnt-over/a-74388180</link><description>Tobacco consumption in Southeast Asia has declined significantly over the past two decades, aided by strong policies and public health initiatives. Despite this progress, the tobacco industry still holds significant power, and the use of e-cigarettes is on the rise. While most countries have implemented anti-smoking measures, Indonesia remains an exception with high smoking rates and minimal regulation. Additionally, the region faces challenges in tackling the growing popularity of e-cigarettes, particularly among youth. Governments are advised to continue enforcing strict tobacco control measures to prevent a resurgence in smoking rates and address the emerging issue of vaping. (Published on October 17, 2025bydw.com)</description></item></channel></rss>