<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:26:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>WHO faces questions on donor-linked funding</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/world/2025/10/21/2449290/who-faces-questions-donor-linked-funding</link><description>A recent report questions the World Health Organization's independence due to significant donations by Bloomberg Philanthropies and undisclosed "dark money". The report highlights concerns over global health policies being influenced by donor-driven agendas, outlining instances where powerful financial interests, like Bloomberg, have shaped WHO's strategies, particularly in tobacco control. Transparency issues arise from the acceptance of undisclosed corporate funds by the WHO Foundation. Allegations point to Bloomberg's influence on public policy globally, bypassing democratic processes. The report urges reforms for accountability, inclusion of diverse voices, and respect for national sovereignty within the WHO's framework to prevent outside influences on health policies. (Published on October 22, 2025byphilstar.com)</description></item><item><title>Philippines Vape Ban Slammed</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-10-21_philippines-vape-ban-slammed.html</link><description>The Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA) has strongly criticized the Philippines’ new vape ban, calling it a “reckless policy” that removes safer alternatives for adult smokers. The ban on open pod systems and uncertified e-liquids has already closed compliant shops and limited consumer choices. Nancy Loucas, CAPHRA’s Executive Coordinator, argued that the government fails to distinguish between different vaping systems, demonstrating a lack of understanding that harms the public. CAPHRA also condemned the Department of Trade and Industry (DTI) for not consulting consumers, leading to policies that undermine effective public health measures. (Published on October 22, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>