<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 18:20:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lives Saved Report: Saving 85,000 Lives in Sri Lanka</title><link>https://tobaccoharmreduction.net/report/lives-saved-report-sri-lanka/</link><description>The Lives Saved Sri Lanka Report presents an urgent call to action for integrating Tobacco Harm Reduction (THR) into Sri Lanka’s tobacco control strategy and evaluates the potential long-term impact of supplementing the WHO MPOWER framework with innovative harm reduction products and improved lung cancer treatment access. (Published on July 31, 2025bytobaccoharmreduction.net)</description></item><item><title>Vape Players Reject Malaysian Ban</title><link>https://thesun.my/business-news/vape-players-reject-ban-call-it-flawed-FH14570522</link><description>A coalition of vape associations has strongly opposed the government’s move to ban vape sales, warning that such a move would harm adult consumers and drive them toward the unregulated black market. (Published on July 31, 2025bythesun.my)</description></item><item><title>Tennessee Vape Shops Confused by New Law’s Rollout</title><link>https://ecigator.com/news/tennessee-vape-law-rollout-confusion/</link><description>Vape shop owners in Tennessee are voicing confusion and concern over the phased implementation of a new state law regulating vapor products. The new regulations are being implemented in three (...) (Published on July 31, 2025byecigator.com)</description></item><item><title>New Zealand: Heated Tobacco</title><link>https://tobaccoinsider.com/new-zealand-heated-tobacco/</link><description>New Zealand’s government has extended its 50 % excise‑tax reduction on heated tobacco until July 2027 to encourage smokers to switch. The trial was inconclusive because Philip Morris’s IQOS device was briefly removed from sale under battery‑safety rules. Critics say the evidence for heated‑tobacco benefits is weak, while PMI argues HTPs are smoke‑free alternatives. (Published on July 31, 2025bytobaccoinsider.com)</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Balancing Vape Safety, Youth Protection, and Public Education</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/07/31/the-importance-of-balancing-vape-safety-youth-protection-and-public-education/#:~:text=Campaigns%20that%20simply%20highlight%20the,term%20harm</link><description>Astudyfrom Georgia State University revealed that most young people who use e-cigarettes are altering their devices—often in ways that could be dangerous. A national survey of nearly 2,000 youth and adults found that over 84% of younger users had modified their vapes. While some changes, such as replacing a coil or installing a manufacturer-approved battery, are considered safe, many involve practices that increase risks. (Published on July 31, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item></channel></rss>