<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:32:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>US adults' complete switching away from cigarettes by menthol- and tobacco-flavored ENDS and by menthol cigarette preference: testing robustness to missing data</title><link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/41559253/</link><description>Use of menthol-flavored (vs. tobacco-flavored) electronic nicotine delivery systems (ENDS) may be associated with higher rates of complete switching among adults who smoke (AWS). This paper evaluates the association over 2 years, while considering robustness across different missing-data approaches. 22,905 US AWS and purchased JUUL ENDS were enrolled in a longitudinal cohort study and completed up to 10 follow-ups. To assess potential bias due to missingness, analyses: (a) compared participant characteristics by levels of missingness and (b) assessed whether tobacco or menthol JUUL was associated with missingness. (Published on January 27, 2026bynih.gov)</description></item><item><title>Azerbaijan bans import and sale of e-cigarettes</title><link>https://news.az/news/azerbaijan-bans-import-and-sale-of-e-cigarettes</link><description>Azerbaijan's new tobacco legislation, approved by President Ilham Aliyev, bans electronic cigarettes and components, classifying them as tobacco products. The law prohibits their import, production, sale, and use, aiming for clearer regulation and enforcement. Heated tobacco products are not considered e-cigarettes under the law. Changes to the Tax Code and Advertising Law accompany the ban, with disposable e-cigarettes no longer subject to taxes. Effective April 1, 2026, the legislation addresses the import, export, manufacture, storage, distribution, and use of these products within the country. (Published on January 27, 2026bynews.az)</description></item><item><title>Oral Lesions, Uptake Data, and Regulation: The Missing Conversation on Nicotine Pouches</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2026/01/26/oral-lesions-uptake-data-and-regulation-the-missing-conversation-on-nicotine-pouches/</link><description>Public health authorities are shifting focus to regulations on oral nicotine pouches as smoking rates decline worldwide. The debate centers on harm reduction benefits over past mistakes, such as youth vaping uptake. US FDA approvals for pouches aim to offer less harmful options to adult smokers. Usage remains low but is growing, particularly among younger adults. Concerns about youth uptake persist, prompting calls for stricter regulations. Sweden shows success in reducing smoking with pouch alternatives. Despite oral health risks, innovation in product design aims to minimize harm. (Published on January 27, 2026byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>Germany Moves to Ban Menthol Vapes in Sweeping Crackdown on “Cooling” Additives</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/germany-moves-to-ban-menthol-vapes-in-sweeping-crackdown-on-cooling-additives/</link><description>Germany is set to ban menthol and cooling additives in e-cigarettes to curb their appeal, especially to young users. The decision is based on the belief that these additives make vaping more attractive and potentially more addictive. Critics argue that evidence supporting increased nicotine uptake is lacking, but the government cites the precautionary principle. The ban would impact both e-cigarettes and refill containers, with estimated compliance costs for the industry. (Published on January 27, 2026byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>OLDCORN: The real reason Ottawa won’t compare vaping, patches, gums, and nicotine pouches</title><link>https://www.westernstandard.news/opinion/oldcorn-the-real-reason-ottawa-wont-compare-vaping-patches-gums-and-nicotine-pouches/70642</link><description>Health Canada’s recent Tobacco Strategy progress report celebrates declining smoking rates and low youth smoking levels. The government aims to reduce tobacco use to under 5% by 2035. However, the report fails to differentiate effective nicotine replacement therapies (NRTs) for quitting smoking. Around 300,000 Canadians quit smoking in 2024, with over half quitting unaided, 25% using NRTs collectively, and 21% turning to vaping products. (Published on January 27, 2026bywesternstandard.news)</description></item></channel></rss>