<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:21:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Panic over vapes, opioids and Dutch teens</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/panic-over-vapes-opioids-and-dutch-teens-what-the-science-actually-says/</link><description>Recent stories about Dutch teens seeking medical attention after vaping and Belgian kids reportedly exposed to opioids through vapes are causing alarm. However, the actual data shows that while teen nicotine use is a concern, the numbers of severe cases are small. Evidence suggests vaping is less harmful than smoking for adults. The issue of opioids in vapes is serious but mainly linked to illegal products, not those from regulated shops. Policy responses should focus on targeted enforcement against illicit products and providing support for nicotine addiction in teens. It's crucial to base policies on evidence rather than misinformation or fear. (Published on December 15, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Province files claim against vaping giant JUUL in B.C. Supreme Court</title><link>https://100milefreepress.net/2025/12/12/province-files-claim-against-vaping-giant-juul-in-b-c-supreme-court/</link><description>B.C. Attorney General Niki Sharma announced the province's civil claim against JUUL, alleging the company targeted youth with addictive products. Premier David Eby aims to hold JUUL accountable, comparing it to actions against tobacco and opioid companies. Filed under the Vaping Product Damages and Health Care Costs Recovery Act, the claim accuses JUUL of contributing to a public health crisis. The move is supported by lawyer Rob Cunningham from the Canadian Cancer Society. The province seeks to recover public health costs and holds other manufacturers accountable. Tough action follows success in reducing smoking rates, with JUUL targeted due to existing lawsuits and evidence. (Published on December 15, 2025by100milefreepress.net)</description></item></channel></rss>