<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 18:17:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Moral Collapse | When Public Health Endorses Teen Smoking to Stop Vaping (Public Statement)</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/moral-collapse-when-public-health-endorses-teen-smoking-to-stop-vaping-public-statement/</link><description>Public health has crossed the line. In a stunning display of moral inversion, officials and mainstream media now endorse teen smoking as an acceptable way to “quit” vaping. In this searing RegWatch public statement, Brent Stafford dissects how a decade of fearmongering and misinformation brought us to this moment—where moral panic replaces science and a jihad against nicotine takes precedence over saving lives. (Published on October 13, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>Leaked WHO Documents Uncover Europe’s New Senseless Nicotine War</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/10/10/leaked-who-documents-uncover-europes-new-senseless-nicotine-war/</link><description>A leaked EU draft proposes treating non-combustible nicotine products like vapes and heated tobacco the same as cigarettes, causing concern for harm reduction progress. The document suggests labeling these products as addictive "gateways," potentially leading to bans and restrictions that disregard harm reduction evidence. Sweden challenges EU bans on nicotine pouches, emphasizing their public health benefits. Critics argue the EU's approach could hinder efforts to reduce smoking-related harm, opposing proven strategies like those in Sweden, Japan, and the UK. Public health advocates call for science-based policies and raise alarm over a potential EU-wide prohibition, warning against ignoring harm reduction in favor of outdated ideology. (Published on October 13, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>A Case for Vaping Freedom As the Path to Economic Revival</title><link>https://www.realclearmarkets.com/articles/2025/10/13/a_case_for_vaping_freedom_as_the_path_to_economic_revival_1140494.html</link><description>Reforming the FDA’s PMTA process would allow U.S. manufacturers and retailers to offer safer alternatives to smoking, such as e-cigarettes, nicotine pouches, and heat-not-burn products. These products are proven to help smokers quit, supporting public health while enabling small businesses to grow, hire more employees, and strengthen local economies. (Published on October 13, 2025byrealclearmarkets.com)</description></item></channel></rss>