<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:58:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Media, Researchers Fuel More Vape Misperceptions</title><link>https://filtermag.org/media-researchers-vape-misperceptions/</link><description>Media often sensationalize tobacco harm reduction, misinterpreting incomplete studies. A Guardian article claimed a study showed a third of UK teen vapers might start smoking, implying a gateway effect. Criticisms, including by Dr. Arielle Selya, questioned the study's methods and conclusions. Selya suggested a neutral approach to interpreting the results. The academic study warned of a potential link between vaping and smoking, while ASH UK reported concerns about vaping misconceptions among adults and youth. Selya attributed these misconceptions to sensationalist media coverage influencing public perception. The complex issue involves conflicting interpretations of data and potential biases. (Published on August 26, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>How Australia Is Failing People With Mental Illness Who Smoke</title><link>https://www.thr101.org/post/how-australia-is-failing-people-with-mental-illness-who-smoke</link><description>Anew study published inHealth Expectationsis providing important insight into smoking cessation among people diagnosed with mental illness. The researchers set out to explore how individuals with mental health conditions experience tobacco use and quitting, why they smoke, what motivates them to stop, and what forms of support they find helpful or lacking. Using in-depth, semi-structured interviews with 17 adults in Queensland – all of whom had a mental health diagnosis and at least one quit attempt in the past five years – the study highlights the complex interplay between tobacco use, mental health, and recovery. (Published on August 26, 2025bythr101.org)</description></item></channel></rss>