<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:24:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Malaysian state assemblyman warns vape smugglers of strict laws in Johor, Singapore</title><link>https://www.straitstimes.com/asia/se-asia/state-assemblyman-warns-vape-smugglers-of-strict-laws-in-johor-singapore</link><description>Over 15,000 vapes and components were seized at land crossings in June and July. Johor authorities warn Malaysians against smuggling vapes into Singapore due to strict laws in both countries. Syndicates use social media to sell vapes and entice locals, especially youth, with large sums of money. The Johor government supports a nationwide vape ban to empower enforcement agencies. Health Minister Dzulkefly Ahmad plans to present a Cabinet Memorandum on the ban by year-end. Recent seizures include 7,400 vape products at Woodlands Checkpoint and 7,680 vape pods at the Second Link crossing. Authorities urge vigilance and highlight the serious consequences of breaking the law in Singapore. (Published on September 15, 2025bystraitstimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Belgium banning smoking and vaping on terraces</title><link>https://euroweeklynews.com/2025/09/14/belgium-banning-smoking-and-vaping-on-terraces-from-january-2027/</link><description>Belgium will ban smoking and vaping on public terraces starting January 1, 2027. The measure aims to protect public health by preventing exposure to harmful smoke. The ban will also eliminate smoking rooms in various venues. Despite opposition, the government prioritizes health concerns over personal freedoms. This move aligns with a wider European trend of restricting smoking in public spaces. The country has seen a decline in cigarette use but a rise in e-cigarette usage. Businesses failing to comply with the new rules may face penalties. (Published on September 15, 2025byeuroweeklynews.com)</description></item><item><title>UK tourists to stop visiting Spain over new law and 'will go elsewhere'</title><link>https://www.birminghammail.co.uk/travel/uk-tourists-stop-visiting-spain-32475336.amp</link><description>A new bill in Spain aims to ban smoking and vaping at outdoor venues, sparking complaints from UK tourists who threaten to stop visiting. The proposed ban covers bars, restaurants, bus stops, stadiums, and beaches. Health Minister Monica Garcia emphasizes public health over private interests, advocating for cleaner air and longer lives. Some smokers express frustration, while others support the ban citing the nuisance of secondhand smoke. Concerns are raised about the impact on businesses and tourism, with some travelers already considering alternative destinations like Portugal. (Published on September 15, 2025bybirminghammail.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Graphic warnings on tobacco products are losing their impact – here are 5 ways to improve them</title><link>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/on-the-inside/573081/graphic-warnings-on-tobacco-products-are-losing-their-impact-here-are-5-ways-to-improve-them</link><description>Large pictorial warning labels on tobacco products aim to reduce smoking appeal through shocking images of health consequences. Approaches like emphasizing costs, family impact, and emotional harm to others are being tested for effectiveness in promoting quitting. Addressing individual experiences, balancing emotions, and rotating warnings regularly are key to improving the impact of on-pack warnings. Enhancing messaging with positive inserts can motivate quitting attempts. Recommendations suggest introducing new warnings every six months to maintain effectiveness. By understanding diverse responses to warnings, tailored approaches can effectively discourage smoking. This initiative aims to complement comprehensive strategies targeting smoking addiction and accessibility. (Published on September 15, 2025byrnz.co.nz)</description></item></channel></rss>