<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 15:17:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Does the WHO really want us to stop smoking?</title><link>https://capx.co/does-the-who-really-want-us-to-stop-smoking</link><description>The WHO spreads misinformation about vaping, failing to differentiate between harmful tobacco and safer alternatives like vapes. Statements made during a recent webinar were misleading and unsupported by evidence, falsely claiming health risks associated with reduced-risk products. This misinformation hinders efforts to reduce smoking rates and protect public health. By advocating for bans on flavors and misrepresenting safer nicotine alternatives, the WHO and governments risk benefiting Big Tobacco and impeding harm reduction efforts. To truly protect lives and combat smoking, the WHO must correct its misinformation and support evidence-based harm reduction strategies. (Published on May 15, 2025bycapx.co)</description></item><item><title>Which European country has the largest nanny state?</title><link>https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/which-european-country-has-the-largest-nanny-state/</link><description>In Europe, the Nanny State Index shows Turkey leading in strict regulations, banning vapes and heavily taxing alcohol. Lithuania follows with harsh restrictions on alcohol and e-cigarettes. Ireland prices cigarettes exorbitantly and controls supermarket choices for citizens. Finland and Hungary also have restrictive policies. Overall, the trend in Europe is towards increased state control over personal freedoms regarding eating, drinking, and smoking. (Published on May 15, 2025byspectator.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #151 | A NEW CHAPTER FOR THR EDUCATION | Chimwemwe Ngoma highlights KAC's brand new THR course!</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-151/</link><description>Building on the strength of its popular Tobacco Harm Reduction Scholarship programme, Knowledge•Action•Change's brand new foundational course 'Understanding Tobacco Harm Reduction' is a free-to-use educational platform designed to help advocates expand their knowledge base. Joining us today to highlight this key new resource is one of its key authors, Chimwemwe Ngoma of KAC! Link to the e-course:https://thr.academy/academy/ (Published on May 15, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Beyond Nicotine Replacement Therapy: Smoking Cessation for Older Americans</title><link>https://www.rstreet.org/research/beyond-nicotine-replacement-therapy-smoking-cessation-for-older-americans/</link><description>Smoking is a major issue among older Americans, with higher rates of smoking and lower quit attempts compared to younger individuals. Nicotine Replacement Therapy (NRT) is effective in aiding smoking cessation, but older smokers face barriers such as cost and access. Combining NRT with Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT) and social support can enhance quitting success. Additionally, promoting non-combustible nicotine products like e-cigarettes can offer alternative quitting methods. To support smoking cessation among older Americans, tailored education, accessible resources, and policy interventions are crucial to increase awareness and decrease environmental triggers. Providing a variety of cessation options is essential for improving the health outcomes of older smokers. (Published on May 16, 2025byrstreet.org)</description></item></channel></rss>