<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:24:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vapes Improve Quit Chances</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2026-01-19_argie-bargy.html</link><description>A new report, Tale of Two Nations: Argentina v Sweden, shows that safer nicotine alternatives such as vapes and oral nicotine pouches significantly improve smokers’ chances of quitting, particularly as part of a New Year’s attempt. The report contrasts Argentina’s rising smoking rates with Sweden’s success in reducing smoking through regulated access to smoke-free alternatives such as vapes. (Published on January 19, 2026byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>The war on snus</title><link>https://cyprus-mail.com/2026/01/11/the-war-on-snus</link><description>Cyprus' unclear regulations on nicotine pouches have created confusion. These pouches lack proper approval for sale, leading to legal issues and public health concerns. Despite potential harm reduction benefits, the inconsistency in regulating these products has left consumers and sellers in a precarious situation. The debate on nicotine pouches, also known as snus, highlights the need for comprehensive legislation to address their sale, composition, and taxation. Failure to establish clear guidelines risks impacting public health, revenue collection, and the prevalence of illicit sales. Addressing these issues through regulation rather than prohibition could provide a more effective solution. (Published on January 20, 2026bycyprus-mail.com)</description></item></channel></rss>