<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 12:29:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #79 | SUICIDAL POLICY | Michelle Minton and America’s War on Safer Nicotine</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-79-suicidal-policy-michelle-minton-and-americas-war-on-safer-nicotine/</link><description>America’s tobacco policy has turned self-destructive. Safer nicotine products are demonized and restricted while combustible cigarettes remain widely available. In this GFN interview, Michelle Minton of the Reason Foundation explains how fear, ideology, and institutional incentives replaced evidence in U.S. tobacco control—pushing consumers back toward smoking and undermining one of the greatest public-health opportunities of our time. (Published on January 12, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>EU commissioner in hot water for smoke-free nicotine statement</title><link>https://www.vejpkollen.se/en/2026/01/eu-kommissionar-i-blasvader-efter-uttalande-om-rokfritt-nikotin/</link><description>EU Health Commissioner Olivér Várhelyi faces backlash for claiming that smokeless nicotine products are as harmful as cigarettes, sparking criticism and strong reactions. Várhelyi, referring to the WHO, suggests taxing these products like cigarettes, despite lacking scientific evidence to support the claim. The debate continues as Várhelyi's stance is questioned by scientists and seen as misinformation by critics, including those in Sweden. The controversy follows past disputed statements by Várhelyi on nicotine, prompting calls for accountability and scrutiny of his role in public health. The European Commission is expected to propose new regulations for nicotine products in 2026, potentially affecting taxes on snus and e-cigarettes. (Published on January 12, 2026byvejpkollen.se)</description></item></channel></rss>