<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:22:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Smokefree 2026 For The Young</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2026-01-13_smokefree-2026-for-the-young.html</link><description>Action on Smoking and Health (ASH) has revealed that new data shows 69% of British 11–17-year-old smokers say that, if they had their time again, they would not have started smoking. Almost two-thirds expressed a desire to quit and the anti-smoking charity says its findings highlights the importance of phasing out the sale of tobacco. ASH’s annual survey covered almost 3,000 children and was conducted by polling company YouGov. (Published on January 14, 2026byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Most Hong Kong residents support more smoking control measures, study finds</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3339788/most-hong-kong-residents-support-more-smoking-control-measures-study-finds</link><description>A survey by the Hong Kong Council on Smoking and Health (COSH) found that 90% of residents back stronger smoking control, and raising tobacco tax could reduce smoking rates over the next decade. The University of Hong Kong (HKU) study, commissioned by COSH, revealed support for expanded smoke-free areas and a smoking ban in outdoor spaces. Conducted from December 2024 to May the following year, the survey had 5,600 participants, including smokers, former smokers, and non-smokers. Assistant Dean Kelvin Wang Man-ping highlighted widespread public support for increased no-smoking areas as a means to protect public health. (Published on January 14, 2026byscmp.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #169 | UK Tobacco &amp; Vapes Bill 2026: Everything You Need to Know</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-169-uk-tobacco-vapes-bill-2026-everything-you-need-to-know/</link><description>Join us for the interview with Martin Cullip as he break down the UK Tobacco and Vapes Bill, expected to become law in 2026. He explores the generational smoking ban, vaping and nicotine regulations, and potential impacts on adult users. Learn why nicotine pouches, flavor restrictions, and ministerial powers are sparking debate, and how consumers and harm-reduction advocates can make their voices heard. (Published on January 14, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Viral “Zynfluencer” TikTok videos may be linked to growing oral nicotine pouch sales</title><link>https://truthinitiative.org/research-resources/emerging-tobacco-products/viral-zynfluencer-tiktok-videos-may-be-linked-growing</link><description>A study by Truth Initiative found a surge in TikTok content featuring pouch products, correlating with a significant growth in oral nicotine pouch sales. The analysis spanning from January 2021 to October 2023 revealed a spike in viral TikTok videos related to pouches, leading to a sales increase of over 12 million units. This trend continued with the market growth rate surpassing 20 million units the following month. The researchers suggest a link between the prevalence of pouch-related TikTok videos and the market expansion, indicating a potential relationship between social media virality and the normalization of nicotine pouch use. (Published on January 14, 2026bytruthinitiative.org)</description></item></channel></rss>