<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 06:49:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The WHO is a risk-factor for cancer</title><link>https://clivebates.substack.com/p/the-who-is-a-risk-factor-for-cancer</link><description>In a new Code Against Cancer, the World Health Organisation opposes the most effective and popular way to reduce the most important modifiable cancer risk, smoking. So, what does that make WHO? (Published on February 25, 2026bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Prohibitive policies drove organised crime in Australia 100 years ago. It’s happening again</title><link>https://theconversation.com/prohibitive-policies-drove-organised-crime-in-australia-100-years-ago-its-happening-again-270171</link><description>Organised crime in Australia, spanning decades, thrives on illegal markets. Historically, prohibition and stringent regulations drive criminal enterprises, like 1920s razor gangs or recent tobacco wars. Despite efforts to curb illicit activities, escalating enforcement hasn't deterred the trade. Today, illicit drug markets cost billions, with drugs like nicotine rapidly growing. Outcomes mirror past failures when suppressing gambling, drugs, and sex work, reinforcing criminal control. Adjusting regulations, as seen in cannabis decriminalization proposals, can reduce organized crime impact and enhance public safety. Balancing control and legality can combat criminal influence and protect consumers, ultimately weakening organized crime's financial incentives and reducing violence in society. (Published on February 25, 2026bytheconversation.com)</description></item><item><title>Could a gene lower nicotine dependence? What a CHRNB3 variant suggests</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2026-02-gene-nicotine-chrnb3-variant.html</link><description>A study in Nature Communications identified a nicotine receptor gene variant linked to lower daily cigarette consumption in Mexican, East Asian, and European populations. Variants in CHRNB3 were found to decrease smoking frequency by 21% to 78%. The study highlights the potential of targeting the β3 subunit for treating nicotine addiction. Further research in larger cohorts is required to fully understand the impact of these genetic variants on smoking dependency. The findings suggest that genetic factors play a role in smoking behavior across different ancestries, indicating potential therapeutic interventions for nicotine addiction. (Published on February 25, 2026bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>WHO chief urges Ireland to close EU nicotine ‘loopholes’ ahead of presidency</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/who-chief-urges-ireland-to-close-eu-nicotine-loopholes-ahead-of-presidency/</link><description>WHO urged Ireland to influence EU regulations on nicotine products due to industry opposition. Tedros emphasized the need for updated laws addressing vapes and nicotine pouches popular among youth, highlighting gaps in EU rules. Ireland's leadership in tobacco regulation was commended. The delay in revising EU rules has led countries like Ireland to enact their measures. The Commission acknowledges the urgency to tackle increased youth vape use. Ireland's vape tax revenue fell short of forecasts, attributed to difficulties in estimating the market size and compliance issues. Responsible Vaping Ireland suggested tax stamps and crackdowns on the black market. EU negotiations on tobacco control laws may start in 2027. (Published on February 25, 2026byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>NNA Briefing on the Proposed Ban of Vaping in Public Places</title><link>https://nnalliance.org/nnanews/news/409-nna-briefing-on-the-proposed-ban-of-vaping-in-public-places</link><description>The government has recently launched a public consultation on a proposed ban on vaping in public places, a move that the New Nicotine Alliance considers misguided and an unnecessary extension of legislative control without sufficient evidence or justification. As a charity dedicated to promoting harm reduction, the organisation believes it is essential that the perspectives of those who understand and have experienced the benefits of safer alternatives to smoking are clearly represented in this process. Personal experiences and informed insights are seen as powerful tools in shaping balanced, evidence-based policies. (Published on February 25, 2026bynnalliance.org)</description></item></channel></rss>