<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 12:28:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>European girls aged 13-15 have world’s highest rate of tobacco use for age group</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2026/feb/27/european-girls-tobacco-smoking-vaping-who</link><description>Teenage girls in Europe have high tobacco and e-cigarette usage rates, with Europe expected to lead in tobacco consumption until 2030. 40% of adult female smokers worldwide are in Europe, while 4 million European teens use tobacco. Europe also has high e-cigarette use among teens and adults. Tobacco-related deaths in Europe total 1.1m annually. WHO warns that without action, Europe will remain the worst region by 2030. The industry's targeting of young people contributes to high e-cigarette use among children. Countries like Belgium, Denmark, and the Netherlands show regulations can combat this trend. Only a third of European countries have comprehensive smoke-free laws. Strong tobacco control measures are needed to address evolving nicotine products and protect public health. (Published on February 27, 2026bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #82 | How Nicotine Pouches Finished What Snus Started?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-82-how-nicotine-pouches-finished-what-snus-started/</link><description>Sweden’s smoke-free success is often credited to snus, but that’s only half the story. While snus appealed to many men looking to quit smoking, for women the smell, taste, and feel left something to be desired. For years, women were left without a viable alternative. That changed with nicotine pouches. Tobacco-free, discreet, and socially acceptable, they became the missing solution. In this GFN Interviews, Carissa Düring explains why nicotine pouches didn’t just complement the Sweden Model, they completed it, delivering the silver bullet public health refuses to acknowledge. (Published on February 27, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>The Irreconcilable Conflict Principle (redux)</title><link>https://clivebates.substack.com/p/the-irreconcilable-conflict-principle</link><description>The governing idea of tobacco control is an irreconcilable conflict between the interests of the tobacco industry and public health. The idea is wrong and dangerous. [This is a substantially updated and expanded version of an article previously published in Tobacco Reporter that is no longer available] (Published on February 27, 2026bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>England May Ban Vaping in Cars When Kids Are Present</title><link>https://filtermag.org/england-ban-vaping-cars-children/</link><description>England is considering a ban on vaping in cars with children to lower exposure to secondhand smoke. This proposal, part of a public consultation, aligns with efforts under a tobacco harm reduction bill. Critics argue against equating vaping with smoking, citing minimal risks from vapor compared to smoke. Advocates stress the importance of recognizing vaping's role in smoking cessation. Enforcement concerns and potential unintended consequences raise doubts about the ban's efficacy. Vaping remains permitted outside certain locations, acknowledging its harm reduction potential. The ban could perpetuate misinformation and harm smokers trying to quit. Public feedback is encouraged to influence the decision before the May 8 consultation deadline. (Published on February 27, 2026byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Brazil Is Losing the Fight</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2026-02-25_brazil-is-losing-the-fight.html</link><description>Brazil is losing the battle against smoking due its negative stance on safer nicotine alternatives, according to a major new report from Smoke Free Sweeden. The leading international health experts have compared Brazil’s experience and New Zealand to reveal how different policy choices are producing sharply different outcomes. Just over a decade ago, New Zealand had a higher smoking rate than Brazil. Today, its rate is around half Brazil’s. (Published on February 27, 2026byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>