<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 12:26:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #6 | Interview with Ian Fearon</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-6-interview-with-ian-fearon</link><description>Flavors can play a key role in helping smokers switch. Many start with tobacco flavor but move to others over time — distancing themselves from the reminder of smoking. As adults, we enjoy sweets, drinks, and treats — why should quitting be any different? (Published on August 12, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Vapes and HTPs Reduce Toxin Exposure by More than 90%, Lithuanian Study Finds</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/vapes-and-htps-reduce-toxin-exposure-by-more-than-90-lithuanian-study-finds</link><description>Heated tobacco products (HTPs) and vapes reduce exposure to harmful chemicals by more than 90 per cent compared to cigarettes, according to a major new study. (Published on August 12, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>WHO Backs Thailand’s E-Cigarette Ban: Ignoring Evidence and Silencing Consumers</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/who-backs-thailands-e-cigarette-ban-ignoring-evidence-and-silencing-consumers</link><description>Thailand’s ongoing ban on e-cigarettes, supported by the World Health Organization (WHO), is a policy deeply disconnected from real-world evidence and the voices of those it most affects: the consumers seeking safer alternatives to smoking. (Published on August 12, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Barbados Has a Unique Opportunity to Champion Harm Reduction at COP11</title><link>https://nationnews.com/2025/08/11/barbados-has-a-unique-opportunity-to-champion-harm-reduction-at-cop11</link><description>This year, the world’s eyes will turn to Geneva as leaders gather for COP11, the World Health Organization’s critical conference on tobacco control. As decisions are made that will impact global health for years to come, Barbados finds itself at a crossroads. Will the country simply follow the crowd, or will it seize the chance to be a bold voice for pragmatic, science-driven solutions like harm reduction? (Published on August 12, 2025bynationnews.com)</description></item><item><title>Flavoured Vaping Products in Tobacco Harm Reduction: A Regulatory Perspective</title><link>https://www.cureus.com/articles/382895-flavoured-vaping-products-in-tobacco-harm-reduction-a-regulatory-perspective</link><description>Reducing the harms associated with cigarette smoking is a global public health priority. Both the individual‑ and population‑level health impacts of smoking can be reduced by novel products which deliver nicotine, but the use of which decreases user exposure to the harmful chemical toxicants responsible for smoking‑related disease. Electronic vaping products (...) (Published on August 12, 2025bycureus.com)</description></item><item><title>The Transition from Disposable to Reusable Vapes</title><link>https://manufacturing-update.co.uk/2025/08/12/the-transition-from-disposable-to-reusable-vapes</link><description>The UK’s ban on single-use vapes has two core aims; to make vaping less appealing to young people while still acting as a smoking cessation tool, and an environmentally friendly initiative by reducing waste and incentivising a transition to reusable products. The ban came into force on June 1, 2025, and one Financial Times report suggests the ban has not had much of (...) (Published on August 13, 2025bymanufacturing-update.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Should We Urge Adult Smokers To Vape?</title><link>https://www.acsh.org/news/2025/08/12/podcast-should-we-urge-adult-smokers-vape-49670</link><description>Smoking kills hundreds of thousands of Americans annually. As this death toll mounts, studies continue to show that nicotine vaping is significantly less harmful than smoking and far more effective than FDA-approved cessation therapies like nicotine gum. (Published on August 13, 2025byacsh.org)</description></item><item><title>CAPHRA Urges Vaping Manufacturers To Champion Environmental Leadership</title><link>https://www.scoop.co.nz/stories/WO2508/S00148/caphra-urges-vaping-manufacturers-to-champion-environmental-leadership.htm</link><description>In response to mounting concerns over the environmental impact of discarded vaping products, the Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA) is calling on manufacturers to show genuine leadership in sustainability and social responsibility. (Published on August 13, 2025byscoop.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>Vape Sellers to Pay Disposal Costs Under Plans to End UK’s “Throwaway Culture”</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/aug/12/vape-sellers-pay-disposal-costs-plans-end-uk-throwaway-culture</link><description>Vape sellers to pay disposal costs under plans to end UK’s "throwaway culture". Ministers say online vendors of electrical goods such as microwaves will also have to contribute to recycling fees. (Published on August 13, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Balearic Government Rejects Smoking Ban on Beaches</title><link>https://www.tobaccojournal.com/news/balearic-government-rejects-smoking-ban-on-beaches</link><description>Spain’s central government wants to extend its smoking ban to beaches and restaurant terraces, but faces resistance from the Balearic Islands. (Published on August 13, 2025bytobaccojournal.com)</description></item></channel></rss>