<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 18:18:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vaping linked to higher COPD risk, meta-analysis finds</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250708/Vaping-linked-to-higher-COPD-risk-meta-analysis-finds.aspx</link><description>Research reveals e-cigarettes are linked to increased risk of chronic lung disease, especially for current and former users. The study analyzed observational data from various countries and found that current users have a 48% higher risk, while former users face an 84% higher risk of COPD. However, causation is not confirmed, and findings could be influenced by factors like smoking history. Transitioning from traditional cigarettes to vaping involves risks, and further longitudinal research is recommended to understand the long-term effects of e-cigarette use on lung health. Public health guidance should aim to balance smoking cessation benefits with potential respiratory harm from vaping. (Published on July 10, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>Sweden rejects EU plan to fund budget with tobacco tax</title><link>https://www.euractiv.com/section/economy-jobs/news/sweden-rejects-eu-plan-to-fund-budget-with-tobacco-tax/</link><description>Swedish Finance Minister Elisabeth Svantesson has rejected an EU proposal to use revenue from increased tobacco taxes to fund the next long-term EU budget, calling it “completely unacceptable.” The idea, mentioned in a German parliamentary document, suggests new funding sources like levies on tobacco and electronic waste for the 2028–2034 budget. Although not yet confirmed by the European Commission, pressure is mounting from at least 15 EU countries to raise tobacco taxes. The Commission is reportedly considering a 139% tax increase on cigarettes and higher taxes on e-cigarettes, nicotine pouches, and heated tobacco. (Published on July 10, 2025byeuractiv.com)</description></item><item><title>In Sweden, smokeless products drive tobacco harm reduction push</title><link>https://rollcall.com/2025/07/10/in-sweden-smokeless-products-drive-tobacco-harm-reduction-push/</link><description>Karl Fagerström, a Swedish researcher and inventor, founded Niconovum for smoking cessation, creating tobacco-free nicotine pouches. Despite public health interest waning, harm reduction advocates emphasize safer nicotine consumption alternatives. In Sweden, smokeless products are popular, prompting tobacco harm reduction support. In the US, former FDA commissioners suggest promoting noncombustible nicotine products. Small companies face challenges in gaining FDA approval, unlike in Sweden where regulations are more flexible. Public health debates the efficacy of harm reduction approaches, acknowledging the addictive nature of nicotine products. The tobacco industry's role in harm reduction efforts remains controversial. (Published on July 10, 2025byrollcall.com)</description></item></channel></rss>