<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 15:19:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Media: EU-level push to drastically raise excise duty on tobacco products</title><link>https://bnn-news.com/media-eu-level-push-to-drastically-raise-excise-duty-on-tobacco-products-268193#google_vignette</link><description>Wealthy EU countries are urging the European Commission to revisit plans for a minimum tax on e-cigarettes and raise excise duties on tobacco products, proposed by Commissioner Wopke Hoekstra. The plan faces opposition from countries with lower tax rates and those investing in innovative tobacco. Italy warns against hindering innovation, as sharp tax hikes could increase smuggling. Concerns are raised over proposed high taxes on new tobacco products lacking EU regulation. The push for a unified EU policy on alternative tobacco products is suggested to address rising smuggling issues. Drastic tax hikes may not be suitable now, as they could strain resources and enforcement without substantial benefits. (Published on May 29, 2025bybnn-news.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #154 | THE PHILOSOPHY OF THR | Featuring Will Godfrey</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-154/</link><description>In this episode of GFN News, Will Godfrey highlights a recent interview between Kiran Sidhu and renowned philosopher Dr. Sridhar Venkatapuram exploring the intersection of philosophy and public health, and the ethical support for tobacco harm reduction using safer nicotine products. (Published on May 29, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>