<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:54:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Wisconsin to enforce new regulations on electronic vaping devices beginning Sept. 1</title><link>https://fox11online.com/news/state/wisconsin-to-enforce-new-regulations-on-electronic-vaping-devices-beginning-sept-1-department-revenue-law-directory-fine-nicotine-hemp</link><description>New regulations in Wisconsin ban the sale of electronic vaping devices not listed on a directory starting Sept. 1. There are currently 216 approved products. Hemp-containing, nicotine-free devices have until July 1, 2026, to comply. Violators face a $1,000 daily fine per device and potential seizure. The Department of Revenue manages the directory. (Published on August 29, 2025byfox11online.com)</description></item><item><title>Are Girls the New Potheads?</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/ie/blog/addiction-outlook/202508/are-girls-the-new-potheads</link><description>In 2024, a Monitoring the Future report revealed a shift with girls using marijuana more than boys, particularly through vaping. The trend reflects girls preferring vaping over smoking, influenced by attractive packaging and discreet use. Females also have a higher prevalence of vaping nicotine. Concerns arise about possible health risks associated with vaping. Girls' increased marijuana use may relate to biological factors and coping mechanisms for mental health issues. The shift highlights the need for tailored prevention strategies and addressing female-specific perceptions about substance use. Additionally, a recent seizure of illegal e-cigarettes emphasizes the importance of regulating vaping products to prevent underage use. (Published on August 29, 2025bypsychologytoday.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #8 | Harm Reduction in Action: A Toxicologist’s View on Safer Nicotine Alternatives</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-8/</link><description>In this episode of GFN Voices 2025, pharmacology and toxicology expert Ingrid Taricano shares why harm reduction isn’t just an option—it’s at the very heart of toxicology. From medicines to food, and even safer alternatives to smoking, toxicology is about understanding limits and reducing risks. Hear Ingrid’s perspective on why science, policy, and public health must embrace harm reduction to create safer choices for people everywhere. (Published on August 29, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Barbados can shape the future of tobacco control</title><link>https://barbadostoday.bb/2025/08/28/barbados-can-shape-the-future-of-tobacco-control/</link><description>Barbados has made strides in reducing smoking rates but can do more, especially in addressing gender disparities. Ahead of COP11, the country can advocate for smarter tobacco policies based on harm reduction, such as vaping and nicotine pouches. Evidence shows harm reduction effectively lowers smoking rates, but global institutions often overlook it. Barbados should assert its leadership by pushing for a dedicated tobacco harm reduction working group at COP11. By prioritizing people's health over politics, Barbados can lead the way towards a smoke-free nation and set an example for other smaller countries. The time is now for Barbados to act decisively in supporting harm reduction and advocating for transparent, evidence-based tobacco control measures. (Published on August 29, 2025bybarbadostoday.bb)</description></item></channel></rss>