<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:21:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Gov't to collect more taxes as e-cigarettes are legally classified as tobacco</title><link>https://www.koreatimes.co.kr/economy/policy/20251203/govt-to-collect-more-taxes-as-e-cigarettes-are-legally-classified-as-tobacco</link><description>A revised law now includes e-cigarettes in tobacco taxation to boost tax collection for financing fiscal policies. The National Assembly expanded the definition of tobacco to cover synthetic nicotine, aiming to generate an estimated 1 trillion won annually. The Ministry of Economy and Finance stated that the revised law encompasses all components of tobacco plants and nicotine. E-cigarettes will face tobacco taxes after a possible two-year grace period. The revision addresses a national tax shortfall and is vital for funding expansionary fiscal policies, as highlighted by the approved 2026 national budget increase to 727.9 trillion won. (Published on December 03, 2025bykoreatimes.co.kr)</description></item><item><title>Researchers alarmed as study suggests many teens vape at night</title><link>https://www.dutchnews.nl/2025/12/researchers-alarmed-as-study-suggests-many-teens-vape-at-night/</link><description>Dutch doctors found high nicotine addiction among teens, affecting over a third of young smokers who wake up needing nicotine. The study surveyed 978 pupils across five secondary schools, highlighting a concerning level of dependency starting at age 13. Researchers stress the need for restrictions on tobacco products and increased awareness among parents. E-cigarettes, widely used by teenagers, pose health risks due to their nicotine content. Night-time vaping can disrupt sleep, impacting mental health and academic performance. An anti-vaping campaign has been launched as cases of severe health issues related to vaping rise in the Netherlands. (Published on December 03, 2025bydutchnews.nl)</description></item><item><title>SGF calls for clear guidance over nicotine pouches in letter to health secretary</title><link>https://www.talkingretail.com/featured/sgf-calls-for-clear-guidance-over-nicotine-pouches-in-letter-to-health-secretary-03-12-2025/</link><description>The convenience store trade body reaffirms responsible retailing commitment to Wes Streeting regarding illegal high-strength nicotine pouches. Highlighting the lack of official guidance, SGF emphasizes the need for clear standards in the sale and promotion of nicotine pouches to prevent sales to minors. It suggests industry-government collaboration to develop guidelines, advocating age restrictions in line with the Tobacco and Vapes Bill. SGF plans to engage with ministers and officials to address the issue. The organization also shares concerns with the Scottish government. SGF stresses that clear guidelines should ensure nicotine pouches are only sold to adults and not marketed to children. Reports of illegal high-strength products with over 100mg of nicotine raise further concerns. (Published on December 03, 2025bytalkingretail.com)</description></item><item><title>Health select committee erupts into heated debate over roll out of oral tobacco and nicotine products</title><link>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/political/580761/health-select-committee-erupts-into-heated-debate-over-roll-out-of-oral-tobacco-and-nicotine-products</link><description>Associate Health Minister Casey Costello faced criticism over government plans to introduce oral tobacco and nicotine products, amidst concerns of big tobacco influence. Costello emphasized the importance of achieving Smokefree 2025 goals, focusing on harm reduction strategies like e-cigarettes. Labour's Dr. Ayesha Verrall questioned the introduction of new nicotine forms, raising concerns about youth addiction. Costello highlighted the need for regulatory control and options for older smokers struggling to quit. ACT's Cameron Luxton highlighted issues in Australia's tobacco regulations. Public health expert Dr. Jude Ball cautioned against introducing more addictive products, citing marketing to youth by tobacco companies. Legislation to reduce nicotine in cigarettes was discussed as a potential solution. (Published on December 03, 2025byrnz.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>Costa Rica Eyes Complete Vape Ban to Combat Rising Teen Use and Risks</title><link>https://ticotimes.net/2025/12/02/costa-rica-eyes-complete-vape-ban-to-combat-rising-teen-use-and-risks</link><description>Costa Rica's ruling party member proposes a bill to ban vapes completely, citing health risks, especially for youth. The bill includes outlawing import, sale, and use, as well as related activities like advertising and distribution. Law 25.309 would also establish a prohibited substances list and repeal a current law with a 20% tax on vaping products. The lawmaker emphasizes minors' easy access to vapes, health issues like lung damage, and industry tactics targeting young users. The proposal mirrors bans in other Latin American countries and faces concerns about potential black markets. The bill is pending further legislative review. (Published on December 03, 2025byticotimes.net)</description></item><item><title>Danish Presidency and European Commission push 'super tax' on heated tobacco as NGO influence overrides member state concerns</title><link>https://www.eureporter.co/politics/european-council/2025/12/02/danish-presidency-and-european-commission-push-super-tax-on-heated-tobacco-as-ngo-influence-overrides-member-state-concerns/</link><description>Denmark’s EU Presidency has proposed a sharp tax increase on heated tobacco products in a last-minute revision of the Tobacco Excise Directive, favoring NGO anti-tobacco demands while ignoring member states’ concerns The new draft, circulated on 28 November, introduces higher minimum taxes, changes product definitions, and sparks criticism for bypassing democratic scrutiny Critics argue the “super tax” undermines harm-reduction goals and reflects advocacy more than EU state consensus. (Published on December 03, 2025byeureporter.co)</description></item></channel></rss>