<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 06:20:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The FDA’s Failure Fuels Confusion and State Overreach on Vaping</title><link>https://dcjournal.com/the-fdas-failure-fuels-confusion-and-state-overreach-on-vaping/</link><description>With most state legislatures on break, vapers have a temporary pause from new taxes and restrictions. However, the FDA’s failure to regulate harm reduction products continues to pose a threat. In 2025, Indiana and Illinois passed major tax hikes on cigarettes and vaping products, while flavor bans failed in states like Hawaii, Oregon, and Washington. A consistent, science-based federal approach is urgently needed. (Published on July 23, 2025bydcjournal.com)</description></item><item><title>#GFN25 Panel Discussion | Reflections on the Framework Convention on Tobacco Control at 20</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn25-panel-discussion-reflections-on-the-framework-convention-on-tobacco-control-at-20/</link><description>Despite its aim to reduce global consumption of cigarettes, the impact of the WHO’s Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) on tobacco use has been heavily contested, particularly in relation to low-income countries. The panel will assess the effectiveness of the convention as it reaches its 20th anniversary, and highlight areas that need drastic change, if it is to have any future relevance in reducing smoking. (Published on July 23, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>French nicotine pouch ban on hold amid EU backlash</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/french-nicotine-pouch-ban-on-hold-amid-eu-backlash/</link><description>France has delayed its ban on nicotine pouches until August 25 due to objections from seven EU countries. The proposed ban would treat nicotine pouches as dangerous substances, with penalties of up to five years in jail for possession. Critics argue banning these safer alternatives could worsen smoking rates. In contrast, Sweden, a leader in harm reduction, saw success in reducing smoking by supporting alternatives. France justifies the ban as a means to protect public health, while opponents, including pouch manufacturers, highlight the pouches' low risk profile compared to traditional smoking products. The EU-mandated pause allows France to reconsider its plan by the new deadline. (Published on July 23, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>We Must Act Now: Ban E-Cigarettes To Protect Our Children And Youth</title><link>https://www.businesstoday.com.my/2025/07/23/we-must-act-now-ban-e-cigarettes-to-protect-our-children-and-youth/</link><description>Teenagers in Malaysia are increasingly addicted to e-cigarettes, leading to a public health crisis. The country implemented stricter regulations in 2024 to combat this issue, including age restrictions and bans on advertising. However, challenges persist with the industry exploiting loopholes and selling dangerous products. E-cigarettes contain toxic substances, have caused injuries, and are increasingly laced with illicit drugs. Malaysia must take decisive action to address this alarming trend. Other countries have banned e-cigarettes to protect public health, highlighting the need for comprehensive measures. Urgent action is essential to prevent further harm to young people and the community. (Published on July 23, 2025bybusinesstoday.com.my)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouch taxes undermine efforts to help smokers quit</title><link>https://reason.org/commentary/nicotine-pouch-taxes-undermine-efforts-to-help-smokers-quit/?utm_campaign=reason_policy&amp;utm_content=&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_term=</link><description>Rhode Island has increased taxes on nicotine pouches by 80%, impacting harm reduction efforts and public health. The FDA approved Zyn pouches as a safer alternative for smokers, reducing tobacco-related harms. The tax hike jeopardizes these benefits, affecting low-income individuals and potentially leading to unintended consequences such as reduced tax revenue and cross-border shopping. The move contradicts harm reduction strategies, neglecting the success of providing safer options. Nicotine pouches offer a less harmful alternative to smoking, yet the tax increase may hinder their accessibility. States should consider evidence-based policies supporting harm reduction to improve public health outcomes instead of punitive taxation. (Published on July 23, 2025byreason.org)</description></item></channel></rss>