<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 12:25:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pakistan Bill Would Treat Vape Like Cigarettes</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2026/01/08/pakistan-bill-would-treat-vape-like-cigarettes/</link><description>Pakistan's Senate Committee approved the Electronic Nicotine Delivery Systems Bill to regulate vaping amid concerns of youth usage. The bill imposes strict controls, including banning sales near educational institutions, setting a minimum age of 18, and prohibiting vaping in public spaces. It aligns vape regulations with traditional tobacco products, enforcing advertising bans and product standards. Penalties include fines up to Rs 50,000 ($175) for offenders. The bill awaits Senate discussion after inter-ministerial review, indicating increased oversight in Pakistan's vaping industry. (Published on January 09, 2026bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Youth Vaping, Smoking and Drinking at Record Lows, Per Latest NIDA Data</title><link>https://filtermag.org/youth-vaping-smoking-and-drinking-at-record-lows-per-latest-nida-data/</link><description>The 2025 Monitoring the Future Survey by NIDA shows stable low rates of youth substance use post-pandemic. Abstention from alcohol, cannabis, vapes, and cigarettes reached record levels across all grades. Factors disrupting drug use during the pandemic may lead to long-term changes. Despite concerns, nicotine vaping among teens remains lower post-pandemic. Heroin and cocaine show slight increases, but are still at low percentages. The MFS has influenced public policy since 1975 and remains unaffected by funding changes. Abstention rates continue to drop, suggesting lasting impacts on youth substance use behaviors. (Published on January 09, 2026byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Dr Dzulkefly warns celebrities against promoting tobacco and vape products</title><link>https://www.thevibes.com/articles/news/117975/dr-dzulkefly-warns-celebrities-against-promoting-tobacco-and-vape-products</link><description>Minister of Health Dr Dzulkefly Ahmad warns that laws against tobacco and vaping promotion apply to all, regardless of status. Comedian Shuib Sepahtu was fined RM10,000 for promoting e-cigarettes, setting an important legal precedent. The Health Ministry stresses the importance of influencers and content creators in addressing smoking culture. The government is committed to enforcing regulations equally to tackle rising youth exposure to tobacco and vaping content online. (Published on January 09, 2026bythevibes.com)</description></item></channel></rss>