<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 12:26:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How much a packet of cigarettes will rise to revealed if Rachel Reeves continues with hike in Budget</title><link>https://www.thesun.co.uk/money/37366532/how-much-a-packet-of-cigarettes-will-rise/</link><description>Annual tobacco tax hikes are set to continue, potentially raising the price of a 20-pack of cigarettes to £17.66. The government aims to discourage smoking through these increases. The cost of rolling tobacco is also expected to rise significantly. Despite price hikes over the years, smoking rates in the UK have declined due to increased awareness of health risks, with a target to become "smoke free" by 2030. Concerns exist over these tax hikes disproportionately affecting low-income smokers and potentially fueling illicit trade. Additionally, new taxes on vaping products may hinder smoking cessation efforts. The Budget may also include tax increases for bookies and the elimination of a fuel duty cut. (Published on November 24, 2025bythesun.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Good COP 2.0 | Day 5 of 5 | RegWatch (Live)</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/good-cop-2-0-day-5-of-5-regwatch-live/</link><description>DAY #5 | Live from Geneva, Switzerland – RegWatch special coverage of the Taxpayers Protection Alliance’s Good COP 2.0, the tobacco harm reduction counter-conference to the World Health Organization’s COP 11. (Published on November 24, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>Denmark is Trying to Ban Nicotine Pouches in Sweden</title><link>https://pouchpatrol.com/harm-reduction/denmark-is-trying-to-ban-nicotine-pouches-in-sweden/</link><description>Secret negotiations in Geneva under the WHO's FCTC on nicotine pouches involve Denmark and Brazil pushing for a global ban, despite the EU allowing them. The closed-door talks lack transparency, potentially leading to undemocratic laws. Sweden's delegation, split on the ban, faces pressure to align with Parliament's stance. Pouch Patrol urges Sweden to defend nicotine pouches, citing their life-saving benefits. Denmark's attempt to reintroduce a ban through the EU is contentious. The EU mandate does not mention a ban, but Denmark seeks to impose restrictions. Controversy surrounds Brazil and Denmark's proposals. (Published on November 24, 2025bypouchpatrol.com)</description></item><item><title>Bureaucrats and busybodies: COP11’s “experts” SA can do without</title><link>https://dailyfriend.co.za/2025/11/22/bureaucrats-and-busybodies-cop11s-experts-sa-can-do-without/</link><description>The COP11 in Geneva convenes to discuss tobacco control, yet critics emphasize the lack of individual rights in global health policy decisions. Foreign influences, like Bloomberg Philanthropies, are accused of promoting draconian measures that infringe on personal freedoms in South Africa's Tobacco Bill. Professor Lekan Ayo-Yusuf's advocacy for stringent controls aligns with international agendas, raising concerns over bodily autonomy and coercion. The narrative questions the intentions behind foreign-funded anti-tobacco campaigns, urging a balanced approach that respects individual choices and harm reduction strategies. (Published on November 24, 2025bydailyfriend.co.za)</description></item></channel></rss>