<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 06:19:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New Technology for Nicotine Pouches May Improve Oral Health</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/06/03/new-technology-for-nicotine-pouches-may-improve-oral-health/</link><description>A study conducted by researchers from various countries, including Sweden and the UK, found that switching to a new, gum-protective technology in nicotine pouches can reverse damage to the gums and oral lining. Twenty-three Swedish dentists switched to using these pouches for five weeks, resulting in a decrease in snus-related lesions by 52% and the elimination of gingivitis. The study highlights the potential for technological innovation to reduce the harm of nicotine products and assist smokers in quitting, promoting public health. Prof. Riccardo Polosa of CoEHAR emphasizes the importance of developing safer alternatives for tobacco harm reduction. (Published on June 05, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>World Vapers’ Alliance Academy 2025</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/academy/</link><description>The World Vapers’ Alliance (WVA) has announced the return of its Academy in 2025. Scheduled to take place on June 18th at 16:00 local time, ahead of the Global Forum on Nicotine in Warsaw, Poland, the initiative aims to bring together vaping advocates from around the world. Participants will have the opportunity to develop advocacy skills, connect with peers, and engage in discussions on tobacco harm reduction and related policy issues. More information is available on theWVA website. (Published on June 03, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Utah Proposes New E-Cigarette Regulations and Taxes</title><link>https://www.thr101.org/post/utah-proposes-new-e-cigarette-regulations-and-taxes</link><description>Utah lawmakers propose an 86.5% tax on e-cigarettes to deter youth use, but experts argue this might harm public health benefits and small businesses. E-cigarettes are considered safer than traditional cigarettes by various health groups. Imposing such a tax could lead to significant financial losses for Utah's vape shops and increase online sales. Data shows youth vaping isn't a widespread issue, and the e-cigarette industry actively supports preventing underage sales. Instead of heavy taxation, policymakers should focus on youth prevention efforts and allocate tax revenues to tobacco cessation programs, not the general fund. (Published on June 05, 2025bythr101.org)</description></item><item><title>US faces vape shortage as China tariffs, seizures hit Geek Bar</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/us-faces-vape-shortage-china-tariffs-seizures-hit-geek-bar-2025-06-05/</link><description>Popular vape brands like Geek Bar may get more expensive in the U.S. - if you can find them at all. Shipments of vapes from China to the U.S. ground to a near halt in May from a year ago, official data shows, hit by U.S. President Donald Trump's tariffs and a crackdown on unauthorised e-cigarettes in the world's biggest market for smoking alternatives. (Published on June 05, 2025byreuters.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine Pouches: A Credible Lifeline for Irish Vapers?</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/nicotine-pouches-a-credible-lifeline-for-irish-vapers/</link><description>The Irish government and media are creating a hostile environment for vaping, prompting consideration of nicotine pouches as an alternative. Ireland's transformative relationship with the EU faced challenges during the financial crisis, revealing issues with the union's governance. Vaping policies align with broader EU/WHO initiatives against harm reduction, with restrictions harming public health efforts. The government's failure to support vaping led citizens to seek alternative solutions. Nicotine pouches could offer a harm reduction option, though government regulation poses a threat. Advocates urge Irish vapers to explore this alternative and prepare for potential regulatory battles. Misguided anti-vaping sentiments hinder public health progress, emphasizing the need for informed decision-making and advocacy. (Published on June 05, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>Vape flavours are a vital and effective tool helping smokers make the life-saving switch, top cardiologist says</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/vape-flavours-are-a-vital-and-effective-tool-helping-smokers-make-the-life-saving-switch-top-cardiologist-says/</link><description>Global health expert Dr. Konstantinos Farsalinos advocates for governments to embrace safer nicotine products, emphasizing that combustion, not nicotine, causes smoking-related deaths. He highlights Sweden's success in reducing smoking rates through alternatives like snus and e-cigarettes. Dr. Farsalinos stresses the importance of flavors in aiding smoking cessation and warns against banning them. He urges policymakers to prioritize evidence-based regulations and support smokers in switching to safer options. Countries like New Zealand and the UK have seen significant reductions in smoking rates due to vaping. On World Vape Day, Dr. Farsalinos urges a shift towards science-based approaches to make nicotine consumption safer and save lives. (Published on June 05, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item></channel></rss>