<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:17:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>WHO’s COP11 Will Threaten Tobacco Harm Reduction Behind Closed Doors</title><link>https://filtermag.org/who-cop11-tobacco-harm-reduction-closed-doors/</link><description>The upcoming COP11 in Geneva will address tobacco control policies with potential impacts on global public health. Concerns exist over the exclusion of THR advocates at previous conferences, affecting the discussions on harm reduction products such as vapes. The complex registration process for COP11 has attracted criticism, with fears of limited public participation. Despite resistance from the WHO, advocates aim to emphasize harm reduction benefits at the conference. Prominent countries like New Zealand have supported THR, indicating a hopeful shift in attitudes towards public health strategies. Advocates stress the need for the FCTC treaty to prioritize smoking-related harm and resist external influences for effective tobacco control. (Published on September 30, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Are vapes 95% safer than smoking? Probably, and scientists should be blunt about it</title><link>https://inews.co.uk/news/vapes-safer-than-smoking-scientists-blunt-2649561</link><description>Vaping is often claimed to be 95% safer than smoking, but there are debates on the accuracy of this statistic. Public health messaging on vaping's safety is under scrutiny, with concerns about potential misinformation leading to increased youth vaping. However, research indicates that while vaping is relatively safer, it is not risk-free. The discussion highlights the importance of transparent communication in public health messaging. Contrary to assumptions, youth perceptions on vaping harm have shifted negatively. Additionally, promoting baby-led weaning and debunking myths about excessive water consumption are other topics of interest in recent articles. Moreover, a group of psychologists is focusing on correcting errors in scientific research. (Published on September 30, 2025byinews.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Harm Reduction: The Next Step for Trinidad and Tobago’s Tobacco Fight</title><link>https://www.guardian.co.tt/opinion/harm-reduction-the-next-step-for-trinidad-and-tobagos-tobacco-fight-6.2.2412610.7e25f0ce2c</link><description>Trinidad and Tobago is shifting towards a progressive tobacco policy, exploring regulation of reduced-risk products like vaping and nicotine pouches. Current approaches focusing on bans haven't reduced smoking rates, with nearly one in five adults smoking. There's a lack of clarity on vaping regulations, leaving users uncertain. Embracing harm reduction strategies, similar to successful models in Sweden and the UK, can improve public health. Despite pushback from WHO, countries like Trinidad and Tobago can lead by prioritizing people's choices and health. It's time to act, collect data, understand risks, and regulate to encourage smokers to switch to safer alternatives, diverging from outdated strategies. (Published on September 30, 2025byguardian.co.tt)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #12 | BRAZIL's EFFORT FOR SAFER NICOTINE | Alexandro Lucian on Translating Science in LATAM</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-12/</link><description>Explore tobacco harm reduction at GFN through a candid interview with Brazilian consumer advocate Alexandro Lucian, who shares why this global event matters, the misinformation challenges in Brazil, and why education and accurate science are essential for safer nicotine choices. Learn how language barriers, anti‑vaping narratives, and limited local research shape public opinion—and how translating complex evidence into Portuguese helps counter myths. (Published on September 30, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>