<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 12:37:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EXCLUSIVE: EU vape and pouch tax by Summer, Commissioner tells Parliament.</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/exclusive-eu-vape-and-pouch-tax-by-summer-commissioner-tells-parliament/</link><description>European Commissioner Hoekstra plans to propose higher taxes on safer nicotine products, aiming for implementation by summer. The proposal includes raising prices on nicotine pouches by over 50% and adding €3 to a 10ml bottle of vaping liquid. Hoekstra is reaching out to national officials for support, targeting countries resistant to the tax hike. While some Commission members question the economic timing, Hoekstra remains adamant against nicotine products, claiming vapes are as harmful as cigarettes. Climate change policy also falls under Hoekstra's jurisdiction, sparking criticism for prioritizing vaping taxes over environmental issues. Resistance from Member States and skepticism within the Commission may hinder the tax plan approval. (Published on May 13, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Cameroon’s opportunity to advance public health through Tobacco harm reduction – Cameroon News Agency</title><link>https://cameroonnewsagency.com/cameroons-opportunity-to-advance-public-health-through-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>Cameroon faces a public health crisis with 8.9% smoking prevalence leading to significant deaths and healthcare costs. Tobacco Harm Reduction (THR), including e-cigarettes and heated tobacco products, offers a safer alternative. However, lack of awareness and regulation hinders progress. Local research and educational campaigns are needed to promote THR and develop effective policies. Integrating THR into national tobacco control is crucial for long-term health outcomes. With the new Tobacco Control Law in place, Cameroon has the opportunity to lead in tobacco control through evidence-based, innovative strategies. Action is imperative to reduce smoking-related harm and improve public health. (Published on May 13, 2025bycameroonnewsagency.com)</description></item><item><title>Cambodian PM reiterates ban on investment in e-cigarette production</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/aseanplus/aseanplus-news/2025/05/14/cambodian-pm-reiterates-ban-on-investment-in-e-cigarette-production</link><description>Cambodian PM Hun Manet stated that e-cigarette production won't be allowed in Cambodia due to health concerns, reaffirming the ban on e-cigarettes and shisha since 2014. The government focuses on preventing illegal tobacco product imports, raising awareness of smoking's health risks. The Ministry of Health warns about e-cigarettes' nicotine content, leading to severe health issues like lung disease and cancer. The PM's decision comes after reports of illegal e-cigarette sales despite the existing ban. Hun Manet's stance aims to protect the public from harmful effects associated with smoking and vaping. (Published on May 14, 2025bythestar.com.my)</description></item><item><title>Lower taxes on Heated Tobacco Products are subsidising tobacco industry – new research</title><link>https://www.bath.ac.uk/announcements/lower-taxes-on-heated-tobacco-products-are-subsidising-tobacco-industry-new-research/</link><description>Research from the University of Bath and Johns Hopkins University reveals that governments lowering taxes on heated tobacco products (HTPs) to deter smokers from traditional cigarettes inadvertently subsidize the tobacco industry. This approach results in decreased tax revenues and undermines public health efforts. The study focused on Ukraine, where HTPs are taxed similarly to cigarettes. While tobacco companies promote HTPs as safer alternatives, evidence on their health impacts remains inconclusive. Tax harmonization, as seen in Ukraine, aligns with WHO recommendations to prevent market manipulation. The researchers stress the importance of taxing HTPs appropriately and urge policymakers to prioritize public health over industry profits. (Published on May 14, 2025bybath.ac.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>