<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 06:15:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>European Union Steps Up Fight Against Cardiovascular Disease</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/european-union-steps-fight-against-cardiovascular-disease-2025a1000ptb?src=rss&amp;form=fpf</link><description>Cardiovascular disease (CVD) is a global leading cause of death. The longevity dividend has brought a "prevention debt." Hypertension is a key risk factor, with low control rates. Obesity, diabetes, and environmental factors like climate change, air pollution, and noise further increase CVD risks. Europe is implementing policies, such as the EU Cardiovascular Health Plan and clean air initiatives, to combat rising CVD rates. Tobacco and new nicotine products pose risks, with the EU taking steps towards regulation. Nutrition and lifestyle changes are crucial for prevention. Measures like the UK's soft drinks tax show promise. Overall, coordinated efforts are vital for tackling CVD effectively. (Published on September 26, 2025bymedscape.com)</description></item><item><title>FDA Vape Regs Need Bold Reform</title><link>https://www.realclearhealth.com/articles/2025/09/26/fda_vape_regs_need_bold_reform_1137406.html</link><description>Last week, officials raided an illegal vape operation near Chicago, seizing 600,000 units. Most vapes on the market are illicit, mainly smuggled from China. FDA regulations on vaping products are stringent, leading to a lack of safe alternatives and favoring cigarettes. The FDA should reform its approval process, focusing on monitoring markets and providing clear safety standards. This approach, as seen in the European Union and the UK, can streamline the process and educate consumers accurately. By prioritizing harm reduction over strict regulations, the FDA can support safer smoking alternatives and combat the illicit market. (Published on September 26, 2025byrealclearhealth.com)</description></item><item><title>TGA and Victoria Police working together to target illegal vape sales in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.tga.gov.au/news/media-releases/tga-and-victoria-police-working-together-target-illegal-vape-sales-melbourne</link><description>A two-day blitz on Chapel Street retailers by the Therapeutic Goods Administration (TGA) and Victoria Police resulted in the seizure of over $40,000 worth of illegal vaping products and more than 24,000 nicotine pouches. Police also confiscated 110,000 illicit cigarettes, 40 kg of loose tobacco, and cash. The crackdown, part of the National Vaping Enforcement Framework, aims to combat the illegal supply of vaping goods and disrupt organised crime. The TGA emphasised the importance of protecting young people’s health, while Victoria Police highlighted that illicit tobacco profits often fund violent crimes such as arson, firearms use, and extortion. (Published on September 26, 2025bytga.gov.au)</description></item><item><title>Regulating the Tobacco and Nicotine Market in the American Public Interest: A Reform Agenda for the FDA</title><link>https://www.aei.org/research-products/report/regulating-the-tobacco-and-nicotine-market-in-the-american-public-interest-a-reform-agenda-for-the-fda/</link><description>In the text, the authors highlight the advantages of transitioning smokers to safer alternatives like vapes but criticize the FDA's barriers hindering these products' market entry, leading to a thriving illicit market. They advocate for significant reforms to the FDA's authorization process, wanting to bring around 4,000 safer products to market, reduce review barriers, and promote a competitive legal market. The text discusses the state of the tobacco and nicotine market, the regulatory challenges, and offers 15 practical reform proposals to improve the system's efficiency, focusing on transparent standards, post-market surveillance, and broadening product availability. (Published on September 26, 2025byaei.org)</description></item><item><title>The war on vapes is plain stupid</title><link>https://thecritic.co.uk/the-war-on-vapes-is-plain-stupid/</link><description>The spread of misinformation about vaping risks is described as a major public health disaster, fueled by myths like “popcorn lung,” the EVALI scare, and the misconception that nicotine causes cancer. Instead of correcting false beliefs, public health figures are accused of reinforcing them. The UK government’s Tobacco and Vapes Bill, which allows vapes to be regulated like cigarettes, is seen as worsening the problem by suggesting their risks are similar. Critics argue that some public health academics and activists undermine vaping despite acknowledging its benefits. (Published on September 26, 2025bythecritic.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Urgent need for regulation of nicotine pouches</title><link>https://www.socialdemocrats.ie/urgent-need-for-regulation-of-nicotine-pouches/</link><description>Social Democrats TD Jennifer Whitmore urgently calls for government regulation of nicotine pouch sales and marketing due to their rising use among teenagers. She stresses the lack of age restrictions and oversight in corner shops, where these products are widely available, aggressively marketed, and flavored to appeal to children. The strong nicotine hit poses addiction risks, and schools report disruptions. Whitmore urges immediate action to ban sales to under-18s, restrict marketing, and provide guidance to schools, as the tobacco industry targets a new generation in the absence of legislation. She emphasizes the need for swift government intervention to address the issue promptly. (Published on September 26, 2025bysocialdemocrats.ie)</description></item></channel></rss>