<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 18:14:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Spain's new smoking law plans could mean big changes for travellers</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/travel/2025/09/11/spains-new-smoking-law-plans-could-mean-big-changes-for-travellers</link><description>Spain's coalition government has passed a draft bill banning smoking and vaping in outdoor spaces, aiming to prioritize public health. This proposal has faced opposition from restaurant and bar owners. The ban includes various outdoor areas and targets a range of tobacco products. The legislation aligns with wider European efforts to curb smoking in public places. Spain aims to reduce tobacco-related deaths, though measures such as plain packaging are not currently included in the bill awaiting parliamentary approval. (Published on September 11, 2025byeuronews.com)</description></item><item><title>Regulation Minister David Seymour won't rule out label changes for nicotine, tobacco, alcohol</title><link>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/political/572713/regulation-minister-david-seymour-won-t-rule-out-label-changes-for-nicotine-tobacco-alcohol</link><description>Changes to warning labels for tobacco, nicotine, and alcohol are under review by David Seymour's Ministry for Regulation. Public health groups expressed concerns, but Seymour indicated no plans to exclude these products. He mentioned the potential for altering label designs, citing an example of the color red used for Fetal Alcohol Spectrum Disorder warnings. Seymour acknowledged cost implications for businesses complying with label requirements. Health advocates stressed the importance of existing warning labels, especially for tobacco and nicotine products. The Ministry is gathering industry feedback through surveys. Concerns were raised about potentially reducing the effectiveness of warning labels on harmful products. (Published on September 11, 2025byrnz.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>Teenagers turn to black market for vapes</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/teenagers-turn-to-black-market-for-vapes/</link><description>A survey reveals that most under-18s obtain vapes through the black market, undermining restrictions. Despite bans, 74% feel stores allow underage purchases easily. Peer pressure drives 61% of youth to vape, and illegal sales soar due to cheaper prices and lack of age checks. Prohibition policies worldwide fail to curb demand, leading to a surge in illicit vape trade. Collaborative efforts are recommended for stricter age verification at point of sale and use, emphasizing the need for a comprehensive approach to tackle youth vaping effectively while avoiding the pitfalls of prohibition. (Published on September 11, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>How the myth that nicotine causes cancer is hurting public health</title><link>https://www.statnews.com/2025/09/10/nicotine-myths-complicate-public-health/</link><description>Nicotine, commonly misunderstood in the U.S., is not the main cause of cancer in cigarettes but is addictive. Smoke-free nicotine options like e-cigarettes and pouches, while not risk-free, reduce harmful chemical exposure compared to smoking. Correcting misconceptions is crucial for harm reduction, encouraging safer alternatives. Educating the public on nicotine's risks and benefits, especially in the context of brain development and pregnancy, is essential. Changing popular notions about nicotine is challenging but necessary for public health. Misunderstandings could impact harm reduction efforts and the usage of low-nicotine cigarettes. Research suggests comprehensive education can combat false beliefs. (Published on September 11, 2025bystatnews.com)</description></item><item><title>New York State Cracks Down on Illegal Online Vape Sales</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/new-york-state-cracks-down-on-online-vape-sales/</link><description>New York State authorities led a crackdown named "Operation Vapers’ Dozen" targeting online vape sellers, resulting in 12 arrests and 38 charges for violating vape laws. The businesses faced charges for selling vapor products unlawfully. The state had banned flavored vapes and all online vape sales in 2020. Governor Kathy Hochul expressed holding these companies accountable for targeting youth. The state has been strict on vaping, with Democrats like Gov. Hochul and former Gov. Cuomo supporting anti-vaping policies. New York City Mayor Eric Adams also launched actions against vape distributors. Online vape sales are restricted in several U.S. states, including Arkansas, Hawaii, and Utah. (Published on September 11, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>Five Years After the PMTA Deadline, the Tobacco Control Act Still Protects Cigarettes Over Smokers – DC Journal</title><link>https://dcjournal.com/five-years-after-the-pmta-deadline-the-tobacco-control-act-still-protects-cigarettes-over-smokers/</link><description>The FDA's strict regulatory process for tobacco products, particularly e-cigarettes, has resulted in the authorization of only 39 products out of millions of applications. The 2009 Tobacco Control Act has contributed to this issue by favoring certain companies and hindering harm reduction efforts. The FDA's delays and limitations have left smokers with limited safer options and stifled innovation, with only a few dominant manufacturers remaining. Congress has the opportunity to amend the act to promote public health and empower businesses. Reforming the FDA's tobacco regulatory system is crucial to achieving a smoke-free future in the United States. (Published on September 11, 2025bydcjournal.com)</description></item></channel></rss>