<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:20:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why Governments Prefer Cigarette Revenue over Safer Alternatives</title><link>https://brownstone.org/articles/why-governments-prefer-cigarette-revenue-over-safer-alternatives/</link><description>The POUCH Act of 2024 would prevent states and cities from banning FDA-authorized lower-risk nicotine products like pouches and vapes, asserting that products deemed appropriate for public health should not be prohibited for political or fiscal reasons. Though modest, the bill represents a rare move toward more rational federal harm-reduction policy. At the same time, it highlights deeper systemic problems in U.S. nicotine regulation, including the protection of cigarette sales, government revenue interests, and regulatory barriers that disadvantage smaller innovators. (Published on December 19, 2025bybrownstone.org)</description></item><item><title>EXCLUSIVE: EU health chief 100% convinced new products as harmful as cigarettes</title><link>https://www.euractiv.com/news/exclusive-eu-health-chief-100-convinced-new-products-as-harmful-as-cigarettes/</link><description>EU Health Commissioner Olivér Várhelyi stated that alternative tobacco products such as e-cigarettes, heated tobacco, and nicotine pouches are just as harmful as traditional cigarettes, rejecting claims that they are safer. He cited recent data linking these products to cardiovascular risks and warned that their impact may be even worse among young people. A new report shows vaping in the EU increased by 45%, reaching 4% of people aged 15 and over in 2024, raising concerns about the spread of new nicotine habits. (Published on December 19, 2025byeuractiv.com)</description></item><item><title>UKVIA Responds to Evidence Call</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-12-16_ukvia-responds-to-evidence-call.html</link><description>The UK Vaping Industry Association (UKVIA) submitted a detailed, evidence-based response to the UK government’s Tobacco &amp; Vapes Bill, emphasizing that regulation should support vaping as a tool for harm reduction rather than make quitting tobacco harder. They advocate for a simple, enforceable product-registration system, robust testing and manufacturing standards aligned with international best practices, and clear rules protecting adult access to flavors and products that help them quit smoking. UKVIA also stressed that enforcement should target illicit sellers and non-compliant imports, not responsible, compliant companies. (Published on December 19, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco tax take to dwindle to almost nothing</title><link>https://www.afr.com/policy/economy/tobacco-tax-take-to-dwindle-to-almost-nothing-20251217-p5nogt</link><description>Illegal tobacco has significantly reduced Australia's tobacco excise tax revenue, with projections showing a $22.3 billion decline by 2028. A former Australian Border Force officer warns that tax collection from tobacco could be minimal due to the impact of illegal tobacco trade. (Published on December 19, 2025byafr.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches use increases among young men as 'targeted' marketing continues</title><link>https://www.thenews.com.pk/latest/1385410-nicotine-pouches-use-increases-among-young-men-as-targeted-marketing-continues</link><description>Nicotine pouch use is rising among young men due to targeted marketing, with about 7.5% of 16-24-year-old men using them. Many users also smoke or vape, with some trying to quit smoking. The effectiveness of pouches in smoking cessation needs further study. Sales are increasing, driven by youthful consumers. Regulations are being considered to restrict sales to under 18 and control marketing. The study suggests monitoring the new regulations to balance harm reduction potential. Nicotine pouches are banned in some countries and facing restrictions in others. (Published on December 19, 2025bythenews.com.pk)</description></item><item><title>Enforcing proposed single-use vape ban may cost over €3m a year, Oireachtas research says</title><link>https://www.irishexaminer.com/news/arid-41763023.html</link><description>A ban on single-use vapes proposed by the Government may cost €3.1m yearly to enforce. This cost includes funding for 40 full-time HSE posts. The aim is to reduce vaping among youth, with potential public health benefits and impacts on the industry. The law will stop single-use vape sales in Ireland, targeting waste and environmental issues. The Government sees it as crucial for protecting children. The ban may affect industry profits, depending on consumer actions. The focus is on reducing youth vaping and any subsequent rise in smoking rates. Additional expenses are expected for further e-cigarette legislation enforcement. (Published on December 19, 2025byirishexaminer.com)</description></item></channel></rss>