<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:18:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UKVIA Says Disposable Ban Driving Smokers Back to Tobacco</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/08/13/ukvia-says-disposable-ban-driving-smokers-back-to-tobacco</link><description>The UK Vaping Industry Association (UKVIA) says new research confirms fears that the UK’s ban on single-use vapes is backfiring, with 26% of former disposable vape users now smoking more, returning to tobacco, or buying illicit products. A survey of 6,000 vapers and smokers, commissioned by ELFBAR, also found that over half of adults (51%) wrongly believe vaping is as harmful as smoking, and awareness of illegal vapes has risen to 22%. (Published on August 14, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Disposable Vapes Still Widely (and Predictably) Sold in Post-Ban UK</title><link>https://filtermag.org/disposable-vapes-ban-still-sold-uk</link><description>Disposable nicotine vapes are still being sold by retailers in the United Kingdom, even though they were recently banned. This was widely predicted by tobacco harm reduction advocates and others, but new research sought to illustrate its extent. (Published on August 14, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Quitting Smoking is Associated with Recovery from Other Addictions</title><link>https://southfloridahospitalnews.com/quitting-smoking-is-associated-with-recovery-from-other-addictions</link><description>Adults who smoke cigarettes and are addicted to alcohol or other drugs were more likely to achieve sustained remission of their substance use disorder symptoms if they also quit smoking, according to scientists at the National Institutes of Health (NIH). Based on their analysis of data from a large U.S. study of smoking and health, researchers believe the results clearly show the benefit of pairing smoking cessation with addiction recovery efforts. (Published on August 14, 2025bysouthfloridahospitalnews.com)</description></item><item><title>AI-Driven Tobacco Control in ASEAN Requires Unified Data Standards</title><link>https://www.lowyinstitute.org/the-interpreter/ai-driven-tobacco-control-asean-requires-unified-data-standards</link><description>Aligning the diverse digital infrastructure across member states offers a chance for effective AI deployment to help the region’s 120 million smokers. (Published on August 14, 2025bylowyinstitute.org)</description></item><item><title>Everything You Need to Know About Giving Up Cigarettes</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/health/Everything-You-Need-to-Know-About-Giving-Up-Cigarettes.aspx</link><description>Comprehensive guide explains that quitting smoking is difficult because nicotine relieves stress, but success is possible with personalised plans, trigger identification and coping strategies. It advises setting a quit date, using nicotine‑replacement products, managing withdrawal and seeking support. (Published on August 14, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item></channel></rss>