<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 17:16:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>World No Tobacco Day Should Protect Youth and Help the 1.3 Billion Adults Who Smoke</title><link>https://www.thr101.org/post/world-no-tobacco-day-should-protect-youth-and-help-the-1-3-billion-adults-who-smoke</link><description>The World Health Organization's focus on protecting youth from tobacco industry influence during World No Tobacco Day overlooks the needs of the 1.3 billion adult smokers. Despite evidence supporting the effectiveness of harm reduction products like e-cigarettes, the WHO continues to advocate for restricting access to these alternatives. While concerns about youth vaping are valid, data shows a decline in usage. The WHO's approach neglects the reasons why youth turn to vaping, such as stress relief. Prioritizing youth protection over adult harm reduction fails to address the complexities of smoking cessation. A shift towards acknowledging and supporting adult smokers in accessing all cessation options is essential for effective global tobacco control efforts. (Published on May 27, 2025bythr101.org)</description></item><item><title>Teen vaping on the rise but fewer young adults smoke tobacco</title><link>https://www.dutchnews.nl/2025/05/teen-vaping-on-the-rise-but-fewer-young-adults-smoke-tobacco/</link><description>Dutch teenagers' vaping rate rose to 7.6%, while smoking increased slightly among 12 to 18-year-olds. Conversely, young adults' vaping decreased to 8.6%. The sale of flavored vape liquids has been banned since 2024, but a black market thrives. Instances of severe health issues due to vaping have been reported, prompting government action. The health ministry is considering raising the legal age to 21, criminalizing flavored vape sales, and advocating for stricter EU regulations on e-cigarettes. (Published on May 28, 2025bydutchnews.nl)</description></item><item><title>Brit holiday warning as major destination BANS nicotine pouches – and visitors face ‘terrifying’ six-figure fine &amp; jail</title><link>https://www.thesun.co.uk/health/35136554/brit-holiday-nicotine-ban-jail-fine-france/</link><description>France has imposed severe penalties for carrying nicotine pouches, harsher than for drugs like heroin. Brits could face five years in jail and a £320,000 fine. The crackdown has been criticized as disproportionate, with warnings that well-meaning tourists could unknowingly break the law. The ban, the strictest in Europe, aims to preserve public health but has sparked controversy. It may lead to a black market and affect athletes using pouches for performance enhancement. Despite concerns, French officials proceeded with the ban, leaving many questioning the logic of making carrying a pouch more dangerous than carrying heroin. (Published on May 27, 2025bythesun.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>The EU Commission’s Misinformation on Vaping: A Deadly Disservice to Public Health</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/the-eu-commissions-misinformation-on-vaping-a-deadly-disservice-to-public-health/</link><description>The European Commission and WHO spread misinformation linking vaping to smoking, hindering harm reduction efforts. Officials like Commissioner Hoekstra falsely equate vaping with smoking, ignoring evidence and discouraging smokers from switching. The WHO director mistakenly claims all tobacco is equally harmful, disregarding vaping's safer profile. This misinformation leads to more deaths and disease by deterring smokers from switching to less harmful alternatives. The upcoming EU directive reviews offer a chance to correct this harmful trend with evidence-based regulation. As World Vape Day nears, contrasting celebrations highlight vaping's success in helping millions quit smoking. It's crucial for the EU Commission and WHO to prioritize public health over ideology and end their harmful stance on harm reduction. (Published on May 28, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>The danger of e-cigarette prohibition and illicit trade</title><link>https://clivebates.com/the-danger-of-e-cigarette-prohibition-and-illicit-trade/</link><description>Outright prohibition of vapes and safer alternatives to cigarettes is the preferred policy of many in tobacco control. Yet it is hard to imagine anything worse. I summarise the arguments against. (Published on May 28, 2025byclivebates.com)</description></item><item><title>Disposable vapes ban could push 200,000 people back to smoking, report warns</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-14751243/Disposable-vapes-ban-push-200-000-people-smoking.html</link><description>A report warns that the upcoming disposable vapes ban could lead to 200,000 people reverting to smoking, potentially hindering the UK's progress towards a smoke-free nation. Concerns arise as 45% of vapers use disposable devices, with the highest prevalence among young adults. The ban may prompt 12% of users to switch back to smoking, while the majority plan to switch to other vapes or consider alternative nicotine replacement therapies. Suggestions include stricter regulations on vape products and a national anti-smoking campaign. Urgent action is advised to prevent unintended consequences and prioritize reducing youth vaping rates. (Published on May 28, 2025bydailymail.co.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>