<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 12:24:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tobacco kills 13.5L Indians yearly, costs nation ₹1.8L crore</title><link>https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/tobacco-crisis-in-india-1-35m-deaths-annually-massive-healthcare-costs/story</link><description>Tobacco is a major health issue in India, causing 1.35 million deaths annually. Treating tobacco-related diseases costs over ₹1.77 lakh crore each year. Only 7% of smokers quit without assistance. Healthcare experts recommend smoke-free nicotine alternatives to reduce harm, with studies showing they are significantly safer than cigarettes. Nicotine pouches, now available in 34 countries, including India, could help smokers switch from cigarettes. Public Health England states these alternatives are up to 95% less harmful than smoking. Dr. Soni from AIIMS-CAPFIMS suggests regulating these products to aid smokers in transitioning away from traditional cigarettes. (Published on September 16, 2025bynewsbytesapp.com)</description></item><item><title>Fed Up with the FDA, Big Tobacco Goes Nuclear</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/big-tobacco-is-fed-up-with-the-fda/</link><description>NJOY, an Altria Group vape subsidiary, has filed a lawsuit against the FDA, claiming delays in deciding on NJOY vape products violate the Tobacco Control Act. On the same day, Altria announced plans to launch a new nicotine pouch brand without FDA authorization. R.J. Reynolds also launched flavored disposable vapes without FDA approval. NJOY argues that the FDA's delayed decisions may suggest a de facto ban on flavored products. Despite providing scientific evidence, NJOY's supervisory appeal has not been resolved after almost three years. Altria and Reynolds are pushing boundaries by introducing new products without FDA consent, citing reasons such as exceeding review timelines and legal loophole interpretations. (Published on September 16, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>Combining vaping and smoking may raise risk of diabetes and prediabetes, study finds</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/health/2025/09/16/combining-vaping-and-smoking-may-raise-risk-of-diabetes-and-prediabetes-study-finds</link><description>A new US study found that e-cigarette users have a 7% higher risk of developing prediabetes compared with non-smokers. The risk is even greater when vaping is combined with traditional smoking. With 22% of European teens (15–16 years old) vaping regularly, researchers warn that e-cigarettes affect not only the lungs but also metabolic health. (Published on September 17, 2025byeuronews.com)</description></item><item><title>New HHS campaign tackles youth vaping, nicotine addiction</title><link>https://www.upi.com/Health_News/2025/09/16/Health-Human-Services-HHS-youth-teen-vaping-e-cigarette/9591758043733/</link><description>U.S. health officials are focusing on reducing youth vaping due to the popularity of e-cigarettes among young people. The Surgeon General's office unveiled a guide to address rising e-cigarette use in America's youth. Vaping is harming children's health, leading to nicotine addiction and potential gateway to smoking. Health officials emphasize the dangers of nicotine in vape products on brain development and overall health. Despite federal efforts, illegal sales of vaping products persist, fueled by targeted marketing to youth. The FDA is seizing illegal vapes and advocating for stricter enforcement to protect American children. Efforts to combat youth vaping include legislative action and unified initiatives. (Published on September 17, 2025byupi.com)</description></item></channel></rss>