<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:59:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Time Cost of Vaping At Work</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-10-27_the-time-cost-of-vaping-at-work.html</link><description>A survey by nicotine pouch company Alternix found that British vapers generally spend more time on their habit than smokers. About 20% of vapers spend 20–39 minutes a day vaping, with 13% vaping over an hour daily, compared to 14% and 8% of smokers, respectively. On average, vaping accounts for around 5% of working hours, roughly 2 hours per week. Men tend to vape more than women. (Published on October 29, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>High-Nicotine Pouches Help People Stay Off Cigarettes—If Available</title><link>https://filtermag.org/high-nicotine-pouches/</link><description>Higher nicotine level pouches are crucial for tobacco harm reduction, tailoring doses to individual needs. A study in Sweden shows increased nicotine delivery and satisfaction with modern pouches. Findings support previous research on safer nicotine products aiding heavy smokers in quitting. FDA authorization for certain pouches is a step forward, yet limited to 6 mg nicotine content. Advocates emphasize the importance of higher doses for effective harm reduction. Some European regulations restricting dosage risk hindering smoking cessation efforts. Lax regulations in Sweden have significantly reduced smoking rates, contrasting with stricter approaches in other European countries. Learning from successful models is crucial in tackling smoking-related deaths globally. (Published on October 30, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>EU softens tone on smoking products</title><link>https://brusselssignal.eu/2025/10/eu-softens-tone-on-smoking-products-ahead-of-who-cop11/</link><description>Brussels has released a revised compromise proposal for the EU's position on the WHO's FCTC, aiming for consensus among 27 nations. The softened document addresses contentious issues like tobacco product regulation, harm reduction, and advertising. It emphasizes evidence-based approaches and individual party policies, reflecting lobbying and FCTC debates. The EU now advocates for proportionate regulation of alternative nicotine products based on scientific evidence. The draft retains measures to reduce single-use plastics in tobacco products but shifts away from binding mandates. Despite dismissing harm reduction as an "industry narrative", the proposal shows a more moderate stance on vaping and nicotine pouches, allowing for national discretion. (Published on October 30, 2025bybrusselssignal.eu)</description></item><item><title>How dual smokers of pot and tobacco feel the burn of higher prices</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-dual-smokers-pot-tobacco-higher.html</link><description>UC San Francisco research shows that people who smoke both tobacco and cannabis are more likely to reduce cigarette consumption when prices increase. Cigarette price hikes have traditionally led to decreased smoking rates, but little was known about dual users. Cannabis users were found to be more sensitive to cigarette costs, with a 2x higher likelihood of cutting back compared to tobacco-only smokers. This study highlights the effectiveness of raising cigarette prices in reducing smoking, particularly among dual users. State pricing data aligns with lower smoking rates in areas with higher prices. Further research is needed to understand if dual users may substitute cannabis for tobacco as prices rise. (Published on October 30, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item></channel></rss>