<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:54:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Contentious Study Gave Pregnant Women Low-Nicotine Cigarettes</title><link>https://filtermag.org/low-nicotine-cigarettes-pregnancy-study/</link><description>A study observed pregnant smokers using very low-nicotine cigarettes (VLNC), sparking debate over reducing harms. Published in Preventative Medicine, it aimed to explore effects on smoking during pregnancy. Yet, critics argue VLNCs may not decrease smoking and could be as harmful. The FDA proposed reducing nicotine in tobacco, claiming it could prevent deaths. However, opponents question its efficacy and advocate for safer alternatives like vaping. The study found VLNCs didn’t reduce smoking in pregnant women but also didn't lead to more smoking. Researchers defended the study's ethical standards, stating it was not a smoking-cessation trial but part of a national policy investigation. Critics, like Dr. Michael Siegel, demand retraction, citing ethical violations. (Published on September 05, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>🍷 A common brain circuit for alcohol and nicotine</title><link>https://www.techno-science.net/en/news/common-brain-circuit-for-alcohol-and-nicotine-N27487.html</link><description>Nicotine and alcohol activate a brain circuit connecting reward and anxiety by triggering an inhibitory feedback loop between dopaminergic neurons. This mechanism explains why these substances reinforce consumption behavior while inducing anxiety. Researchers used optogenetics to block this loop and prevent anxious behavior. The study sheds light on the link between reward and negative emotions, providing insights into addiction and co-use of tobacco and alcohol. (Published on September 05, 2025bytechno-science.net)</description></item><item><title>Should Denver Ban Flavored Tobacco and Nicotine Products?</title><link>https://www.westword.com/news/denver-ban-flavored-tobacco-nicotine-going-to-election-25469434</link><description>Denver's ban on flavored tobacco products, signed by Mayor Mike Johnston, targets vapes, e-cigarettes, and menthol cigarettes, with full enforcement set for January 1, 2026. Supporters argue these products are marketed to youth and minority communities. A coalition is pushing to repeal the ban, collecting over 17,000 signatures. Proponents, such as health organizations, formed Denver Kids vs Big Tobacco to promote the ban. Critics, led by the Rocky Mountain Smoke Free Alliance, advocate for stricter regulations instead. The ban's fate will be determined by voters this November, shaping Denver's stance against the tobacco industry. The move follows a vetoed 2021 ban and aligns Denver with other Colorado cities combatting flavored tobacco. (Published on September 05, 2025bywestword.com)</description></item><item><title>Forget vapes: Nicotine pouch startup Sesh raises $40 million from 8VC, Post Malone, and Diplo to take on Zyn</title><link>https://fortune.com/2025/09/04/forget-vapes-nicotine-pouch-startup-sesh-raises-40-million-from-8vc-post-malone-and-diplo-to-take-on-zyn/</link><description>Sesh, a newcomer in the nicotine product market, aims to challenge established brands like Zyn by offering safer white pouches. Backed by celebrities and $40 million in funding, Sesh's unique formula sets it apart. While still addictive, pouches are seen as a less harmful alternative to cigarettes and vapes. Despite concerns about attracting new users, Sesh focuses on responsible marketing and growth. With FDA approval and growing popularity, Sesh strives to redefine nicotine consumption and compete with Big Tobacco. The company's success reflects a shift towards safer nicotine products and away from traditional smoking methods. (Published on September 05, 2025byfortune.com)</description></item></channel></rss>