<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:55:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Combining vaping and smoking may raise risk of diabetes and prediabetes, study finds</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/health/2025/09/16/combining-vaping-and-smoking-may-raise-risk-of-diabetes-and-prediabetes-study-finds</link><description>A new US study found that e-cigarette users have a 7% higher risk of developing prediabetes compared with non-smokers. The risk is even greater when vaping is combined with traditional smoking. With 22% of European teens (15–16 years old) vaping regularly, researchers warn that e-cigarettes affect not only the lungs but also metabolic health. (Published on September 17, 2025byeuronews.com)</description></item><item><title>New HHS campaign tackles youth vaping, nicotine addiction</title><link>https://www.upi.com/Health_News/2025/09/16/Health-Human-Services-HHS-youth-teen-vaping-e-cigarette/9591758043733/</link><description>U.S. health officials are focusing on reducing youth vaping due to the popularity of e-cigarettes among young people. The Surgeon General's office unveiled a guide to address rising e-cigarette use in America's youth. Vaping is harming children's health, leading to nicotine addiction and potential gateway to smoking. Health officials emphasize the dangers of nicotine in vape products on brain development and overall health. Despite federal efforts, illegal sales of vaping products persist, fueled by targeted marketing to youth. The FDA is seizing illegal vapes and advocating for stricter enforcement to protect American children. Efforts to combat youth vaping include legislative action and unified initiatives. (Published on September 17, 2025byupi.com)</description></item><item><title>Flavours attract youth to use e-cigarettes - study</title><link>https://dailynews.co.za/lifestyle/family/2019-10-29-flavours-attract-youth-to-use-e-cigarettes-study/</link><description>Research found that non-menthol e-cigarette flavors attract youth and contribute to increased usage. These findings published in the British Medical Journal Open highlight the link between flavors, youth interest, and potential harm to developing brains. Fruit and candy flavors specifically reduce perceived harm and increase appeal. Researchers advocate for banning non-menthol flavors to curb youth e-cigarette use, emphasizing the addictive nature of nicotine and potential health risks. Studies also show flavor influence on adult usage. Overall, flavors play a significant role in attracting both youth and adults to e-cigarettes, impacting preferences, appeal, willingness to use, and product harm perceptions. (Published on September 17, 2025bydailynews.co.za)</description></item><item><title>Commission says Sweden’s snus will contribute to EU budget</title><link>https://www.euractiv.com/news/commission-says-swedens-snus-will-contribute-to-eu-budget/</link><description>The European Commission has proposed that 15% of national tobacco tax revenues be redirected to the EU budget (2028–2034) under the “TEDOR” plan. This includes Sweden’s oral tobacco product snus, despite questions from Swedish conservative MEPs. Budget Commissioner Piotr Serafin confirmed no exemptions for any tobacco products, stressing equal treatment of member states. (Published on September 17, 2025byeuractiv.com)</description></item><item><title>Prohibition Does Not Work: Global Bans &amp; Their Harmful Impact ft. Tim Andrews | Ep. 86</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v2vzX-DWyA4</link><description>In this episode of Vaping Unplugged, our host Liza Katsiashvili, Director of Operations at the WVA, sits down with Timothy Andrews, Director of Consumer Issues at the Tholos Foundation and a leading partner of the initiative Prohibition Does Not Work. (Published on September 17, 2025byyoutube.com)</description></item></channel></rss>