<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:19:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Resistance to the Anti-Nicotine Movement Has Roots in a Betrayal</title><link>https://filtermag.org/anti-nicotine-resistance/</link><description>Resistance to flavor bans, taxes, and restrictions on nicotine use stems from harm reduction advocates' belief in personal freedom and distrust in tobacco control's motives. Many have successfully quit smoking by switching to safer alternatives, yet face stigma and exclusion. Misinformation and stigma harm those relying on harm reduction products, leading to social and personal consequences. Advocates fight for sensible regulation, truth, and the shared goal of saving lives. Inclusion of their voices in policy discussions is crucial. The fight is not against public health but for it, seeking to safeguard access to harm reduction products and prioritize individual choices for a smoke-free future. (Published on October 28, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>GOVERNMENT TO BACK VAPING AT COP 11</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/uk-backs-vaping-cop11-geneva/</link><description>The Department of Health will advocate harm reduction through vaping at the upcoming Geneva COP 11 conference. The UK government supports the use of vapes as a safer alternative to smoking, emphasizing its effectiveness in helping adults quit smoking. Health Minister Ashley Dalton reiterated the government's stance on vaping being less harmful than smoking while warning against non-smokers and young individuals using vapes. Advocates, like We Vape, urge for clear public communication to dispel misconceptions about vaping. The WHO, despite facing criticism for anti-vaping policies, will host COP 11 in Geneva. The UK's substantial financial support to the WHO reinforces its influence. (Published on October 28, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>UK Tobacco and Vapes Bill: why so many are wrong to support it</title><link>https://clivebates.com/uk-tobacco-and-vapes-bill-why-so-many-are-wrong-to-support-it/</link><description>In the history of wrongness, it is hard to find greater wrongness than uncritical support for the UK Tobacco and Vapes Bill. The legislation is likely to do more harm than good, yet attracts widespread but uncritical support. The UK Tobacco and Vapes Bill is steadily making its way toward becoming law, facing almost no opposition and reportedly enjoying the backing of 1,200 “health leaders,” according to The Guardian. (Published on October 28, 2025byclivebates.com)</description></item><item><title>Active cigarette smoking linked to elevated pneumonia rates in COPD</title><link>https://www.healio.com/news/pulmonology/20251027/active-cigarette-smoking-linked-to-elevated-pneumonia-rates-in-copd</link><description>Active cigarette smoking in COPD patients was found to significantly increase pneumonia rates, as shown in a study presented at the CHEST Annual Meeting. Data from the study did not show the same association for active e-cigarette or cigar smoking. The research involved 777 adults with COPD, indicating that active cigarette smoking led to a higher risk of pneumonia over a 12-month period. Other factors like age, sex, and comorbidities were also considered. Importantly, smoking cessation efforts may be crucial in reducing pneumonia risk for individuals with COPD. (Published on October 28, 2025byhealio.com)</description></item><item><title>Thai Government to Crack Down on Vaping as User Count Hits 400,000</title><link>https://www.nationthailand.com/news/general/40057428</link><description>The Thai Cabinet has ordered an urgent amendment to the Tobacco Act to control e-cigarettes and combat nicotine addiction, especially among youth. The move follows a substantial increase in e-cigarette users, from 78,252 in 2021 to over 400,000 in 2024. The Health Ministry will lead the drafting of these stricter regulations, proposing extensive measures to regulate e-cigarettes and new tobacco products. (Published on October 28, 2025bynationthailand.com)</description></item><item><title>Oral nicotine pouches studied as a tool to quit smoking</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-oral-nicotine-pouches-tool.html</link><description>A University of Massachusetts Amherst researcher reviewed oral nicotine pouches as a smoking cessation aid, finding reduced exposure to harmful substances but unclear quitting benefits. Cochrane's investigation aims to gather more data on the product's efficacy. Despite not being FDA-approved, oral nicotine pouches like Zyn offer potential health benefits over risks, shifting users away from smoking. These pouches, not involving tobacco leaf, differ from snus, promoting harm reduction. While nicotine products aid in smoking cessation, starting nicotine use is discouraged due to addiction risks. Detailed regulation and ongoing research could prove oral nicotine pouches as a viable alternative for smokers. (Published on October 28, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item></channel></rss>