<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 01:00:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Denver Voters Uphold Flavor Ban, in Blow to Tobacco Harm Reduction</title><link>https://filtermag.org/denver-voter-ban-vape-flavors/</link><description>Denver voters have upheld a ban on flavored nicotine products, rejecting efforts for a repeal. The ban, imposed in 2024, prohibits the sale of menthol cigarettes, flavored cigars, and fruity vapes. Supporters claimed flavors drive youth vaping, while opponents argued it could harm small businesses and increase cigarette sales. The highly funded “Yes on 310” campaign prevailed over the underfunded opposition. Despite hopes for a different outcome, Denver joins other cities in Colorado with similar bans. The ban's impact on public health and smoking cessation efforts is now being monitored closely by experts. (Published on November 06, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches: What are they and why are they a problem?</title><link>https://www.bbc.co.uk/newsround/videos/c70912ezk14o</link><description>The UK banned disposable vapes to prevent child access. Concerns are rising over nicotine pouches, with 43% of 11-18 year-olds aware of them in June 2024, up from 38%. Public health charity ASH is monitoring the trend closely. Nina discussed the issue with school students and a health specialist. (Published on November 06, 2025bybbc.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Young people’s views of nicotine pouches in the UK</title><link>https://natcen.ac.uk/publications/young-peoples-views-nicotine-pouches-uk</link><description>A study in the UK examined young people's views and use of nicotine pouches, with findings showing high awareness and experimental use, especially among boys. School staff were largely unaware of the pouches. The research recommends enforcing restrictions on sales to under 18s, and regulating marketing and packaging to protect youth. Older boys were found to use pouches discreetly, with reports of adverse effects from users, including gum pain and sickness. The study involved 16 focus groups and interviews with school staff, conducted in Scotland by the Scottish Centre for Social Research. The data highlighted the need for stricter regulation on nicotine pouches to safeguard the well-being of young people. (Published on November 06, 2025bynatcen.ac.uk)</description></item><item><title>Heated tobacco and cigarettes cause the same gut and vascular damage, study finds</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20251103/Heated-tobacco-and-cigarettes-cause-the-same-gut-and-vascular-damage-study-finds.aspx</link><description>Exposure to traditional and heated tobacco, whether active or passive, can lead to intestinal issues, oxidative stress, and vascular problems, challenging the notion that "smokeless" means safe. Research shows that both types of tobacco smoke cause oxidative stress and endotoxemia, impacting the gut barrier and cardiovascular health. Despite claims of reduced harm, heated tobacco products (HTPs) still pose risks comparable to conventional cigarettes. Children are particularly vulnerable to these effects. Studies outline the relationship between tobacco exposure, circulating endotoxins, and oxidative pathways, emphasizing the importance of stricter tobacco control measures for public health protection. (Published on November 06, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>GFN Insights #9 | POWER, AIRFLOW &amp; TEMPERATURE EXPLAINED! | SCIENCE OF VAPING</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-insights-9-power-airflow-temperature-explained-science-of-vaping/</link><description>Discover the real science behind effective vaping. In this episode, Joanna Junak talks with vaping science researcher Roberto Sussman about how power, airflow, and resistance shape vapor production, flavor, and efficiency. Learn why temperature control isn’t the key factor—and how adjusting wattage, coil resistance, and airflow settings can completely change your vaping experience. If you’ve ever wondered how to tune your vape for better performance, this episode explains the physics behind it all—clearly and scientifically. (Published on November 06, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>America’s Focus on Vaping Misses the Point – DC Journal</title><link>https://dcjournal.com/americas-focus-on-vaping-misses-the-point/</link><description>The Lancet report reveals a rise in untimely young adult deaths due to mental health issues, overdoses, and chronic diseases, despite a global decline in death rates. While youth vaping is a concern, policymakers must address the actual pressing problems like mental health and chronic diseases. Worldwide, anxiety and depression have increased, with lifestyle diseases on the rise among younger populations. Lawmakers' focus on vaping doesn't align with evidence that it's not a gateway to smoking. To combat youth mortality, prioritizing mental health services and addressing actual drivers of the crisis is crucial, while restrictions on vaping could divert attention from more significant issues impacting young people. (Published on November 06, 2025bydcjournal.com)</description></item></channel></rss>