<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:22:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Health expert says 'it's a mystery' why WA is falling behind eastern states on illegal tobacco laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/wa-falls-behind-on-tobacco-laws/106220752</link><description>A leading public health expert expressed puzzlement over why Western Australia has fallen behind other states in modernizing its illicit tobacco laws. The expert highlighted the clear rise of illegal tobacco outlets in Perth and regional areas, which has increased pressure on authorities to respond. Research has shown that this trade is closely connected to organized crime networks across the country. While other states have implemented stronger, updated legislation to tackle the issue, in WA the responsibility falls on the Health Department to inspect and sanction shops under the Tobacco Control Act 2006. This approach has left the state lagging in enforcement compared with the rest of the nation. (Published on January 13, 2026byabc.net.au)</description></item><item><title>Saudi consumer awareness and regulatory collaboration bolster Philip Morris’ efforts toward a smoke-free future: Akiki</title><link>https://www.saudigazette.com.sa/article/658154/BUSINESS/Saudi-consumer-awareness-and-regulatory-collaboration-bolster-Philip-Morris-efforts-toward-a-smoke-free-future-Akiki</link><description>Christian Akiki, Managing Director of Philip Morris Saudi Arabia Trading, says that Saudi consumers are increasingly digitally connected, globally aware, and open to new experiences, influencing market trends. He notes that this shift aligns with Philip Morris International’s strategy of offering smoke‑free products like IQOS, nicotine pouches, and e‑cigarettes. Akiki emphasizes that achieving a smoke‑free future relies on close collaboration with Saudi regulators, especially the SFDA. He also highlights the importance of transparent communication with consumers and leveraging local talent to implement strategies effectively. (Published on January 13, 2026bysaudigazette.com.sa)</description></item><item><title>Can Future-Focused Thinking Help Smokers Quit?</title><link>https://www.newswise.com/articles/can-future-focused-thinking-help-smokers-quit2</link><description>Jeff Stein, a health behaviors researcher at Virginia Tech, received a grant to test a low-cost intervention helping rural residents quit smoking. Less than 1 in 10 smokers succeed in quitting despite knowing the risks. The study will use episodic future thinking to promote healthier choices by focusing on long-term rewards. Participants will receive smoking cessation resources in a remote study, aiming to tailor public health interventions for tobacco use. Stein's research shows promising results in influencing addictive behaviors. (Published on January 13, 2026bynewswise.com)</description></item></channel></rss>