<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:27:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Spain moves forward with smoking ban on bar and restaurant terraces</title><link>https://spanishnewstoday.com/spain_moves_forward_with_smoking_ban_on_bar_and_restaurant_terraces_1000250096-a.html</link><description>Spain is considering a nationwide ban on smoking in outdoor spaces like terraces, parks, and playgrounds, including traditional cigarettes and e-cigarettes. The law, which has passed the draft stage, aims to extend existing restrictions, crack down on new smoking devices, and prohibit tobacco advertising. Fines could reach €600,000 for serious violations, impacting not only smokers but also establishments failing to enforce the ban. Public consultation and further legislative steps are needed before the law can take effect, stirring debate on the impact of these measures. (Published on December 08, 2025byspanishnewstoday.com)</description></item><item><title>Ideology and Bloomberg Dollars Distort Global Tobacco Treaty</title><link>https://filtermag.org/at-cop11-ideology-bloomberg-tobacco/</link><description>The World Health Organization (WHO) has shifted towards an ideological stance on tobacco, neglecting science and favoring donor interests at COP11. Despite evidence showing reduced-risk nicotine products are safer, the WHO prioritizes harsher regulation on them over more harmful cigarettes. Delegates resisted these unfounded proposals, criticizing the WHO's bias and cult-like behavior. The WHO's hypocrisy was evident in biased awards and a funding ecosystem influenced by billionaire donors like Michael Bloomberg. In contrast, open dialogue at the "Good COP" conference highlighted the need for transparent, evidence-based public health policies, criticizing the WHO's failure to prioritize harm reduction. The WHO's deviation from its duty poses a threat to global public health. (Published on December 08, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #78 | YOUTUBE CRACKDOWN | Safer Nicotine Flagged As Medical Misinformation</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-78-youtube-crackdown-safer-nicotine-flagged-as-medical-misinformation/</link><description>YouTube’s new AI enforcement wave looks less like a policy update and more like the World Health Organization’s crusade against nicotine. In this worrying GFN Interview, GrimmGreen shows how safer-nicotine content is now being flagged as “medical misinformation” under rules that echo the WHO’s narrative: nicotine equals harm—no nuance allowed. After sixteen years as one of the most trusted voices helping adult smokers escape combustible tobacco, GrimmGreen is once again fighting to keep his channel alive. (Published on December 08, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Debunking the Myths: What the Evidence Really Says About Vaping vs Smoking</title><link>https://vsml.co.za/debunking-the-myths-what-the-evidence-really-says-about-vaping-vs-smoking/</link><description>Misleading claims about vaping, like those circulating in South Africa, are addressed by major health bodies. Vaping significantly reduces carcinogens and toxins compared to smoking, debunking myths about risks like Popcorn Lung and oil-containing liquids. Regulated vaping excludes harmful chemicals found in illicit products. Extensive evidence supports vaping as a less harmful alternative to smoking, promoting quitting. The public should be informed with accurate information to make informed decisions, emphasizing harm reduction and controlled youth access. (Published on December 08, 2025byvsml.co.za)</description></item><item><title>Zyn launches campaign to hero X-low variant</title><link>https://www.talkingretail.com/products-news/tobacco/zyn-launches-campaign-to-hero-x-low-variant-08-12-2025/</link><description>ZYN X-Low is the newest addition to the brand’s nicotine pouch range, catering to adult users exploring pouches for the first time. This product complements the existing ZYN lineup, offering retailers a diverse selection to meet customer preferences. With flavors like Spearmint and Black Cherry, ZYN X-Low provides a smoother experience with reduced tingle. Available at various retailers and through online platforms, this 1.5mg nicotine pouch aims to expand product options and promote a smoke-free future. Backed by a nationwide campaign, the launch emphasizes ZYN’s innovation and range of strength options for adult nicotine users. (Published on December 08, 2025bytalkingretail.com)</description></item><item><title>New Nordic data blows up nicotine ‘gateway myth’</title><link>https://snusforumet.se/en/new-nordic-data-blows-up-nicotine-gateway-myth/</link><description>The fresh Nordics report shows snus and nicotine pouches are not a gateway to smoking but a way out. The NORMO 2025 report reveals declining smoking rates and rising use of smokeless nicotine products, challenging the gateway theory. This trend holds across the Nordic countries, indicating products like snus replace cigarettes, not vice versa. Smokers are switching to snus or pouches, leading to historic reductions in smoking. Evidence from Sweden, Norway, and Finland supports this shift towards harm reduction, debunking the gateway myth. Policymakers should take note of these findings, emphasizing the success of harm reduction strategies in public health. (Published on December 08, 2025bysnusforumet.se)</description></item><item><title>Protecting Youth: Viet Nam must keep its comprehensive ban on e-cigarettes and heated tobacco products, says World Health Organization</title><link>https://www.who.int/vietnam/news/commentaries/detail/protecting-youth--viet-nam-must-keep-its-comprehensive-ban-on-e-cigarettes-and-heated-tobacco-products--says-world-health-organization</link><description>Viet Nam's National Assembly made history by passing a ban on e-cigarettes and heated tobacco products to safeguard the health of young people. Since the ban, there has been a 70% decrease in emergency cases related to these products. The dangers of nicotine use, especially for teenagers, are highlighted, with severe health implications. The importance of a comprehensive ban without exceptions is stressed to prevent legal loopholes. International evidence supports this approach, with 42 countries banning e-cigarettes and 24 banning heated tobacco products. Maintaining the ban is crucial to protect Viet Nam's progress in public health. Lawmakers are urged to ensure all relevant legislation reflects this ban for the well-being of Vietnamese youth. (Published on December 08, 2025bywho.int)</description></item></channel></rss>