<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:18:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GOOD COP 2.0 | Day 1 of 5 | RegWatch (Live)</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/good-cop-2-0-day-1-of-5-regwatch-live/</link><description>Live from Geneva, Switzerland – RegWatch brings you exclusive coverage of the Taxpayers Protection Alliance’s Good COP 2.0, a tobacco harm reduction counter-conference held alongside the WHO’s COP 11. Good COP 2.0 gathers 37 experts from 22 countries to distinguish facts from myths and challenge the misinformation influencing global health policy. (Published on November 17, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>Denmark sees dramatic drop in youth smoking rates as vaping increases</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/denmark-sees-dramatic-drop-in-youth-smoking-rates-as-vaping-increases/</link><description>Danish youth smoking rates hit record lows, with only 2.7% smoking daily, down from 15.4% in 2014, as per Aarhus University's survey. While cigarette use decreases, alternative nicotine product use rises, with a shift towards vapes and nicotine pouches as less harmful choices. These trends align with broader Nordic patterns, where e-cigarette and oral nicotine product use increases among youth. Denmark faces the challenge of regulating these products to curb youth access while acknowledging harm reduction benefits for adult smokers transitioning to non-combustible options. The data suggests a societal shift towards less harmful nicotine consumption among Danish youth. (Published on November 17, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>GOLDBERG: Governments must target the black market, not legal vendors, to crack down on youth vaping</title><link>https://winnipegsun.com/opinion/goldberg-governments-must-target-the-black-market-not-legal-vendors-to-crack-down-on-youth-vaping</link><description>Policymakers throughout Canada have valid reasons to be concerned about vapes reaching vulnerable youth. The illicit market continues to grow nationwide, prompting many governments to take action. In their 2025 budgets, Alberta, Ontario, and Saskatchewan each allocated funds to combat contraband tobacco and tackle the broader illicit market. (Published on November 17, 2025bywinnipegsun.com)</description></item><item><title>Ex-WHO officials call for global tobacco control reset to save millions</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/11/17/news/national/ex-who-officials-call-for-global-tobacco-control-reset-to-save-millions/2224913</link><description>Former WHO officials have called on governments to revamp global tobacco control strategies, warning that ignoring tobacco harm reduction (THR) could cost millions of lives. In a new report, Tikki Pang, Derek Yach, Chris Snowdon, and Peter Beckett argued that the Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) needs a “reset” to include safer nicotine products like e-cigarettes, heated tobacco devices, and oral nicotine pouches. They emphasized that broader access to these lower-risk alternatives could sharply reduce smoking-related deaths, especially in low- and middle-income countries with high cigarette consumption. (Published on November 17, 2025bymanilatimes.net)</description></item><item><title>Stricter Rules for E-Cigarettes from December in the Czech Republic</title><link>https://www.praguedaily.news/2025/11/17/stricter-rules-for-e-cigarettes-from-december-in-the-czech-republic/</link><description>New Czech regulations from December aim to protect young people by banning e-cigarettes with sugar flavors and cannabinoids to reduce addiction potential. Manufacturers must sell off existing stock in seven months. A study by the State Health Institute shows a rise in e-cigarette use, especially among those aged 15-24. Regulations will now require clearer indication of nicotine content on packaging. Additionally, products must have warnings if nicotine-free and cannot contain oils, fats, cannabinoids, or sugar flavors. Information, including a Ministry of Health registration number, must be printed on products directly. The Ministry hopes these measures will deter children from using e-cigarettes. (Published on November 17, 2025bypraguedaily.news)</description></item><item><title>Disposable vapes ban: a lot of hot air or a slow-burn success?</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy4p9pvwr49o.amp</link><description>The ban on disposable vapes aims to reduce environmental damage and curb nicotine addiction. Despite the ban, young people in Hull have not significantly changed their vaping habits. The Office for National Statistics revealed a slight decrease in daily or occasional e-cigarette use among 16-24 year olds. The ban, part of the Tobacco and Vapes Bill, intends to discourage youth vaping. While there are concerns about the attractiveness of vape flavors and packaging to young people, enforcement against illicit vapes is being strengthened. However, some worry that reusable vapes may still appeal to youths. Overall, the ban is seen as a success in reducing environmental impact, though its full impact on youth vaping remains to be seen. (Published on November 17, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item></channel></rss>