<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:18:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Richard Hogan: Vaping is not a healthy alternative to smoking — full stop</title><link>https://www.irishexaminer.com/lifestyle/people/arid-41728191.html</link><description>The text highlights the deceptive marketing tactics of vaping companies, particularly targeting children with appealing flavors. Vaping is shown to be harmful, with high nicotine levels and toxic chemicals inhaled, leading to addiction and health issues. Parents are urged to recognize the dangers and take action, while the government is called upon to implement stricter regulations on marketing, flavors, and misinformation about vaping. It is emphasized that prevention programs in schools are crucial to educate teenagers on the risks of vaping. Urgent measures are needed to address the increasing trend of teenage vaping and promote healthier socialization alternatives. (Published on October 23, 2025byirishexaminer.com)</description></item><item><title>Opinion: B.C.'s voodoo vaping legislation</title><link>https://financialpost.com/opinion/bc-voodoo-vaping-legislation</link><description>The article criticizes British Columbia’s new Bill 24, introduced by Attorney General Niki Sharma, which allows the government to fine and sue vaping vendors for health damages. The author argues that vaping is not a public health problem but rather a solution to smoking-related harm. They claim the bill will only stigmatize vaping and push the industry underground. The writer believes laws should focus on protecting children from nicotine addiction while allowing adults to make their own choices. (Published on October 24, 2025byfinancialpost.com)</description></item><item><title>Stalled smoking rates spark funding questions</title><link>https://healthandcare.scot/mobile_default.asp?page=story&amp;story=4314</link><description>Scotland's smoking rates have plateaued, raising concerns about NHS cessation service funding transparency. While 14% of Scots still smoke, funding for cessation services has decreased. ASH Scotland urges the government to reveal spending details to drive progress in achieving a tobacco-free Scotland by 2034. Quit attempts with NHS support slightly increased, but most boards miss cessation targets. Efforts include promoting services in deprived areas, where smoking rates are highest. The Public Health Minister emphasizes the benefits of quitting and urges people to utilize free support. Collaboration with NHS and pharmacists aims to aid smokers in achieving a tobacco-free Scotland by 2034. (Published on October 24, 2025byhealthandcare.scot)</description></item><item><title>FCTC COP-11 – a survival guide for delegates</title><link>https://clivebates.com/cop11/</link><description>The passage argues that the best way to achieve the goals of the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) is to make nicotine use safer by shifting from smoking to low-risk, smoke-free nicotine products. Despite years of tobacco control, over a billion people still use nicotine, and millions die annually from smoking. Since nicotine use is likely to continue, the focus should be on reducing smoking through tobacco harm reduction — encouraging the use of safer alternatives rather than trying to eliminate nicotine entirely. (Published on October 24, 2025byclivebates.com)</description></item><item><title>Anti-tobacco fanatics need to lighten up</title><link>https://thecritic.co.uk/anti-tobacco-fanatics-need-to-lighten-up/</link><description>The article criticizes the World Health Organization’s upcoming Conference of the Parties (COP) to the Framework Convention on Tobacco Control, describing it as a secretive and extreme anti-smoking event. It claims that government-funded “anti-nicotine zealots” meet to create harsh tobacco control measures. Among the proposed ideas are bans on cigarette filters and smoking in private homes, which the author calls excessive and unreasonable forms of prohibition. (Published on October 24, 2025bythecritic.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>The Ask | Vapers Demand Freedom from FDA Control | RegWatch (Live)</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/the-ask-vapers-demand-freedom-from-fda-control-regwatch-live/</link><description>Déjà vu in Washington. With Donald J. Trump back in the White House, public health officials, regulators, and anti-vaping activists have renewed their war on vaping — and this time, they may succeed. The FDA’s crackdown on nicotine vapes is intensifying, thousands of vape shops have closed, and vaping advocacy is struggling to survive. But déjà vu cuts both ways. The movement that once shook Washington with the “We Vape, We Vote” uprising is surging back with one mission: freedom from FDA control. At the center of this renewed fight is a familiar warrior: Tristan Thompson, Board President of the United Vapers Alliance and Head of The Vaping Legion. (Published on October 24, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>