<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 12:26:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Health authorities concerned over ‘toxic, addictive’ nicotine product</title><link>https://timesofmalta.com/article/health-authorities-concerned-toxic-addictive-nicotine-product.1112645</link><description>Health authorities in Malta are concerned about the rising popularity of unregulated nicotine pouches among young people. The product poses health risks such as addiction and serves as a potential gateway to tobacco use for children. These concerns will be addressed in the forthcoming Tobacco Control Strategy 2025-2030. Nicotine pouches are sold in colourful containers with various flavors and nicotine strengths, commonly found in small stores and bars. While some users believe it helps cut down on smoking, authorities worry about its widespread availability and the misconception that it is less harmful than tobacco. The product's unregulated status raises concerns about its impact on public health. (Published on July 09, 2025bytimesofmalta.com)</description></item><item><title>Australia’s youth smoking and vaping rates surge after vape ban</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/australias-youth-smoking-and-vaping-rates-surge-after-vape-ban/</link><description>Smoking and vaping rates among young Australians, particularly in the 18 to 24 age group, have surged despite a ban on vapes. Data shows 28% engage in smoking or vaping, with significant increases seen within a year. Vaping rates are at 20.5%, while cigarette use also rose. The ban on vapes has not curbed usage, leading to concerns of a shift to illicit tobacco products. Organized crime is thriving due to the rise in black market tobacco sales. Efforts to combat non-therapeutic vaping have had unintended consequences, with young adults being disproportionately affected. Illicit vape sales now outnumber legal ones in Australia. (Published on July 09, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Just How Harmful Is Vaping? More Evidence Is Emerging.</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/07/09/well/vaping-health-risks.html</link><description>The popularity of vapes as a healthier alternative to cigarettes is waning as studies reveal health hazards. Recent research showed high levels of heavy metals in vape mist, raising concerns about heart, lung, and brain impacts. Funding cuts for anti-vaping programs and limited data on long-term effects add to worries. Understanding the full extent of vaping risks is hindered by the relationship between vaping and cigarette use, especially among teens and young adults. Despite being used by a small percentage of adults, vaping rates among high school students remain higher. (Published on July 09, 2025bynytimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping linked to higher COPD risk, meta-analysis finds</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250708/Vaping-linked-to-higher-COPD-risk-meta-analysis-finds.aspx</link><description>Research reveals e-cigarettes are linked to increased risk of chronic lung disease, especially for current and former users. The study analyzed observational data from various countries and found that current users have a 48% higher risk, while former users face an 84% higher risk of COPD. However, causation is not confirmed, and findings could be influenced by factors like smoking history. Transitioning from traditional cigarettes to vaping involves risks, and further longitudinal research is recommended to understand the long-term effects of e-cigarette use on lung health. Public health guidance should aim to balance smoking cessation benefits with potential respiratory harm from vaping. (Published on July 10, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item></channel></rss>