<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:55:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hoekstra: Tobacco industry's vape claims echo 'light' cigarette lies</title><link>https://www.euractiv.com/news/hoekstra-tobacco-industrys-vape-claims-echo-light-cigarette-lies/</link><description>EU Climate Commissioner Wopke Hoekstra warned that the tobacco industry’s claims about vapes being less harmful than cigarettes mirror past misleading tactics used with “light” cigarettes. He stressed that nicotine in new products is still very harmful, damaging blood vessels, impairing vascular function, and stimulating tumour growth. The European Commission is now preparing its first assessment of the health impacts of new tobacco and nicotine products, with a focus on preventing youth uptake. Hoekstra has also been pushing for higher taxation on cigarettes, e-cigarettes, heated tobacco, and nicotine pouches. (Published on October 01, 2025byeuractiv.com)</description></item><item><title>Kazakhstan has been a regional leader in tobacco control — WHO Representative on shisha regulation and public health</title><link>https://qazinform.com/news/kazakhstan-has-been-a-regional-leader-in-tobacco-control-who-representative-on-shisha-regulation-and-public-health-6537b3</link><description>The World Health Organization supports Kazakhstan's ban on shisha smoking in public places due to health risks. Shisha smoke contains harmful substances and poses dangers to users and passive smokers. The misconception that shisha is safer than cigarettes is refuted by evidence showing its links to cancer and other diseases. WHO recommends upholding the ban to protect public health, especially with the popularity of shisha among the youth. Despite economic claims, tobacco-related diseases outweigh short-term gains. Media and civil society are crucial in raising awareness, and WHO provides scientific guidance on waterpipe smoking's health effects. Kazakhstan's tobacco control efforts align with WHO standards, emphasizing public health over commercial interests. (Published on October 01, 2025byqazinform.com)</description></item><item><title>Licensing shake-up could block access to vapes, warn retailers</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/licensing-shake-up-could-block-access-to-vapes-warn-retailers/</link><description>New government licensing rules could restrict vape access for smokers, worrying retailers about increased smoking rates and black market activity. The Tobacco and Vapes Bill proposes licensing for all tobacco and vape sellers by January 2027, without "grandfathering" existing sellers. Concerns arise over the impact on convenience stores and potential restrictions near schools. The UK Vaping Industry Association criticizes categorizing vape shops alongside unwanted businesses, emphasizing vaping's role in smoking cessation and public health. Licensing could target rogue traders and fund enforcement efforts, supporting responsible retailers and public health goals. (Published on October 01, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>14 countries on Sweden's side on nicotine tax</title><link>https://www.vejpkollen.se/en/2025/09/eu-budget-hotad-14-lander-pa-sveriges-sida-om-nikotinskatt/</link><description>The European Commission faces opposition over its record budget due to proposed new nicotine and corporate taxes, prompting 14 member states, led by Sweden, to oppose the plan. Concerns exist about tax revenue distribution, harm reduction perspectives, and market harmonization. The dispute may lead to a budget overhaul to secure necessary support. (Published on October 01, 2025byvejpkollen.se)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #73 | EMOTIONAL OVERRIDE | Why Feelings, Not Facts, Distort the Risk of Safer Nicotine</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-73/</link><description>Public health’s assault on vaping and safer nicotine products isn’t guided by evidence, it’s driven by fear, outrage, and a profound misunderstanding of risk. At GFN 2025 in Warsaw, David Zaruk, the “Risk-Monger,” reveals how emotion overrides science in policymaking. From the misuse of the Precautionary Principle to the denormalization of entire industries, Zaruk argues that activist zeal and WHO dogma have turned nicotine into a moral battleground, sacrificing harm reduction and leaving millions of smokers without safer options. (Published on October 01, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>What’s at stake for Malaysia as it eyes total ban on vapes by mid-2026?</title><link>https://www.channelnewsasia.com/asia/malaysia-vapes-ban-2026-health-minister-businesses-5375581</link><description>In Kuala Lumpur, a vape shop faces closure due to Malaysia's planned vape ban by mid-2026, leading to uncertain industry regulations. Health experts advocate for controlled regulation over a complete ban, citing concerns of boosting an illicit market. Authorities are urged to enhance enforcement of existing tobacco product laws. While some warn of health risks, others propose a harm reduction approach. Public Health Ministry's comment is awaited amid industry uncertainties. (Published on October 01, 2025bychannelnewsasia.com)</description></item></channel></rss>