<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:28:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN26 Proudly Announces our First Speaker  and Michael Russell Orator</title><link>https://gfn.events/</link><description>The Global Forum on Nicotine 2026 team is delighted to announce Dr Alex Wodak AM as our first speaker and who will deliver this year’s Michael Russell Oration. Alex is a retired physician, former President of the Australian Drug Law Reform Foundation, and has worked on drug law reform and tobacco harm reduction in his retirement. This year’s event is themed Prohibition and Public Health, and takes place from 3 - 5 June 2026 in Warsaw, Poland. Register athttps://gfn.events/registration/. Entry is open for GFN Science Lab, offering the opportunity to showcase your scientific success. (Published on January 30, 2026bygfn.events)</description></item><item><title>Nearly half of smokers quit after switching to nicotine pouches, U.S. study finds</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/nearly-half-of-smokers-quit-after-switching-to-nicotine-pouches-u-s-study-finds/</link><description>A study tracking adults using nicotine pouches found that nearly half of smokers quit after 10 weeks. Cigarette use decreased from 15.9% to 8.1%. Some users switched from other tobacco to pouches. Data showed declines in smoking and smokeless tobacco, validating pouches as harm reduction tools. Motivation to quit smoking was high, with some participants stopping all tobacco use. Most users cited reducing or quitting smoking as reasons for pouch use. Study limitations included self-reported data and a non-representative sample. Researchers advocate for further research on pouches' long-term impact on public health and smoking cessation. (Published on January 30, 2026byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco, Vape and Nicotine: Still a vital category</title><link>https://www.asiantrader.biz/tobacco-vape-nicotine-vital-category</link><description>The UK convenience retail sector sees the tobacco, vape, and nicotine category driving footfall and profits, despite volatility due to shifting policies, consumer behaviors, and the growing illicit trade. While cigarette sales decline, nicotine demand remains strong, leading to opportunities with modern nicotine products like pouches and vape formats. The tobacco market remains stable, though price-driven, and premium segments like roll-your-own continue to lure loyal customers. Nicotine pouches are rapidly expanding, offering retailers operational benefits. Compliance, merchandising, and understanding consumer habits are crucial, especially as the category diversifies and regulations evolve. (Published on January 30, 2026byasiantrader.biz)</description></item><item><title>Disengaging from the stakeholders</title><link>https://thecritic.co.uk/disengaging-from-the-stakeholders/</link><description>Last November, I reported on the EU’s plan to force member states to levy punitive taxes on e-cigarette fluid and nicotine pouches. The European Commission launched a public consultation which received 18,480 responses, overwhelmingly from consumers who were against. Having lost the numbers game, anti-nicotine NGOs went running to Politico who published an article claiming that the consultation had been “swamped with pro-industry feedback”. (Published on January 30, 2026bythecritic.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #172 | Is Africa at a Turning Point on Nicotine Policy?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-172-is-africa-at-a-turning-point-on-nicotine-policy/</link><description>2026 could be a turning point for nicotine policy in Africa. In this episode of GFN News, Joanna Junak speaks with Joseph Magero, consumer advocate and Chairman of the Campaign for Safer Alternatives, about the challenges and opportunities for harm reduction, the impact of restrictive policies, and how countries like South Africa, Kenya, and Nigeria are shaping the future of safer nicotine products. (Published on January 30, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>