<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 06:21:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>World fights nicotine addiction but Switzerland continues to drag feet</title><link>https://www.swissinfo.ch/eng/international-geneva/world-fights-nicotine-addiction-but-switzerland-continues-to-drag-feet/90575384</link><description>Switzerland's failure to ratify the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control despite hosting WHO's headquarters allows the tobacco industry to wield significant influence. Despite COP11 decisions to tackle issues like environmental pollution and deceptive industry claims, the tobacco lobby continues to impede global tobacco control efforts. Switzerland's strong ties between the tobacco industry and politicians hinder progress, with the country ranking poorly in the Global Tobacco Industry Interference Index. The tobacco industry's active presence in policymaking highlights the weaknesses in Swiss tobacco control legislation, as seen through the watering down of key regulations. This contributes to Switzerland's low ranking in tobacco control policy implementation compared to other European countries. (Published on December 04, 2025byswissinfo.ch)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches glamourized on social media, little talk about risks for youth, study finds</title><link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/british-columbia/nicotine-pouch-youth-study-9.7002330</link><description>Researchers at UBCO warn that TikTok videos glamorizing nicotine pouch use are shaping a trendy image, particularly among youth. Despite Health Canada authorizing these pouches for adult smoking cessation, they're off-limits for under-18s. Dr. Laura Struik's analysis of 250 videos, totaling nearly 2 million shares, highlights how users portray pouches as seamless with daily life. The videos fail to address potential health risks like gum recession and heart problems from prolonged use. Struik suggests involving young people in policy discussions about these products. Health Canada is enforcing regulations on approved pouch brands due to concerns about unauthorized sales to minors. (Published on December 04, 2025bycbc.ca)</description></item><item><title>NZ Minister Grilled Over Oral Nicotine Plan</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/12/03/nz-minister-grilled-over-oral-nicotine-plan/</link><description>Associate Health Minister Casey Costello was questioned about the government's plan to permit oral nicotine products, despite denying ties to the tobacco industry. Costello emphasized harm reduction and safety precautions to prevent youth access. Labour's Dr. Ayesha Verrall cautioned against potential new addictions in youths, urging Costello to follow expert advice before introducing the products. Public health researcher Dr. Jude Ball highlighted the lack of evidence supporting oral nicotine products for smoking cessation and warned about tobacco companies promoting youth consumption. Costello is still reviewing recommendations on the matter. (Published on December 04, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Brain enzyme that drives nicotine addiction and smoking dependence identified</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-12-brain-enzyme-nicotine-addiction.html</link><description>Research reveals that astrocytes' enzyme, glutamine synthetase, plays a crucial role in nicotine addiction, influencing brain changes and addictive behavior. Led by Prof. Choe, the study found that astrocytes interact with neurons to regulate nicotine-dependent behavior. Nicotine exposure stimulates receptors on astrocytes, triggering a calcium surge and signaling pathways that enhance locomotor sensitization. By blocking specific interactions in rats' brains, researchers dampened locomotor sensitization, underscoring astrocytic signaling's significance in nicotine-induced brain changes. These findings suggest a new avenue for addiction research, emphasizing glia communication and potential therapeutic strategies for smoking cessation. (Published on December 04, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Cotton-candy countdown: new vape rules target rising youth addiction</title><link>https://english.radio.cz/cotton-candy-countdown-new-vape-rules-target-rising-youth-addiction-8870827</link><description>A new Czech law bans candy-flavored electronic cigarettes, giving stores seven months to sell existing stocks. The law aims to protect youth as over a quarter of young users prefer candy flavors. Experts warn that nicotine in e-cigarettes harms adolescent brain development, leading to addiction and behavioral issues. The ban targets flavors attracting minors, while adult users can still access other options. The move follows concerns that e-cigarettes increase smoking rates, especially among minors. Critics suggest enforcing existing laws against selling any cigarettes to minors. Addiction specialist Adam Kulhánek supports the ban on candy flavors to safeguard children's health. (Published on December 04, 2025byradio.cz)</description></item><item><title>EXCLUSIVE: “Rethink the status quo” – two former WHO directors call for radical overhaul of global nicotine policy</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/exclusive-rethink-the-status-quo-two-former-who-directors-call-for-radical-overhaul-of-global-nicotine-policy/</link><description>Former WHO Directors Derek Yach and Tikki Pang advocate a radical overhaul of the WHO's tobacco control treaty for harm reduction. They emphasize the need for courage from governments, industry, and civil society to prioritize public health over old beliefs. Highlighting the importance of informing healthcare professionals, they urge scientific societies and journals to support harm reduction strategies. The authors stress the urgency for low-income countries to adopt these measures to prevent long-term health and economic burdens. Contrasting progress in developed and developing nations, they argue for embracing safer alternatives to reduce smoking-related harm. Despite past mistrust of tobacco companies, they call for a pragmatic shift towards harm reduction to save lives. (Published on December 04, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Clive Bates: when tobacco control turns against public health</title><link>https://open.spotify.com/episode/3xBz9wBfMEWbwzD71vwkM5?flow_ctx=1a82ac13-a610-45d3-bbd1-91bf4085b1e7%3A1764882080</link><description>The text discusses an episode of "Aclaremos las cosas" with Clive Bates on tobacco control policy. The conversation criticizes the WHO Framework Convention for being bureaucratic and anti-industry instead of harm reduction-focused. It highlights issues like Article 5.3, excluding dissenting voices, organized crime impacts of bans, and missed opportunities for harm reduction. The episode calls attention to philanthropic foundation influence on global narratives about nicotine. (Published on December 04, 2025byspotify.com)</description></item><item><title>The Problems With ASH Scotland’s Midwife’s Guide to NRT</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/ash-scotland-midwife-nrt-guide-problems/</link><description>ASH Scotland released a guide for midwives on addressing nicotine use during pregnancy, causing confusion rather than clarity. The guide implies medicinal nicotine replacement therapy (NRT) is far safer than commercial products, despite both containing the same compound. Differences lie in purity, dose, and regulation, but evidence doesn't conclusively support medicinal NRT being "far safer." Caution is advised for pregnant individuals until further research clarifies the risks. (Published on December 04, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>