<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 18:17:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>“Ugly” COP11 Attacks THR, But Nations Avert Worst Damage</title><link>https://filtermag.org/cop11-attacks-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>The World Health Organization's COP11 on tobacco control ended, criticizing harm reduction measures as industry tactics. New Zealand's success in reducing smoking rates with THR was scorned, earning them the "Dirty Ashtray" award. Mexico, despite high smoking rates, was celebrated for banning vapes. COP11 excluded THR advocates and was funded by anti-THR entities. Calls for transparency and evidence-based regulations were made. The agenda items impacting THR were deferred to COP12 in 2027. Despite some positive agreements on tobacco control funding, COP11 mainly resulted in a stalemate for THR advocates, while bans on safer alternatives were pushed. Policymaking at COP11 was seen as ineffective in tackling smoking-related harm. (Published on November 27, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>The Ongoing Failure of UK Tobacco Control</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/uk-tobacco-control-failure-cop11-harm-reduction/</link><description>Before the WHO’s FCTC COP11 meeting, the UK’s public health minister promised to support tobacco harm reduction, but the UK delegation ultimately did not follow through. During the opening plenary, the UK expressed interest in forward-looking measures, even though these threatened vaping and other reduced-risk products. The delegation emphasized the dangers of tobacco but highlighted policies under the Tobacco and Vapes Bill that could hinder safer nicotine alternatives. Rather than advocating for harm reduction, the statement focused on concerns about new nicotine products. Overall, the UK appeared more interested in aligning with the WHO and promoting a generational tobacco ban than in supporting smokers seeking safer options. (Published on November 27, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>