<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:20:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Brennan: Generational nicotine ban exercise in overreach</title><link>https://www.bostonherald.com/2025/12/17/brennan-generational-nicotine-ban-exercise-in-overreach/</link><description>Communities like Ashland and Westminster resist oppressive "nicotine-free generation" laws that ban tobacco for anyone born after a certain date. The pushback warns against undemocratic tactics and emphasizes the importance of civil liberties. Advocates argue that such laws fail to curb smoking and only create more problems. The backlash against these policies continues to grow as more towns reject them, advocating for education over bans. The narrative underscores the need to protect adult rights, transparency, and democratic processes. Stoughton is encouraged to reject similar legislations to safeguard individual liberties and prevent regulatory overreach. (Published on December 18, 2025bybostonherald.com)</description></item><item><title>WVA attacks EU ‘Safe Hearts Plan’ for ignoring harm reduction</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/wva-attacks-eu-safe-hearts-plan-for-ignoring-harm-reduction/</link><description>The European Commission's Safe Hearts Plan aims to address cardiovascular issues by involving safer nicotine products in harm reduction. Despite smoking's impact on heart health, EU smoking rates have barely decreased. The plan's failure to prioritize harm reduction may delay the 5 percent target by 2040 to 2100. The World Vapers' Alliance criticizes the plan for overlooking the benefits of alternatives like vaping and snus used successfully in countries such as Sweden. The Alliance suggests the EU should adopt risk-based regulation to achieve smoke-free goals, as demonstrated by successful examples in countries like Sweden, the Czech Republic, and Greece. (Published on December 18, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Robotic Methadone Tech Not the Answer to Clinics’ Culture of Cruelty</title><link>https://filtermag.org/robotic-methadone-tech-clinics-cruelty/</link><description>Technology is reshaping the methadone industry, aiming to increase efficiency and profit. Companies like Opio are introducing robotic machines like ZING to speed up the dosing process and reduce nurse turnover. ZING Satellite extends this technology to remote locations, monitored by DEA-approved cameras. While these innovations aim to improve access, they raise concerns about dehumanizing patient care. Despite technological advancements, the root issue lies in the lack of accessible, non-stigmatizing opioid treatment. Ultimately, the focus should shift towards community-based solutions rather than complex and expensive tech fixes like ZING. (Published on December 18, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Smokers and Vapers Face Price Shock Under Brussels Tax Plan</title><link>https://europeanconservative.com/articles/news/smokers-and-vapers-face-price-shock-under-brussels-tax-plan/</link><description>Brussels plans a substantial tax increase on nicotine products in Europe that many governments claim was influenced by activists rather than elected officials. The draft proposes significantly higher taxes, with some nations seeing prices rise immediately. Concerns have been raised about the influence of activist networks like Smoke-Free Europe on shaping policy. Member States are dismayed at the lack of basic safeguards and transparency in the process. The directive, if implemented, could shape nicotine policy in the EU for the next decade, potentially undermining trust in EU decision-making and exacerbating divisions between member states. The debate reflects a larger question about who ultimately dictates public-health policy in Europe. (Published on December 18, 2025byeuropeanconservative.com)</description></item><item><title>How Bad Is Vaping for the Environment?</title><link>https://impakter.com/how-bad-is-vaping-for-environment/</link><description>Disposable vapes pose environmental and health risks due to improper disposal and complex recycling requirements. With millions discarded annually, fires and pollution increase. Most users do not recycle, missing the chance to repurpose valuable materials like lithium batteries. Vapes contribute to global e-waste issues, generating plastic and electronic waste and leaching toxins into the environment. Some vape companies falsely claim eco-friendliness, contributing to the problem. Countries like India, Brazil, and the UK are banning disposable vapes to reduce their impact. More research and awareness are required to address this growing issue effectively. (Published on December 18, 2025byimpakter.com)</description></item><item><title>EU states seek tighter limits on cross-border tobacco and alcohol shopping</title><link>https://www.euractiv.com/news/countries-want-to-curb-cross-boarder-shopping-of-tobacco-alcohol/</link><description>Several EU countries are considering changes to single-market rules to limit how much tobacco individuals can bring across borders. Denmark, holding the EU Council presidency, proposed this during early December talks on revising the Tobacco Taxation Directive. The proposal aims to balance disagreements between countries pushing for higher tobacco taxes and those opposing them by combining softer tax increases with stricter limits on intra-EU tobacco imports. (Published on December 18, 2025byeuractiv.com)</description></item></channel></rss>