<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 12:54:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>England’s poorest areas have 70% more vape shops and bookmakers than wealthier ones</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2026/feb/09/englands-poorest-areas-have-70-more-vape-shops-and-bookmakers-than-wealthier-ones</link><description>A study by the Independent Commission on Neighbourhoods highlights disparities in neighborhood amenities, with poorer areas having more vape shops and bookmakers but fewer cafes and gyms. Keir Starmer's government is focusing on regenerating high streets through the "pride in place" program. However, there are concerns that vital neighborhood shopping precincts are being overlooked. Research warns of high vacancy rates in deprived areas and the lack of social infrastructure. Farage's Reform UK is also emphasizing rejuvenating high streets. The decline of high streets is a major concern, particularly in Labour strongholds, with repercussions on community cohesion and potentially fueling radical politics online. (Published on February 09, 2026bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco Harm Reduction Policy Brief</title><link>https://www.harmreductionaustralia.org.au/tobacco-harm-reduction-policy-brief/</link><description>See HRA’s new Tobacco Harm Reduction Policy Brief to understand why Australia should urgently reform its current tobacco control strategy to an evidenced-based harm reduction approach including reducing tobacco excise, establishing a legal, regulated market for lower risk nicotine products and, shifting investment from enforcement to regulation… (Published on February 09, 2026byharmreductionaustralia.org.au)</description></item><item><title>Netherlands plans to raise nicotine purchase age to 21, including vapes</title><link>https://www.2firsts.com/news/netherlands-plans-to-raise-nicotine-purchase-age-to-21-including-vapes</link><description>The Netherlands plans to raise the legal age for buying nicotine products, including vapes, from 18 to 21, aligning with European trends. Concerns over youth vaping are driving the change, echoing similar moves in Latvia, Ireland, and Finland. Industry groups criticize the proposal, citing legal adult status at 18 and warning of potential illicit trade. The impact of such measures is being monitored, with differing approaches in neighboring countries. (Published on February 09, 2026by2firsts.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #175 | What the Research on Vaping and Harm Reduction Really Says?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-175-what-the-research-on-vaping-and-harm-reduction-really-says/</link><description>Behavioral science consultant Arielle Selya joins GFN News to discuss her new YouTube channel and why she’s breaking down tobacco harm reduction research. From misperceptions about vaping to the gateway hypothesis, she explains what the science actually shows—and how studies are often misrepresented. (Published on February 09, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Victorian Liberal MP Mary Aldred demands federal govt get AFP involved in ‘serious’ illicit tobacco industry</title><link>https://www.skynews.com.au/australia-news/crime/victorian-liberal-mp-mary-aldred-demands-federal-govt-get-afp-involved-in-serious-illicit-tobacco-industry/news-story/7c7bd63c1f71c39442e0e7b39840242d</link><description>Victorian Liberal MP Mary Aldred has rebuked the federal government for not engaging law enforcement to tackle the “serious problem” of illicit tobacco across the country - which is costing Australia billions. In recent months, the Albanese government has faced mounting pressure over the “staggering” level of black market tobacco and e-cigarette trading in Australia, which has boomed as a result of Labor’s excise settings. (Published on February 09, 2026byskynews.com.au)</description></item></channel></rss>