<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 06:21:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Britain’s move to ban youngsters from smoking breaks international law, says five European countries</title><link>https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/37550399/britain-smoking-ban-breaks-international-law/</link><description>Five European countries believe the UK's smoking ban for youngsters breaches international law, risking penalties. The ban, proposed by Sir Keir Starmer, might violate EU law for Northern Ireland under the Windsor Framework. The group warns of legal consequences, stressing the importance of compliance with the Single Market rules. Former Lord Chancellor Robert Buckland urges the UK government to address the conflict to avoid a constitutional crisis. Despite calls for closer EU ties post-Brexit, Starmer opposes joining the Customs Union. The UK affirms the Tobacco and Vapes Bill aligns with their obligations, aiming for a smoke-free generation. (Published on December 09, 2025bythesun.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Singapore takes tough measures against e-cigarettes</title><link>https://en.vietnamplus.vn/singapore-takes-tough-measures-against-e-cigarettes-post333952.vnp</link><description>A 16-year-old Singaporean is the first etomidate abuser admitted to a Singaporean rehab center following its classification as a controlled drug. Singapore's Ministry of Home Affairs and Health Sciences Authority reported his admission for a two-month program after three etomidate-related offenses. The rehab includes psychology-based programs, family support, and religious counseling. Additionally, a 15-year-old Myanmar national had her visit pass revoked for possessing an etomidate e-vaporizer. This is the first foreigner case under Singapore's anti-vaping laws, where possessing etomidate can lead to deportation and a ban from re-entry. (Published on December 09, 2025byvietnamplus.vn)</description></item><item><title>Brickbat: Puff and Pay</title><link>https://reason.com/2025/12/09/brickbat-puff-and-pay/</link><description>The Scottsdale, Arizona, city council has updated its smoking restrictions to include e-cigarettes and vape pens, banning their use in enclosed public spots (such as malls, theaters, bars, and restaurants), in city-owned areas (such as bus stops, playgrounds, pools, and stadiums), and anywhere within 50 feet of public schools. Violators could face fines of up to $300. (Published on December 09, 2025byreason.com)</description></item><item><title>Chinese vape imports surge despite crackdown</title><link>https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/news/investigations/3908636/chinese-vape-imports-surge-despite-trump-administrations-crackdown-data/</link><description>President Trump's efforts to reduce Chinese vape imports recorded a decrease from April to June, but a surge in July to October. Despite U.S. import declines since 2023, Chinese export data revealed a steady increase. Conflicting trade records show illicit vapes dominating the market, while efforts continue to curb their sale. Possible explanations include underreported imports and deceptive tactics by manufacturers. Investigations unveiled networks aiding illegal vape flow into the U.S. Officials seized significant amounts of illicit vapes, yet the total imported remains unaccounted for. Ongoing efforts to combat this issue involve increased enforcement actions and coordination between government agencies. The FDA and CBP play significant roles, with allocated funds for e-cigarette enforcement. (Published on December 09, 2025bywashingtonexaminer.com)</description></item><item><title>COPCast: Ignacio Leiva &amp; Maria Papaioannoy-Duic</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9A0UeI15vQE&amp;list=PLhdEh66F_r_4pH3FTXz4-ueqSwNUSwxZF&amp;index=1</link><description>Ignacio Leiva is a journalist specializing in informatics and multimedia platforms and a leading advocate for vaping in Chile. In 2010 he led a communication campaign that helped prevent a vaping ban and has since focused on educating and strengthening the vaping community. He is the founder and current president of the Association of Vaporizer Consumers of Chile ASOVAPE and serves as secretary of ARDT Iberoamerica. Ignacio organized the first pro vaping public demonstration in Latin America and actively promotes tobacco harm reduction initiatives in Chile and internationally. He also played a key role in the legislative process that led to the enactment of Chile’s vaping law which came into force this year. (Published on December 09, 2025byyoutube.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #166 | WHAT HAPPENED AROUND FCTC's COP11?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-166-what-happened-around-fctcs-cop11/</link><description>Join Joanna Junak on GFN News as she speaks with Kurt Yeo, co-founder of Vaping Saved My Life, about the key moments and conversations surrounding COP11. Kurt shares his impressions from the unofficial Good COP 2.0 meeting in Geneva and offers insights into the broader discussions on harm reduction and tobacco policy. (Published on December 09, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Illegal vapes still on sale as fires surge six months after UK ban</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/illegal-vapes-still-on-sale-as-fires-surge-six-months-after-uk-ban/</link><description>The disposable vape ban, implemented six months ago, has not effectively reduced the availability of illicit products. Despite fewer shops selling banned devices, illegal vapes are still easily accessible. Compliance is mixed, with some retailers offering only legal products, while others sell banned vapes alongside upgrades. Concerns over enforcement persist, as some sellers disregard rules. Additionally, the improper disposal of vapes, including rechargeable models, is causing a rise in dangerous fires. Waste management companies report a surge in vape-related incidents, highlighting the ban's unintended consequences. The ban struggles to change behavior, with evidence indicating it may exacerbate issues instead of resolving them. (Published on December 09, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item></channel></rss>