<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 12:25:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Governments “Hate” Big Tobacco—Yet Hand Them the Nicotine Market</title><link>https://filtermag.org/governments-big-tobacco-nicotine-market/</link><description>Despite governments' public denouncement of Big Tobacco and promotion of a smoke-free future, their policies often favor the tobacco industry, limiting competition from safer nicotine products. Laws like Arkansas' vaping ban and the UK's restrictive Tobacco and Vapes Bill hinder harm reduction efforts and innovation. Such regulations, influenced by tobacco lobbying and misinformation, paradoxically benefit cigarette companies. By stifling alternative options, governments trap millions of smokers. Instead, supporting harm reduction, fostering competition, and embracing innovation could truly combat smoking's harms. Policies restricting safer choices maintain cigarettes' dominance, contradicting public health intentions. Prioritizing practical harm reduction strategies over outdated approaches is crucial for reducing tobacco's deadly grip. (Published on June 18, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #157 | POLAND'S TRICKY RELATIONSHIP WITH TOBACCO HARM REDUCTION</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-157/</link><description>Poland is forging ahead with new restrictions on safer nicotine products, whilst still equating vaping with smoking - is this anti-THR messaging harming efforts to reduce smoking in the country? Przemysław Bobiński of #GFN25 media partner Vapour Poland joins us to discuss this and more! (Published on June 18, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>More and more children aware of nicotine pouches, charity warns</title><link>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/government-ash-dorset-berkshire-oxfordshire-b2771185.html</link><description>A charity warns of increasing awareness and use of nicotine pouches among youngsters, lacking clear health effects. A survey reveals rising teen exposure, with 4% having tried them. Usage is up among adults aged 18-34, driven by aggressive marketing. Though less harmful than smoking, no regulations exist on nicotine strength or marketing. Parliament is considering the Tobacco and Vapes Bill to ban advertising and sales to under-18s. Concerns about tobacco industry tactics targeting youth have sparked calls for urgent government action. The Bill aims to protect minors and regulate product promotion, flavors, and packaging. (Published on June 18, 2025byindependent.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Smoke Free Sweden: Oral Nicotine Pouches Are Game-changer for Women in Sweden's Smoke-free Success</title><link>https://en.antaranews.com/news/360081/smoke-free-sweden-oral-nicotine-pouches-are-game-changer-for-women-in-swedens-smoke-free-success</link><description>Oral nicotine pouches significantly contribute to reducing smoking rates in Sweden, especially among women. Their effectiveness in aiding smoking cessation has led to a nearly 200% increase in quit rates for women. These pouches are preferred over other quit aids, such as vapes and gum, due to being clean, socially acceptable, and stigma-free. Sweden's successful harm reduction strategy has lowered the smoking rate to 5.3%, with notable decreases in lung and total cancer deaths. However, excessive regulation could hinder progress, particularly for women. Providing access to effective quit aids like nicotine pouches is crucial for achieving a smoke-free future. (Published on June 18, 2025byantaranews.com)</description></item><item><title>Are Disposable Vapes Hiding a Sweet Trap?</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/are-disposable-vapes-hiding-sweet-trap-2025a1000g7m?form=fpf</link><description>A study by Yale and Duke Universities found neotame, a very sweet artificial sweetener, in many popular disposable e-cigarettes in the US and EU. While safe in food, its inhalation effects are unknown. Neotame is used to enhance flavors like cherry lemonade in e-cigarettes, appealing to young users but unregulated. Neotame was detected in 78% of e-cigarette samples, especially in disposable and nicotine-free products. Concerns include potential addiction and lack of data on its health effects when inhaled. Researchers suggest stricter regulation of sweeteners in e-cigarettes due to their appeal. Comprehensive studies on the toxic effects and addictive potential of neotame are urged for future regulatory decisions. (Published on June 18, 2025bymedscape.com)</description></item><item><title>Global Panel Urges Rapid Reform of WHO and FCTC to Embrace Science, Transparency, and Consumer Voices</title><link>https://www.newswire.ca/news-releases/global-panel-urges-rapid-reform-of-who-and-fctc-to-embrace-science-transparency-and-consumer-voices-896267708.html</link><description>The Taxpayers Protection Alliance leads a call for reform within the WHO's tobacco control arm, citing politicized policymaking and lack of consumer input. Amid criticism of the WHO's pandemic response, advocates push for evidence-based changes at the Framework Convention on Tobacco Control. Consumer voices stress the need for transparency and science-based policymaking for effective reform. The panel urges the WHO and FCTC to prioritize pragmatic strategies over prohibitionist approaches to combat smoking rates and health inequities. The key message is to prioritize scientific integrity and consumer inclusion for meaningful reform in international health institutions. (Published on June 18, 2025bynewswire.ca)</description></item></channel></rss>