<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 01:05:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HSE cannot support vaping and nicotine pouch addiction through quit smoking programmes</title><link>https://www.irishexaminer.com/news/arid-41669015.html</link><description>The HSE lacks funding for vaping and nicotine pouch addiction support in quit smoking programs, despite increased demand. A proposal for a cessation service awaits government approval, needing additional resources. Currently, services cater to those quitting tobacco or dual users. Concerns arise as vaping and nicotine pouch use surges among non-tobacco smokers. Regulation gaps and increased uptake of pouches prompt calls for expanded legislation. Efforts by the Minister of State for Public Health focus on youth addiction awareness and regulatory changes, like banning disposable vapes and limiting flavors. Cooperation with the Health Minister is essential to develop comprehensive strategies for vaping and pouch cessation within the overall health plan. (Published on July 15, 2025byirishexaminer.com)</description></item><item><title>Iceland gov’t faces backlash over plan to tighten nicotine pouch access</title><link>https://www.westernstandard.news/international/iceland-govt-faces-backlash-over-plan-to-tighten-nicotine-pouch-access/65995</link><description>Iceland's government is facing backlash over a proposed bill that would tighten all tobacco and nicotine regulations under one law. The draft, released in June, aims to ban flavored nicotine pouches, require plain packaging, prohibit online sales, and impose heavy fines on retailers who violate age verification rules. Manufacturers would also need new permits to sell their products. Public response has been mostly negative—by the July 3 deadline, 190 formal submissions were received, with many accusing the health ministry of overreaching. (Published on July 15, 2025bywesternstandard.news)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine Myth | Two-Thirds of U.S. Healthcare Providers Think It Causes Cancer | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/nicotine-myth-two-thirds-of-u-s-healthcare-providers-think-it-causes-cancer-regwatch/</link><description>A new study from Philip Morris International reveals that widespread misconceptions about nicotine are undermining tobacco harm reduction in clinical care. Nearly two-thirds of U.S. healthcare professionals, including primary care doctors, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants, mistakenly believe that nicotine causes cancer. In this episode of RegWatch, filmed on location at the 2025 Global Forum on Nicotine in Warsaw, we unpack the findings with Dr. Pritika Kumar, U.S. Director of Scientific Engagement at Philip Morris International. (Published on July 15, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>You Don’t Know Nicotine: Apple TV</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-07-14_you-dont-know-nicotine-apple-tv.html</link><description>You Don’t Know Nicotine, now on Apple TV, is a documentary by Aaron Biebert exploring the science, politics, and public debate around nicotine. It contrasts a transparent nicotine production process in France with fear and misinformation in the U.S. The film features voices from both sides of the debate, including activists and researchers, aiming to clarify what nicotine really is. Reviewers praise it for its balance, attention to detail, and focus on truth and evidence. (Published on July 15, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Reports of US children ingesting nicotine pouches surge, study says</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jul/14/nicotine-pouches-children-poisoning</link><description>In the US, children under six consuming nicotine pouches increased by 763% in three years, with some needing intensive care and two deaths reported. The surge in poisonings coincides with rising sales of nicotine pouches like Zyn, popular for their flavors that appeal to youth. Despite most cases resulting in minor effects, there were serious outcomes recorded, emphasizing the need for safe storage away from children and vigilance in usage around them. Experts advise calling the Poison Help line at 1-800-222-1222 if a child ingests a pouch, highlighting the dangers of nicotine poisoning in young children due to its effects on the heart. Measures to prevent accidental ingestion include secure storage and avoiding use in front of children, who are prone to imitating adults. (Published on July 15, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping a better quit help than gum and lozenges for some disadvantaged smokers: trial</title><link>https://www.unsw.edu.au/newsroom/news/2025/07/vaping-quitting-smoking-gum-lozenges</link><description>Vapes with nicotine are more effective for socially disadvantaged adults to quit smoking than nicotine gum or lozenges, as shown in a study by NDARC. While vapes helped 28.4% quit compared to 9.6% with NRT, 58% continued vaping after quitting smoking. Australia has high smoking rates among socially disadvantaged groups, despite lower overall rates. Vapes offer a promising option for smokers who struggle to quit, but the long-term safety of vaping is uncertain. The study suggests tailored vaping options and support are crucial for successful cessation. Health professionals should consider vaping as a cessation aid for individuals who have not quit with traditional therapies. (Published on July 15, 2025byunsw.edu.au)</description></item><item><title>The new nicotine product replacing e-cigarettes to addict teens</title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/07/15/zyn-nicotine-pouches-teens-tobacco/</link><description>Nicotine use among teens saw a decline from a peak in 2019 but is now threatened by the popularity of nicotine pouches. These pouches, marketed as a safer alternative for adults, are addicting a new generation to nicotine, undoing public health progress. Nicotine poses significant health risks, impacting brain development and increasing addiction. Pouches, with various flavors and high nicotine content, appeal to youths with discreet use and social media marketing. Policy solutions include restricting access, banning flavors, and curbing advertising, despite opposition from tobacco companies. These companies, targeting young users, aim to maintain a steady demand for nicotine products. (Published on July 15, 2025bywashingtonpost.com)</description></item></channel></rss>