<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 18:51:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EU vs. Consumers: The Commission is Choosing Ideology Over Lives</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/eu-vs-consumers-the-commission-is-choosing-ideology-over-lives/</link><description>The European Commission fails to uphold its promise of evidence-based legislation with the Tobacco Products Directive update. Misinformation and ignoring harm reduction success stories in Member States like Sweden, the Czech Republic, and Greece are concerning. Public input is dismissed, with citizens supporting harm reduction strategies being ignored in favor of anti-nicotine organizations. Accusations of fake consultation responses fuel a smear campaign. The Commission risks harming public health by equating nicotine products with cigarettes. Embracing harm reduction is crucial for saving lives. The Commission must prioritize facts, listen to science, and respect democratic voices in policymaking for a smoke-free future. (Published on February 12, 2026byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Mark Tyndall: The harm reduction doctor who took on tobacco’s last taboo</title><link>https://snusforumet.se/en/mark-tyndall-the-harm-reduction-doctor-who-took-on-tobaccos-last-taboo/</link><description>In this instalment of the “Harm Reduction Heroes” series, Snusforumet speaks with Mark Tyndall, a Canadian infectious-disease physician who played a key role in developing pragmatic responses to HIV and overdose crises. He now argues that the global refusal to embrace safer nicotine alternatives represents a major public health failure that remains largely overlooked despite its clear consequences. (Published on February 12, 2026bysnusforumet.se)</description></item><item><title>A Turning Point For Policy</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2026-02-09_a-turning-point-for-policy.html</link><description>The United States’ decision to leave the World Health Organization is seen as a major turning point for policy in the Asia-Pacific region, according to the Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA). The group is urging governments to review the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC), while New Zealand’s Foreign Minister Winston Peters has also questioned continued funding for the treaty. The US cited WHO mismanagement as a reason for its withdrawal, and Peters criticized the organization as unaccountable and in need of taxpayer scrutiny. CAPHRA’s Executive Coordinator, Nancy Loucas, argued that the US exit should prompt a reassessment of the FCTC, particularly regarding its approach to harm reduction tools such as vaping and nicotine pouches. (Published on February 12, 2026byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>