<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 18:19:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>22nd Century Applauds the American Academy of Family Physicians Comments and Support of the FDA’s Proposed Reduced Nicotine Mandate to Reduce Smoking</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/news/6167025</link><description>In this press release, 22nd Century Group praises the American Academy of Family Physicians for supporting the FDA’s proposal to cap nicotine content in cigarettes at 0.7 mg per gram. The company notes that smoking kills over 480 000 Americans annually and costs $600 billion in healthcare and productivity. (Published on August 01, 2025bytaiwannews.com.tw)</description></item><item><title>Altria Beats Quarterly Estimates on Robust Nicotine Pouch Demand</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/altria-beats-quarterly-estimates-robust-nicotine-pouch-demand-2025-07-30/#:~:text=Gifford%20said%2C%20adding%20wholesalers%20had,reported%20supply%20shortages</link><description>Reuters reports that strong demand for Altria’s on! nicotine pouches drove shipments up 26.5%, offsetting a 10.2% drop in cigarette volumes. Revenue rose 1.2% and profits exceeded expectations. CEO William Gifford noted that increased seizures of illicit disposable vapes have limited imports but provide only slight benefit to the company (Published on August 01, 2025byreuters.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine Bans Are Tired "Nanny State" Politics</title><link>https://commonwealthbeacon.org/opinion/nicotine-bans-are-tired-nanny-state-politics/#:~:text=MASSACHUSETTS%20LAWMAKERS%20are%20again%20trying,%E2%80%9D</link><description>In an era where transparency, government accountability and personal freedoms are in peril every day, it is rather stunning that state legislators want to impose bans on tobacco and nicotine products that will forever prohibit anyone born after January 1, 2006, from being able to purchase legal adult products. (Published on August 01, 2025bycommonwealthbeacon.org)</description></item><item><title>Flavor Bans Linked to Drop in E-Cigarette Use but May Slow Decline in Smoking</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250730/Flavor-bans-linked-to-drop-in-e-cigarette-use-but-may-slow-decline-in-smoking.aspx#:~:text=A%20new%20study%20by%20investigators,to%20states%20that%20did%20not.</link><description>A new study by investigators from Mass General Brigham examined the effects of policies banning flavored e-cigarettes on adults and young people. Investigators found that e-cigarette use significantly declined among young adults and adults in states that had enacted flavor bans relative to states that did not. (Published on August 01, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco Lobby Keen for Government to Regulate New Golden Goose</title><link>https://www.irishtimes.com/business/2025/07/31/tobacco-lobby-keen-for-government-to-regulate-new-golden-goose/#:~:text=The%20tobacco%20industry%20is%20continuing,alternative%20products</link><description>The tobacco industry is continuing its streak of pushing the Government to increase regulation and taxation on its new golden goose: smoking-alternative products. British American Tobacco (Bat) is warning the Government that the State’s illicit vape trade will thrive unless the excise tax on vapes is urgently rolled out alongside “strong enforcement measures”. (Published on August 01, 2025byirishtimes.com)</description></item><item><title>State E-Cig Flavor Bans Show Mixed Impact on Tobacco Use</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/state-e-cig-flavor-bans-show-mixed-impact-on-1506229/#:~:text=State%20E,Mixed%20Impact%20on%20Tobacco%20Use</link><description>A new study by investigators from Mass General Brigham examined the effects of policies banning flavored e-cigarettes on adults and young people. Investigators found that e-cigarette use significantly declined among young adults and adults in states that had enacted flavor bans relative to states that did not. However, declines in cigarette smoking also slowed in those states with flavor bans relative to other states—a potential unintended consequence of the bans. (Published on August 01, 2025bymiragenews.com)</description></item></channel></rss>