<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:18:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Grassroots Harm Reduction Sidelined in NY Opioid Fund Spending</title><link>https://filtermag.org/new-york-opioid-funds-harm-reduction/</link><description>Alexis Pleus shared how her son's opioid addiction journey began with a knee injury and prescribed medication, leading to addiction and tragic consequences. She founded Truth Pharm for harm reduction advocacy after losing her sons to overdose. Despite effective community outreach, small organizations like hers lack funding, with major portions going to large hospitals. New York's $3 billion Opioid Settlement Fund mostly supports big institutions, sidelining local groups. The Drug Policy Alliance calls for equitable distribution to combat overdose fatalities, highlighting discriminations faced by those with substance use disorders. Pleus emphasizes the vital role of grassroots groups in filling gaps left by larger systems. (Published on November 14, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Hostile WHO | Exclusionary Tactics Threaten Tobacco Harm Reduction | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/hostile-who-exclusionary-tactics-threaten-tobacco-harm-reduction-regwatch/</link><description>As the WHO’s Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) prepares for COP11 in Geneva, its track record of silencing dissent and bending evidence to demonize safer nicotine products stands exposed. Through tortured data, selective science, and an absolutist anti-nicotine agenda bankrolled by billionaire donors, the FCTC has shifted from a treaty against smoking to a template for exclusionary global health governance—one that ignores evidence, excludes dissenting experts, and punishes nations that embrace harm reduction. Joining RegWatch to dissect this threat is Dr. Roger Bate, PhD economist, international health policy researcher, and nonresident scholar at the International Center for Law and Economics. Dr. Bate explains how WHO’s hostility to market-driven alternatives isn’t just misguided—it’s dangerous. (Published on November 14, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>WHO position on harm reduction : enough is enough</title><link>https://profetter.substack.com/p/who-position-on-harm-reduction-enough</link><description>The WHO recently released a paper on tobacco control and harm reduction before the FCTC COP-11. It discusses harm reduction in tobacco and nicotine products, refuting claims that non-combustible products are as harmful as cigarettes and criticizing the WHO's stance on harm reduction as aligned with the tobacco industry. The document calls for prohibition and restrictive measures against these products, ignoring their potential role in reducing harm from smoking. These recommendations may inadvertently protect the cigarette market, contradicting the WHO's objectives. It emphasizes the need for a balanced approach to tobacco control. (Published on November 14, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item></channel></rss>