<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 00:57:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Texas law banning marketing, sale of certain e-cigarette products takes effect</title><link>https://thedailytexan.com/2025/09/07/texas-law-banning-marketing-sale-of-certain-e-cigarette-products-takes-effect/</link><description>Texas now prohibits the marketing and sale of most disposable e-cigarette products, including THC vapes, under Senate Bill 2024, effective from Sept. 1. The law targets products designed to appeal to minors and those produced in certain countries. Despite concerns about impacting businesses like The Glassmith, some individuals like Andrés Valdez rely on THC and vapes for medical reasons. Critics, including Tyler Varisco, question the ban's effectiveness in managing substance use. Meanwhile, students like Matthew Handojo highlight the potential risks of obtaining vapes from unregulated sources. (Published on September 08, 2025bythedailytexan.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping is hooking a new generation of Irish people on nicotine, Lancet study suggests</title><link>https://www.thejournal.ie/vaping-ireland-e-cigarettes-young-people-6807263-Sep2025/</link><description>A recent study in The Lancet reveals a rise in e-cigarette use among Irish people, particularly the youth, without a strong link to quitting smoking. Although some evidence suggests that e-cigarettes may assist in smoking cessation, concerns about health risks and a new generation getting hooked on nicotine are growing. The research calls for urgent action to curb vaping, especially among young people. Despite declining smoking rates in Ireland, the use of nicotine products, including e-cigarettes, has surged. The study, based on data from the Healthy Ireland survey, warns of a significant public health issue and emphasizes the need for stricter regulations on vaping. (Published on September 08, 2025bythejournal.ie)</description></item><item><title>Smoking and Vaping in People With Substance Use Disorders</title><link>https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/addiction-outlook/202509/smoking-and-vaping-in-people-with-substance-use-disorders</link><description>Quitting smoking significantly boosts recovery from substance use disorders (SUDs), with odds rising up to 42 times. The importance of addressing smoking in addiction treatment is emphasized by experts like Dr. Volkow and Dr. Compton. Historical views linking quitting smoking with hindering recovery are debunked by studies showing no negative impact on SUD outcomes. Treatments like nicotine replacement therapy and medications are recommended. Vaping's role in SUD recovery is uncertain but reducing nicotine intake is advised. Smoking cessation, including vaping, is crucial for SUD patients' health and healing, as all addictive substances impact recovery pathways in the brain. Prioritizing smoking cessation in addiction treatment is vital for positive outcomes. (Published on September 08, 2025bypsychologytoday.com)</description></item><item><title>MRECA calls for inclusive consultation on vape regulations</title><link>https://thesun.my/business-news/mreca-calls-for-inclusive-consultation-on-vape-regulations-II14853865</link><description>The Malaysia Retail Electronic Cigarette Association criticizes the Health Parliament Special Select Committee's biased report recommending a complete e-cigarette ban without input from stakeholders. MRECA stresses the importance of consulting industry members, including manufacturers and consumers, before making allegations. They advocate for transparent regulations based on evidence and call for fair consultation processes to prevent biased recommendations. MRECA emphasizes the need for comprehensive reviews based on factual data to avoid unjustly targeting the vape industry. Adzwan Ab Manas urges inclusive decision-making to maintain credibility and ensure industry involvement in public health solutions. (Published on September 08, 2025bythesun.my)</description></item><item><title>Exclusive: US FDA to fast-track nicotine pouch reviews amid White House pressure</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/sustainability/boards-policy-regulation/us-fda-fast-track-nicotine-pouch-reviews-amid-white-house-pressure-2025-09-08/</link><description>The U.S. FDA will launch a pilot program to fast-track reviews of nicotine pouches from four major tobacco companies — Philip Morris International, Altria, Reynolds American, and Turning Point Brands. The goal is to complete assessments by December, a significant acceleration compared to the years-long approval process seen in the past. Products like PMI’s new Zyn Ultra are awaiting clearance, while FDA authorization would also legitimize items already on the market and reduce enforcement risks. (Published on September 08, 2025byreuters.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #70 | EXTREME BURDEN | Nicotine Control Threatens Canada’s Progress</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-70/</link><description>Canada’s war on nicotine has reached an extreme burden. With a 124% tax hike, sweeping flavor bans, and a “nicotine control” agenda, millions of adult vapers are in danger of being pushed back to smoking. Shot on location at GFN 2025 in Warsaw, Sam Tam, president of the Canadian Vaping Association, warns that misguided policies are destroying small businesses, fueling the black market, and undermining Canada’s smoke-free future. (Published on September 08, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>