<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 12:25:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>When It Comes to Tobacco Harm Reduction, the AMA Can’t See the Forest for the Trees</title><link>https://www.rstreet.org/commentary/when-it-comes-to-tobacco-harm-reduction-the-ama-cant-see-the-forest-for-the-trees/</link><description>The AMA article raises concerns about youth vaping, overlooking e-cigarettes' harm reduction potential for adult smokers. The text emphasizes risks for adolescents but fails to acknowledge studies supporting vaping as an effective cessation tool. While advocating for measures to prevent underage use, it notes potential negative impacts on adults, like flavor bans hindering smoking cessation. The article misses a balanced discussion on harm reduction, urging for a more nuanced approach by supporting adult access to safer alternatives and evidence-backed cessation strategies. Emphasizing comprehensive public health messaging is crucial to differentiate between youth and adult vaping and promote reduced-risk options for smokers. (Published on June 04, 2025byrstreet.org)</description></item><item><title>Scientific and public health experts support consumer position on tobacco taxation</title><link>https://ethra.co/news/171-scientific-and-public-health-experts-support-consumer-position-on-tobacco-taxation</link><description>Scientists and public health experts advocate for EU tax policies supporting safer alternatives to smoking, like nicotine products, to reduce harm. Concerns were raised over potential tax hikes on these products. ETHRA, representing millions of European consumers, refuted claims that vaping is as harmful as smoking. Inaccurate information from EU policymakers was criticized. Increasing prices of safer alternatives could hinder efforts to make Europe tobacco-free by 2040. Commissioner Hoekstra's comments on vaping were disputed. Science, not misinformation, should shape tobacco policies. Expert-backed concerns were outlined in a letter to the EU Commission. (Published on June 04, 2025byethra.co)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #155 | THAI THR ADVOCATES FIGHT BACK AGAINST VAPE BAN | Featuring Asa Saligupta</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-155/</link><description>For 11 years Thailand has enforced a strict prohibition of vapes, with the resulting crackdown allegedly pushing vapers towards the black market. But advocates have created a strong community opposed to this ban, emphasising the right of people who smoke to quit using safer nicotine products. To examine the intricacies of Thailand's vape ban, we're joined today by Asa Saligupta, a leading Thai vaping advocate. (Published on June 04, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>'We need less research, better research, and research done for the right reasons…'</title><link>https://www.bps.org.uk/psychologist/we-need-less-research-better-research-and-research-done-right-reasons</link><description>Doug Altman emphasized the need for more valuable and purpose-driven research in various disciplines. Academia faces challenges with overwhelming publications and underpowered studies, leading to a lack of quality and significance in research outcomes. Researchers should focus on conducting fewer, better-designed studies addressing important questions. Academic culture should shift towards prioritizing impactful research over quantity. Self-correction and admitting when further research is futile are crucial to advancing knowledge effectively. Academics must collectively drive change in the system, emphasizing meaningful contributions over publication volume. Prioritizing quality and purpose in research can lead to a more fulfilling academic career. (Published on June 04, 2025bybps.org.uk)</description></item><item><title>Smoking Cessation: Overview of Pharmacological and Non-Pharmacological Treatment Options</title><link>https://www.imt.ie/features-opinion/smoking-cessation-overview-of-pharmacological-and-non-pharmacological-treatment-options-04-06-2025/</link><description>Smoking is a major health issue among young adult men in Ireland, with high prevalence rates leading to preventable diseases and mortality. Despite a decline, smoking remains more common among men, particularly aged 25-34. Men face barriers to quitting like perceived invulnerability and social influences. Smoking increases risks of cancer, cardiovascular disease, respiratory conditions, and reproductive issues. Pharmacological options like NRT, varenicline, bupropion, and cytisine are effective, with NRT available through the HSE. Behavioral interventions and support, such as counseling and digital tools, are crucial for cessation success. Combining pharmacological and behavioral support improves quitting rates. A comprehensive approach tailored to young men is essential for successful smoking cessation in Ireland. (Published on June 04, 2025byimt.ie)</description></item><item><title>New Technology for Nicotine Pouches May Improve Oral Health</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/06/03/new-technology-for-nicotine-pouches-may-improve-oral-health/</link><description>A study conducted by researchers from various countries, including Sweden and the UK, found that switching to a new, gum-protective technology in nicotine pouches can reverse damage to the gums and oral lining. Twenty-three Swedish dentists switched to using these pouches for five weeks, resulting in a decrease in snus-related lesions by 52% and the elimination of gingivitis. The study highlights the potential for technological innovation to reduce the harm of nicotine products and assist smokers in quitting, promoting public health. Prof. Riccardo Polosa of CoEHAR emphasizes the importance of developing safer alternatives for tobacco harm reduction. (Published on June 05, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>World Vapers’ Alliance Academy 2025</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/academy/</link><description>The World Vapers’ Alliance (WVA) has announced the return of its Academy in 2025. Scheduled to take place on June 18th at 16:00 local time, ahead of the Global Forum on Nicotine in Warsaw, Poland, the initiative aims to bring together vaping advocates from around the world. Participants will have the opportunity to develop advocacy skills, connect with peers, and engage in discussions on tobacco harm reduction and related policy issues. More information is available on theWVA website. (Published on June 03, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Utah Proposes New E-Cigarette Regulations and Taxes</title><link>https://www.thr101.org/post/utah-proposes-new-e-cigarette-regulations-and-taxes</link><description>Utah lawmakers propose an 86.5% tax on e-cigarettes to deter youth use, but experts argue this might harm public health benefits and small businesses. E-cigarettes are considered safer than traditional cigarettes by various health groups. Imposing such a tax could lead to significant financial losses for Utah's vape shops and increase online sales. Data shows youth vaping isn't a widespread issue, and the e-cigarette industry actively supports preventing underage sales. Instead of heavy taxation, policymakers should focus on youth prevention efforts and allocate tax revenues to tobacco cessation programs, not the general fund. (Published on June 05, 2025bythr101.org)</description></item></channel></rss>