<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 12:28:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>It’s Not Big Tobacco, But Big Pharma That’s Behind Vape Ban Push</title><link>https://www.scoop.my/podaboom/266743/its-not-big-tobacco-but-big-pharma-behind-vape-ban-push-industry-leader</link><description>The push for a nationwide vape ban is allegedly being fuelled by pharmaceutical companies, claims the president of the Malaysian Organisation of Vape Entity (Move), Samsul Kamal Ariffin. (Published on August 06, 2025byscoop.my)</description></item><item><title>Experts Urge South Korea’s Government to Raise Cigarette Prices</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/08/05/experts-urge-south-koreas-government-to-raise-cigarette-prices</link><description>Anti-smoking experts are calling on South Korea’s new government to double cigarette prices and strengthen tobacco regulations to curb smoking rates and protect public health. In a new report, Professor Cho Hong-joon of Ulsan University and Lee Sung-kyu of the Korea Tobacco Control Research Education Center outlined seven key policy recommendations, including raising (...) (Published on August 06, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>UN Treaty Must Ban Cigarette Filters – Global Health and Environmental Groups Urge Action</title><link>https://ash.org/un-treaty-must-ban-cigarette-filters-global-health-and-environmental-groups-urge-action</link><description>Starting today, governments from around the world are meeting in Geneva for the final round of negotiations for a new international treaty to tackle plastic pollution. Among the sources of plastic pollution under discussion, cigarette butts are a major but often overlooked and very toxic contributor. (Published on August 06, 2025byash.org)</description></item><item><title>Smoke-Free Products Behind the Counter: Lessons from Pharmacist-Only Access in Canada and Australia</title><link>https://www.ginn.global/smoke-free-products-behind-the-counter-lessons-from-pharmacist-only-access-in-canada-and-australia</link><description>In late July 2025, a national association of Canadian pharmacists firmly rejected proposals to expand nicotine pouch availability beyond pharmacy walls. A government order from the previous year requires that these pouches be sold only behind the counter of licensed pharmacies. Pharmacists oppose relaxing that restriction, arguing that the products require professional oversight and age verification and should not be stocked in general retail stores. (Published on August 06, 2025byginn.global)</description></item><item><title>Court Strikes Down FDA Civil‑Money‑Penalty Provision for Tobacco Products</title><link>https://www.thefdalawblog.com/2025/08/federal-court-declares-fdas-civil-monetary-penalty-provisions-for-tobacco-products-unconstitutional</link><description>FDA Law Blog explained that a U.S. District Court found the Food and Drug Administration’s civil‑penalty process unconstitutional because it allows the agency to impose fines without a jury trial. (Published on August 06, 2025bythefdalawblog.com)</description></item></channel></rss>