<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 04:25:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EL CHIDIAC: Why does Canada follow UN guidelines in its war on smokers?</title><link>https://www.westernstandard.news/opinion/el-chidiac-why-does-canada-follow-un-guidelines-in-its-war-on-smokers/64883</link><description>Most Canadians are unaware of the WHO’s Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC), despite Canada signing and ratifying it 20 years ago. The treaty, adopted by 182 countries, influences smoking and harm reduction policies worldwide. In Canada, critics argue that FCTC’s strict regulations have led to a rigid, anti-harm-reduction stance that may be harming smokers seeking to quit. (Published on May 25, 2025bywesternstandard.news)</description></item><item><title>Disposable vapes ban: Why people are stockpiling ahead of June deadline</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvgvw2ydg33o</link><description>Vapers are panic-buying disposable vapes before a UK ban on June 1, stocking up on their favorite flavors. The ban aims to reduce environmental impact and youth vaping. Concerns arise over the transition to rechargeable vapes, impacting ex-smokers like Baroness Fox. Retailers worry about losing customers to cigarettes post-ban. A poll reveals vapers' intentions post-ban, with some planning to stockpile or go back to smoking. Small businesses, heavily reliant on disposable vapes, fear losses. Despite regulations, vapers question the ban's effectiveness and accessibility of alternatives. (Published on May 26, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>E-Cigarettes Reinforce Nicotine Addiction, Study Says</title><link>https://www.usnews.com/news/health-news/articles/2025-05-23/e-cigarettes-reinforce-nicotine-addiction-study-says</link><description>A lab study found pod-style e-cigarettes to be more addictive than nicotine gum, posing challenges for vapers trying to quit. E-cigarettes better reduced cravings and withdrawal symptoms compared to gum, making users more satisfied. Researchers note e-cigarettes' potential to addict youth and young adults unfamiliar with nicotine due to their appealing design, flavors, and discreet use. Nicotine salts in e-cigarettes provide a smoother experience than traditional cigarettes. The study, published in Nicotine and Tobacco Research, suggests that pod-style e-cigarettes reinforce addiction more than nicotine gum, especially among young users. (Published on May 26, 2025byusnews.com)</description></item><item><title>70% of Hongkongers under 25 have tried e-cigarettes: university poll</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/news/hong-kong/health-environment/article/3311549/70-hongkongers-under-25-experimented-e-cigarettes-university-poll</link><description>A university study in Hong Kong found that almost 70% of under 25-year-olds have tried e-cigarettes, with 60% citing peer pressure. Another study showed over a third of regular smokers support plain cigarette packaging, planned by 2027. The government proposed 10 tobacco control measures in June last year, including banning flavoured cigarettes and alternative smoking products. Associate Professor Eva Ho Ka-yan expressed concerns about teenagers being misled by online promotions, making them think e-cigarettes are harmless. The accessibility of such products in clubs, bars, and online tutorials was highlighted. A research program engaged 2,000 individuals and assisted 2,500 in smoking cessation inquiries. (Published on May 26, 2025byscmp.com)</description></item></channel></rss>