<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:26:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>As illicit tobacco sales rise into the billions, economist Arthur Laffer puts blame on high tobacco taxation rate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-14/illegal-tobacco-sales-billions-arthur-laffer-critiques-australia/105873994</link><description>Internal tobacco industry data suggest that illicit tobacco now accounts for 64% of all tobacco and 82% of total nicotine consumed in Australia. As of September, the black market is estimated to be worth nearly $10 billion. This surge in illegal tobacco use has caused federal tobacco excise revenue to plummet—from over $16 billion in 2020 to $7.4 billion in 2025—with further declines expected. In addition, the federal tobacco excise increased by another 5% last month, on top of regular indexation. (Published on October 15, 2025byabc.net.au)</description></item><item><title>Government Consultation Amid UK Plan to Treat Vape Shops as “Unwanted”</title><link>https://filtermag.org/vapes-uk-consultation-shops-nimby/</link><description>The UK government seeks expert input on achieving smoke-free status by 2030, with a focus on the Tobacco and Vapes Bill limiting smoking and imposing regulations on retailers. Concerns arise over potential impact on harm reduction access and the balance between youth protection and vape usability. Critics question if evidence contradicts government intentions while a licensing scheme aims to prevent rogue retailers. Debate surrounds potential effects on responsible retailers and concerns that limitation of vape shops could harm public health. Calls for evidence also raise worries about the government's stance on harm reduction. The "Pride in Place" program allows communities to restrict vape shops, sparking concerns over potential stigma. (Published on October 15, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Africa: Nicotine Isn't the Enemy - World Expert Corrects a Century of Misconception</title><link>https://allafrica.com/stories/202510150380.html</link><description>Misinformation about nicotine causing cancer persists among the public and medical professionals, as highlighted by Professor David Khayat in a Rutgers-led study. Despite decades of using nicotine replacement therapy for smoking cessation, misconceptions remain. Khayat emphasizes lifestyle factors like diet and exposure to carcinogens in the prevalence of cancer. He advocates for oncologists to educate on Tobacco Harm Reduction, emphasizing tobacco's significant role in cancer mortality. The economic burden of tobacco-related cancers in Africa is a growing concern due to rising smoking rates. Khayat urges proactive measures to prevent a looming cancer epidemic on the continent. (Published on October 15, 2025byallafrica.com)</description></item><item><title>The pros and cons of Prop. 310 banning flavored nicotine products in Denver (Letters)</title><link>https://www.denverpost.com/2025/10/15/prop-310-ban-flavored-nicotine-products-denver-vape-shops/</link><description>Denver small businesses oppose billionaire funding to maintain a flavored tobacco ban. Referendum 310 gives voters the chance to decide on flavored vape sales to adults, protecting local revenue and businesses. On the other hand, supporters of the ban argue for health reasons due to nicotine's addictiveness. Meanwhile, Lakewood faces zoning conflicts over residential density changes. Proponents seek affordability and vibrancy, while others fear losing open space and trees. The impact on infrastructure and existing homeowners is a concern. The decision could shape the city's future. (Published on October 15, 2025bydenverpost.com)</description></item><item><title>EXCLUSIVE: EU to launch review of EU Tobacco Control law next year</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/exclusive-eu-to-launch-review-of-eu-tobacco-control-law-next-year/</link><description>The European Commission will release an evaluation report on the EU's Tobacco Control policy, focusing on the Tobacco Products Directive from 2016, regulating vaping and heated tobacco. The Tobacco Advertising Directive will also be part of the review. Commissioner Oliver Varheyli, criticized for misinformation about safer nicotine products, oversees the evaluation despite controversy. The report initiates the process to amend EU tobacco rules, leading to new proposals and consultations by 2027. EU countries and the European Parliament will need to agree on any changes, following disagreements such as rejecting a public vaping ban. (Published on October 15, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>The FDA’s plan to fast-track nicotine pouches is long overdue. But why aren’t vapes included?</title><link>https://reason.org/commentary/the-fdas-plan-to-fast-track-nicotine-pouches-is-long-overdue-but-why-arent-vapes-included/</link><description>The FDA initiated a pilot program to speed up the approval of nicotine pouches. The move is welcomed by advocates who criticize the agency's slow approval process that favored traditional cigarettes over safer alternatives like e-cigarettes. Legacy tobacco firms have benefited from exemptions that hinder newcomers. The flawed process led to the dominance of Big Tobacco in the e-cigarette market, causing harm to smaller companies like Juul. Expanding the program to include e-cigarettes is crucial to provide smokers with safer options and combat the illicit market. The accelerated pathway is a step towards rectifying regulatory failures and improving public health. (Published on October 15, 2025byreason.org)</description></item></channel></rss>