<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 01:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Smoke-free alternatives could help cut smoking deaths in South Africa, say industry players</title><link>https://iol.co.za/business-report/companies/2025-10-13-smoke-free-alternatives-could-help-cut-smoking-deaths-in-south-africa-say-industry-players/</link><description>Industry representatives say that expanding access to smoke-free products could help South Africa reduce smoking-related deaths as the government finalises new tobacco legislation. However, the high cost of such alternatives remains a major concern. South Africa has over 8.6 million smokers, and smoking causes around 32,000 deaths each year, according to Tobacco Control Data. Companies like Philip Morris International (PMI) argue that smoke-free products such as nicotine pouches could play a crucial role in cutting smoking-related deaths. (Published on October 21, 2025byiol.co.za)</description></item><item><title>EXCLUSIVE: Belgian Deputy Prime Minister to host public anti-nicotine seminar during COP 11</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/exclusive-belgian-deputy-prime-minister-to-host-public-anti-nicotine-seminar-during-cop-11/</link><description>Belgium's ex-Health Minister Franck Vandenbroucke will lead a seminar on vaping at the WHO conference in November. He criticizes vaping as dangerous and aims to eliminate it globally. Despite strict tobacco controls in Belgium, smoking rates stagnate at 21%, with new bans on nicotine pouches and disposable vapes creating a thriving black market. Vandenbroucke plans to involve ministers worldwide in the seminar, but the public's role remains unclear. Efforts to reduce smoking without new policies have proven ineffective, with reports of ongoing sales of banned products in Belgium. (Published on October 21, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Editorial: We must admit the risks of vaping and take action</title><link>https://www.timescolonist.com/opinion/editorial-we-must-admit-the-risks-of-vaping-and-take-action-11358664</link><description>Attorney General Niki Sharma says the vaping industry is misleading young people through its advertising and packaging. British Columbia has already won a $3.6 billion settlement from tobacco companies over 18 years and now plans similar legal action against vaping firms. The structure of the lawsuit and the health-care costs linked to vaping are still being determined. While manufacturers claim vaping helps smokers quit tobacco, Sharma argues that because e-cigarettes contain addictive nicotine, they merely replace one harmful habit with another. (Published on October 21, 2025bytimescolonist.com)</description></item><item><title>Warns of WHO's plans: "Unelected bureaucrats control Swedish nicotine policy"</title><link>https://www.vejpkollen.se/en/2025/10/varnar-for-whos-planer-icke-folkvalda-byrakrater-styr-svensk-nikotinpolitik/</link><description>WHO is considering stricter regulations on nicotine products, with the Swedish Parliament defending their harm reduction approach. Tobias Andersson emphasizes the importance of Sweden standing up for its policies. Concerns arise as EU and WHO propose measures against e-cigarettes and snus. Andersson advocates for extending Sweden's model internationally. Elisabeth Lann highlights Sweden's low tobacco-related mortality. Transparency issues are raised regarding the upcoming WHO meeting. The debate focuses on harm reduction benefits of snus compared to smoking. The Minister of Health stresses the milder effects of snus. Questions remain on Sweden's stance at the COP11 meeting. The need for clarity on influencing WHO decisions is emphasized. (Published on October 21, 2025byvejpkollen.se)</description></item><item><title>Ireland Is Failing at Smoking Cessation. Now It Will Tax Vapes Hard.</title><link>https://filtermag.org/ireland-high-vape-tax/</link><description>Ireland will implement a tax of €0.50 per milliliter on all vaping e-liquids, becoming the highest in the EU. The government aims to further restrict vape products and flavors, despite missing smoke-free targets. Advocates argue that high vape taxes hinder smoking cessation efforts, especially as vapes were aiding in reducing smoking rates. The tax is viewed as counterproductive, disproportionately affecting low-income individuals and leading to a potential rise in smoking and black-market product use. While the government cites youth protection and reducing accessibility, critics believe it penalizes smokers trying to quit. The tax contradicts evidence showing affordable vape access aids in smoking cessation. (Published on October 21, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>A science-based product regulation: the time has come to reduce toxic emissions to reduce harm</title><link>https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/public-health/articles/10.3389/fpubh.2025.1687986/full</link><description>The focus on tobacco control has been on reducing usage rather than regulating product toxicity. Implementing FCTC's Articles 9 and 10 to lower toxic emissions has been delayed, highlighting the need for setting emission thresholds for toxicants. A shift towards a science-based regulatory approach, targeting priority toxicants, can accelerate harm reduction for the 1 billion smokers worldwide. The upcoming 11th FCTC Conference of the Parties in 2025 offers an opportunity to develop a toxicity reduction strategy. A dynamic, evidence-based regulatory framework, similar to other sectors, can enhance public health by categorizing products based on emission benchmarks and promoting harmful product awareness through clear labeling. (Published on October 21, 2025byfrontiersin.org)</description></item></channel></rss>