<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:57:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why a tax-hike on e-cigarettes is prompting vapers to bulk buy</title><link>https://www.rte.ie/radio/radio1/clips/22554885/</link><description>Interview with Mark Murphy (Senior Policy Manager with the Irish Heart Foundation) and Dr Garrett McGovern (Medical Director and Addiction Specialist at the Priority Medical Clinic) on RTÉ Radio — discussing the recent major tax hike on e-cigarettes in Ireland and its public health implications. (Published on October 27, 2025byrte.ie)</description></item><item><title>Vaping reaches alarming levels among Cyprus teens</title><link>https://knews.kathimerini.com.cy/en/news/vaping-reaches-alarming-levels-among-cyprus-teens</link><description>Cyprus teens are vaping heavily with 11% of 16-year-olds using e-cigarettes daily, marking one of Europe's highest rates. Cannabis remains the top illegal substance, while cocaine is on the rise, and offline gambling is popular. Alcohol use has slightly decreased, especially among boys, but binge drinking is up among girls. The survey also reveals that students find it easy to access cannabis and highlights the prevalence of hookah smoking. The study, conducted by the Cyprus Addiction Treatment Authority, KENTHEA, and the Ministry of Education, monitors youth behaviors since 1995, shedding light on evolving trends and concerns. (Published on October 27, 2025bykathimerini.com.cy)</description></item><item><title>Over 1,200 health leaders call for swift passage of UK tobacco and vapes bill</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/27/uk-tobacco-and-vapes-bill-experts-letter</link><description>Over 1,200 health leaders urge swift passage of the tobacco and vapes bill in the UK parliament to protect future generations. The bill aims to ban tobacco sales to those born after 2009 and regulate e-cigarette packaging and marketing. Advocates emphasize the urgency of the legislation in preventing deadly addictions and saving lives. Tobacco groups oppose the bill, seeking support to weaken it. Various proposals, including delaying a ban on heated tobacco, have sparked controversy. Survey results show public support for alternative approaches to tobacco sales, such as maintaining the legal age at 18 or raising it to 21. (Published on October 27, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #75 | EMINENCE-BASED | How Misinformation About Nicotine Took Hold</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-75/</link><description>Public health’s war on nicotine has spiraled into hysteria—untethered from science and reason. In this hard-hitting GFN Interviews, addiction specialist Dr. Garrett McGovern exposes how ideology, fear, and institutional ego are driving the misinformation crisis around vaping and safer nicotine products—and why it’s time to bring smoking harms back to the center of the debate. (Published on October 27, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Denver’s Flavor Ban a Poor Solution Looking for a Problem</title><link>https://i2i.org/denvers-flavor-ban-a-poor-solution-looking-for-a-problem/</link><description>Denver voters face Referendum 310, deciding on a ban on flavored nicotine products. Proponents aim to curb youth access, but opponents argue it's unnecessary due to declining underage vaping rates. The ban overlooks harm-reducing alternatives like e-cigarettes and nicotine pouches. Similar bans in other places led to revenue loss and thriving black markets. Advocates suggest focusing on education and enforcement, not prohibition. The ban could push consumers to neighboring areas, causing economic losses. Critics warn of repeating past policy failures and urge for a balanced approach. Ultimately, the ban might do more harm than good, impacting public health, freedom, and the economy. (Published on October 27, 2025byi2i.org)</description></item><item><title>Over a thousand profiles offer drugs on social media</title><link>https://cphpost.dk/2025-10-27/news/round-up/over-a-thousand-profiles-offer-drugs-on-social-media/</link><description>A study by Analyse &amp; Tal for netstof.dk found 1,341 profiles on Snapchat, TikTok, and Reddit selling illegal nicotine products and drugs such as cannabis and cocaine. This sale is accompanied by effective communication strategies, with young people encountering attractive ads and profiles selling puff bars and drugs. Snapchat claims to monitor and remove such accounts, while Reddit and TikTok have not responded. (Published on October 27, 2025bycphpost.dk)</description></item></channel></rss>