<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:56:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What New York’s Cigarette Litter Says About Tobacco Control</title><link>https://filtermag.org/new-york-cigarette-packs-tobacco-control/</link><description>New York City faces a high rate of cigarette tax evasion due to exorbitant prices, leading to a thriving illicit market. The study found a decline in packs with official tax stamps, leading to concerns about the impact of high tobacco taxes on smokers. While smoking rates have decreased, experts debate whether it's due to taxes or the rise of safer nicotine products like vapes. Strategies to combat the illegal cigarette trade, including a track-and-trace system, are discussed. However, punitive measures like those on flavored vapes might drive consumers back to more harmful options, highlighting the need for harm reduction approaches. (Published on September 10, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids Decries Supposed Fast-Tracking of Safer Alternatives to Cigarettes But Says Nothing About FDA's Inaction on Real Cigarettes</title><link>https://tobaccoanalysis.blogspot.com/2025/09/campaign-for-tobacco-free-kids-decries.html</link><description>According to Reuters, the FDA is preparing to accelerate the review of applications for the sale of nicotine pouches. These products are considered far less harmful than traditional cigarettes, as they contain no tobacco, require no combustion, and do not involve inhalation.  [...] The FDA is being criticized for taking “shortcuts” in reviewing nicotine pouch applications, but the reality is that reviews often take years instead of the 180 days required by law — Zyn, for example, took five years. Speeding up this process is not a threat to kids’ health but a necessary step to bring safer alternatives to smokers more quickly. Meanwhile, groups like the Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids remain silent on the FDA’s continued approval of deadly cigarettes, never calling for their removal or even stricter safety standards. (Published on September 10, 2025byblogspot.com)</description></item><item><title>Spanish government moves to ban smoking on bar terraces</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/09/spanish-government-moves-ban-smoking-bar-terraces</link><description>The Spanish government approved a draft tobacco law banning smoking and vaping on bar terraces. The law prohibits minors from using vapes, single-use e-cigarettes, and other products, treating them like regular cigarettes. It extends to enclosed public spaces and outdoor areas like stadiums and educational facilities. The legislation aims to curb smoking-related cancer cases in a country where 140 people die daily from tobacco-related illnesses. While the bill doesn't yet include plain packaging or price hikes, the health ministry may push for these changes. Anti-tobacco groups advocate for plain packaging to deter smoking initiation, pointing out its success in other countries. Smoking rates in Spain stand at 28.9% for men and 22.6% for women. (Published on September 10, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Doctors and Harm Reduction: The Fight for Honest Tobacco Policy</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/09/08/doctors-and-harm-reduction-the-fight-for-honest-tobacco-policy/</link><description>Smoking remains a global public health crisis, leading to millions of preventable deaths annually. Despite the clear risks, countries often resist harm reduction strategies, but some doctors advocate for evidence-based approaches. In India, vaping products are banned, yet high smoking rates persist. In the U.S., many clinicians lack information on harm reduction, hindering progress. Europe also faces challenges with illegal vape sales to youth. Prohibition fuels black markets and misinformation, impacting public health. Doctors worldwide call for education, regulation, and safer alternatives to combat smoking effectively and shift from managing to preventing the tragic consequences of smoking. (Published on September 10, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>Marijuana may cause chromosomal defects in human egg cells, study finds</title><link>https://edition.cnn.com/2025/09/09/health/marijuana-female-fertility-study-wellness</link><description>New research suggests that higher levels of THC in marijuana may harm unfertilized eggs, potentially leading to infertility, miscarriage, and genetic defects in babies. A cautious approach to cannabis use when planning to conceive is advised. Studies show a rise in marijuana use during pregnancy, linked to negative outcomes like poor fetal development. The study highlights the impact of THC on egg maturation and chromosome formation but further research is needed. The increasing potency of THC poses risks, as consumers may not be aware of the levels in products. Experts recommend considering safer alternatives to manage symptoms. (Published on September 10, 2025bycnn.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #158 | New Taxes on Safer Nicotine Products Could Push Smokers Back to Cigarettes</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-158/</link><description>Across Europe, health experts are raising alarm over the European Commission’s plan to impose new taxes on reduced-risk nicotine products such as e‑cigarettes, heated tobacco and nicotine pouches. In this episode of GFN News on GFN.TV, Joanna Junak speaks with leading international specialists — including Fernando Bueno, Bernd Mayer, Garrett McGovern and Konstantinos Farsalinos — who explain why such taxation could have serious unintended consequences. (Published on September 10, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>