<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 04:23:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Lawsuits could choke off the candy‑flavored vape pipeline</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-05-lawsuits-candyflavored-vape-pipeline.html</link><description>A study by Rutgers Health and NYC advocates suggests using state and local lawsuits to target domestic vape distributors, focusing on regulating flavored e-cigarettes. They propose legal actions against distributors to ensure compliance with FDA regulations. The study emphasizes imposing heavy fines and legal consequences instead of imprisonment. By holding distributors financially accountable, the aim is to align vape products with legal standards and deter non-compliance. This strategy has seen progress in lawsuits filed by various states against vape distributors. The initiative aims to address the potential risks posed by unregulated, high-dose vape products entering the market. (Published on May 12, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>New nicotine product being used by Gen Z as alternative to vapes</title><link>https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/health/what-zyn-tobacco-product-gen-35159551</link><description>Gen Z faces a ban on disposable vapes in the UK but has turned to nicotine pouches as an alternative. The ban, effective June 1, targets single-use vape products to decrease litter. The rise in nicotine pouch popularity offers a new way to consume nicotine, favored by young adults. With higher nicotine content and discreet use, pouches are becoming a replacement. However, possible health risks include gastrointestinal issues and cardiovascular effects. Additionally, concerns arise over unregulated and potentially dangerous nicotine pouches being sold, posing risks, especially to youth. Restrictions and the rise of alternative products are changing young adults' nicotine consumption habits. (Published on May 12, 2025bymirror.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>No watchdog, more risk: Vape misuse soars amid regulatory void</title><link>https://www.nst.com.my/news/nation/2025/05/1214762/no-watchdog-more-risk-vape-misuse-soars-amid-regulatory-void</link><description>The lack of a regulatory body in Malaysia to oversee vape product quality has contributed to their misuse, including drug consumption. Ridhwan Rosli of the Malaysian Vape Chamber of Commerce highlighted that without proper oversight, there’s no way to ensure product safety, leading to cases where vapes are used for illicit drug use. (Published on May 12, 2025bynst.com.my)</description></item><item><title>Thailand officially bans e-cigarettes in schools, offices</title><link>https://en.vietnamplus.vn/thailand-officially-bans-e-cigarettes-in-schools-offices-post318886.vnp</link><description>Thailand's Education Ministry has prohibited e-cigarette use in schools and offices to combat youth vaping. Concerned about rising popularity due to accessibility and targeted ads, the ministry aims to protect children's health. Measures like awareness campaigns, installing no-vaping signs, and stricter supervision are implemented nationwide. (Published on May 12, 2025byvietnamplus.vn)</description></item><item><title>GFN Insights #7 | THE CHEMICAL COMPOSITION OF VAPOR | GFN SCIENCE FAQ: PART 4 | Featuring Roberto Sussman</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-insights-7/</link><description>Vaping has been shown to be 95% safer than smoking, but what do the chemistry of vapor and smoke, and the key differences between them, tell us about WHY these products are so different? Joining us again for the fourth part of our vaping science series is astrophysicist Roberto Sussman, who expertly explains the science behind vaping! (Published on May 12, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Swedish MEP Jessica Polfjärd: Europe needs more snus, not more bans</title><link>https://snusforumet.se/en/swedish-mep-jessica-polfjard-europe-needs-more-snus-not-more-bans/</link><description>Swedish MEP Jessica Polfjärd defends Sweden's low smoking rate using snus and nicotine pouches. She warns against overregulation proposed by some EU countries, advocating for safer alternatives to smoking. Polfjärd highlights Sweden's success and urges learning from their model rather than suppressing it. She emphasizes the importance of not restricting adult access to these products. Polfjärd stresses the need to prioritize public health over fear-based policies in tobacco regulations, calling for a shift in Europe's attitude towards snus. (Published on May 12, 2025bysnusforumet.se)</description></item><item><title>SPILLANE: What Prohibitionists Get Wrong About Flavors and Youth Vaping</title><link>https://nhjournal.com/spillane-what-prohibitionists-get-wrong-about-flavors-and-youth-vaping/</link><description>New Hampshire is debating measures to protect youth from smoking while aiding adult smokers. Science and real-world impact should guide decisions, considering flavored alternatives' role in quitting smoking. Bans could harm adult smokers without curbing youth access. Data from Massachusetts and the CDC show benefits of varied nicotine products, with e-cigarettes being significantly less harmful. Despite declines in youth vaping and adult smoking rates, public health groups push for prohibitions. Mental health issues drive youth vaping more than flavors. Flavors assist adults in quitting smoking, as supported by the FDA. It's crucial to acknowledge progress in reducing smoking rates and advocate for a regulated marketplace promoting harm reduction. (Published on May 12, 2025bynhjournal.com)</description></item></channel></rss>