<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 18:19:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>“Infantile” UK Plan Would Fine People Who Vape at Bus Stops</title><link>https://filtermag.org/uk-vaping-bus-stops-fine/</link><description>A proposed law in the UK may fine vapers up to £100 for using e-cigarettes at outdoor bus stops. This would expand current bans on vaping in public areas, aiming to discourage the habit. The rationale behind the law is debated, with experts arguing that passive vaping poses minimal risk. Critics fear the fine could unfairly impact low-income individuals and send negative messages about harm reduction. The focus shifts towards evidence-based solutions like education and regulation, rather than penalizing those trying to quit smoking through vaping. Opposition parties and industry representatives have voiced concerns over the potential legislation. (Published on July 29, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Unforgiving Logic | The Crusade That Forgot Its Cause | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/unforgiving-logic-the-crusade-that-forgot-its-cause-regwatch/</link><description>Tobacco control is all virtue, no restraint. And when it deploys power, it does so as if it holds absolute moral authority: unquestionable, unforgiving, and unshakably certain of its final destination. It doesn’t ask “Does this reduce harm?” In this RegWatch public statement, we expose the divide between tobacco harm reduction and the ideology driving tobacco control. Moral absolutism rooted in resentment, not science, has shaped a global war on safer nicotine products that smears vaping, discredits researchers, and marginalizes anyone who refuses to walk the path of abstinence. (Published on July 29, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>