<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 12:23:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>“Profiteering from the misery of smokers”: Five WHO anti-vape bureaucrats making more than UK PM, French President</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/profiteering-from-the-misery-of-smokers-five-who-anti-vape-bureaucrats-making-more-than-uk-pm-french-president/</link><description>Five World Health Organisation tobacco control department staff earn more than UK and French leaders, with the top earner taking home around $300,000 annually. The Secretariat requested over $8.5 million to cover 19 staff for two years, seeking an 8% pay rise. The lowest-paid earns $96,930, well above global averages. Concerns were raised about prioritizing staff salaries over supporting Low and Medium Income Countries. Contributions from the UK, EU, and others mainly cover staff costs. Critics argue that funds could be used more efficiently. The FCTC Secretariat's high salaries are criticized as prioritizing self-interest over public health. (Published on September 02, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Vaping may be causing irreversible harm to children’s health, doctors say</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/sep/01/vaping-may-be-causing-irreversible-harm-children-health-doctors</link><description>Doctors globally are highly concerned about the negative impact of vaping on children's health. They warn of irreversible harm caused by exposure to toxins and carcinogens, including unknown risks. Nicotine in e-cigarettes poses addiction and brain development hazards for adolescents, leading to cardiovascular issues. Studies show vaping increases stroke risk and releases harmful chemicals impacting the heart. Experts fear vaping may become a gateway to smoking and stress the urgent need for regulations to protect young people. Long-term effects are still unknown, but a ban on e-cigarette sales is suggested to prevent harm based on existing data and concerns. (Published on September 02, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>OP-ED: RFK Jr. is right on nicotine pouches, while Canada barrels ahead with bad policy</title><link>https://www.junonews.com/p/op-ed-rfk-jr-is-right-on-nicotine</link><description>RFK Jr. has expressed false views like WIFI causing brain damage. Despite this, he is correct about the safety of nicotine pouches, supported by Health Canada. Canada's restrictions on pouch sales are deemed counterproductive and hypocritical compared to Sweden's successful use. Embracing pouches as a cessation tool, as seen in Sweden, could significantly reduce smoking rates and related illnesses in Canada. The focus should shift to harm reduction and adopting successful strategies from other countries. (Published on September 02, 2025byjunonews.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping Is for Enjoying Nicotine, Not Just Quitting</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/prohibitionist-delusion-vaping-enjoyment-not-cessation/</link><description>A New Zealand academic misunderstands vaping, claiming it's for smoking cessation only, not pleasure. Vaping was created for safer nicotine enjoyment. Prohibitionists ignore vaping's origins, pushing abstinence and overlooking harmlessness. John Stuart Mill's harm principle supports individual choice, not authoritarianism like in Singapore. Prohibitionists' stance threatens personal freedoms and safer alternatives, aiming to infantilize adults and limit pleasure. Vaping is about enjoyment, not just quitting smoking. Prohibitionists' views could be more dangerous than vaping itself. The focus should be on individual choice and harm reduction, not imposing moral judgements. (Published on September 02, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>Dr. Ziauddin Islam: Smoke-Free Pakistan — Dream or Reality?</title><link>https://www.2firsts.com/news/exclusive-2firsts-contribution--dr-ziauddin-islam-smoke-free-pakistan--dream-or-reality</link><description>Dr. Ziauddin Islam's article discusses how Pakistan can learn from Sweden's success in becoming the first "smoke-free" nation. By adopting strict policies, harm reduction strategies, and promoting reduced-risk products, Pakistan can work towards reducing its tobacco-related deaths. Sweden's success in lowering smoking rates through evidence-based policies and harm reduction serves as a model for other countries. Pakistan faces challenges in enforcing tobacco control laws and lacks research on harm reduction products. Emulating Sweden's comprehensive approach and promoting public awareness can help Pakistan move towards a smoke-free future. Dr. Islam emphasizes the importance of determination and effective policymaking in combating the tobacco epidemic. (Published on September 02, 2025by2firsts.com)</description></item><item><title>Australia E-Cigarette Market: A Smoke-Free Future Gaining Momentum</title><link>https://vocal.media/journal/australia-e-cigarette-market-a-smoke-free-future-gaining-momentum</link><description>System could not access the page, the text article must be completed manually (Published on September 03, 2025byvocal.media)</description></item></channel></rss>