<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 01:02:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>EU Commission faces rising pressure to tax vapes and nicotine pouches</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2025/06/02/eu-commission-faces-rising-pressure-to-tax-vapes-and-nicotine-pouches</link><description>Countries such as Italy, Greece, and Romania, which have lower tax rates, oppose the proposal to increase taxes on nicotine products. Meanwhile, pressure is mounting on the EU to tax vapes and nicotine pouches. Last week, 15 finance and economy ministers urged EU Commission President Ursula von der Leyen to publish the long-delayed Tobacco Taxation Directive (TTD), arguing that the current rules are outdated and don't cover newer nicotine products like e-cigarettes and heated tobacco. The revision was initially proposed in 2022 as part of Europe's Beating Cancer Plan. (Published on June 02, 2025byeuronews.com)</description></item><item><title>MOH Confirms Nicotine Manufacturing Licence For US-Based Vape Company</title><link>https://codeblue.galencentre.org/2025/06/moh-confirms-nicotine-manufacturing-licence-for-us-based-vape-company/</link><description>The Ministry of Health (MOH) confirmed a foreign vape company received a nicotine manufacturing license from MIDA. The Act 852 regulates e-cigarette import, manufacture, and distribution. The company, Ispire Technology Inc., was granted an interim manufacturing license under MITI and MIDA. MOH emphasized Act 852's strict regulation of e-cigarette liquids and smoking products. The MOH aims to ensure public health and safety in line with Madani values. Malaysia aims to be smoke-free by 2040. Ispire manufactures cannabis vaporizers but the MOH did not address this. The MOH did not disclose if Ispire had authorization to produce cannabis-related products. (Published on June 02, 2025bygalencentre.org)</description></item><item><title>Which vapes are still legal in the UK?</title><link>https://www.lbc.co.uk/news/health/which-electronic-cigarettes-legal-uk/</link><description>Single-use vapes are now banned in the UK to reduce litter and prevent youth nicotine addiction. The government aims to promote reusable vapes for smoking cessation. Retailers faced a sudden ban, but reusable vapes with refillable containers and rechargeable batteries remain legal. Disposable vapes are prohibited, impacting users and sellers. Nicotine intake from vaping is low, with the main health concern being nicotine addiction. Cannabis edibles like gummies are illegal in the UK due to their classification as a class B drug, associated with negative side effects. (Published on June 02, 2025bylbc.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>WHO lauds South Africa for efforts in strengthening anti-tobacco laws</title><link>https://smilefm.co.za/who-lauds-south-africa-for-efforts-in-strengthening-anti-tobacco-laws/</link><description>WHO praised South Africa for enhancing anti-tobacco laws on World No-Tobacco Day. The country aims to ban tobacco and vaping advertising, regulate e-cigarettes, and combat manipulative marketing targeting youth. The Tobacco Products Control Bill addresses health risks from tobacco and e-cigarettes by banning advertising, regulating e-cigarettes, and protecting youth from predatory marketing. The bill seeks to reduce smoking and vaping among young people and challenge Big Tobacco's strategies. Its focus is on public health and ending nicotine addiction in South Africa by closing regulatory gaps and protecting the youth. (Published on June 02, 2025bysmilefm.co.za)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #65 | CRITICAL MASS | Safer Nicotine Hits Escape Velocity</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-65/</link><description>Goldman Sachs predicts safer nicotine will overtake cigarettes in the U.S. this year. Millions have already made the switch, despite tobacco control efforts, not because of it. David Sweanor breaks down the consumer-led collapse of smoking and how it likely can’t be stopped. (Published on June 02, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>