<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 18:20:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Disposable product: Federal government announces ban on disposable e-cigarettes</title><link>https://www.heise.de/en/news/Disposable-product-Federal-government-announces-ban-on-disposable-e-cigarettes-11088541.html</link><description>The German federal government is responding to pressure by considering a ban on disposable e-cigarettes due to environmental and safety concerns. The Bundesrat has passed an amendment to address the issue despite opposition. The ban aims to reduce the 60 million e-cigarettes discarded annually in Germany, which pose environmental and fire risks. The government is urged to act quickly following calls from various associations and citizens for a ban, aligning with actions taken in other European countries. The revised Electrical Equipment Act also targets better management of electronic waste and increased manufacturer responsibility. The ban on disposable e-cigarettes is seen as a long-overdue step towards protecting public health. (Published on November 25, 2025byheise.de)</description></item><item><title>VIDEO: What is really in a vape?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-24/what-is-really-in-a-vape-/106047546</link><description>High concentrations of nicotine in vapes are contributing to a wave of sleeplessness and anxiety in teenagers and young adults. (Published on November 25, 2025byabc.net.au)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #77 | TOBACCO SCORECARD | Real Progress Tobacco Control Fails to Admit</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-77-tobacco-scorecard-real-progress-tobacco-control-fails-to-admit/</link><description>Former Iowa Attorney General Tom Miller—America’s longest-serving AG and a principal architect of the Master Settlement Agreement—joins GFN.TV with a clear warning: the U.S. is making extraordinary progress against combustible tobacco, yet the public isn’t hearing about it. Smoking has collapsed to historic lows, youth vaping has fallen 70% since 2019, and millions of adults have shifted to far safer non-combustible nicotine products. By any honest measure, it’s one of the most significant public-health successes in decades. So why isn’t tobacco control talking about it? (Published on November 25, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Communications ConCOPtions</title><link>https://www.thefirebreak.org/p/communications-concoptions</link><description>The UN COP30 Climate and COP11 Tobacco Control conferences were criticized for ineffectiveness and wastefulness. COP30 focused on blaming the fossil fuel industry for lack of progress, while COP11 discussed tobacco harm reduction. Both events faced challenges and backlash from various parties. Despite ambitious aims, the UN quietly pushed through demanding climate goals. The FCTC, on the other hand, emphasized nicotine control over tobacco control. These conferences continue to face criticism for their narratives and agendas, leading to doubts about their effectiveness and impact on real-world issues. The focus seems to be more on maintaining a cycle of failures rather than achieving tangible results. (Published on November 25, 2025bythefirebreak.org)</description></item><item><title>COP11 Wrap-Up: The WHO Loses Control Over Its Prohibitionist Agenda</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/cop11-wrap-up-the-who-loses-control-over-its-prohibitionist-agenda/</link><description>The WHO held COP11, its tobacco control conference, facing pushback against strict measures targeting vaping and nicotine products. Countries like New Zealand, Albania, and Serbia advocated for harm reduction over prohibition, leading to softened regulations. The EU's internal conflict was exposed when some nations resisted global bans. COP11 ended with voluntary guidelines, signaling a rejection of the top-down model. The FCTC Secretariat postponed decisions to COP12. Despite some progress in harm reduction advocacy, transparency and consumer inclusion issues persist. Demands for evidence-based policies continue amidst a call for WHO accountability and EU negotiations scrutiny. Accelerating momentum for change is crucial at this juncture. (Published on November 25, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Are Methadone Clinics Really “Evolving” Toward Harm Reduction?</title><link>https://filtermag.org/methadone-clinics-evolving-harm-reduction/</link><description>The AATOD conference focused on evolving opioid treatment, acknowledging the need for change post-pandemic. Senator Norcross proposed altering methadone clinic regulations, but opposition persists. Clinics resist giving more take-home medication to maintain control and profits. SAMHSA's updated rules aim to increase patient retention and engagement, aligning with harm reduction principles. However, clinic systems' rigid structure challenges full harm reduction integration, emphasizing surveillance over patient autonomy. The DEA's role in clinics is questioned as the sector shifts towards patient-centered care. Despite incremental progress, the methadone industry remains resistant to fundamental changes. Efforts to align clinics with harm reduction principles face significant obstacles within the current treatment model. (Published on November 25, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Officials stunned by unintended consequence of major product ban: 'Not yet working as expected'</title><link>https://www.thecooldown.com/green-business/uk-disposable-vape-ban-black-market/</link><description>The U.K. ban on disposable vapes has led to a surge in illegal sales, with 63% of users still buying them easily. The black market trade poses challenges for regulation, as these devices are harmful to health and the environment. Concerns include plastic pollution, toxic residues, and fire hazards from lithium batteries. Authorities are cracking down on black market sellers, but more robust enforcement and education are needed to address these risks. Users can help by recycling properly, choosing refillable options, and advocating for stricter oversight. (Published on November 25, 2025bythecooldown.com)</description></item></channel></rss>