<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:53:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Look Behind the Headlines About Rising Vape-Related ER Visits</title><link>https://filtermag.org/rising-vape-related-er-visits/</link><description>A report from the Kentucky Injury Prevention and Research Center highlighted a rise in emergency department visits linked to vaping, sparking moral panic and alarming headlines. However, the increase in cases is influenced by coding changes and increased documentation, rather than solely reflecting a surge in vaping-related illnesses. Medical coding and biases play a significant role in this trend, raising questions about the accuracy of data and the need for transparent reporting. Policymakers and public health officials should carefully interpret the numbers to avoid misallocating resources and address the real health risks, such as smoking-related illnesses that remain a more significant public health concern. (Published on October 03, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Concerns Raised Over Unregulated e-Cigarettes Flooding the Market</title><link>https://nilepost.co.ug/health/292132/concerns-raised-over-unregulated-e-cigarettes-flooding-the-market</link><description>The Uganda Health Communication Alliance (UHCA) has warned that “unregulated” e-cigarettes and tobacco products are increasingly entering Uganda, posing serious public health risks. Richard Baguma, UHCA’s national coordinator, said the proliferation of these products is driven in part by weak regulatory enforcement and inadequate taxation. Speaking during a Media Orientation on Tobacco Taxation organised by UHCA, Baguma noted that some products are deliberately designed to evade detection and appeal to young people. (Published on October 03, 2025bynilepost.co.ug)</description></item><item><title>Science and Citizens Ignored as Várhelyi Pushes Harmful Vape Tax</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/science-and-citizens-ignored-as-varhelyi-pushes-harmful-vape-tax/</link><description>The World Vapers’ Alliance strongly criticizes European Health Commissioner Várhelyi's plan to equalize taxes on vaping products and cigarettes, citing a misunderstanding of harm reduction. Várhelyi's claims disregard scientific evidence showing vaping is safer than smoking. Despite an ongoing public consultation until October, the Commissioner dismisses citizen opinions prematurely, overlooking the millions benefiting from switching to vaping. Critics, including public health experts, warn that the tax plan goes against science and could push people back to smoking. They advocate for fair taxation based on actual risks, as demonstrated in countries like the UK and Sweden. The European Commission should support harm reduction instead of undermining it. (Published on October 03, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Over 60 vape shops in Perak must cease operations by Jan 1 2026</title><link>https://thesun.my/malaysia-news/over-60-vape-shops-in-perak-must-cease-operations-by-jan-12026-JG15022281</link><description>Licensed premises selling electronic cigarettes or vape in Perak must close by January 1, confirmed by State Government Committee chairman Sandrea Ng. No new licences will be issued, and existing ones will be revoked once current stock is sold. This aligns with Perak's policy to ban e-cigarette sales after the deadline. Enforcement is under local authorities, with a grace period until January for traders to adjust. The ban is set for October 1, following a proposal by the Health Department, presented at a State Executive Council meeting on September 22. The government will ensure compliance and support affected businesses in transitioning to other operations. (Published on October 03, 2025bythesun.my)</description></item><item><title>Vape advocacy group warns of potentially devastating impact of COP 11</title><link>https://www.conveniencestore.co.uk/news/vape-advocacy-group-warns-of-potentially-devastating-impact-of-cop-11/710004.article#toggle</link><description>We Vape, an advocacy group, is concerned about the upcoming COP 11 meeting in Geneva potentially impacting the vaping industry. They warn that proposed bans on vaping could harm lives and small businesses, leading to black market growth. We Vape launched a 'Back Vaping Save Lives' campaign, critiquing the WHO's potential policy decisions. They urge the public to engage with MPs to challenge these regulations. The group emphasizes the negative impacts on small businesses and public health caused by these distant policies, pushing for transparency and accountability in global decision-making processes. (Published on October 03, 2025byconveniencestore.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>GFN25 Commentary Team #4 | Australia’s Vape Prohibition Backfire | Hosted by Fiona Patten</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn25-commentary-team-4/</link><description>Australia’s vape prohibition is fueling a booming illicit market—while New Zealand’s regulated approach sees smoking rates fall faster. In this GFN 2025 conversation, Fiona Patten speaks with Rohan Pike and Asa Saligupta about what’s broken in tobacco control, what actually works in harm reduction. (Published on October 03, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>