<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 06:22:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cannabis THC vapes a 'threat to younger generation'</title><link>https://www.aol.com/articles/cannabis-thc-vapes-threat-younger-124944281.html</link><description>The rising use of cannabis vapes, containing THC, in Bradford poses a threat to youth. Despite being illegal for recreational use, these products were found on sale in the area. A recent raid discovered vapes with pure cannabis at a local off-licence. Concerns were raised about youths being hospitalized due to vaping, as they find it appealing for being odorless and discreet. Some vapes even contained Spice. Authorities discussed the issue during a licensing meeting and emphasized the dangers, including potential overdoses. A shop linked to such activities had its alcohol license revoked. Drug charity Forward Leeds warned about the risks of consuming THC through vaping. (Published on January 05, 2026byaol.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping safer than smoking – so why are people struggling to quit e-cigarettes?</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2026/jan/03/vaping-safer-than-smoking-so-why-are-people-struggling-to-quit-e-cigarettes</link><description>Vaping has surpassed smoking in the UK, with concerns rising about its addictive nature. While less harmful than smoking due to lack of combustion, vaping still poses risks, especially for young people. Quitting vaping involves addressing both physical and behavioral components of addiction, with support options such as text messages, medications, and therapy showing promise. To quit successfully, it's crucial to identify triggers, reduce gradually, set limits, consider lower nicotine products, change flavors, manage cravings, seek professional help, and build a support system. For young people, avoiding vaping altogether is advised, with understanding and tailored support essential for cessation. (Published on January 05, 2026bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Can Nicotine Pouches Help People Quit Smoking?</title><link>https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2843607</link><description>When e-cigarettes first appeared, many public health professionals saw them as a potential tool to help people who smoke transition away from combustible cigarettes to a less harmful source of nicotine. While this approach worked for some individuals, aggressive and risky marketing strategies contributed to a surge in vaping among young people. Now, a new effort from the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) suggests that the agency may be shifting its harm-reduction strategy toward another product: nicotine pouches. (Published on January 05, 2026byjamanetwork.com)</description></item><item><title>Fragmented nicotine laws leave Europe's youth vulnerable despite policy aims</title><link>https://www.brusselstimes.com/1898870/fragmented-nicotine-laws-leave-europes-youth-vulnerable-despite-policy-aims</link><description>The European Commission's Safe Hearts Plan aims to protect youth from nicotine harms. Harmonizing regulations on online sales can prevent minors' access. Different EU countries have varying rules on nicotine products, leading to price and availability differences. A ban on cross-border online sales of nicotine products is crucial to uphold tobacco policy goals, prevent illicit trade, secure tax revenues, and support compliant domestic businesses. Norway's upcoming ban sets an example for the EU to follow in the revised Tobacco Products Directive. By implementing this ban, the EU can better protect public health and prevent underage sales effectively. (Published on January 05, 2026bybrusselstimes.com)</description></item><item><title>How Much Nicotine Is in a Cigarette?</title><link>https://vaping360.com/learn/nicotine-in-a-cigarette/</link><description>Many vapers ask how much nicotine is in a cigarette to estimate the nicotine strength they need in e-liquids and replicate the sensation of smoking. However, nicotine intake from cigarettes doesn’t directly translate to vaping because the delivery methods are very different. Even similar nicotine amounts can feel stronger in cigarettes than in vapes. Since most vapers are former smokers and many smokers seek less harmful alternatives, understanding nicotine in all its forms is important. This topic may become even more relevant if the FDA successfully reduces nicotine levels in cigarettes below addictive thresholds. (Published on January 05, 2026byvaping360.com)</description></item></channel></rss>