<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jun 2025 01:08:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Something’s very wrong at Global Action to End Smoking</title><link>https://medium.com/the-great-vape-debate/somethings-very-wrong-at-global-action-to-end-smoking-c50c2e29d8bc</link><description>Global Action to End Smoking is facing turmoil, with its president Cliff Douglas laid off amid financial struggles. Renamed from the Foundation for A Smoke Free World, the organization supports tobacco harm reduction but has difficulty raising funds. The board of directors, paying themselves generously, recently made layoffs and hired a new chief development officer. Critics question the board's motives and expertise in tobacco control. The foundation, originally linked to Philip Morris, has battled reputational issues. Despite grants for research and agricultural projects, its impact is debated. Lack of advocacy and engagement in e-cigarette debates raise concerns about its effectiveness. The future role of Global Action in shaping the tobacco market remains uncertain. (Published on June 21, 2025bymedium.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine vs. combustion: Sweden’s THR blueprint for health</title><link>https://delano.lu/article/nicotine-vs-combustion-swedens-thr-blueprint-for-health</link><description>BAT aims to promote tobacco harm reduction through alternatives like vaping and heated tobacco. Fierens Gevaert advocates for informed choices, highlighting Sweden's success in reducing smoking rates using products like nicotine pouches. He emphasizes the importance of distinguishing nicotine from tobacco combustion as the main cause of smoking-related diseases. Omni, BAT's knowledge-sharing platform, seeks to address misconceptions and provide evidence for harm reduction. Fierens Gevaert suggests that adopting Sweden's approach could save lives across Europe, emphasizing the role of reduced-risk products in public health strategies. (Published on June 21, 2025bydelano.lu)</description></item><item><title>More than 2,000 disposable vapes seized in Kent after ban</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cz6gx9d6nxvo</link><description>Since the ban on disposable vapes, over 2,000 illegal products were seized from Kent shops by Trading Standards. Inspections were conducted in over 80 stores, with some not complying with the ban. Further checks will be done to enforce the ban. Violators can face fines and prison time, as the ban aims to reduce the environmental impact of disposable vapes. The seized items will be recycled, and stricter regulations now require vapes to be reusable. This clampdown follows the confiscation of over six million illegal vaping products across England in recent years. (Published on June 21, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item></channel></rss>