<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 18:18:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nicotine Consumer Advocates Share Strategies, Support Amid Hostility</title><link>https://filtermag.org/nicotine-consumer-advocates-hostility/</link><description>Consumer advocate Maria Papaionnoy-Duic emphasized the importance of collaboration between advocates and activists when promoting safer nicotine products at the Global Forum on Nicotine in Warsaw. She highlighted the need for effective communication and personal storytelling to counter misinformation and garner support. Papaionnoy-Duic and Ignacio Leiva hosted a workshop on mobilizing consumer voices and shared successful advocacy strategies, such as leveraging personal stories and engaging with lawmakers. The event also showcased THR scientists and advocates from around the world, encouraging consumers to collaborate with researchers for impactful advocacy. The key message: empower individuals, share stories, and engage with policymakers to advance tobacco harm reduction globally. (Published on June 26, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Irish premier brands vaping ‘revenge of Big Tobacco’ amid EU push for tighter regulation</title><link>https://www.euractiv.com/section/health-consumers/news/hold-wed-pm-irish-premier-brands-vaping-revenge-of-big-tobacco-amid-eu-push-for-tighter-regulation/</link><description>Speaking at the World Conference on Tobacco Control, Irish Prime Minister Micheál Martin called for stronger measures against vaping, warning that the industry is using tactics similar to those once employed by the tobacco industry to target youth. He acknowledged that Ireland had been slow to act but said new restrictions—including limits on product placement, flavours, and packaging—will take effect in February 2026. Martin emphasized growing international and national evidence on the health harms of vaping, calling it a threat to both young people and adults. (Published on June 26, 2025byeuractiv.com)</description></item><item><title>New, urgent warning about the ‘hidden risk’ of e-cigarettes and vapes issued by scientists</title><link>https://nypost.com/2025/06/25/health/urgent-warning-about-hidden-risk-of-e-cigarettes-and-vapes/</link><description>E-cigarettes were initially marketed for smoking cessation but are now widely used by both smokers and non-smokers, with over 11 million Americans vaping regularly. Recent research in the journal ACS Central Science revealed high levels of toxic metals in some e-cigarettes, raising health concerns. The study found that disposable vapes may emit more toxins than refillable ones. Manufacturers dispute the findings, citing inaccurate testing. Researchers are calling for more studies and regulations due to the growing e-cigarette market surpassing scientific knowledge. Despite restrictions on flavored e-cigarettes, enforcement remains lax, allowing new products to flood the market. (Published on June 26, 2025bynypost.com)</description></item><item><title>#GFN25 Keynote #1 | What's so scary about tobacco harm reduction?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn25-keynote-1-whats-so-scary-about-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>GFN 2025 Keynote #1 - delivered by Mark Tyndall, hosted by Paddy Costall, response from Carolyn Beaumont - titled "What's so scary about tobacco harm reduction?". Mark will explore the lessons he has learned from the harm reduction movement, not least the way stigma experienced by people who use drugs, and moral judgements about drug-taking affect policy and political decision making. Consumer advocates and tobacco harm reduction campaigners face significant challenges engaging lawmakers and public health organisations, including structural opposition to safer nicotine products. How can we convince those in power that this consumer-led public health revolution can lead to real-world change? (Published on June 26, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Misleading vape research threatens public health policy, expert review warns</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/misleading-vape-research-threatens-public-health-policy-expert-review-warns/</link><description>A 2024 meta-analysis by Glantz et al on vaping is criticized for flaws, including misclassification of diseases and reliance on weak study designs. Experts warn that such poor-quality research distorts public health policies and discourages smokers from switching to safer alternatives. The analysis's reliance on inconsistent data may overstate vaping harms, despite high-quality studies finding no serious respiratory harm in non-smokers who vape. Concerns include double-counting cases, grouping different illnesses together, and flawed methodology. The study's conclusions suggesting vaping risks similar to smoking are deemed unreliable. The editorial urges better standards in conducting and interpreting meta-analyses, cautioning against misleading data that could impact public understanding and policy decisions. (Published on June 26, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Vapes are safe alternatives to smoking. And other lies they told us</title><link>https://bhekisisa.org/health-news-south-africa/2025-06-26-vapes-are-safe-alternatives-to-smoking-and-other-lies-they-told-us/</link><description>Smoking on planes was once normal, but tobacco control laws changed that. Now, using e-cigarettes in public places like shopping centres is becoming the new norm. As global cigarette use declines, the tobacco industry is shifting focus to products like vapes and heated tobacco. The WHO’s Global Tobacco Epidemic report, launched at the World Conference on Tobacco Control in Dublin, highlights how graphic warnings and anti-tobacco campaigns can counter this trend. The report is especially relevant for South Africa, where a long-delayed tobacco control bill—now including electronic products—is finally being reviewed by Parliament. (Published on June 26, 2025bybhekisisa.org)</description></item></channel></rss>