<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 01:29:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>WHO Exit By The United States Forces FCTC Accountability: A Turning Point For Asia Pacific Policy</title><link>https://www.scoop.co.nz/stories/WO2602/S00069/who-exit-by-the-united-states-forces-fctc-accountability-a-turning-point-for-asia-pacific-policy.htm</link><description>The Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA) calls on Asia-Pacific governments to review WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) following US withdrawal from WHO (22 January 2026) and New Zealand Foreign Minister Winston Peters questioning continued funding. The US cited WHO’s mismanagement whilst Peters called the WHO “unelected globalist bureaucrats” demanding taxpayer scrutiny on international commitments. “The US exit demands FCTC reassessment, especially across Asia-Pacific,” said Nancy Loucas, Executive Coordinator of CAPHRA. “Article 1(d) mandates harm reduction, but WHO blocks vaping and nicotine pouches. Why fund ideology contradicting the treaty?” (Published on February 10, 2026byscoop.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>Vaping ban up in smoke - Lifestyle News</title><link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/lifestyle/vapingnbspbannbspup-in-smoke/4134774/</link><description>Despite the ban, vaping products are widely available in local markets and online. Vapes are seen as a 'cool' choice by many, particularly the younger generation. The ban, ineffective and circumvented, led to a flourishing black market. The ban lacks robust enforcement and is criticized by experts, who suggest a UK-like model. Vapes are considered a safer alternative to traditional tobacco, but health risks remain. The ban's impact on reducing tobacco consumption in India has been questioned. Enforcement of the ban is inconsistent, leading to widespread availability of vapes, particularly through the black market. (Published on February 10, 2026byfinancialexpress.com)</description></item><item><title>EU backlash grows over Spain’s nicotine pouch restrictions</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/eu-backlash-grows-over-spains-nicotine-pouch-restrictions/</link><description>Growing opposition within the EU challenges Spain's strict regulations on nicotine products. Concerns expressed by member states highlight fear of hindering harm reduction efforts, distorting the internal market, and promoting cigarette use. Spain's proposal faces resistance from governments aiming to prevent trade barriers and ensure laws comply with single-market rules. Critics cite frustration with regulations contradicting evidence and striving for lower smoking rates. Calls to respect successful harm reduction strategies, like Sweden's, emphasize the need for balanced legislation. The objections trigger review periods, emphasizing the gravity of the situation and cautioning against repeating ineffective policies at the EU level. (Published on February 10, 2026byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>EU countries scale back tobacco tax proposal</title><link>https://www.theexamination.org/articles/eu-countries-scale-back-tobacco-tax-plan</link><description>European Union's proposal to increase tobacco taxes from 1.80 to 4.30 euros per pack faces opposition, with Cyprus revising it to 4 euros. The WHO backs tax hikes to reduce tobacco use. Cyprus suggests a slower tax increase timeline and lower rates for e-cigarettes and heated tobacco products like IQOS. Critics argue lower taxes lead to higher consumption and health risks. The tobacco industry opposes high taxes and prefers lower rates for new products. Revisions by various presidencies aim to find consensus on rates for all tobacco categories. Ireland looks to raise taxes, while Greece's input is expected in 2027. Cyprus's low tax rates spark debate on potential business impacts and illicit trade concerns. (Published on February 10, 2026bytheexamination.org)</description></item></channel></rss>