<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 12:25:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Thai government to crack down on vaping as user count hits 400,000</title><link>https://asianews.network/thai-government-to-crack-down-on-vaping-as-user-count-hits-400000/</link><description>The Thai Cabinet orders an urgent amendment to the Tobacco Act to regulate e-cigarettes and tackle nicotine addiction, especially among youth. The Ministry of Public Health will lead in drafting the changes following a sharp increase in e-cigarette users, from 78,252 in 2021 to over 400,000 in 2024. The amendments aim to introduce comprehensive measures to control e-cigarettes and new tobacco products. (Published on October 29, 2025byasianews.network)</description></item><item><title>Exclusive: BAT pauses unlicensed US vape launch as FDA action accelerates</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/bat-pauses-unlicensed-us-vape-launch-fda-action-accelerates-2025-10-28/</link><description>British American Tobacco has suspended its pilot project to introduce an unlicensed disposable vape in the U.S., as the Food and Drug Administration intensifies its efforts to crack down on unregulated products and accelerate the approval process for licences. The previously unreported reversal by BAT (BATS.L) highlights the complex challenges major tobacco companies face in trying to compete with a surge of unregulated products—mostly from China—that have eroded profits in the $22 billion U.S. market for smoking alternatives. (Published on October 29, 2025byreuters.com)</description></item><item><title>When science fails: 3 anti-vape studies that didn’t survive scrutiny</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/when-science-fails-3-anti-vape-studies-that-didnt-survive-scrutiny/</link><description>Recent years have seen sensational claims about vaping dangers in studies later retracted for flaws. One study alleging a cancer link was pulled due to concerns over methodology. Another claiming vaping caused heart attacks failed due to timing issues. A study on liver disease linked to vaping faced critique for not considering key factors. The damage of misinformation lingers, with retractions often overlooked after headlines spread globally. The impact of flawed research online can distort public understanding, illustrating the need for careful scrutiny of vaping studies. (Published on October 29, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item></channel></rss>