<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:29:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vaping: Schools want help in 'lonely battle'</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2pj2ez7evo.amp</link><description>Schools are struggling with vaping issues, feeling isolated in the battle against student addiction. Teachers report installing vape detectors, deploying extra staff, and altering school grounds to curb vaping. Some students have ended up in hospitals due to spiked vapes. Schools face financial strain and disrupted learning environments. Efforts to tackle vaping include educating students and seeking government support. The World Health Organisation warns of a youth vaping epidemic, with children being nine times more likely to vape than adults. Schools advocate for clearer guidance, parental support, and stricter measures to address the problem. Legislators are urged to act swiftly to prevent long-term consequences of youth vaping. (Published on January 07, 2026bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>Resources available to help Wisconsinites break free of nicotine addiction</title><link>https://wisconsinindependent.com/features/resources-available-to-help-wisconsinites-break-free-of-nicotine-addiction/</link><description>Tobacco contributes to 8,000 deaths annually in Wisconsin. Around 20% of Wisconsinites use tobacco, with Truth Initiative offering support for those aiming to quit in 2026. "You Got This Day" on Jan. 9 promotes quitting resources, including the research-driven EX Program in partnership with the Mayo Clinic. Vaping, prevalent among youth, is as harmful as smoking. Only 3-5% succeed in quitting cold turkey, but using the EX Program can increase success rates by 40%. Two-thirds of 18-24-year-olds who smoke or vape plan to quit this year. The EX Program offers a free, anonymous digital quitting program. (Published on January 07, 2026bywisconsinindependent.com)</description></item><item><title>VPZ Wants Vape Bill Action</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2026-01-06_vpz-wants-vape-bill-action.html</link><description>VPZ, the UK’s largest specialist vape retailer dedicated to harm reduction and responsible vaping, has urged MPs returning from their Christmas recess holidays to prioritise the Tobacco and Vapes Bill as one of their first priorities of the New Year. As a start, it says it wants the politicians to confirm a date for its Report Stage as soon as possible. (Published on January 07, 2026byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>