<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:29:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vietnam Introduces Strict Ban on E-Cigarettes, Heated Tobacco Products</title><link>https://laotiantimes.com/2026/01/05/vietnam-introduces-strict-ban-on-e-cigarettes-heated-tobacco-products/</link><description>Vietnam has banned e-cigarettes and heated tobacco products to safeguard public health, imposing fines on users and property owners. The Ministry of Health warns of health risks like addiction, cancer, and respiratory issues. Enforced from December 31, 2025, violations can lead to fines between VND 3-10 million. Vietnam joins five other Southeast Asian countries in outlawing these products, supported by the World Health Organization. Similar measures were also taken by Laos in 2021. The move aims to curb rising usage, especially among youth, with health concerns leading to over 1,200 hospitalizations in 2023. (Published on January 05, 2026bylaotiantimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Cannabis THC vapes a 'threat to younger generation'</title><link>https://www.aol.com/articles/cannabis-thc-vapes-threat-younger-124944281.html</link><description>The rising use of cannabis vapes, containing THC, in Bradford poses a threat to youth. Despite being illegal for recreational use, these products were found on sale in the area. A recent raid discovered vapes with pure cannabis at a local off-licence. Concerns were raised about youths being hospitalized due to vaping, as they find it appealing for being odorless and discreet. Some vapes even contained Spice. Authorities discussed the issue during a licensing meeting and emphasized the dangers, including potential overdoses. A shop linked to such activities had its alcohol license revoked. Drug charity Forward Leeds warned about the risks of consuming THC through vaping. (Published on January 05, 2026byaol.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping safer than smoking – so why are people struggling to quit e-cigarettes?</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2026/jan/03/vaping-safer-than-smoking-so-why-are-people-struggling-to-quit-e-cigarettes</link><description>Vaping has surpassed smoking in the UK, with concerns rising about its addictive nature. While less harmful than smoking due to lack of combustion, vaping still poses risks, especially for young people. Quitting vaping involves addressing both physical and behavioral components of addiction, with support options such as text messages, medications, and therapy showing promise. To quit successfully, it's crucial to identify triggers, reduce gradually, set limits, consider lower nicotine products, change flavors, manage cravings, seek professional help, and build a support system. For young people, avoiding vaping altogether is advised, with understanding and tailored support essential for cessation. (Published on January 05, 2026bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Can Nicotine Pouches Help People Quit Smoking?</title><link>https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2843607</link><description>When e-cigarettes first appeared, many public health professionals saw them as a potential tool to help people who smoke transition away from combustible cigarettes to a less harmful source of nicotine. While this approach worked for some individuals, aggressive and risky marketing strategies contributed to a surge in vaping among young people. Now, a new effort from the US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) suggests that the agency may be shifting its harm-reduction strategy toward another product: nicotine pouches. (Published on January 05, 2026byjamanetwork.com)</description></item></channel></rss>