<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 09:19:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Poland’s parliament approves ban on selling vapes to minors</title><link>https://tvpworld.com/86834937/polands-lower-house-of-parliament-approves-ban-on-selling-vapes-to-minors</link><description>Poland’s lower house of parliament has approved a bill banning the sale of all types of vapes to minors, including disposable and reusable e-cigarettes, regardless of nicotine content. The bill, which received strong support with 417 votes in favor, now moves to the Senate and, if approved, will go to the president for signing. This ban is part of wider reforms to Poland’s tobacco and vaping laws, aiming to better protect young people from nicotine addiction and related health risks, as previous legislation did not address newer nicotine products. (Published on May 22, 2025bytvpworld.com)</description></item><item><title>The WHO Doesn’t Deserve a Raise—Patients Do</title><link>https://consumerchoicecenter.org/the-who-doesnt-deserve-a-raise-patients-do/</link><description>The World Health Organization (WHO) plans to raise assessed contributions by 20%, equating to an extra $120 million yearly. Despite strains on global healthcare, the WHO diverts funds into unrestricted areas instead of vital programs like polio eradication. The organization's top-heavy structure allows excessive spending, including lavish staff benefits. The WHO's move towards unaccountable core funding shifts focus from critical health initiatives to administrative expansion. To improve transparency, trim senior compensations, and prioritize patient care, national governments must demand reforms before approving contribution hikes. The WHO should prioritize patient needs over bureaucracy. (Published on May 22, 2025byconsumerchoicecenter.org)</description></item><item><title>Hungary Should Call Out the WHO’s Harm Reduction Hypocrisy at COP11</title><link>https://www.thr101.org/post/hungary-should-call-out-the-who-s-harm-reduction-hypocrisy-at-cop11</link><description>Despite joining the FCTC in 2004, Hungary has only seen a slight decrease in smoking rates over two decades. Recent adoption of harm reduction products like heated tobacco has led to significant reductions in cigarette consumption. The WHO's skepticism despite scientific evidence hinders progress. Illicit cigarette trade is growing due to bans on flavored HTPs. Hungary needs to consider the efficacy of harm reduction at COP11 to address the limitations of traditional anti-smoking policies. (Published on May 22, 2025bythr101.org)</description></item><item><title>What Happens in the Real World When Flavors Are Banned in Nicotine Products?</title><link>https://www.fdli.org/2025/05/what-happens-in-the-real-world-when-flavors-are-banned-in-nicotine-products/</link><description>Recent regulatory activities in the nicotine industry involve the withdrawal of a proposed menthol ban on cigarettes in the U.S. and FDA's approval of ZYN nicotine pouch products. Proposals hint at limiting nicotine levels and antagonizing flavors. Regulatory policies seek good intentions but may raise smoking rates and create black markets. U.S. regulations delay reduced-risk products, favoring large companies. Flavors aid smoking cessation, especially with adult smokers. Bans can boost cigarette sales and illicit markets, endangering public health. The focus should be on evidence-based regulations allowing flavored options for adult smokers while curbing youth access. The goal is to reduce smoking-related harm through pragmatic approaches. (Published on May 22, 2025byfdli.org)</description></item><item><title>Number of smokers drops further in Luxembourg</title><link>https://www.luxtimes.lu/luxembourg/number-of-smokers-drops-further-in-luxembourg/68322750.html</link><description>A survey in Luxembourg showed a decrease in smoking rates, with 23% of residents smoking in 2024 compared to 27% in 2023. Concerns remain about the rising popularity of alternative nicotine products among young people, such as e-cigarettes and nicotine pouches. The Cancer Foundation calls for regulations to protect youth from these products. High levels of passive smoking were also highlighted. Efforts to help residents quit smoking are increasing, with 46% expressing a desire to quit, rising to 62% among 16- to 24-year-olds. A support campaign coinciding with World No Tobacco Day aims to assist those wanting to quit. (Published on May 22, 2025byluxtimes.lu)</description></item><item><title>Most teenagers who vape had never smoked cigarettes before, and 14 is the most common age to start</title><link>https://www.thejournal.ie/most-teenagers-who-vape-had-never-smoked-cigarettes-before-and-14-is-the-most-common-age-to-start-6710802-May2025/</link><description>Research shows most teenage vapers had not smoked cigarettes before starting. The average age for starting e-cigarettes was 14. The study by the TobaccoFree Research Institute of Ireland revealed 76% of e-cig users had never tried traditional cigarettes first. While overall smoking rates are down, 13% of 16-year-old girls still smoke. Additionally, 36% had tried a nicotine product, and 24% admitted to trying smoking. Alcohol consumption among 15 to 16-year-olds has decreased, with two-thirds ever trying it and 28% ever getting drunk. The study highlights a rise in alternative tobacco products among teenagers. (Published on May 22, 2025bythejournal.ie)</description></item></channel></rss>