<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 01:03:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Opening Substack post: an interview with me</title><link>https://clivebates.substack.com/p/opening-substack-post-an-interview?r=h6qd1&amp;utm_medium=ios&amp;shareImageVariant=overlay&amp;triedRedirect=true</link><description>The text discusses the author's views on tobacco control, harm reduction, and challenges faced in the field, emphasizing the importance of informed consent, reducing harm, and addressing regulatory complexities. Critiques are made on current tobacco policies, industry practices, and the WHO's stance on harm reduction. The author advocates for harm reduction over harm elimination, acknowledging the need for a new approach to tobacco regulation. A shift towards safer nicotine products is proposed, focusing on informed consent, consumer protection, and adjusting regulations to reduce smoking rates effectively without driving illicit trade. Criticism is directed towards Michael Bloomberg's influence and the limitations of current regulatory frameworks. (Published on January 12, 2026bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Expanded school-based program linked to lower youth tobacco use rates in California</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2026-01-school-based-linked-youth-tobacco.html</link><description>A study by University of California San Diego shows California's school-based tobacco prevention program, TUPE, led to 20% lower overall tobacco use and 23% lower vaping among middle and high school students. The program, funded by Proposition 56, provided education and activities that significantly reduced tobacco use rates. TUPE-funded schools saw more prevention education and anti-tobacco activities, contributing to lower tobacco use compared to non-TUPE schools. The findings highlight the importance of investing in effective prevention strategies to safeguard young people from addiction. School-based prevention programs, when combined with strong policies, play a key role in comprehensive tobacco control efforts, offering long-term public health benefits. (Published on January 12, 2026bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Why the FDA makes it easier to approve a cigarette than a vape | Guest column</title><link>https://richmond.com/opinion/column/article_731ee121-587b-4e8d-a3d9-1d04e98a330b.html</link><description>Despite political debate, the most effective way to reduce tobacco-related disease is to help smokers switch to much less harmful alternatives. Instead, the FDA has imposed regulatory barriers that keep safer vaping products off the market. At the same time, traditional cigarettes remain widely available. These outdated regulations work against public health goals. As a result, smokers are denied access to tools that could help them quit and save lives. (Published on January 12, 2026byrichmond.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #79 | SUICIDAL POLICY | Michelle Minton and America’s War on Safer Nicotine</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-79-suicidal-policy-michelle-minton-and-americas-war-on-safer-nicotine/</link><description>America’s tobacco policy has turned self-destructive. Safer nicotine products are demonized and restricted while combustible cigarettes remain widely available. In this GFN interview, Michelle Minton of the Reason Foundation explains how fear, ideology, and institutional incentives replaced evidence in U.S. tobacco control—pushing consumers back toward smoking and undermining one of the greatest public-health opportunities of our time. (Published on January 12, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>EU commissioner in hot water for smoke-free nicotine statement</title><link>https://www.vejpkollen.se/en/2026/01/eu-kommissionar-i-blasvader-efter-uttalande-om-rokfritt-nikotin/</link><description>EU Health Commissioner Olivér Várhelyi faces backlash for claiming that smokeless nicotine products are as harmful as cigarettes, sparking criticism and strong reactions. Várhelyi, referring to the WHO, suggests taxing these products like cigarettes, despite lacking scientific evidence to support the claim. The debate continues as Várhelyi's stance is questioned by scientists and seen as misinformation by critics, including those in Sweden. The controversy follows past disputed statements by Várhelyi on nicotine, prompting calls for accountability and scrutiny of his role in public health. The European Commission is expected to propose new regulations for nicotine products in 2026, potentially affecting taxes on snus and e-cigarettes. (Published on January 12, 2026byvejpkollen.se)</description></item></channel></rss>