<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 12:23:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prohibition Does Not Work</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-09-08_prohibition-does-not-work.html</link><description>Last week marked the launch of Prohibition Does Not Work, an international coalition backed by think tanks and aimed at promoting evidence-based harm reduction policies over prohibitionist approaches. The group argues that prohibition has failed, fueling crime, black markets, and public health risks, while blocking access to safer alternatives. Partners such as the Tholos Foundation and the Australian Taxpayers’ Alliance stress that governments should follow the science, adopt harm reduction strategies, and curb the unintended consequences of restrictive tobacco and nicotine laws. (Published on September 09, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Anti-tobacco groups hail France's decision to ban nicotine pouches in 2026</title><link>https://www.rfi.fr/en/france/20250906-anti-tobacco-groups-hail-france-s-decision-to-ban-nicotine-pouches-in-2026</link><description>France will ban nicotine sachets, balls, and gum due to toxicity concerns and addiction risks, effective from March 2026. The ban follows the prohibition of disposable e-cigarettes and aims to protect young people from nicotine-related dangers. The government's decision has been praised by anti-tobacco associations as a crucial measure. Critics argue the ban may deprive adult smokers of regulated alternatives and fuel illegal drug trafficking. Nicotine pouches are said to cause poisonings, especially among children and adolescents, leading to severe health issues. The move reflects a shift in tobacco regulation to tackle addiction and public health concerns. (Published on September 09, 2025byrfi.fr)</description></item><item><title>Don’t Ignore the People: The WHO and EU Must Listen to Consumers on Tobacco Harm Reduction</title><link>https://www.republicworld.com/initiatives/dont-ignore-the-people-the-who-and-eu-must-listen-to-consumers-on-tobacco-harm-reduction</link><description>Policymakers and health officials convening in Dublin overlook consumer perspectives on tobacco regulation, focusing on prohibitive measures influenced by powerful stakeholders. This ignores evidence supporting harm reduction strategies and excludes those benefiting from safer alternatives in countries like Sweden and the UK. Proposed EU regulations, aligning with the WHO's strict abstinence model, risk hindering public health by restricting access to less harmful nicotine products. Amidst global policy debates, it is crucial for decision-makers to prioritize evidence-based approaches and engage with consumer voices to ensure effective and inclusive tobacco control strategies at COP11 and beyond. (Published on September 09, 2025byrepublicworld.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches may offer path to reduced tobacco harm</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-09-nicotine-pouches-path-tobacco.html</link><description>Adults in the U.S. are turning to nicotine pouches as a potential step down from more harmful nicotine products. A study by Rutgers Health found that most users have a history of tobacco use, with some using pouches to quit. Despite low overall usage rates, concerns about the long-term health effects, addiction, and youth uptake persist. Researchers emphasize the need for monitoring and regulation to prevent uncontrolled proliferation. While potentially beneficial for established tobacco users seeking harm reduction, caution is advised for non-users. Understanding usage patterns is crucial as these products gain popularity. The study provides valuable insights into current trends around nicotine pouch use. (Published on September 09, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>What New York’s Cigarette Litter Says About Tobacco Control</title><link>https://filtermag.org/new-york-cigarette-packs-tobacco-control/</link><description>New York City faces a high rate of cigarette tax evasion due to exorbitant prices, leading to a thriving illicit market. The study found a decline in packs with official tax stamps, leading to concerns about the impact of high tobacco taxes on smokers. While smoking rates have decreased, experts debate whether it's due to taxes or the rise of safer nicotine products like vapes. Strategies to combat the illegal cigarette trade, including a track-and-trace system, are discussed. However, punitive measures like those on flavored vapes might drive consumers back to more harmful options, highlighting the need for harm reduction approaches. (Published on September 10, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids Decries Supposed Fast-Tracking of Safer Alternatives to Cigarettes But Says Nothing About FDA's Inaction on Real Cigarettes</title><link>https://tobaccoanalysis.blogspot.com/2025/09/campaign-for-tobacco-free-kids-decries.html</link><description>According to Reuters, the FDA is preparing to accelerate the review of applications for the sale of nicotine pouches. These products are considered far less harmful than traditional cigarettes, as they contain no tobacco, require no combustion, and do not involve inhalation.  [...] The FDA is being criticized for taking “shortcuts” in reviewing nicotine pouch applications, but the reality is that reviews often take years instead of the 180 days required by law — Zyn, for example, took five years. Speeding up this process is not a threat to kids’ health but a necessary step to bring safer alternatives to smokers more quickly. Meanwhile, groups like the Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids remain silent on the FDA’s continued approval of deadly cigarettes, never calling for their removal or even stricter safety standards. (Published on September 10, 2025byblogspot.com)</description></item><item><title>Spanish government moves to ban smoking on bar terraces</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/sep/09/spanish-government-moves-ban-smoking-bar-terraces</link><description>The Spanish government approved a draft tobacco law banning smoking and vaping on bar terraces. The law prohibits minors from using vapes, single-use e-cigarettes, and other products, treating them like regular cigarettes. It extends to enclosed public spaces and outdoor areas like stadiums and educational facilities. The legislation aims to curb smoking-related cancer cases in a country where 140 people die daily from tobacco-related illnesses. While the bill doesn't yet include plain packaging or price hikes, the health ministry may push for these changes. Anti-tobacco groups advocate for plain packaging to deter smoking initiation, pointing out its success in other countries. Smoking rates in Spain stand at 28.9% for men and 22.6% for women. (Published on September 10, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Doctors and Harm Reduction: The Fight for Honest Tobacco Policy</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/09/08/doctors-and-harm-reduction-the-fight-for-honest-tobacco-policy/</link><description>Smoking remains a global public health crisis, leading to millions of preventable deaths annually. Despite the clear risks, countries often resist harm reduction strategies, but some doctors advocate for evidence-based approaches. In India, vaping products are banned, yet high smoking rates persist. In the U.S., many clinicians lack information on harm reduction, hindering progress. Europe also faces challenges with illegal vape sales to youth. Prohibition fuels black markets and misinformation, impacting public health. Doctors worldwide call for education, regulation, and safer alternatives to combat smoking effectively and shift from managing to preventing the tragic consequences of smoking. (Published on September 10, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item></channel></rss>