<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 08:25:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>E-cigarette use among youth on the rise</title><link>https://theedgemalaysia.com/node/754142</link><description>The prevalence of e-cigarette and HTP use is now close to smoking incidence in Malaysia, according to a regional study conducted by Singapore-based consumer insights firm Milieu Insight. (Published on May 08, 2025bytheedgemalaysia.com)</description></item><item><title>New York City’s Campaign Against Vapes Will Cost Lives</title><link>https://filtermag.org/new-york-city-campaign-against-vapes/</link><description>New York City Health Department's press release, allegedly led by Michael Bloomberg, showcases a biased approach against tobacco harm reduction. Equating vaping to the leading cause of death misleads the public. While smoking rates have declined, the city demonizes vaping rather than celebrating its role in smoking cessation. Crackdowns on vaping products prevail, while ignoring the benefits they offer smokers. The city's lawsuit against flavored vapes exemplifies a misguided focus on youth appeal, neglecting adult preferences. Disregarding harm reduction principles, the city's stance on nicotine perpetuates cigarette consumption over safer alternatives. The campaign reflects a lack of access to truthful health information and obstructs progress towards saving lives. (Published on May 08, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #150 | FDA'S RELUCTANCE ON FULL SHOW | Featuring Lindsey Stroud</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-150/</link><description>Despite the growing use of safer nicotine being strongly associated with declining smoking rates, there is still systemic opposition to these products from institutions and NGOs - but why is this the case? In this episode Lindsey Stroud joins us to unpack the FDA's reluctance to approve new nicotine products, and the misinformation used to prop up the opposition to THR. (Published on May 08, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Against zombie prohibitionism</title><link>https://thecritic.co.uk/against-zombie-prohibitionism/</link><description>The International Agency for Research on Cancer (IARC), established by the WHO in 1965 to investigate cancer causes, has reportedly shifted toward activism over the decades. A recent article in theNew England Journal of Medicine, titled"The IARC Perspective on the Effects of Policies on Reducing Alcohol Consumption", advocates for prohibition as an evidence-based measure. However, a disclaimer at the end of the article states that the views expressed do not necessarily reflect those of IARC or the WHO, raising questions about how it can be called an "IARC perspective" at all. (Published on May 08, 2025bythecritic.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>The real problem with vaping</title><link>https://www.vox.com/public-health/410443/vaping-conundrum-public-health-youth-ecigarettes</link><description>Cigarettes are highly addictive and dangerous, contributing to serious health issues like lung cancer and heart disease. Although smoking rates in the U.S. have declined since the mid-20th century, about 29 million Americans still smoke. Smoking remains the leading cause of preventable death in the U.S., responsible for around 500,000 deaths annually, including 125,000 from lung cancer. E-cigarettes were created specifically to tackle this public health crisis by providing nicotine to dependent users without the harmful chemicals found in traditional cigarettes. (Published on May 08, 2025byvox.com)</description></item><item><title>Teens who want to quit vaping have another medication option</title><link>https://www.sciencenews.org/article/varenicline-teen-vaping-medication-drug</link><description>A recent study showed that varenicline, used to help smokers quit, may also assist teens in quitting vaping. In a 12-week trial paired with counseling, 51% of participants on varenicline abstained from vaping, compared to 14% on a placebo. The drug's effectiveness continued post-trial, with a 28% abstinence rate at 24 weeks. Vaping in adolescents can lead to nicotine addiction, impacting brain development. State laws on treating minors vary, posing challenges for underage patients seeking help. Varenicline, binding to nicotine receptors, reduces cravings and withdrawal symptoms. Dr. McGee suggests discussing quitting with parents and considers varenicline as a treatment option for young patients. (Published on May 08, 2025bysciencenews.org)</description></item></channel></rss>