<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:56:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Africa: FCTC's 20 Years of Stagnation - Smoking Rates in LMICs Barely Shifted in Two Decades</title><link>https://allafrica.com/stories/202511040115.html</link><description>The World Health Organization reports tobacco kills over 7 million people annually. Experts suggest reevaluating the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control, as smoking rates and related deaths persist globally. Despite efforts like taxation and cessation programs, little progress is evident. Criticisms include a lack of transparency on smoking prevalence rates and failure to focus on Harm Reduction strategies. Concerns persist over high smoking rates in regions like Indonesia and China. The WHO is accused of hindering Tobacco Harm Reduction progress. Experts call for more effective approaches, especially for long-term heavy smokers. Discussions at the Global Forum on Nicotine highlight challenges faced by low- and middle-income countries under the WHO FCTC. (Published on November 07, 2025byallafrica.com)</description></item><item><title>Banned disposable vapes still sold as UK’s Tobacco and Vapes Bill faces scrutiny</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/banned-disposable-vapes-still-sold-as-uks-tobacco-and-vapes-bill-faces-scrutiny/</link><description>Despite a ban in the UK, disposable vapes are openly sold, with a new investigation revealing ongoing challenges in enforcing regulations. The Tobacco and Vapes Bill is undergoing detailed scrutiny in the House of Lords to regulate tobacco and vaping sales. Illicit single-use vapes were found in Brighton, indicating a struggle with enforcement despite seizures. The ban aimed to reduce youth vaping and environmental harm but may inadvertently fuel an illicit market. Responsible retailers have adapted to the ban, promoting reusable products. The bill aims for a smoke-free generation and stricter regulations, while industry experts stress the need for better enforcement and standards. (Published on November 07, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Fierce EU battle on smoke-free nicotine ahead of WHO tobacco meeting</title><link>https://www.vejpkollen.se/en/2025/11/hard-eu-strid-om-rokfritt-nikotin-infor-whos-tobaksmote-sverige-pa-frontlinjen/</link><description>The EU faces a battle over smokeless nicotine products ahead of the WHO summit on the tobacco convention. Sweden and other countries advocate for snus and e-cigarettes to reduce smoking, opposing the European Commission's strict regulation approach almost like a ban. The Commission's stance surprises as countries resist, fearing a potential ban on popular products like nicotine pouches. History reflects similar past clashes over e-cigarettes. Lobbying intensifies for a ban through the WHO Convention, but pragmatic countries like Sweden challenge the Commission. Threats of bans on flavors in e-liquids and nicotine pouches loom. The closed-door WHO meeting on November 17-22 may shape future EU tobacco policies amid transparency concerns. (Published on November 07, 2025byvejpkollen.se)</description></item><item><title>Does the EU Commission think you are a rat?</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/does-the-eu-commission-think-you-are-a-rat/</link><description>EU Commissioner Olivér Várhelyi discussed plans at the FILTERED Conference to increase taxation and regulations on nicotine products like vaping. The conference, funded by the EU, is run by a group advocating for strict rules on vaping, raising concerns of conflicts of interest. The group also pushes to exclude industry representatives and consumers from policy discussions. The EU Commission aims to tighten controls on tobacco, vaping, unhealthy foods, and alcohol. However, restricting less harmful alternatives may not align with evidence or promote harm reduction. A balanced approach should prioritize access to less harmful options, accurate information, and proportional regulation that respects adult choice and democratic participation. (Published on November 07, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #76 | HARM IS HARM | Breaking Down the WHO’s Ideological Wall</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-76-harm-is-harm-breaking-down-the-whos-ideological-wall/</link><description>The World Health Organization is no longer just fighting smoking—it’s waging an ideological war against nicotine itself. In this blistering interview, former WHO official Professor Tikki Pang exposes how the global health establishment has become evidence-blind, influenced by Bloomberg funding, and driven by a moral crusade that erases the distinction between smoking and safer alternatives. From “harm is harm” rhetoric to regulatory capture, Pang warns that WHO’s stance is fueling misinformation, stifling science, and putting millions of lives at risk. (Published on November 07, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Safer Solutions: When will the facts about tobacco harm reduction trickle down to veterans?</title><link>https://www.rstreet.org/commentary/safer-solutions-when-will-the-facts-about-tobacco-harm-reduction-trickle-down-to-veterans/</link><description>Veterans have high smoking rates, leading to increased healthcare costs and mortality. Although the VA offers smoking cessation programs, many veterans struggle to quit, especially those with PTSD. Despite FDA support for harm reduction with e-cigarettes and nicotine pouches, the VA has been slow to endorse these options. Some veterans are independently turning to reduced-risk products to quit smoking. Experts within the VA are advocating for harm reduction strategies, citing success in reducing smoking rates. Official VA guidance on harm reduction is lacking, but embracing reduced-risk products could further reduce smoking rates, save lives, and cut costs, benefiting veterans' health and well-being. (Published on November 07, 2025byrstreet.org)</description></item></channel></rss>