<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:19:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Swapping Cigarettes for Vapes or HTP Rapidly Boosts Fitness, Study Finds</title><link>https://filtermag.org/quitting-cigarettes-vapes-boost-fitness/</link><description>Switching from smoking to vapes or heated tobacco products can lead to improved fitness levels in just four weeks, according to a study published in Scientific Reports. Researchers at the University of Catania found significant increases in aerobic capacity among participants who made the switch, regardless of using e-cigarettes or heated tobacco products. These gains in fitness can motivate younger individuals to opt for safer nicotine alternatives. The study highlights the potential of smoke-free products as effective harm reduction tools, with improvements in cardiovascular efficiency seen as early as four weeks after quitting smoking. The findings suggest that both e-cigarettes and heated tobacco products can enhance cardiovascular fitness post-smoking cessation. (Published on July 21, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>The rising use of nicotine pouches snus</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9395ywzg73o</link><description>Teens misuse high-nicotine pouches causing health issues. Finn admits using them in school, affecting focus and health. Nicotine pouch use is on the rise, especially among the youth. The addictive pouches are easy to access and come in various flavors and strengths. There are concerns about their impact on gums, with potential long-term health risks. Despite being less harmful than cigarettes, they can still cause damage. Experts urge stricter regulations and warn of potential health hazards. Users like Finn and a student share experiences of gum damage and addiction. Research shows risks of gum disease and bone loss, highlighting the need for more awareness and regulation. (Published on July 21, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>More Reasons Why the Clinical Trial of Low Nicotine Cigarettes for Pregnant Smokers Was Unethical</title><link>https://tobaccoanalysis.blogspot.com/2025/07/more-reasons-why-clinical-trial-of-low.html</link><description>Last week, Iexplainedthat a recentclinical trialof very low nicotine cigarettes for pregnant smokers was unethical because neither the intervention nor control groups were offered usual care: being instructed by a physician to quit smoking and being offered behavioral interventions, asspecifiedby the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force. However, in addition to this ethical breach, there are several other aspects of the research which contribute to its impropriety. (Published on July 21, 2025byblogspot.com)</description></item><item><title>Popular vape flavors found to boost nicotine reward in adolescent mice</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-07-popular-vape-flavors-boost-nicotine.html</link><description>A study by Marshall University shows that e-cigarette flavors like vanilla and cherry can drive vaping behavior in adolescents, similar to nicotine. The research, using an EVSA assay on mice, found vanilla and benzaldehyde triggered reward-seeking responses. Even without nicotine, vanilla flavor alone led to addictive behavior. These flavored additives may affect the brain's dopamine system, potentially causing addiction-like behaviors in teens. The study highlights the impact of flavorings on nicotinic receptors, key in nicotine addiction. Lead investigator Henderson warns of the risks of flavored vapes marketed as nicotine-free. (Published on July 21, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Juul will be allowed to sell e-cigarettes ending long fight over flavored tobacco on store shelves</title><link>https://www.aol.com/news/juul-allowed-sell-e-cigarettes-185709289.html?guccounter=1&amp;guce_referrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8&amp;guce_referrer_sig=AQAAAKGKaWi3X_D2_k2r5tTGSXCoyc2TTVv5XgGQT60k8mnmbBpOPj7wZNFRTfntfg8b-EY6uBhGna1yiQ85QXxbQ3Zr9tl6RvSuksVH7F8nn3Blu8HFLtWVK_lc--3FL3UvgGU7IVpjiZ6SBB6RK7S2C_9I0eiJfJdmx2sXSs40nkYP</link><description>The FDA allowed Juul to keep selling e-cigarettes and refill cartridges. Despite facing legal challenges, Juul convinced the FDA of the benefits for adult smokers switching from cigarettes. Although Juul discontinued some flavors to deter teenage users, the FDA's decision sparked controversy due to concerns about youth vaping. The FDA emphasized that non-smokers should avoid e-cigarettes. Juul faced lawsuits over teen vaping but argued for their product's safety. The FDA recognized Juul's potential harm reduction for smokers. Juul CEO Crosthwaite welcomed the ruling, emphasizing the importance for adult smokers to have regulated alternatives. (Published on July 21, 2025byaol.com)</description></item><item><title>Study shows vaping beats gum, lozenges for quitting smoking</title><link>https://www.westernstandard.news/international/study-shows-vaping-beats-gum-lozenges-for-quitting-smoking/66153</link><description>A new Australian clinical trial shows that vaping flavored nicotine liquids is significantly more effective for quitting smoking than traditional nicotine gum or lozenges. Reported in the Annals of Internal Medicine on July 14, the study found that smokers using vaping devices were three times more likely to quit after six months. Over 1,000 government-assisted Australians took part, all of whom wanted to quit. Participants were randomly assigned to use either vaping or traditional nicotine replacement therapy. (Published on July 21, 2025bywesternstandard.news)</description></item><item><title>Chinese pharmacist who made e-cigs possible</title><link>https://www.dailyexpress.com.my/news/262883/chinese-pharmacist-who-made-e-cigs-possible/</link><description>Electronic cigarettes owe their existence to Chinese pharmacist Hon Lik, who sought to quit smoking in 2001. Using nicotine patches at the time, he began experimenting with vaporizing nicotine using food additives as solvents. In 2000, he developed the concept of using a piezoelectric ultrasound element to vaporize a nicotine-propylene glycol solution, stored in a disposable plastic cartridge. After refining the device into a handheld size, he patented it in China, and the first e-cigarette was manufactured in Beijing. His innovations laid the foundation for modern e-cigarettes. Hon’s story was presented at the 12th Global Forum on Nicotine (GFN 2025) in Warsaw, where he has supported the forum since 2015, promoting tobacco harm reduction. (Published on July 21, 2025bydailyexpress.com.my)</description></item></channel></rss>