<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 18:17:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why We Need Greater, Not Less, Access to Reduced-Risk Nicotine Products</title><link>https://www.cureus.com/articles/404214-why-we-need-greater-not-less-access-to-reduced-risk-nicotine-products#!/</link><description>Cigarette smoking is the leading preventable cause of death and disease, linked to cardiovascular disease, chronic lung disease, and cancer. Novel nicotine products such as e-cigarettes and nicotine pouches can lower exposure to harmful chemicals and reduce smoking-related risks, supporting national “SmokeFree” strategies. However, their effectiveness depends on accessibility. While some advocate for prescription-only models, such restrictions may limit access for smokers and lead to unintended consequences, including black markets, crime, and health risks from unregulated products. (Published on August 19, 2025bycureus.com)</description></item><item><title>Indian Doctors Join Call to End the Country’s Vape Ban</title><link>https://filtermag.org/indian-doctors-end-vape-ban/</link><description>India's vape ban has lasted six years, despite over 1 million smoking-related deaths yearly. Doctors from AIIMS advocate for a reevaluation, suggesting e-cigarettes aid cessation. They challenge the ban despite AIIMS' support. With high tobacco use, advocates call for harm reduction policies like those in the UK. The ban failed, leading to a booming illicit market. Public health experts urge a review for a safer approach. Doctors witness smoking's harm daily, supporting a reevaluation for better public health. Researchers emphasize the need for evidence-based policies to combat smoking's devastating impact. (Published on August 19, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Illegal vape seizures soar as UK disposable ban risks fuelling black market</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/illegal-vape-seizures-soar-as-uk-disposable-ban-fuels-black-market/</link><description>Seizures of illegal vapes are surging in the UK due to the disposable ban, driving more activity to the black market. Sussex confiscated 21,200 illicit vape products in 2024 compared to zero four years earlier. In Surrey, seizures rose from 500 to 14,140 last year. While councils see it as progress, critics say more funding is needed for Trading Standards to combat dangerous products. Industry advocates argue crackdowns on rogue traders are essential. Despite efforts, the ban on disposable vapes is backfiring, with illegal sales persisting across the UK. The rise in unlawful vapes poses health risks and undermines the vaping industry's credibility. (Published on August 19, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Govt hears from industry on proposed tobacco ban</title><link>https://www.chronicle.gi/govt-hears-from-industry-on-proposed-tobacco-ban/</link><description>The Gibraltar Government is considering legislation to ban tobacco sales to residents born after January 1, 2009. Feedback from industry and retailers highlighted economic concerns. The Minister acknowledges the addictive nature of nicotine but clarifies smoking remains legal. The goal is to prevent youth smoking and create a smoke-free environment. If approved, the law would take effect in 2027. Penalties for violating the law could be up to £10,000 for individuals and up to £20,000 for businesses. The legislation also targets single-use vapes, tobacco product imitations, and vending machine sales. (Published on August 19, 2025bychronicle.gi)</description></item><item><title>Illinois now taxing Zyn and nicotine pouches</title><link>https://www.axios.com/local/chicago/2025/08/14/illinois-tobacco-tax-budget-2026-zyn-nicotine-products?utm_source=chatgpt.com</link><description>Illinois has raised its tobacco tax from 36% to 45% as part of the 2026 budget, which now also applies to nicotine pouches like Zyn. The change, effective July 1, is expected to generate about $53 million in new revenue. Zyn pouches, popular among young people for their discreet use and flavored options, are now taxed similarly to cigarettes, though they remain cheaper—a tin starts at $5.60 before tax and about $9.92 after. By contrast, heavy taxation makes cigarettes in Chicago cost up to $20 per pack, the highest in the U.S. (Published on August 19, 2025byaxios.com)</description></item><item><title>When Foreign Influence Clouds Local Voices  | The Pack Breakers Podcast Reaction</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i3bhwYX7h30</link><description>In this special reaction episode, we break down a powerful moment from The Pack Breakers podcast when a South African MP boldly questioned the influence of foreign-funded NGOs and international institutions like the WHO in shaping South Africa’s tobacco control legislation. (Published on August 19, 2025byyoutube.com)</description></item></channel></rss>