<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 18:18:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Smoke-free brand rethinks nicotine, harm reduction</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/06/25/entertainment-lifestyle/life-times/smoke-free-brand-rethinks-nicotine-harm-reduction/2138428</link><description>Nicotine isn't the main smoking risk; tobacco combustion is. Philip Morris' Iqos warms, not burns, tobacco to reduce harmful chemicals. In the Philippines, awareness is growing through education and the "Forever Curious" campaign. Launched in 2014, Iqos focuses on engaging consumers and promoting better alternatives to traditional smoking. With close to 150,000 users in the Philippines, understanding the product is crucial. The brand's global event in Milan highlights its innovative approach and commitment to transformation. (Published on June 24, 2025bymanilatimes.net)</description></item><item><title>Why is Harm Reduction such a Hard Sell?</title><link>https://www.thefirebreak.org/p/why-is-harm-reduction-such-a-hard?r=5t47ie&amp;triedRedirect=true</link><description>Harm reduction is a pragmatic health approach aiming to minimize harm from risky behaviors. Challenges arise due to opposition from health campaigners, criticizing harm reduction for potentially promoting risky behavior. Examples include distributing free needles for drug users. Misinformation campaigns against vaping and reduced harm alternatives to smoking are a concern, hindering public health progress. Concerns about harm reduction strategies influencing youth behavior exist but may be overstated. The WHO spreads misinformation on nicotine products, while activist NGOs align with anti-vaping rhetoric. Genuine public health leaders include passionate vaping advocates advocating for reduced harm alternatives. Issues arise from misinformation, corporate interests, and lack of support for harm reduction efforts. (Published on June 25, 2025bythefirebreak.org)</description></item><item><title>Mónica García Wants to Ban What Works. Literally.</title><link>https://consideratepouchers.org/monica-garcia-wants-to-ban-what-works-literally/</link><description>Spain's Ministry of Health's proposed regulation to ban flavored nicotine pouches and cap nicotine levels may unintentionally drive former smokers back to cigarettes. A survey shows most users switched to pouches to quit smoking and strongly oppose the ban. Many fear a return to cigarettes if the regulation is enforced. Instead of blanket bans, age verification and vendor penalties could better prevent youth access. The current approach risks fueling a black market and increasing smoking rates. Effective public health policies should focus on education and responsible sales rather than punishing consumers. Protecting the vulnerable means regulating with evidence, not fear. (Published on June 25, 2025byconsideratepouchers.org)</description></item><item><title>Global elites think you’re too stupid for soda and beer</title><link>https://www.theblaze.com/columns/opinion/global-elites-think-youre-too-stupid-for-soda-and-beer</link><description>Global public health elites propose a 50% tax increase on tobacco, alcohol, sugary drinks, and processed foods to raise $3.7 trillion, seen as governmental theft. These "health taxes" aim to expand state control rather than combat illness. The burden falls heavily on working-class individuals. The strategy is viewed as economic punishment, not health promotion. Taxing small pleasures disproportionately affects the most vulnerable. Prohibitive pricing can lead to black markets and overlooks personal freedoms and informed choices. Public health should focus on harm reduction and education, not coercive taxation. Respecting individual autonomy and promoting innovation yields better outcomes than punitive measures. (Published on June 25, 2025bytheblaze.com)</description></item><item><title>Social media content exposure linked to teen vaping and cannabis use</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250624/Exposure-to-social-media-posts-linked-to-teen-vaping-and-cannabis-use.aspx</link><description>Exposure to cannabis and e-cigarette posts on social media influences teen substance use, with dual use being common. Although youth e-cigarette use is decreasing, adolescents are still vaping, using cannabis, and combining both. Researchers at USC's Keck School of Medicine found that TikTok poses the highest risk for substance use exposure. Influencers play a significant role, as their posts without disclosed brand partnerships can affect teen behavior. Social media guidelines need improvement to prevent youth substance use. Future studies will delve into cannabis influencer marketing effects. (Published on June 25, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>Belgium Health Minister Urges EU-wide Ban on Vapes</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/06/24/belgium-health-minister-urges-eu-wide-ban-on-vapes/</link><description>Belgian Health Minister called for a Europe-wide ban on e-cigarettes, aiming to prevent youth nicotine addiction. He also emphasized the need for preventive measures on alcohol and tobacco use during the Luxembourg Health Council meeting. Vandenbroucke highlighted the dangers of flavored e-cigarettes, urging the inclusion of vaping in the EU's anti-cancer efforts. (Published on June 25, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Don’t ignore the people: The WHO and the EU must listen to consumers on tobacco harm reduction</title><link>https://www.brusselstimes.com/1641943/dont-ignore-the-people-the-who-and-the-eu-must-listen-to-consumers-on-tobacco-harm-reduction</link><description>Global tobacco and nicotine regulation discussions lack consumer representation, disadvantaging smokers and vapers. The World Conference on Tobacco Control overlooks harm reduction strategies, favoring prohibitionist policies influenced by figures like Michael Bloomberg and the WHO. The upcoming COP11 and EU regulations could shape future nicotine policies, potentially blocking safer alternatives. Despite successful harm reduction examples in certain countries, the EU is leaning towards restrictive measures like flavor bans and tax hikes. Advocates emphasize the need for evidence-based, consumer-centric policies to combat smoking-related illnesses. Policymakers face a crucial decision: prioritize public health or maintain outdated ideologies at the expense of consumer well-being. (Published on June 25, 2025bybrusselstimes.com)</description></item></channel></rss>