<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 06:39:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Germany Moves to Ban Menthol Vapes in Sweeping Crackdown on “Cooling” Additives</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/germany-moves-to-ban-menthol-vapes-in-sweeping-crackdown-on-cooling-additives/</link><description>Germany plans a strict ban on menthol and other cooling additives in e-cigarettes to deter young users. The government cites health risks such as increased nicotine uptake. Critics argue about the lack of evidence on menthol's effects, as it is used in medicines. Manufacturers would need to adjust products or leave the market, facing compliance costs. Tighter rules on labeling and product testing are also included. The ban aims to be in effect within six months, aligning with EU discussions on similar bans. The impact of these measures on harm reduction versus limiting choices for smokers is uncertain. (Published on February 02, 2026byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>EU Opinion Sparks Backlash</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2026-01-28_eu-opinion-sparks-backlash.html</link><description>A draft report on the European Union cardiovascular diseases strategy has sparked a backlash, according to the World Vapers’ Alliance. Produced by Rapporteur Romana Jerković for the Committee on Public Health, it claims to emphasise “the importance of strong regulatory measures to reduce the affordability, appeal and harmfulness of tobacco and nicotine products, heated tobacco products, e-cigarettes and nicotine pouches, including through flavour bans, limits on nicotine”. (Published on February 02, 2026byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Australia Thought It Beat Smoking. Then the Black Market Took Off</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2026-01-29/australia-s-anti-smoking-efforts-undermined-by-illicit-cigarettes</link><description>The chain-smoking protagonist of Mad Men should be far removed from the life of a modern young Australian — particularly when it comes to tobacco. Australia has been a global leader in anti-smoking policy. Cigarettes there are among the most expensive in the world and are sold in plain packaging plastered with graphic health warnings. Yet just as authorities believed they were winning the battle against smoking, experts say the country is facing a new tobacco crisis. While overall smoking rates continue to fall, research shows progress in reducing teen smoking has slowed — likely due to vaping, which researchers say can act as a gateway to cigarettes. (Published on February 02, 2026bybloomberg.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #173 | Are Safer Nicotine Alternatives Being Misrepresented in the EU?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-173-are-safer-nicotine-alternatives-being-misrepresented-in-the-eu/</link><description>EU nicotine policy is under fire after claims that smoke-free nicotine products are as harmful as cigarettes. In GFN News, Joanna Junak interviews Bengt Wiberg of Stingfree AB on why experts dispute these statements, what science says about nicotine pouches, snus, and vaping, and how the debate could impact tobacco harm reduction and future EU regulation. (Published on February 02, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>