<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 06:18:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Treat smoking with same strategy used to combat HIV/Aids, tobacco company urges parliament</title><link>https://www.timeslive.co.za/news/south-africa/2025-08-28-treat-smoking-with-same-strategy-used-to-combat-hivaids-tobacco-company-urges-parliament/</link><description>Philip Morris South Africa urged Parliament’s health committee to apply a harm reduction strategy to smoking, similar to the approach that helped combat HIV/AIDS in the country. The company argued that the current Tobacco Products and Electronic Delivery Systems Control Bill does not differentiate between traditional combustible cigarettes and what it claims are less harmful alternatives, such as heated tobacco products, e-cigarettes, and oral nicotine products. (Published on August 28, 2025bytimeslive.co.za)</description></item><item><title>Researcher Awarded $3 Million To Fight Nicotine Addiction</title><link>https://medicine.missouri.edu/news/researcher-awarded-3-million-fight-nicotine-addiction</link><description>The University of Missouri researcher received over $3 million from NIH to develop treatments for substance use disorders, focusing on helping people quit smoking. Brett Froeliger, PhD, aims to disrupt habitual nicotine use through brain stimulation. His research investigates TBS's effects on brain areas involved in addiction and aims to identify optimal stimulation targets for therapy. Nearly 50 million US adults used tobacco in 2022, underlining the need for effective cessation programs. Froeliger's grant supports a 5-year study exploring how brain stimulation can treat addiction beyond nicotine. (Published on August 28, 2025bymissouri.edu)</description></item><item><title>New research shows 'stealth vaping is everywhere'</title><link>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/te-manu-korihi/571379/new-research-shows-stealth-vaping-is-everywhere</link><description>Research by Dr. Robin Quigg from the University of Otago highlights how the discreet design of vaping devices allows young Māori to vape in prohibited areas, leading to normalization of vaping and nicotine addiction. The study emphasizes the urgent need for tighter regulations on vape device design, advocating for larger sizes, therapeutic designs, and less appealing odors. Despite many marae offering designated vaping areas, some sacred places like marae and wharenui are being disrespected. Quigg stresses the importance of implementing stricter regulations to curb the allure of vaping among young people in New Zealand. (Published on August 28, 2025byrnz.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>Caffeine pouches are getting popular among young people. Are they safe?</title><link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/health/caffeine-pouches-viral-1.7618255</link><description>Caffeine pouches, popular among young people, can contain high levels of caffeine, reaching 200mg. These small packets resemble nicotine pouches and are placed between the lip and gums for quick absorption. Health professionals warn that excessive use can lead to health risks, including rapid heart rate and dependence. Companies selling these products deny targeting minors and claim to adhere to restrictions set by Health Canada. Experts stress the importance of limiting caffeine intake, with pediatricians advising a maximum of 200mg per day. Concerns also arise about potential long-term health effects, such as addiction and sleep problems. Regulations and clear health warnings on these products are recommended. (Published on August 28, 2025bycbc.ca)</description></item></channel></rss>