<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 18:18:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why Dr. Mark Tyndall Is Taking a Stand for Tobacco Harm Reduction</title><link>https://filtermag.org/mark-tyndall-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>Dr. Mark Tyndall advocates for tobacco harm reduction by promoting safer nicotine products for vulnerable groups. His book, "Vaping: Behind the Smoke and Fear," stresses the importance of integrating harm reduction into healthcare. Tyndall's extensive experience with harm reduction in HIV and drug use informs his support for safer options for smokers. He criticizes the stigma against harm reduction and highlights the benefits of nicotine. The high smoking rates among specific populations, like Indigenous communities, are a key concern. Tyndall emphasizes the need for medical professionals to embrace tobacco harm reduction to save lives. (Published on July 25, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Opinion | Do nicotine pouches have a public health benefit? It’s complicated.</title><link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2025/07/24/nicotine-pouches-harm-reduction-addiction/</link><description>The text discusses concerns about Big Tobacco's new nicotine pouches potentially addicting youths. While some find these products helpful in cutting back on cigarettes, studies show dual-use may not reduce harm significantly. The FDA emphasizes approved nicotine replacement therapies for smoking cessation. PMI aims for smokers to switch to lower harm products but dual-use could be risky for health, as shown in research. The complexity of dual-use needs further investigation to understand its impact. The FDA warns against switching between tobacco products and stresses the importance of proven cessation methods. The text raises questions about unintentional harm and the risk of nicotine addiction in new generations. (Published on July 25, 2025bywashingtonpost.com)</description></item><item><title>Smokeless nicotine is at the heart of Sweden’s smoking decline, says leading expert</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/smokeless-nicotine-is-at-the-heart-of-swedens-smoking-decline-says-leading-expert/</link><description>Sweden’s smoking decline is credited to smokeless nicotine products, led by researcher Karl Fagerström. Niconovum pioneered tobacco-free nicotine pouches, aiming for a safer way to quit smoking. Public health has been slow to embrace harm reduction due to industry ties. Sweden acknowledges snus' role in reducing smoking. Experts advocate for noncombustible nicotine delivery for smokers. Regulating such products is costly and complex, hindering market access. FDA approval delays for harm-reduction measures have faced criticism, urging faster action. Public debates continue on the future of nicotine consumption and harm reduction, highlighting the need for regulatory changes to promote safer alternatives. (Published on July 25, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Adolescent tobacco and e-cigarette use tied to increased depression and anxiety, especially with dual use</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-07-adolescent-tobacco-cigarette-depression-anxiety.html</link><description>The study by Abdulhay et al. found that adolescents using e-cigarettes or tobacco products had higher rates of depression and anxiety. The complex relationship between tobacco use and mental health highlights the importance of addressing these issues during adolescence. Data from the National Youth Tobacco Survey showed that both e-cigarette and conventional tobacco use were linked to mental health problems. Tailored interventions are needed to address these concerns and combat tobacco use among teenagers. (Published on July 25, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>The EU’s War on Harm Reduction – A Public Health Calamity</title><link>https://tobaccoharmreduction.net/article/war-on-harm-reduction-a-public-health-calamity/</link><description>The European Commission's proposed revision to the Tobacco Excise Directive is criticized for targeting vaping products and safer nicotine alternatives, potentially increasing smoking rates. The taxing system could make these products more expensive than cigarettes, opposing harm reduction efforts. Scientific evidence proving the lower harm of alternatives is disregarded. By attacking harm reduction instead of combating smoking, the EU might unintentionally promote smoking and illicit trade. The UK's independent stance is highlighted as an opportunity to reject harmful policies. Embracing tobacco harm reduction is crucial for public health progress, requiring a rejection of the Commission's damaging proposals. (Published on July 25, 2025bytobaccoharmreduction.net)</description></item></channel></rss>