<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 12:27:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #5 | Tackling Misinformation in Nicotine Policy</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-5-tackling-misinformation-in-nicotinepolicy/</link><description>In this episode of GFN Voices we're joined by Dorrie Heemskerk to bring you some expert insight into efforts to counter misinformation in public policy. (Published on August 08, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Are Tobacco Taxes Still a Reliable Source of Revenue?</title><link>https://taxfoundation.org/blog/tobacco-taxes-cigarette-tax-revenue</link><description>Tobacco taxes have been a cash cow for governments around the world. World Health Organization (WHO) data suggest that combined annual global taxes on cigarettes are approaching $1 trillion. In many countries, however, cigarette tax collections shrink each year because fewer people smoke. This tremendous win for public health should be a cause for celebration. But for governments that have become (...) (Published on August 08, 2025bytaxfoundation.org)</description></item><item><title>Ireland’s Crackdown on Vape Sales to Minors Sees Few Consequences</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/08/07/irelands-crackdown-on-vape-sales-to-minors-sees-few-consequences</link><description>Nearly 15% of retailers across Ireland have been caught violating laws banning the sale of vapes to children, with only a fraction facing legal consequences, according to new figures from the Health Service Executive (HSE). Enacted in December 2023, the law makes it illegal to sell nicotine-inhaling products to those under 18 years old. (Published on August 08, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>85% of UK Vapers Switch to Reusables Post Single-Use Ban</title><link>https://grocerytrader.co.uk/85-of-uk-vapers-switch-to-reusables-post-single-use-ban</link><description>New research shows that the majority of UK vapers now use reusable devices and are purchasing refills following the single-use vapes ban – indicating a positive shift toward more sustainable vaping behaviours. (Published on August 08, 2025bygrocerytrader.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Can Nicotine Pouches Help Break the Coffee-Jitter Cycle?</title><link>https://nerdbot.com/2025/08/07/can-nicotine-pouches-help-break-the-coffee-jitter-cycle</link><description>The modern professional’s relationship with coffee often becomes a complex dance of energy highs and jittery lows, creating a cycle of dependency that can interfere with sustained productivity and well-being. As more individuals seek alternatives to the caffeine rollercoaster, the question arises: can nicotine pouches provide the focused energy we crave without the uncomfortable side effects that often accompany excessive coffee consumption? (Published on August 08, 2025bynerdbot.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine Pouches vs. E-Cigarettes: Navigating Harm Reduction for Smokers</title><link>https://www.igeekphone.com/nicotine-pouches-vs-e-cigarettes-navigating-harm-reduction-for-smokers</link><description>For adult smokers seeking alternatives to combustible cigarettes, the landscape of nicotine products has expanded significantly. Two prominent options are nicotine pouches and e-cigarettes (vapes). Both deliver nicotine without tobacco combustion – the primary source of smoking’s devastating health harms – but they work very differently. The question of which is (…) (Published on August 08, 2025byigeekphone.com)</description></item></channel></rss>