<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 12:26:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New study finds hidden diabetes danger in vaping</title><link>https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2025/11/251112111029.htm</link><description>Research from the University of Georgia shows that using e-cigarettes, traditional cigarettes, or both increases the risk of developing diabetes. Lead author Sulakshan Neupane highlights the potential health risks associated with e-cigarette use, with vaping alone linked to a 7% increase in prediabetes risk. The study also found that smoking cigarettes or cigars raised prediabetes risk by 15%, with even higher risks for dual users. Factors such as weight, income, and demographics further influenced the likelihood of developing these conditions. Neupane suggests that regular physical activity may help counter some harmful effects. The study emphasizes the need for public health efforts to address smoking and diabetes outcomes. (Published on November 13, 2025bysciencedaily.com)</description></item><item><title>Opinion: How e-cigarettes compromise children's human rights</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-11-opinion-cigarettes-compromise-children-human.html</link><description>Experts argue that exposing children to e-cigarettes violates their rights, urging regulations prioritizing children's well-being. With youth e-cigarette use outpacing adults' globally, the World Health Organization stresses that children are more vulnerable to nicotine's harms due to ongoing brain development. Despite legal obligations to protect children under the UN Convention, 62 countries lack e-cigarette regulations. Advocates emphasize the need for stringent regulations to curb youth usage, including sales bans and marketing restrictions. Governments must address enforcement challenges like online marketing to effectively safeguard children's health. Neglecting children's well-being in e-cigarette regulation may have enduring negative repercussions. (Published on November 13, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>International researchers: “WHO risks lives by discouraging smoke-free alternatives”</title><link>https://www.vejpkollen.se/en/2025/11/internationella-forskare-who-riskerar-liv-nar-man-motarbetar-rokfria-alternativ/</link><description>Leading scientists criticize the WHO for discouraging smoke-free alternatives like e-cigarettes, snus, and nicotine pouches that can reduce nicotine risks. The organization views harm reduction as a tobacco industry scheme, sparking debate among experts who argue for a more science-based approach. Researchers urge the WHO to engage in open dialogue on smoke-free nicotine products to advance public health goals. Critics note the success of these alternatives in helping smokers quit and reducing harm. The debate highlights the need for evidence-based regulation and a shift towards inclusive discussions to promote a smoke-free society globally. (Published on November 13, 2025byvejpkollen.se)</description></item></channel></rss>