<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 05:19:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pod-style electronic cigarettes found to be more addictive than nicotine gum</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250520/Pod-style-electronic-cigarettes-found-to-be-more-addictive-than-nicotine-gum.aspx</link><description>A study in Nicotine and Tobacco Research by Oxford University Press reveals that modern pod-style e-cigarettes are more addictive than nicotine gum, posing a high risk of abuse. These devices, favored by youth, deliver nicotine efficiently, especially to non-smokers. Researchers compared pod-style e-cigarettes to nicotine gum in nonsmoking young adults and found e-cigarettes more satisfying and craving-reducing. The appeal of these devices lies in the use of nicotine salts, which lessen the unpleasant taste of higher nicotine levels. The study emphasizes the addictive potential of e-cigarettes, particularly among inexperienced users like youth and young adults, prompting caution. (Published on May 21, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #152 | PAKISTAN'S TOBACCO CONTROL PROBLEM | Can Pakistan get on track with tobacco harm reduction?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-152-pakistans-tobacco-control-problem-can-pakistan-get-on-track-with-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>30 million people currently smoke in Pakistan, but could safer nicotine products such as nicotine pouches succeed where other tobacco control efforts have struggled? Joining us today is Ziauddin Islam, a tobacco control expert and former Technical Representative to the WHO FCTC and ITP, to highlight the direction of Pakistan's tobacco control efforts. (Published on May 21, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Safer Solutions: Common Ground on Harm Reduction in Drugs and Tobacco</title><link>https://www.rstreet.org/commentary/safer-solutions-common-ground-on-harm-reduction-in-drugs-and-tobacco/</link><description>Text advocates for collaboration in harm reduction for drug and tobacco use. Both groups face addiction, health risks, and stigmas. Support for harm reduction tools like syringe programs and e-cigarettes can improve health outcomes. Political divides, misinformation, and discomfort hinder progress. Bridging the gap and recognizing commonalities could lead to a more effective, holistic approach. Recent efforts show promise in integrating harm reduction strategies. Encouraging collaboration between drug and tobacco harm reduction supporters is crucial for comprehensive support. Recognizing shared challenges can help create a united front transcending ideological differences. (Published on May 21, 2025byrstreet.org)</description></item><item><title>The Real Threat? The Hypocrisy Behind Flavored Vape Bans</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/the-real-threat-the-hypocrisy-behind-flavored-vape-bans-while-flavored-alcohol-gets-a-free-pass/</link><description>The U.S. crackdown on flavored vapes raises concerns of a double standard compared to alcohol products marketed with kid-friendly flavors. Despite alcohol's proven harm to youths, focus remains on banning vapes to safeguard minors, overlooking their role in harm reduction for adult smokers. Sweeping bans benefit big tobacco, shutting out small vape shops and effective quitting tools. To truly prioritize public health, the government should regulate flavored vapes like alcohol, fund education, and support safer vape products while addressing adult smokers' needs. The struggle against flavored vapes reflects control issues rather than youth protection, urging a shift towards harm reduction recognition and better policy decisions. (Published on May 21, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>The effects of vaping on your body just one hour after first puff</title><link>https://www.dailyrecord.co.uk/lifestyle/effects-vaping-your-body-just-35264494</link><description>Vaping, even just one hour after the first puff, can lead to immediate effects such as increased heart rate and blood pressure, along with potential lung irritation. Disposable vapes will soon be banned in the UK, with concerns about their impact on health. While vaping may have fewer harmful chemicals than traditional smoking, it still poses risks like chronic lung damage. The long-term effects of vaping are still being studied, but evidence suggests it could lead to reduced lung function and skin issues over time. Traditional smoking has more immediate negative impacts, including cardiovascular strain and lung damage. (Published on May 21, 2025bydailyrecord.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Tectonic Shift | Consumers Leave Tobacco Control Behind | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/tectonic-shift-consumers-leave-tobacco-control-behind-regwatch/</link><description>Over the past decade, tobacco control has waged war on vaping. They have demonized, taxed, restricted, and banned safer nicotine products. They’ve misrepresented science and misinformed the public, all in a misguided effort to eliminate nicotine use entirely. But U.S. consumers aren’t buying it. They’re rejecting the panic, sidestepping the bans, and switching to nicotine vapes by the millions.  According to Goldman Sachs, sales of smoke-free nicotine products will overtake combustible cigarettes in the U.S. this year. It’s a seismic shift in the nicotine market, and yet public health remains silent. Joining RegWatch to break down this realignment is Dr. Charles Gardner, a key figure in tobacco harm reduction and a relentless advocate for evidence-based public health. Gardner says the age of smoking is ending and almost nobody knows it. (Published on May 21, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>‘Vape products should be taxed higher than cigarettes’</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/business/2025/05/20/2444291/vape-products-should-be-taxed-higher-cigarettes</link><description>The government discussed taxing vape products higher than cigarettes due to increasing youth consumption. BIR suggested different tax rates for vapes to prevent revenue loss. Concerns over vape use by adolescents were raised, with a 40% increase since 2021. Measures like excise stamps were implemented to regulate vape products. Senate deliberations include proposals to amend tobacco excise taxes to address illicit trade. PMFTC recommended an odd-even tax scheme for tobacco products to enhance revenue. Enforcement against illicit trade is considered crucial over tax adjustments. The aim is to balance tax rates while combating illegal activities in the industry. (Published on May 21, 2025byphilstar.com)</description></item></channel></rss>