<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 12:24:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>FDA calls for child-resistant packaging for nicotine pouches</title><link>https://www.packaging-gateway.com/news/us-fda-child-resistant-packaging-nicotine/</link><description>The US FDA has called on nicotine pouch manufacturers to use child-resistant packaging after a rise in accidental exposures, most involving children under five. The products contain high levels of nicotine, which can be dangerous or even fatal to young children in small amounts. Toxic reactions have been documented in children with nicotine amounts as low as 1mg to 4mg, according to the US federal agency. Symptoms associated with nicotine poisoning can include confusion, vomiting and loss of consciousness. (Published on September 03, 2025bypackaging-gateway.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #9 | Is the Media Stuck in the Past on Tobacco and Vaping?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-9/</link><description>The media often frames tobacco in a way that feels stuck in the 1990s—ignoring new science and harm reduction tools like e-cigarettes, snus, and nicotine pouches. In this interview, journalist Jacob Grier explains why coverage of smoking and tobacco policy is often outdated, how this impacts public perception, and why it’s time to rethink the conversation around nicotine. (Published on September 03, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Doctors Want FDA to Share Up-to-Date Info on Lower-Risk, Smoke-Free Products, Survey Finds</title><link>https://www.thewellnews.com/opinions/doctors-want-fda-to-share-up-to-date-info-on-lower-risk-smoke-free-products-survey-finds/</link><description>Many healthcare professionals find it difficult to keep up with rapid changes in nicotine products. A survey suggests the FDA could play a key role in providing guidance, but the agency has so far remained largely absent from the discussion. A recent national survey found that 93% of medical professionals believe the FDA has a duty to inform the medical community when a smoke-free product is shown to carry less risk than smoking. Nearly all (95%) said they would pass this information on to their adult patients who smoke. However, the FDA has remained largely silent on the issue, and many healthcare providers are unaware of which products regulators have reviewed for safety and efficacy. (Published on September 03, 2025bythewellnews.com)</description></item><item><title>Seriously, it’s time to sort out cigarettes and vapes</title><link>https://citynews.com.au/2025/seriously-its-time-to-sort-out-cigarettes-and-vapes/</link><description>The black market for cigarettes, tobacco, and vapes in Australia is growing and leading to violence. Despite high cigarette prices, illegal supplies are popular, with a significant black market presence. Vaping restrictions have not been successful, prompting increased vaping black market activities. The high cigarette excise has unintended negative consequences, with estimates of a $10 billion annual revenue loss for the government. New Zealand's successful approach to promoting safer nicotine options over cigarettes highlights Australia's failure in tobacco and vaping policies. Suggestions include reducing cigarette excise and increasing availability of safer nicotine products. The tobacco industry is shifting towards smoke-free products, which are becoming more profitable. Australia should consider following NZ's lead in tobacco harm reduction policies to combat the black market. (Published on September 03, 2025bycitynews.com.au)</description></item><item><title>España, ante un nuevo frente en Bruselas por la guerra de Mónica García a las bolsas de nicotina</title><link>https://www.libertaddigital.com/libremercado/2025-08-27/mi-espana-ante-un-nuevo-frente-en-bruselas-por-la-guerra-de-monica-garcia-a-las-bolsas-de-nicotina-7288902/?utm_campaign=url_rewrite&amp;utm_medium=Social&amp;utm_source=Twitter</link><description>The Spanish government is in conflict with Brussels again, this time over a Health Ministry bill pushed by the left-wing Sumar coalition. The proposal seeks to heavily restrict the vaping and nicotine pouch market by banning all e-cigarette flavors except tobacco and capping nicotine pouches at 0.99 mg, which would effectively remove them from the market. The plan has sparked strong criticism within the EU. Seven countries — Hungary, Italy, Romania, Sweden, Greece, the Czech Republic and Croatia — along with the European Commission, have raised formal objections, arguing that Spain’s proposal violates the principle of free movement of goods, a cornerstone of the single market. Currently, 18 member states allow flavored vapes and 13 permit nicotine pouches. (Published on September 03, 2025bylibertaddigital.com)</description></item><item><title>Australia E-Cigarette Market: A Smoke-Free Future Gaining Momentum</title><link>https://vocal.media/journal/australia-e-cigarette-market-a-smoke-free-future-gaining-momentum</link><description>Australia’s tobacco industry is shifting as more consumers turn to e-cigarettes. The e-cigarette market, valued at US$ 572.1 million in 2024, is projected to reach US$ 1,479.6 million by 2033, growing at a CAGR of 11.1%. E-cigarettes are battery-powered devices that heat a liquid containing nicotine and flavorings, simulating smoking without burning tobacco, thus avoiding tar and many harmful chemicals found in conventional cigarettes. (Published on September 03, 2025byvocal.media)</description></item></channel></rss>