<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 06:18:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Does Diacetyl Cause Popcorn Lung from Vaping?</title><link>https://vaping360.com/learn/popcorn-lung-diacetyl/</link><description>"Popcorn lung, or bronchiolitis obliterans, is a severe lung condition where the smallest airways scar and decrease efficiency. It has no cure except for lung transplant and can be caused by infections or exposure to chemical particles. Diketones like diacetyl are commonly linked to the condition, but other chemicals such as chlorine and ammonia can also lead to it. Interestingly, lung transplants, the main treatment, can also cause popcorn lung, contributing to bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome, a major form of lung transplant rejection." (Published on June 12, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>Freely available nicotine replacement therapy raises rate of people who quit smoking</title><link>https://www.irishexaminer.com/news/arid-41649287.html</link><description>Research in Ireland shows higher smoking cessation rates after the introduction of free nicotine replacement therapy. The study found that access to free NRT led to 41% of smokers quitting after four weeks, compared to 29% when it was not free. The findings suggest the benefits of providing free NRT to smokers. The study also noted an increase in NRT uptake and identified groups, such as women and long-term smokers, benefitting from the free therapy. The results highlight the importance of universal NRT access in promoting successful smoking cessation and call for equitable access on an international scale to combat smoking-related deaths. (Published on June 12, 2025byirishexaminer.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping industry calls for smarter nicotine policies as smoking rates surge in South Africa</title><link>https://africannewsagency.com/vaping-industry-calls-for-smarter-nicotine-policies-as-smoking-rates-surge-in-south-africa/</link><description>The vaping industry in South Africa calls for smarter nicotine policies amidst rising tobacco smoking rates. Parliament is reviewing the Tobacco Bill to regulate product processing, advertising, and appearance. Vaping advocates stress the need for evidence-based nicotine policies, cessation support, and harm reduction tools like e-cigarettes. With smoking prevalence increasing, there's a call for a shift towards safer alternatives and better enforcement. The Advertising Regulatory Board supports regulating vapor products, highlighting health benefits for smokers who switch. It emphasizes clear communication of benefits while discouraging non-smokers from vaping. Collaboration with the industry led to guidelines including restrictions on marketing to minors and health claims. (Published on June 12, 2025byafricannewsagency.com)</description></item><item><title>A public health milestone</title><link>https://www.brecorder.com/news/amp/40367280</link><description>The Punjab government led by Chief Minister Maryam Nawaz Sharif has enforced a ban on e-cigarettes, vapes, and nicotine pouches to safeguard public health, citing concerns over youth usage. Health experts highlight the harmful effects of nicotine products on various body systems. The move follows similar bans in other countries due to safety concerns. Advocates stress the need for a national ban to protect youth from addiction and health risks. Punjab's proactive step underscores the urgency for broader regulations and enforcement nationwide to align with global tobacco control standards. The ban reflects a critical shift towards prioritizing public health over industry profits. (Published on June 12, 2025bybrecorder.com)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco excise has passed a ‘tipping point’ and is fuelling black market, economists warn</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jun/11/tobacco-excise-isnt-making-australians-smoke-less-and-should-be-frozen-to-curb-black-market-economists-say?CMP=share_btn_url</link><description>Economists suggest freezing or reducing the tobacco excise to tackle Australia's booming illegal cigarette market, as raising the excise further has failed to curb smoking rates. However, public health advocates warn against drastic tax cuts. The excise, which has tripled in the past decade, comprises a major portion of cigarette prices. Despite successful past policies reducing smoking rates, current measures are ineffective. Border seizures of illegal tobacco have surged, prompting calls for stronger enforcement over tax decreases. Experts argue that the excise level has become counterproductive, suggesting a temporary radical cut. The excise rate, now heavily indexed and escalating annually, needs revision to combat illicit tobacco trade. (Published on June 12, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item></channel></rss>