<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:16:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vape boss says allowing 'strict' ads would help smokers quit</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c3w5y7979vzo</link><description>BAT's UK and Ireland boss advocates for a "very strict" marketing framework to encourage smokers to switch to vapes. While the UK opposes further vape marketing, BAT sees advertising as essential for informing smokers about alternatives. The company's focus on closed vaping systems aims to reduce smoking rates. Despite concerns over vaping's long-term effects, it's considered less harmful than smoking. The Tobacco and Vapes Bill aims to restrict advertising and underage sales to achieve a smoke-free generation. BAT opposes the bill's restrictions and argues for looser advertising rules and more penalties for underage sales. Ertonguc believes these measures will have a bigger impact on reducing smoking rates than the government's current legislation. (Published on October 10, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>The Precautionary Principle and Harm Reduction</title><link>https://www.thefirebreak.org/p/the-precautionary-principle-and-harm</link><description>Precaution is essential for safety, but when translated into regulatory concepts by the European Commission, conflicts arise. The Gee Definition shifts the burden of proof for safety onto producers, hindering innovation. This approach, applied to GMOs and tobacco harm reduction products, leads to bans despite strong evidence of safety. Activists push a hazard-based approach, impacting regulations like the Sustainable Use of Pesticides Directive. The Commission's confusion between the precautionary principle and risk management hinders the acceptance of harm reduction alternatives. A shift towards understanding and implementing basic risk management concepts is crucial for rational policymaking. (Published on October 10, 2025bythefirebreak.org)</description></item><item><title>Consumer group slams 900% vape tax proposal as ‘illogical and self-defeating’</title><link>https://www.scoop.my/news/270432/consumer-group-slams-900-vape-tax-proposal-as-illogical-and-self-defeating/?fbclid=IwQ0xDSwNT36VjbGNrA1PfnmV4dG4DYWVtAjExAAEeeIwYzQ6WTHoYrFffgti4ddMIgkaGv5Hr0t8JlRVB5aUj3MBcnVE0EOTYzEQ_aem_KbY1TW6HibFpisirU0XFTw</link><description>Samsul Kamal Ariffin critiqued Malaysia's Health Ministry proposal to raise vape liquid excise duty by 900%, considering it illogical and detrimental to public health objectives. He emphasized the importance of treating vaping as a tobacco harm reduction tool to assist smokers in quitting. Samsul warned that banning or heavily taxing vape products could lead to an increase in the black market and harm stakeholders. The Finance Ministry had initially considered a more moderate tax increase from 40 sen to 80 sen per milliliter. Samsul urged the government to regulate vaping effectively for the benefit of public health, retailers, and tax revenue. (Published on October 10, 2025byscoop.my)</description></item><item><title>Shops to require licence to sell vapes under proposed crackdown on rogue traders</title><link>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/business/government-shops-stephen-kinnock-lga-vaping-b2841642.html</link><description>The Government plans to introduce licensing for shops selling vapes and tobacco to combat rogue traders targeting children. The licensing aims to shut down illicit operators and support legitimate retailers, with fines for rule breakers. The Tobacco and Vapes Bill will also ban advertising, regulate flavors, and restrict where products are displayed. The move aims to protect children and curb youth vaping. Various organizations, including ASH and IBVTA, support evidence-based regulations. Local councils seek a balanced licensing system to safeguard youth without burdening responsible retailers. (Published on October 10, 2025byindependent.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Health NZ seeking to give more vaping kits to smokers wanting to quit, talks up PR benefits to suppliers</title><link>https://www.nzherald.co.nz/nz/health-nz-seeking-to-give-more-vaping-kits-to-smokers-wanting-to-quit-talks-up-pr-benefits-to-suppliers/DATIHYPFJJG5DN2QOHBJINKXLM/</link><description>Health NZ's pilot programme provided vapes to 29 smoking cessation programs. Approximately 33% of 4326 individuals who quit smoking in seven months used the vaping kits. Health NZ is seeking quotes for more vapes to potentially continue the program permanently, depending on results. Vapes with various nicotine strengths and flavors are being requested. The pilot's success has prompted confidence in the continuation of supplying vapes. However, concerns have been raised by medical professionals and organizations regarding the approach of using vapes as a smoking cessation tool due to limited evidence supporting its efficacy and potential risks. (Published on October 10, 2025bynzherald.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #74 | STONEWALLED | The March Toward Nicotine Prohibition</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-74-stonewalled-the-march-toward-nicotine-prohibition/</link><description>It was perhaps inevitable that once smoking was “handled,” tobacco control would turn its fire on nicotine. From the UK’s disposable vape ban to EU pouch restrictions and the WHO’s war on nicotine, prohibition is on the march. Shot on location at GFN 2025 in Warsaw, Christopher Snowdon, Head of Lifestyle Economics at the Institute of Economic Affairs, delivers a stark assessment: public health is recycling old fears, ignoring evidence, and steering policy into prohibitionist chaos. With governments fueling black markets and pushing vapers back to smoking, Snowdon warns the war on nicotine has only just begun. (Published on October 10, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>