<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:27:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From cessation to celebration: Nicotine pouches go viral on TikTok</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-12-cessation-celebration-nicotine-pouches-viral.html</link><description>UBC Okanagan research by Dr. Struik warns of the misleading trendiness of oral nicotine pouches promoted on TikTok, particularly Zyn, as pleasurable lifestyle choices instead of cessation aids. Social media glamorizes these products, increasing appeal among youth despite health risks like oral cancer and heart issues. 250 TikTok videos analyzed show normalization of use, with some videos highlighting multiple pouch use and integration into daily life. This normalization, along with a sense of empowerment and exclusivity, contributes to their popularity among teens. Dr. Struik emphasizes the urgent need for public health efforts to combat the tobacco industry's exploitation of social media in targeting vulnerable youth for nicotine addiction. (Published on December 02, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Health Canada let kids get nicotine while blaming industry</title><link>https://www.rebelnews.com/nicotine_pouches_blamed_for_federal_government_failures</link><description>Nicotine pouches causing controversy in Canada due to harm to children, monopolies, rising black markets, and restricted industry regulations. Pouches, alternative to cigarettes, contain nicotine but lack full health understanding. Despite health risks, popular demand prompted growth. Regulators approved Zonnic by Imperial Tobacco as a nicotine replacement therapy. With minimal existing restrictions, critics pushed for tighter laws to protect youth. In 2024, Health Canada began stringent regulations, limiting sales to pharmacies and mint flavor only. While criticized for monopoly control, government action sought to limit accessibility but did not ban sales to minors. Pharmaceutical industry is scrutinized less for harmful products compared to tobacco industry. (Published on December 02, 2025byrebelnews.com)</description></item><item><title>Why the World Health Organization’s anti-nicotine policy could keep millions smoking</title><link>https://reason.org/commentary/why-the-world-health-organizations-anti-nicotine-policy-could-keep-millions-smoking/</link><description>The WHO urges strict regulation and even bans on e-cigarettes and other nicotine alternatives like heated tobacco. Despite successful harm reduction in countries like the UK, the WHO promotes quit helplines and nicotine replacement therapies, which have lower success rates and are inaccessible in low-income areas. The organization's stance goes against evidence that vaping is safer, with countries like the US, UK, and Canada endorsing it. The WHO's strategy risks hindering smokers from switching to safer options, leading to more smoking-related deaths and illnesses. Overlooking the success of harm reduction methods, the WHO's recommendations may perpetuate smoking-related health issues globally. (Published on December 02, 2025byreason.org)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco control measures shouldn't go up in smoke</title><link>https://www.chinadaily.com.cn/a/202512/02/WS692e23e1a310d6866eb2c5b9.html</link><description>China has struggled with high smoking rates despite efforts. In the past decade, the number of smokers decreased but remains at 300 million. Public opinion on smoking has shifted due to campaigns and regulations. China now aims to further reduce smoking rates to 20% by 2030. Challenges include enforcement in public spaces and among businesses. Stricter laws and increased tobacco taxes have shown progress, with 60 million fewer smokers in recent years. To meet future targets, continued public and administrative support is crucial. Failure to enforce regulations may hinder efforts to improve public health and reduce smoking rates in China. (Published on December 02, 2025bychinadaily.com.cn)</description></item></channel></rss>