<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 12:26:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>#GFN25 Keynote #3 | Battling misinformation from the newsroom to the Facebook comment section</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn25-keynote-3-battling-misinformation-from-the-newsroom-to-the-facebook-comment-section/</link><description>GFN 2025 Keynote #3 - delivered by Maria Papaioannoy-Duic, hosted by Jagannath Sarangapani, response from Konstantinos Farsalinos. A consumer advocates’ approach, cutting through the noise to deliver factually accurate information about safer nicotine products is a constant struggle. Maria will present a ‘real-world how-to guide’, drawn from the lived experience of consumer advocates, identifying some useful tools to counter vaping and THR misinformation. (Published on July 17, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Global scholarship programme seeks tobacco harm reduction leaders of tomorrow – two weeks left to apply — Global State of Tobacco Harm Reduction</title><link>https://gsthr.org/media-centre/global-scholarship-programme-seeks-tobacco-harm-reduction-leaders-of-tomorrow-two-weeks-left-to-apply/</link><description>K·A·C's Tobacco Harm Reduction Scholarship Program is open for its eighth cohort, with a deadline on July 31, 2025, offering mentoring, policy grounding, stipend, and 25 entry-level positions. The program aims to develop tobacco harm reduction leaders globally. Applicants must complete an online course before submitting project ideas. THRSP focuses on low and middle-income countries to reduce smoking-related deaths and enhance research and practice in harm reduction. Scholars undertake projects to improve understanding or communication in their regions. Past scholars have contributed research, networks, and media resources in the field. (Published on July 17, 2025bygsthr.org)</description></item><item><title>Op-Ed: It’s time for NJ to finish the job on flavored vapes</title><link>https://www.njspotlightnews.org/2025/07/op-ed-urges-nj-get-real-about-enforcing-flavored-vape-ban/</link><description>New Jersey, a longtime leader in tobacco prevention, banned flavored vaping products in 2020 to protect youth. However, e-cigarette use among teens remains high, with 18.2% of high school students reporting current use. New legislation aims to strengthen enforcement of the ban by increasing penalties, requiring more inspections, and prohibiting deliveries to those under 21. Lawmakers are urged to pass these measures quickly to better protect young people’s health. (Published on July 17, 2025bynjspotlightnews.org)</description></item><item><title>My new white paper, "Tobacco Harm Reduction: Policy And Practice" published by the Hispanic Leadership Fund</title><link>https://carlvphillips.substack.com/p/my-new-white-paper-tobacco-harm-reduction</link><description>The text discusses a white paper on Tobacco Harm Reduction (THR) by Carl V. Phillips, highlighting the benefits of low-risk nicotine alternatives like vaping for reducing smoking rates. It criticizes U.S. policies hindering THR progress and emphasizes the need for targeted education and policy changes to support harm reduction, especially in Hispanic and minority communities. International examples show the positive impact of supportive environments on smoking reduction. Recommendations include ending misinformation campaigns, reducing barriers to low-risk products, and focusing on underserved populations. Overall, the paper advocates for government support of harm reduction to improve public health, particularly in marginalized communities. (Published on July 17, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches sold to children mimic sweets, says UK trading standards body</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jul/17/nicotine-pouches-sold-to-children-mimic-sweets-says-uk-trading-standards-body</link><description>Nicotine pouches, marketed with sweet flavors and colorful packaging similar to sweets, are being sold legally to children due to regulatory gaps. While single-use vapes were banned in England to prevent youth use, there are no age restrictions for nicotine pouches. The Chartered Trading Standards Institute is concerned about the appeal of these products to minors. Legislation in the tobacco and vapes bill aims to restrict flavors, packaging, and advertising targeting children. Urgent action is needed to protect youth from the risks of nicotine pouches. The bill is in progress in the House of Lords, with a focus on preventing underage access and harmful marketing practices. (Published on July 17, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Juul can keep selling tobacco and menthol e-cigarettes, FDA decides</title><link>http://cbsnews.com/news/juul-sell-tobacco-menthol-e-cigarettes-fda-decides/</link><description>The FDA has decided to allow Juul to continue selling its tobacco and menthol-flavored e-cigarettes. The agency stated that Juul's research shows these products are less harmful for adult smokers who switch completely from traditional cigarettes. This decision follows years of controversy, with Juul being widely blamed for contributing to the rise in teen vaping. The ruling applies only to the tobacco and menthol versions, as Juul had already pulled its fruit and candy flavors from the market due to their appeal to teens. (Published on July 18, 2025bycbsnews.com)</description></item></channel></rss>