<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 01:02:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HSE issues vapes alert on six e-cigarettes falsely labelled as nicotine-free</title><link>https://www.irishexaminer.com/news/arid-41662427.html</link><description>The HSE warns against using six mislabeled vapes containing high levels of nicotine. Customers can return them to the store where purchased. Identified products are listed, with nicotine levels up to 30 mg/ml. Retailers are urged to ensure compliance to prevent risks and legal consequences. Irish regulations prohibit vape sales to under-18s and propose further restrictions on vape products, including color and flavor limits. Concerns persist about vaping's impact on smoking rates, prompting ongoing policy reviews. The Public Health Bill aims to curb youth vaping. Legislation was passed to raise the tobacco sales age to 21. Tobacco Free Ireland policy is being reviewed to achieve a tobacco-free country. (Published on July 03, 2025byirishexaminer.com)</description></item><item><title>Unflavored electronic cigarette exposure induces alterations in airway ciliary structure and function - Respiratory Research</title><link>https://respiratory-research.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12931-025-03302-w</link><description>Human airway basal stem cells were exposed to e-cigarette aerosols with various flavors, showing donor-dependent responses. Different flavors had minimal impact on cell populations, with strawberry flavor causing increase in basal and ciliated cells. Donor heterogeneity was observed in responses to different flavors. Unflavored e-cig aerosols affected ciliary function without cell loss, altering ciliary beat frequency and ultrastructure. Phosphoproteomic analysis revealed phosphorylation changes in pathways related to cilium organization, cadherin and actin binding, and Rho GTPase signaling. Dysregulation of these pathways may contribute to ciliary dysfunction caused by e-cig exposure. (Published on July 03, 2025bybiomedcentral.com)</description></item><item><title>Peer influence drives youth vaping epidemic, researchers find</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-07-peer-youth-vaping-epidemic.html</link><description>University of Queensland research reveals that youths with friends who vape are 15 times more likely to use e-cigarettes. Studies show a rise in underage vaping of cannabis compounds, with an alarming increase in synthetic cannabinoids use, posing health risks. Peer influence significantly impacts vaping trends, with disapproval from influential figures reducing likelihood of vaping. Social media plays a role in promoting vaping as a trendy lifestyle choice. More regulation, campaigns, and research are needed to address these concerning trends. Key findings include increased vaping of cannabis products and shifting social norms towards cigarette and e-cigarette use among American teens. (Published on July 03, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Ketamine: Would making the drug class A stop Gen Z using it?</title><link>https://www-bbc-com.cdn.ampproject.org/c/s/www.bbc.com/news/articles/c7vrdn6qejpo.amp</link><description>Vicky Unwin's warning against classifying ketamine as Class A stems from her daughter's fatal overdose. She advocates for legal regulation over criminalization of drugs. On the other hand, Dorset's PCC, David Sidwick, supports the move to Class A, citing a need for increased awareness and treatment resources. Ketamine misuse can lead to bladder damage, with a surge in usage among young adults. Parents like Unwin and Anne-Marie Cockburn advocate for harm reduction strategies and better drug education. Despite government concerns and potential reclassification, some feel more action is needed to address the growing drug issue among youth. (Published on July 03, 2025byampproject.org)</description></item><item><title>BAT France Welcomes New Standard for Nicotine Pouches</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/07/02/bat-france-welcomes-new-standard-for-nicotine-pouches/</link><description>BAT France welcomed the new AFNOR experimental standard XP V37-500, ensuring safety, quality, and transparency of nicotine pouches by setting strict guidelines. Developed with industry experts, it covers key areas like product composition (natural nicotine capped at 16.6 mg), manufacturing (GMP and traceability), toxicological evaluation, packaging (complying with European standards), and labeling (nicotine content, ingredients, allergens, warnings). Sébastien Charbonneau, BAT France's public affairs director, praised the standard as providing quality assurance and transparency for adult consumers in professional networks. (Published on July 03, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item></channel></rss>