<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:52:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>WHO urged to embrace harm reduction in tobacco convention</title><link>https://globalnation.inquirer.net/291248/who-urged-to-embrace-harm-reduction-in-tobacco-convention</link><description>International experts, including from the Philippines, are urging delegates to the WHO tobacco control meeting in November 2025 to back harm reduction. In a joint statement, they called on the WHO FCTC to fully integrate harm reduction into tobacco control, stressing that “combustion kills, not nicotine.” The appeal was made during a September 3 briefing in Makati City, organized by the Consumer Choice Center. (Published on September 12, 2025byinquirer.net)</description></item><item><title>Are Nicotine Pouch Poisonings Out of Control?</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/nicotine-pouch-poisonings-facts-vs-fear/</link><description>Nicotine pouch ingestions are receiving attention, with a reported 763% increase in cases. Data shows cigarettes are the main source of poisonings among children. Nicotine pouches, accounting for 1.4% of cases, have seen a rise in incidents. These pouches, easier to swallow, lead to more hospitalizations and complications. Child-resistant packaging for e-liquids reduced liquid nicotine poisonings by half. Some pouch brands have safety features, but there are concerns about non-approved products. Innovative solutions like ClicCan aim to enhance pouch security. Despite rising numbers, most incidents involve very young children at home. Brands should prioritize safety, but personal vigilance is crucial for child protection. (Published on September 12, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>