<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 12:22:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Marijuana may cause chromosomal defects in human egg cells, study finds</title><link>https://edition.cnn.com/2025/09/09/health/marijuana-female-fertility-study-wellness</link><description>New research suggests that higher levels of THC in marijuana may harm unfertilized eggs, potentially leading to infertility, miscarriage, and genetic defects in babies. A cautious approach to cannabis use when planning to conceive is advised. Studies show a rise in marijuana use during pregnancy, linked to negative outcomes like poor fetal development. The study highlights the impact of THC on egg maturation and chromosome formation but further research is needed. The increasing potency of THC poses risks, as consumers may not be aware of the levels in products. Experts recommend considering safer alternatives to manage symptoms. (Published on September 10, 2025bycnn.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #158 | New Taxes on Safer Nicotine Products Could Push Smokers Back to Cigarettes</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-158/</link><description>Across Europe, health experts are raising alarm over the European Commission’s plan to impose new taxes on reduced-risk nicotine products such as e‑cigarettes, heated tobacco and nicotine pouches. In this episode of GFN News on GFN.TV, Joanna Junak speaks with leading international specialists — including Fernando Bueno, Bernd Mayer, Garrett McGovern and Konstantinos Farsalinos — who explain why such taxation could have serious unintended consequences. (Published on September 10, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Spain's new smoking law plans could mean big changes for travellers</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/travel/2025/09/11/spains-new-smoking-law-plans-could-mean-big-changes-for-travellers</link><description>Spain's coalition government has passed a draft bill banning smoking and vaping in outdoor spaces, aiming to prioritize public health. This proposal has faced opposition from restaurant and bar owners. The ban includes various outdoor areas and targets a range of tobacco products. The legislation aligns with wider European efforts to curb smoking in public places. Spain aims to reduce tobacco-related deaths, though measures such as plain packaging are not currently included in the bill awaiting parliamentary approval. (Published on September 11, 2025byeuronews.com)</description></item></channel></rss>