<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Feb 2026 06:34:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Majority of French smokers turning to cross-border and illegal markets as prices rise, study finds</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/majority-of-french-smokers-turning-to-cross-border-and-illegal-markets-as-prices-rise-study-finds/</link><description>A survey by Ifop reveals that many French smokers buy cigarettes from abroad due to high taxes and regulations. Over half sourced products internationally, with wealthier consumers often traveling for cheaper options. Illicit markets are also prevalent, particularly among young, low-income individuals. The study found illegal vapes still in use despite bans. Cost primarily influences consumer choices, with many willing to turn to non-traditional channels if prices rise. Despite concerns, safety risks do not deter buyers. The research, based on 3,000 respondents, highlights the complex nature of France's tobacco and vaping market behavior. (Published on February 12, 2026byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Banning vaping in public? What is Labour smoking?</title><link>https://www.spiked-online.com/2025/09/23/banning-vaping-in-public-what-is-labour-smoking/</link><description>The UK government plans to ban vaping in public places, citing health concerns about exposure to nicotine and toxicants. However, this decision is not backed by scientific evidence supporting vaping as a safer alternative to smoking. Previous reviews by Public Health England found no significant health risks from passive vaping. The proposed ban lacks justification and could deter smokers from switching to less harmful alternatives. Banning vaping without conclusive evidence of harm may infringe on personal freedoms and perpetuate misconceptions about the risks of vaping compared to smoking. A precautionary approach without substantial risk assessment could hinder tobacco harm reduction efforts. (Published on February 13, 2026byspiked-online.com)</description></item><item><title>Limited remaining opportunities to present YOUR science at GFN26 in Warsaw</title><link>https://gfn.events/films/science-lab/</link><description>The hugely popularGFN ScienceLabreturns to GFN26, offering you the opportunity to present your science focussed THR-related research to the GFN audience. With only a limited number of presentation spots available, we don’t want you to miss the opportunity to showcase your amazing work in Warsaw. The deadline for submitting is17 April 2026but GFN ScienceLab sessions are popular, so early submissions are encouraged.Submit your GFN Science Lab films here. If selected to present a GFN ScienceLab session, participants will need topurchase a registrationto attend GFN 2026 in person. Take advantage of a GFN26 discount at the Warsaw Presidential via ouraccommodation page. (Published on February 13, 2026bygfn.events)</description></item><item><title>China regulator orders e-cigarette makers to halt new plants</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/china-regulator-orders-e-cigarette-makers-halt-new-plants-2026-02-13/</link><description>On Friday, the State Tobacco Monopoly Administration of China issued a notice aimed at curbing price wars in the country’s e-cigarette industry. The regulator instructed manufacturers to address overcapacity by suspending new investment projects and halting the construction of additional production plants. Although it stated that the overall capacity utilisation rate remains at a high level, the authority expressed concern about excessive expansion and intensified competition. The notice also warned companies not to circumvent the directive by building facilities officially designated for other products but in reality used to manufacture e-cigarettes. (Published on February 13, 2026byreuters.com)</description></item></channel></rss>