<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 12:28:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Will "Third of UK Teenagers Who Vape... Go On to Start Smoking"?</title><link>https://arielleselyaphd.substack.com/p/will-third-of-uk-teenagers-who-vape</link><description>A new study suggests youth vapers in 2018 share risk factors with teen smokers in 1974, but doesn’t prove vaping causes smoking. Actual smoking rates keep falling. The media overstated findings, ignoring that the study used estimated—not real—smoking rates, which may be inflated and misleading. (Published on August 04, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Environmental Impact of Vaping Devices: A Global Approach to Sustainability</title><link>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=5287029</link><description>The research explores the types of waste generated by vaping devices, including plastics that are difficult to degrade and potentially dangerous lithium batteries. It also analyzes the negative effects of this waste on nature and life, from soil and water pollution to impacts on flora and fauna. (Published on August 04, 2025byssrn.com)</description></item><item><title>When Good Intentions Go Wrong: How The UK’s Hardline Vape Measures are Backfiring</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/08/01/when-good-intentions-go-wrong-how-the-uks-hardline-vape-measures-are-backfiring/#:~:text=In%20the%20weeks%20following%20the,into%20effect%20on%20June%201st</link><description>As a result of the recent UK ban, we now have more evidence of how harsh vape restrictions risk backfiring, fueling black markets and misinformation—ultimately undermining harm reduction and making safer alternatives harder to access. (Published on August 04, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>France Moves Toward Balanced Regulation of Nicotine Pouches</title><link>https://www.ginn.global/france-moves-toward-balanced-regulation-of-nicotine-pouches</link><description>France is at a pivotal moment in determining the future of nicotine pouches, a tobacco-free oral product increasingly used by adult smokers as a lower-risk alternative to cigarettes. In 2024, the French government took a prohibitionist stance, notifying a draft decree that aimed to ban nicotine pouches entirely, including their production, sale, possession, and use. Framed as a youth protection measure, the proposal triggered immediate backlash from scientists, harm reduction advocates, and members of Parliament who viewed the move as excessive and counterproductive. (Published on August 04, 2025byginn.global)</description></item><item><title>Altria: Oral Nicotine Pouches Continue to Drive Growth</title><link>https://www.convenience.org/Media/Daily/2025/August/1/1_Altria-Oral-Pouches-Drive-Growth__Finance</link><description>In a recent earnings report, Altria said the category ‘grew to 52.0% of its U.S. oral tobacco category.’ In its earnings call this week, Altria Group Inc. reported total net revenues decreased (...) (Published on August 04, 2025byconvenience.org)</description></item></channel></rss>