<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 01:08:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vape Flavor Bans Increase Cigarette Sales in Canada, Too</title><link>https://filtermag.org/vape-flavor-bans-increase-cigarette-sales-canada/</link><description>Banning vape flavors can lead to increased cigarette sales, as shown by a study in Canada. Research demonstrates that restrictions on vape flavors backfire, causing a spike in cigarette purchases. Despite strict tobacco laws, flavor bans have proven counterproductive. Experts highlight the substitution effect between vapes and cigarettes, emphasizing the need for evidence-based public health policies. Advocates urge policymakers to consider the unintended consequences of flavor bans, which can undermine harm reduction efforts and public trust in health authorities. Calls for a science-based approach to regulating nicotine products aim to protect access to safer alternatives and prevent harmful outcomes. (Published on January 21, 2026byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Vaping after stopping smoking linked to lower risk of relapse back to smoking</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2026-01-vaping-linked-relapse.html</link><description>A study led by Queen Mary University of London found that smokers who quit with e-cigarettes and continue vaping may reduce the risk of relapse back to smoking. Compared to nicotine replacement therapies, e-cigarette use showed higher effectiveness in helping smokers stay smoke-free. Continuing vaping was associated with lower relapse rates, suggesting it could have a positive health impact. The study highlights the importance of further research to confirm these findings over a longer period. (Published on January 21, 2026bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Georgia targets tobacco-free status by 2040 amid surge in e-cigarette</title><link>https://georgiatoday.ge/georgia-targets-tobacco-free-status-by-2040-amid-surge-in-e-cigarette/</link><description>Georgia aims to be tobacco-free by 2040 but faces challenges due to increasing use of e-cigarettes. Despite progress in reducing tobacco use, consumption rates are high. The Tobacco Control Alliance urges action, emphasizing the need to curb alternative nicotine product use, particularly among the youth. To achieve the tobacco endgame policy, measures include taxing all tobacco equally, joining the Protocol to Eliminate Illicit Trade in Tobacco Products, and implementing plain packaging. Other recommendations involve restricting flavors, raising the legal age for tobacco purchase, and enforcing stricter regulations. Public support for these actions is high, emphasizing the need for political commitment to prioritize public health over tobacco industry interests. (Published on January 21, 2026bygeorgiatoday.ge)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #171 | Experts Clash Over European Heart Journal Claims</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-171-experts-clash-over-european-heart-journal-claims/</link><description>A new European Heart Journal report has reignited the debate over nicotine, heart health, and harm reduction. In this GFN News interview, Will Godfrey of Filter examines the claims that all forms of nicotine pose equal cardiovascular risk and the strong backlash from independent experts. The discussion explores criticisms of the report’s scientific approach, evidence from population studies, and concerns that its conclusions could influence upcoming EU tobacco, taxation, and health policies. With Europe already facing the world’s highest smoking rates, the video asks whether this narrative could undermine harm reduction efforts and discourage smokers from switching to less harmful alternatives. (Published on January 21, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>"A distinction without a difference" Hochul admin proposes tax on nicotine pouches</title><link>https://13wham.com/news/local/a-distinction-without-a-difference-hochul-admin-proposes-tax-on-nicotine-pouches-zyn-governor-new-york-blake-washington-budget-director-public-health-smoking-philip-morris-international</link><description>Governor Hochul's FY2027 budget proposes taxing nicotine pouches like Zyn under the tobacco products definition, drawing criticism from Philip Morris International. The FDA authorized Zyn in 2025 as a safer alternative for smokers. The Hochul Administration sees nicotine pouches as a public health concern despite their potential benefits. The proposed tax aims to generate $54 million in revenue, but critics argue it hinders smokers seeking healthier options. (Published on January 21, 2026by13wham.com)</description></item></channel></rss>