<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 12:25:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Smokeless Shift | Tobacco Exec on PMTA, Science &amp; Missed Opportunity | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/smokeless-shift-tobacco-exec-on-pmta-science-missed-opportunity-regwatch/</link><description>Youth smoking in the United States has collapsed to historic lows, yet public health remains silent. At the same time, adult smokers are moving in record numbers to safer nicotine products, signaling a profound market shift that regulators struggle to keep pace with. In this episode of RegWatch, Dr. Chris Junker [...], discusses the FDA’s slow-moving PMTA process, the collapse of youth smoking, and the importance of scientific transparency in tobacco harm reduction. (Published on September 29, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>French Nicotine Pouch Ban Even Prohibits Personal Possession</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/french-nicotine-pouch-ban-even-prohibits-personal-possession/</link><description>France will enforce a total ban on nicotine pouches starting in March 2026, following a decree from the health ministry. Despite objections from other EU countries, the government argues the measure is needed to protect public health, especially young people, as nicotine is deemed a health hazard. (Published on September 29, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping During Pregnancy Could Be Associated With Increased Risk of Adverse Events</title><link>https://www.drugtopics.com/view/vaping-during-pregnancy-could-be-associated-with-increased-risk-of-adverse-events</link><description>Vaping during pregnancy poses risks such as preterm birth, low birth weight, and fetal growth issues. A study suggests complete nicotine cessation for pregnant individuals due to harmful substances in e-cigarettes. Up to 7% of women vape during pregnancy, increasing concerns despite some considering it safer than smoking. Research shows a 40% higher risk of preterm birth, 49% risk of low birth weight, and 32% risk of small-for-gestational-age babies with vaping. The study reviewed data from 9 studies involving 423,680 pregnant women. Advocates stress the need to educate on risks, support quitting, and regulate vaping marketing to protect maternal and fetal health. (Published on September 29, 2025bydrugtopics.com)</description></item><item><title>WHO’s COP11 Will Threaten Tobacco Harm Reduction Behind Closed Doors</title><link>https://filtermag.org/who-cop11-tobacco-harm-reduction-closed-doors/</link><description>The upcoming COP11 in Geneva will address tobacco control policies with potential impacts on global public health. Concerns exist over the exclusion of THR advocates at previous conferences, affecting the discussions on harm reduction products such as vapes. The complex registration process for COP11 has attracted criticism, with fears of limited public participation. Despite resistance from the WHO, advocates aim to emphasize harm reduction benefits at the conference. Prominent countries like New Zealand have supported THR, indicating a hopeful shift in attitudes towards public health strategies. Advocates stress the need for the FCTC treaty to prioritize smoking-related harm and resist external influences for effective tobacco control. (Published on September 30, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item></channel></rss>