<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 12:26:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>'E-cigarette smoking' is a misleading term: a critical review of its use in academic literature</title><link>https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/40533720/</link><description>The academic literature's terminology around e-cigarette behaviors is crucial. Despite differences between vaping and tobacco smoking, terms like "e-cigarette smoking" are used interchangeably, potentially causing confusion. A study reviewed articles from 2015 to 2024 to assess the prevalence of these terms and their impact. The search across various databases identified widespread use of "e-cigarette smoking" and variants. Some highly cited studies also inaccurately linked e-cigarette use with smoking. Misleading terms could distort views on nicotine dependence, harm reduction, and policy-making. Standardizing language in research is vital for accurate communication and effective public health efforts. (Published on June 23, 2025bynih.gov)</description></item><item><title>Australia: Black Market Vape Sales Outpace Legal Products 1,700 to 1</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/8417/australia-black-market-vape-sales-outpace-legal-products/</link><description>Australia's legal vape market collapsed due to a government mandate forcing sales to pharmacies, leading to a thriving illicit market controlled in part by organized crime. Government data reveal that legal sales make up just 1 in 1,700 transactions, while over 10 million vapes are sold monthly on the black market. The pharmacy-only system, introduced in 2024, lacks widespread support among pharmacies, with only 700 out of 5,900 participating. This approach contrasts with the previous accessibility of vaping products. The failed policy has exacerbated black-market activities, decreased tobacco tax revenues, and spurred criminal involvement in the vape trade, resulting in violent conflicts among gangs. Legalizing and regulating vapes as consumer goods is a potential remedy. (Published on June 23, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>Australia risks losing ‘war on nicotine’ in same way as war on drugs as illegal tobacco sales explode</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/jun/23/australia-tobacco-excise-vape-regulation-war-on-nicotine?CMP=Share_iOSApp_Other</link><description>Australia is struggling with an ineffective approach to reducing nicotine use, sparking debate on combating the rise of illicit tobacco trade. Experts James Martin and Edward Jegasothy propose revamping tobacco taxation and vaping regulations. They argue that expensive legal cigarettes and restricted e-cigarette sales fuel the illegal market. Despite successful anti-smoking efforts, officials push for stricter enforcement over lower tobacco taxes. Calls for harm reduction strategies, including temporary excise removal and wider vape availability, arise. Concerns persist about illicit trade's impact on public health, with emphasis on balancing risks of smoking and vaping. Experts advocate for controlling supply and updating regulations to address the evolving tobacco landscape. (Published on June 23, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Evidence over Eminence | Garrett McGovern calls for tobacco control rethink at #GFN25</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/evidence-over-eminence-garrett-mcgovern-calls-for-tobacco-control-rethink-at-gfn25/</link><description>Ahead of the upcoming World Conference on Tobacco Control, leading addiction and harm reduction specialist Garrett McGovern sat down with Brent Stafford to underscore the issues with Tobacco Control's rejection of tobacco harm reduction, and why following the science is the only rational approach to public health policy. (Published on June 23, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>