<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 01:00:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nicotine inhalators discontinued: are vapes an alternative?</title><link>https://www.australianpharmacist.com.au/nicotine-inhalators-discontinued-are-vapes-a-suitable-alternative/</link><description>Although it was somewhat kept under wraps, nicotine inhalators – produced by companies such as Pfizer and Kenvue – have been discontinued. Are Pharmacist Only vapes the next best alternative? Deepali Gupta, an advanced cardiac pharmacist at Queensland Health and co-chair of the Statewide Smoking Cessation Working Group, first heard rumours in mid-2024 that nicotine inhalators would be discontinued. ‘It started with some reports from overseas,’ she said. ‘The reason for the discontinuation was that the resin needed to make the mouthpieces can no longer be sourced.’ This development impacts a significant group of patients with mental health conditions, many of whom have higher smoking rates and currently rely on inhalators as part of their nicotine replacement therapy. (Published on November 05, 2025byaustralianpharmacist.com.au)</description></item><item><title>Two Former WHO Leaders Warn: Rejecting Harm Reduction Will Cost 100 Million Lives</title><link>https://apnews.com/press-release/ein-presswire-newsmatics/two-former-who-leaders-warn-rejecting-harm-reduction-will-cost-100-million-lives-e190369c7d6701c720e9729fdd976f4d</link><description>Former WHO staff urges governments to adopt tobacco harm reduction, potentially saving 100 million lives. Experts Derek Yach and Tikki Pang advocate for revising the Tobacco Control Convention before the COP11 meeting. They emphasize the need for policy changes to promote safer nicotine products and criticize barriers to harm reduction in medical practices. Highlighting successful examples like Japan and the US, they warn of the health and economic burden on developing countries. Embracing harm reduction is crucial, especially in regions with high smoking rates. The experts urge a shift in approach towards tobacco control policies for improved public health outcomes globally. (Published on November 05, 2025byapnews.com)</description></item><item><title>Vapers overtake smokers for first time in Great Britain</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ceq0z9e2wwwo</link><description>In Great Britain, more adults now use vapes than smoke cigarettes for the first time according to the Office for National Statistics. Daily vape use is popular among 25-49 year olds, with increasing numbers of women vaping. Vaping has fewer risks than smoking, but long-term effects are uncertain. Health experts advise against vaping for non-smokers and children. Although smoking rates have decreased, there are still concerns about addiction and its impact on public health. Government measures have contributed to reducing smoking rates, with ongoing efforts to support communities with high smoking rates. Legislation is being introduced to restrict tobacco sales to those born after 2009. (Published on November 05, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping: A disruptive innovation of smoking and rapidly replacing cigarettes</title><link>https://johnmenadue.com/post/2025/11/vaping-a-disruptive-innovation-of-smoking-and-rapidly-replacing-cigarettes/</link><description>"Disruptive innovations" revolutionize markets by meeting consumer needs in new ways. The shift from cigarettes to safer nicotine products is akin to the transition from combustion engine cars to electric vehicles. Vaping, heated tobacco products, and nicotine pouches have gained popularity, with over 140 million users worldwide. Despite rapid growth, some countries resist these alternatives. Policies in the US and New Zealand support the transition, while Australia faces challenges due to restrictions leading to a growing black market. Ultimately, the trend towards safer nicotine options is reshaping the market, asserting its importance over traditional cigarettes globally. (Published on November 05, 2025byjohnmenadue.com)</description></item><item><title>GOLDBERG: Health Canada twists itself into pretzels to defy common sense</title><link>https://torontosun.com/opinion/columnists/health-canada-twists-into-pretzels-to-defy-common-sense</link><description>Health Canada is struggling to justify its decision to keep nicotine pouches out of convenience stores and restrict their sale to pharmacies. During a committee hearing, Deputy Health Minister Greg Orencsak acknowledged that the products were initially approved as a “less harmful” alternative to smoking and that Health Canada remains committed to helping Canadians quit. Despite this, the agency continues to support former health minister Mark Holland’s order requiring nicotine pouches to be sold only in pharmacies, limiting access to this effective smoking cessation aid. (Published on November 05, 2025bytorontosun.com)</description></item></channel></rss>