<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 12:23:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #73 | EMOTIONAL OVERRIDE | Why Feelings, Not Facts, Distort the Risk of Safer Nicotine</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-73/</link><description>Public health’s assault on vaping and safer nicotine products isn’t guided by evidence, it’s driven by fear, outrage, and a profound misunderstanding of risk. At GFN 2025 in Warsaw, David Zaruk, the “Risk-Monger,” reveals how emotion overrides science in policymaking. From the misuse of the Precautionary Principle to the denormalization of entire industries, Zaruk argues that activist zeal and WHO dogma have turned nicotine into a moral battleground, sacrificing harm reduction and leaving millions of smokers without safer options. (Published on October 01, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>What’s at stake for Malaysia as it eyes total ban on vapes by mid-2026?</title><link>https://www.channelnewsasia.com/asia/malaysia-vapes-ban-2026-health-minister-businesses-5375581</link><description>In Kuala Lumpur, a vape shop faces closure due to Malaysia's planned vape ban by mid-2026, leading to uncertain industry regulations. Health experts advocate for controlled regulation over a complete ban, citing concerns of boosting an illicit market. Authorities are urged to enhance enforcement of existing tobacco product laws. While some warn of health risks, others propose a harm reduction approach. Public Health Ministry's comment is awaited amid industry uncertainties. (Published on October 01, 2025bychannelnewsasia.com)</description></item></channel></rss>