<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 12:43:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Azerbaijan to impose fines on e-cigarettes sellers</title><link>https://www.muslimnetwork.tv/azerbaijan-to-impose-fines-on-e-cigarettes-sellers/</link><description>Azerbaijan plans to introduce fines for various activities related to electronic cigarettes, as outlined in a proposed draft law. The fines would apply to individuals, officials, and legal entities, with penalties ranging from 350 to 500 manat for individuals, 1,650 to 2,200 manat for officials, and 4,000 to 5,000 manat for legal entities. The legislation also includes confiscation of related goods. The amendments are set to take effect on April 1, 2026, alongside a broader ban on the import, export, production, storage, sale, and use of electronic cigarettes in Azerbaijan. (Published on February 24, 2026bymuslimnetwork.tv)</description></item><item><title>New York Gov. Hochul’s nicotine pouch tax would be bad for public health</title><link>https://reason.org/commentary/new-york-gov-hochuls-nicotine-pouch-tax-would-be-bad-for-public-health/</link><description>Gov. Hochul's $260 billion budget includes a new tax on nicotine pouches to match cigarette prices, raising $18 million initially and $44 million later. While meant to improve public health, pouches don't contain tobacco or produce smoke. They offer a safer alternative as proven by the FDA approval. However, taxing them heavily may deter smokers from switching, consequently boosting cigarette sales. Existing tobacco tax revenue could be better used to enforce compliance and prevention programs instead of introducing new taxes. (Published on February 24, 2026byreason.org)</description></item><item><title>That Vape in Your Bag Could Be a Problem on Your Next Mexico Cruise</title><link>https://www.aol.com/articles/vape-bag-could-problem-next-121000527.html?guccounter=1</link><description>Mexico has implemented a ban on vapes and e-cigarettes, including disposable and refillable devices, due to legal reforms. Travelers risk confiscation, fines, and even detainment if caught with vaping devices upon entering the country. While most cruise lines allow vaping onboard, bringing devices ashore in Mexico may lead to severe consequences. It's advised to leave vapes on the ship or avoid bringing them to Mexico altogether to avoid legal issues and penalties. Enforcement of the ban is increasing, making it a risky endeavor for travelers. (Published on February 24, 2026byaol.com)</description></item><item><title>Malaysia’s vape ban plan leaves 1.4 million users in regulatory limbo</title><link>https://www.scmp.com/week-asia/health-environment/article/3344146/malaysias-vape-ban-plan-leaves-14-million-users-regulatory-limbo</link><description>In Malaysia, vaping has shifted underground, becoming discreet and less openly available. Batrisyia notes the disappearance of prominent displays and online sales. Vapes are now sold quietly in some shops. The discreet pen-like devices offer a simple, odorless experience. In Pontian, Malaysia, where Batrisyia resides, the appeal of discretion has grown due to the underground nature of the trade. (Published on February 24, 2026byscmp.com)</description></item><item><title>“Disguised” Vape Flavor Ban Threatens Harm Reduction in Germany</title><link>https://filtermag.org/germany-vape-flavor-ban-menthol/</link><description>Germany plans to ban menthol vapes and cooling-flavored e-liquids to deter vaping appeal despite a high smoking rate. The ban aims to curb nicotine intake and dependence among young users. Critics argue insufficient evidence supports the ban and fear it will lead to increased smoking rates and youth access to unregulated products. Similar flavor bans have backfired in other countries, pushing consumers back to combustible cigarettes. Experts urge a harm reduction approach to nicotine to save lives effectively. The ban is deemed unrealistic in achieving Germany's smoking rate reduction goal. (Published on February 24, 2026byfiltermag.org)</description></item></channel></rss>