<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:18:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PMI Gets Approval to Produce Nicotine Pouches in Bangladesh</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/10/30/pmi-gets-approval-to-produce-nicotine-pouches-in-bangladesh/</link><description>Philip Morris got permission to set up a nicotine pouch factory in Bangladesh's Narayanganj with a $5.8 million investment. The annual production target is 536.3 million units. Anti-tobacco groups oppose the move but authorities view the pouches as non-nicotine items. While e-cigarettes are banned, these pouches are not. Regulatory checks are ongoing, with Philip Morris awaiting environmental clearance. (Published on October 31, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Luxembourg regulates nicotine pouches</title><link>https://delano.lu/article/luxembourg-regulates-nicotine-pouches</link><description>Luxembourg is enhancing its public health policy with Bill 8333, aligning anti-smoking laws with EU regulations. The bill bans flavorings in heated tobacco products, enforces health warnings, and sets marketing restrictions. It regulates nicotine pouches, limiting nicotine content and banning additives. Reactions are mixed, with health organizations supporting the stricter measures while the Chamber of Commerce criticizes potential economic impacts. The Council of State approved the bill in July 2025, and it will take effect soon. (Published on October 31, 2025bydelano.lu)</description></item><item><title>Cost of vaping to rise tomorrow as new tax on e-liquid kicks in</title><link>https://www.thejournal.ie/new-tax-vapes-eliquid-to-kick-in-6861204-Oct2025/</link><description>Starting tomorrow, a new tax of 50c per ml on e-liquid products in Ireland will increase vaping costs. The tax includes both nicotine and non-nicotine e-liquids, affecting prices significantly. To protect public health, the Minister for Finance stated the tax aims to curb youth consumption. Legislation is being drafted to ban single-use vapes and regulate flavors and packaging. A recent Lancet study shows a rise in nicotine use, especially among young people, linking it to vape availability since 2019. The tax reflects Ireland's dedication to public health amidst concerns over the increasing popularity of vapes among the youth. (Published on October 31, 2025bythejournal.ie)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #16 | HOW TO COMMUNICATE TOBACCO HARM REDUCTION?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/how-to-communicate-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>“Challenging Perceptions” — hear voices from around the world on how to communicate tobacco harm reduction effectively. From researchers to advocates, GFN 2025 brought powerful insights on evidence, empathy, and engagement. (Published on October 31, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Calling on users to have their say on EU nicotine taxes</title><link>https://www.vejpkollen.se/en/2025/10/uppmanar-brukare-att-tycka-till-om-eus-nikotinskatter-over-13-000-svar/</link><description>The European Commission is collecting feedback on a proposal to tax new nicotine products, causing concern in Sweden. The Swedish Snus Association opposes the tax hike, arguing it may hinder smoking reduction efforts. Over 13,000 European comments have been submitted, with many Swedes warning against increased prices for nicotine pouches. Users stress the importance of snus in reducing smoking rates and suggest taxing products based on risk level. Danish and French users agree, emphasizing the need for realistic alternatives and harm reduction. Concerns include potential black market growth and negative impact on national strategies to reduce smoking. (Published on October 31, 2025byvejpkollen.se)</description></item></channel></rss>