<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:57:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>LETTER: Cigarettes are everywhere, nicotine pouches hidden: How am I suppose to stay off the butts?</title><link>https://www.saltwire.com/newfoundland-labrador/letter-cigarettes-are-everywhere-nicotine-pouches-hidden-how-am-i-suppose-to-stay-off-the-butts</link><description>Cigarettes are everywhere. In gas stations, corner stores and vending machines. You can drive through half the outports in Newfoundland and Labrador and never worry about not finding a pack. Nicotine pouches on the other hand, are nowhere. Maybe at pharmacy counters if they happen to stock the right kind, and if you make it there before closing, and if you’re lucky enough they’re not sold out. (Published on September 18, 2025bysaltwire.com)</description></item><item><title>Why smoke-free innovation needs a multi-category strategy to succeed</title><link>https://www.thegrocer.co.uk/the-grocer-vision/whats-driving-the-next-gen-nicotine-category/709382.article</link><description>As cigarette sales decline and more adult smokers look for alternatives to cigarettes, smoke-free products are the next generation of innovation. (Published on September 18, 2025bythegrocer.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>‘UK Must Defend Safer Nicotine Alternatives’ - Report Shows Global Benefits</title><link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/uk-must-defend-safer-nicotine-123400502.html</link><description>International health experts emphasize the UK's success in reducing smoking rates by promoting safer nicotine alternatives, such as vaping, resulting in significant health benefits and saving lives. The UK's approach, integrated into NHS services, has led to a remarkable drop in smoking rates, with positive impacts on public health. Similar success stories are seen in Sweden, Japan, and New Zealand. While vaping has helped millions quit smoking, ongoing regulatory discussions may jeopardize progress. To maintain the momentum towards a smoke-free future, experts urge continued support for these products rather than restrictions. The report projects significant future health benefits from embracing harm reduction strategies. (Published on September 18, 2025byyahoo.com)</description></item><item><title>Burned Again | FDA Crackdown &amp; WHO’s Sly Corruption | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/burned-again-fda-crackdown-whos-sly-corruption-regwatch/</link><description>Donald Trump promised to save vaping. Twice. Once during his first term and again before winning the 2024 election. But in 2025, America’s vapers are feeling burned. Instead of delivering on his promise, Trump’s FDA staged the largest vape seizure in U.S. history while fast-tracking Big Tobacco’s nicotine pouches. (Published on September 18, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>Alcohol, tobacco and food giants block health reforms, says WHO</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/alcohol-tobacco-food-giants-block-health-reforms-says-who-2025-09-18/</link><description>The World Health Organization warned on Thursday that lobbying by the tobacco, alcohol, and ultra-processed food industries is preventing governments from implementing health policies that could save lives. Next Thursday, during the UN’s annual meeting in New York, a special day will be devoted to addressing non-communicable diseases such as cancer and heart disease, which the WHO says are fueled by these products. (Published on September 18, 2025byreuters.com)</description></item><item><title>#GFN25 Commentary Team #3 | Beyond Bans — Media, Regulators, and the Harm Reduction Gap | Hosted by Paddy Costall</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn25-commentary-team-3-by-paddy-costall/</link><description>At GFN25 in Warsaw, Paddy Costall hosts Dorrie Heemskerk and David Williams to tackle risk communication, smarter regulation without bans, and consumer-led tobacco harm reduction—from vapes and pouches to heated tobacco—amid WHO/FCTC headwinds and Europe’s tightening rules. (Published on September 18, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Sabine Benoit: Ottawa's nicotine policy is failing smokers</title><link>https://nationalpost.com/opinion/sabine-benoit-ottawas-nicotine-policy-is-failing-smokers</link><description>Health Canada is conducting its third review of the Tobacco and Vaping Products Act (TVPA), but critics argue the current approach to nicotine regulation is failing. Smoking in Canada remains at 11.4% in 2023, decreasing too slowly compared to Sweden’s 5%, achieved through promoting harm reduction tools like snus and nicotine pouches, which are far less harmful than cigarettes. Instead of higher taxes or bans, experts suggest amending the TVPA to encourage harm reduction products. (Published on September 18, 2025bynationalpost.com)</description></item></channel></rss>