<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 12:25:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Are vapes 95% safer than smoking? Probably, and scientists should be blunt about it</title><link>https://inews.co.uk/news/vapes-safer-than-smoking-scientists-blunt-2649561</link><description>Vaping is often claimed to be 95% safer than smoking, but there are debates on the accuracy of this statistic. Public health messaging on vaping's safety is under scrutiny, with concerns about potential misinformation leading to increased youth vaping. However, research indicates that while vaping is relatively safer, it is not risk-free. The discussion highlights the importance of transparent communication in public health messaging. Contrary to assumptions, youth perceptions on vaping harm have shifted negatively. Additionally, promoting baby-led weaning and debunking myths about excessive water consumption are other topics of interest in recent articles. Moreover, a group of psychologists is focusing on correcting errors in scientific research. (Published on September 30, 2025byinews.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Harm Reduction: The Next Step for Trinidad and Tobago’s Tobacco Fight</title><link>https://www.guardian.co.tt/opinion/harm-reduction-the-next-step-for-trinidad-and-tobagos-tobacco-fight-6.2.2412610.7e25f0ce2c</link><description>Trinidad and Tobago is shifting towards a progressive tobacco policy, exploring regulation of reduced-risk products like vaping and nicotine pouches. Current approaches focusing on bans haven't reduced smoking rates, with nearly one in five adults smoking. There's a lack of clarity on vaping regulations, leaving users uncertain. Embracing harm reduction strategies, similar to successful models in Sweden and the UK, can improve public health. Despite pushback from WHO, countries like Trinidad and Tobago can lead by prioritizing people's choices and health. It's time to act, collect data, understand risks, and regulate to encourage smokers to switch to safer alternatives, diverging from outdated strategies. (Published on September 30, 2025byguardian.co.tt)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #12 | BRAZIL's EFFORT FOR SAFER NICOTINE | Alexandro Lucian on Translating Science in LATAM</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-12/</link><description>Explore tobacco harm reduction at GFN through a candid interview with Brazilian consumer advocate Alexandro Lucian, who shares why this global event matters, the misinformation challenges in Brazil, and why education and accurate science are essential for safer nicotine choices. Learn how language barriers, anti‑vaping narratives, and limited local research shape public opinion—and how translating complex evidence into Portuguese helps counter myths. (Published on September 30, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Hoekstra: Tobacco industry's vape claims echo 'light' cigarette lies</title><link>https://www.euractiv.com/news/hoekstra-tobacco-industrys-vape-claims-echo-light-cigarette-lies/</link><description>EU Climate Commissioner Wopke Hoekstra warned that the tobacco industry’s claims about vapes being less harmful than cigarettes mirror past misleading tactics used with “light” cigarettes. He stressed that nicotine in new products is still very harmful, damaging blood vessels, impairing vascular function, and stimulating tumour growth. The European Commission is now preparing its first assessment of the health impacts of new tobacco and nicotine products, with a focus on preventing youth uptake. Hoekstra has also been pushing for higher taxation on cigarettes, e-cigarettes, heated tobacco, and nicotine pouches. (Published on October 01, 2025byeuractiv.com)</description></item><item><title>Kazakhstan has been a regional leader in tobacco control — WHO Representative on shisha regulation and public health</title><link>https://qazinform.com/news/kazakhstan-has-been-a-regional-leader-in-tobacco-control-who-representative-on-shisha-regulation-and-public-health-6537b3</link><description>The World Health Organization supports Kazakhstan's ban on shisha smoking in public places due to health risks. Shisha smoke contains harmful substances and poses dangers to users and passive smokers. The misconception that shisha is safer than cigarettes is refuted by evidence showing its links to cancer and other diseases. WHO recommends upholding the ban to protect public health, especially with the popularity of shisha among the youth. Despite economic claims, tobacco-related diseases outweigh short-term gains. Media and civil society are crucial in raising awareness, and WHO provides scientific guidance on waterpipe smoking's health effects. Kazakhstan's tobacco control efforts align with WHO standards, emphasizing public health over commercial interests. (Published on October 01, 2025byqazinform.com)</description></item><item><title>Licensing shake-up could block access to vapes, warn retailers</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/licensing-shake-up-could-block-access-to-vapes-warn-retailers/</link><description>New government licensing rules could restrict vape access for smokers, worrying retailers about increased smoking rates and black market activity. The Tobacco and Vapes Bill proposes licensing for all tobacco and vape sellers by January 2027, without "grandfathering" existing sellers. Concerns arise over the impact on convenience stores and potential restrictions near schools. The UK Vaping Industry Association criticizes categorizing vape shops alongside unwanted businesses, emphasizing vaping's role in smoking cessation and public health. Licensing could target rogue traders and fund enforcement efforts, supporting responsible retailers and public health goals. (Published on October 01, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>14 countries on Sweden's side on nicotine tax</title><link>https://www.vejpkollen.se/en/2025/09/eu-budget-hotad-14-lander-pa-sveriges-sida-om-nikotinskatt/</link><description>The European Commission faces opposition over its record budget due to proposed new nicotine and corporate taxes, prompting 14 member states, led by Sweden, to oppose the plan. Concerns exist about tax revenue distribution, harm reduction perspectives, and market harmonization. The dispute may lead to a budget overhaul to secure necessary support. (Published on October 01, 2025byvejpkollen.se)</description></item></channel></rss>