<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:55:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UK must defend safer alternatives that are saving lives worldwide</title><link>https://smokefreesweden.org/2025/10/23/uk-must-defend-safer-alternatives-that-are-saving-lives-worldwide/</link><description>The UK has significantly reduced smoking rates by promoting vaping and safer nicotine alternatives, leading to a 166,000 decrease in premature deaths. This strategy has lowered smoking rates and improved health outcomes, with cardiovascular mortality down and fewer smoking-related hospital admissions. These results showcase the success of tobacco harm reduction. However, challenges such as potential restrictions on vaping products could slow progress. Countries like Sweden, Japan, and New Zealand have also seen success with harm reduction strategies. To continue this positive trend, it's crucial for the UK to defend the role of vaping and reduced-risk products. Global leadership in this area must be protected to benefit millions more. (Published on October 23, 2025bysmokefreesweden.org)</description></item><item><title>Swedish Innovator Eyes U.S. Launch with Fast-Acting Nicotine Pouch</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/10/21/swedish-innovator-eyes-u-s-launch-with-fast-acting-nicotine-pouch/</link><description>Swedish biotech firm Emplicure AB plans to seek U.S. approval for its quick-delivery nicotine system, Seratek, aiming to offer a more efficient smokeless alternative for adult users. Seratek released 80% of nicotine in five minutes, outperforming competitors in a recent study. Emplicure aims to file a PMTA for U.S. sales, with CEO Mattias Josander highlighting nicotine pouches as a potential public health breakthrough. (Published on October 23, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Juul is waging a comeback with high-tech safeguards meant to keep vapes away from teens</title><link>https://nypost.com/2025/10/23/business/juul-is-back-to-its-original-mission-with-a-second-generation-e-cigarette/</link><description>Juul Labs, tarnished by legal battles, aims for a comeback by focusing on adult smoking cessation with their new device, Juul2. Equipped with biometric safeguards and a companion app, the product targets smokers while restricting access for minors. Despite controversy and financial setbacks, investor James Sagan sees potential in Juul's resurgence. The company, once linked to youth vaping, faces regulatory challenges and mixed scientific opinions on its effectiveness. Embracing independence after Altria's exit, Juul's future hinges on Juul2's success in a competitive market. Sagan remains hopeful about Juul’s mission to address public health issues. (Published on October 23, 2025bynypost.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping during pregnancy harms offspring even without nicotine, study finds</title><link>https://www.oncology-central.com/vaping-during-pregnancy-harms-offspring-even-without-nicotine-study-finds/</link><description>A study showed that vaping during pregnancy in rats led to weight gain, memory loss, behavioral changes, and premature aging in the offspring. Both e-liquid and nicotine impact development, causing health consequences from early development into adulthood. The study, conducted at West Virginia University, found that vaping resulted in cognitive impairment and negative effects on brain health, with e-liquid being a key factor in blood vessel impairment. Nicotine wasn't the sole factor in harm, as vaping without it still resulted in offspring damage. The study suggests that vaping poses similar cardiovascular risks as smoking, highlighting the need for caution, especially during pregnancy. (Published on October 23, 2025byoncology-central.com)</description></item><item><title>Cambodia introduces new anti-vape measures</title><link>https://asianews.network/cambodia-introduces-new-anti-vape-measures/</link><description>Cambodia's government has imposed strict measures to ban the import, sale, and use of vapes and shishas to safeguard public health. The prohibition, driven by Prime Minister Hun Manet's order, aims to protect youth from the dangers associated with heated tobacco products. Various ministries have been instructed to enforce the ban, with penalties for violators including warnings, confiscation of devices, and suspension of commercial licenses. Educational institutions are also mandated to educate and prevent the use of such products on their premises. The goal is to curb the potential gateway effect of vaping devices to illicit drug use in the country. (Published on October 23, 2025byasianews.network)</description></item><item><title>Richard Hogan: Vaping is not a healthy alternative to smoking — full stop</title><link>https://www.irishexaminer.com/lifestyle/people/arid-41728191.html</link><description>The text highlights the deceptive marketing tactics of vaping companies, particularly targeting children with appealing flavors. Vaping is shown to be harmful, with high nicotine levels and toxic chemicals inhaled, leading to addiction and health issues. Parents are urged to recognize the dangers and take action, while the government is called upon to implement stricter regulations on marketing, flavors, and misinformation about vaping. It is emphasized that prevention programs in schools are crucial to educate teenagers on the risks of vaping. Urgent measures are needed to address the increasing trend of teenage vaping and promote healthier socialization alternatives. (Published on October 23, 2025byirishexaminer.com)</description></item></channel></rss>