<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 12:43:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mexico’s Vape Prohibition Is Already Biting</title><link>https://filtermag.org/mexico-vape-ban-consequences/</link><description>Mexico has constitutionally banned nicotine vapes, affecting imports, distribution, and ads but not possession. Gray market products' sales are halted; users face fines and prison. Lack of clarity risks user abuse. The ban might fuel illegal markets, echoing drug policy flaws. Vapes could become a profit source for criminal networks. US regulation differences facilitate unsafe vape flows into Mexico. Prohibition threatens consumer safety and may escalate criminal activities. Mexico's history warns against the ban's adverse effects. Stronger drug cartels may control the market, increasing risks. Inconsistencies in enforcement heighten uncertainties for users and market dynamics, potentially leading to more harm than good. (Published on February 23, 2026byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #178 | IS MEXICO GOING TOO FAR ON VAPING?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-178-is-mexico-going-too-far-on-vaping/</link><description>In this video, Joanna Junak speaks with Juan José Cirión Lee, president of Mexico y el Mundo Vapeando, about the growing restrictions on vaping in Mexico. They discuss how the new ban impacts harm reduction efforts, limits public access to information, and challenges organizations working to support smokers seeking alternatives. Hear firsthand insights on the future of vaping, public health policy, and advocacy in an increasingly restrictive environment. (Published on February 23, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Consumers urge Sweden to veto EU Tobacco Tax</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/consumers-urge-sweden-to-veto-eu-tobacco-tax/</link><description>Nine organizations representing users of safer nicotine products urge the Swedish Government to veto EU's proposal for significant tax hikes on vapes and nicotine pouches. Seen as a threat to the Swedish Model, the plan could harm public health by treating safer nicotine options like cigarettes. Sweden's success in low smoking rates is attributed to these products, making the directive a direct attack. The suggested minimum excise duty is deemed unreasonably high, potentially pushing consumers back to smoking. The plea calls for differentiation in taxes based on risk and protection of national sovereignty to maintain successful harm reduction strategies. EU countries will discuss the proposal this week. (Published on February 23, 2026byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>“One Word: Inevitable”—Tobacco Harm Reduction’s Heavy Hitter</title><link>https://filtermag.org/tobacco-harm-reduction-clive-bates/</link><description>In the tobacco harm reduction (THR) debate, Clive Bates stands out for his impactful advocacy efforts. Bates, a key figure in the THR movement, is known for his no-nonsense approach and deep knowledge, challenging opposition with credible analyses. He tirelessly engages in global debates and policy-making to promote safer nicotine products. Bates criticizes the resistance to harm reduction, highlighting missed opportunities to save lives. Despite facing opposition and disinformation, he remains a strong advocate for rational policymaking in public health. (Published on February 23, 2026byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>The Updated Meta-Analysis of E-Cigs &amp; Health Outcomes: Still Critically Flawed</title><link>https://arielleselyaphd.substack.com/p/the-updated-meta-analysis-of-e-cigs?r=45yctx&amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;utm_medium=web&amp;triedRedirect=true</link><description>Two years ago, tobacco control activist Stanton Glantz and his colleagues published a meta-analysis on e-cigarettes and health outcomes. They systematically reviewed existing studies, grouped them by disease categories such as cardiovascular disease and COPD, and calculated pooled effects for each outcome. However, a meta-analysis is only as reliable as the studies it includes. Most of the underlying papers were based on population survey data that showed correlations between e-cigarette use and nearly every measured health condition. Such correlations are often methodologically weak, as they are prone to confounding and do not establish causation. (Published on February 23, 2026bysubstack.com)</description></item></channel></rss>