<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 21:15:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump urged to crack down on Chinese vapes</title><link>https://www.washingtonexaminer.com/news/white-house/3401231/trump-chinese-vapes-crackdown-bipartisan-pressure/</link><description>Activists urge President Trump to tackle the sale of illicit Chinese e-cigarettes to U.S. youths. Hispanic Business Caucus President wrote a letter calling for stricter regulations and border security to combat black market vapes. The CDC reports a decrease in teenage vaping, but over 1.6 million students used e-cigarettes in 2024. Most illicit vapes are traced back to China, fueling a billion-dollar market by 2030. Dubbed "Not For Sale In China," these products harm American youth. Legislative steps include Trump's ban proposal on flavored e-cigs and raising the tobacco buying age. Despite bipartisan efforts, administrative hurdles pose challenges in enforcing regulation and penalties on offenders. (Published on May 07, 2025bywashingtonexaminer.com)</description></item><item><title>Rights4Vapers Congratulates New Liberal Government, Urges Action On Safer Nicotine Policy Reform</title><link>https://www.rights4vapers.com/rights4vapers-congratulates-new-liberal-government-urges-action-on-safer-nicotine-policy-reform/</link><description>Rights4Vapers congratulates the Liberal Party on forming the new federal government in Canada. They urge Prime Minister Mark Carney and the Health Ministers to prioritize harm reduction and Canadians' health with evidence-based nicotine policies. The advocacy group stresses the importance of distinguishing safer nicotine products like vaping devices from traditional cigarettes and establishing a Safer Nicotine Act. They call for the reversal of restrictions on nicotine pouch sales and emphasize the need for updated regulations to support smoking cessation effectively. (Published on May 07, 2025byrights4vapers.com)</description></item><item><title>Crackdown on snus-style nicotine pouches in ‘smokefree generation’ law</title><link>https://www.the-independent.com/news/uk/home-news/snus-illegal-vapes-smoking-law-b2745627.html</link><description>Nicotine pouches, known as "snus," will face tighter regulations in the UK following the distribution of free samples, raising addiction and health concerns. The Scottish Government backs stricter control over these products to limit availability and harm, as discussed in the Tobacco and Vapes Bill. The legislation aims for a smoke-free generation, addressing new tobacco products like snus. Concerns raised by health experts emphasize the addictive nature and potential health risks of nicotine pouches. The Scottish Government supports incorporating these measures to protect young people from marketing tactics and ensure better control over such products. (Published on May 07, 2025bythe-independent.com)</description></item></channel></rss>