<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 18:18:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Transition from Disposable to Reusable Vapes</title><link>https://manufacturing-update.co.uk/2025/08/12/the-transition-from-disposable-to-reusable-vapes</link><description>The UK’s ban on single-use vapes has two core aims; to make vaping less appealing to young people while still acting as a smoking cessation tool, and an environmentally friendly initiative by reducing waste and incentivising a transition to reusable products. The ban came into force on June 1, 2025, and one Financial Times report suggests the ban has not had much of (...) (Published on August 13, 2025bymanufacturing-update.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Should We Urge Adult Smokers To Vape?</title><link>https://www.acsh.org/news/2025/08/12/podcast-should-we-urge-adult-smokers-vape-49670</link><description>Smoking kills hundreds of thousands of Americans annually. As this death toll mounts, studies continue to show that nicotine vaping is significantly less harmful than smoking and far more effective than FDA-approved cessation therapies like nicotine gum. (Published on August 13, 2025byacsh.org)</description></item><item><title>CAPHRA Urges Vaping Manufacturers To Champion Environmental Leadership</title><link>https://www.scoop.co.nz/stories/WO2508/S00148/caphra-urges-vaping-manufacturers-to-champion-environmental-leadership.htm</link><description>In response to mounting concerns over the environmental impact of discarded vaping products, the Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA) is calling on manufacturers to show genuine leadership in sustainability and social responsibility. (Published on August 13, 2025byscoop.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>Vape Sellers to Pay Disposal Costs Under Plans to End UK’s “Throwaway Culture”</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/aug/12/vape-sellers-pay-disposal-costs-plans-end-uk-throwaway-culture</link><description>Vape sellers to pay disposal costs under plans to end UK’s "throwaway culture". Ministers say online vendors of electrical goods such as microwaves will also have to contribute to recycling fees. (Published on August 13, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Balearic Government Rejects Smoking Ban on Beaches</title><link>https://www.tobaccojournal.com/news/balearic-government-rejects-smoking-ban-on-beaches</link><description>Spain’s central government wants to extend its smoking ban to beaches and restaurant terraces, but faces resistance from the Balearic Islands. (Published on August 13, 2025bytobaccojournal.com)</description></item></channel></rss>