<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 12:28:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Coffee, Nicotine, and the Politics of Acceptable Addiction</title><link>https://brownstone.org/articles/coffee-nicotine-and-the-politics-of-acceptable-addiction/</link><description>Caffeine is socially accepted and even praised, while nicotine is often stigmatized as a vice. Both substances are mild stimulants that increase alertness and can lead to dependence. Neither is inherently harmful in non-combustible forms, yet society treats them very differently. This contrast reflects cultural attitudes rather than scientific evidence. Essentially, the moral judgment placed on nicotine is inconsistent with its actual effects compared to caffeine. (Published on December 22, 2025bybrownstone.org)</description></item><item><title>Vape crackdown risks sidelining older smokers trying to quit</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/vape-crackdown-risks-sidelining-older-smokers-trying-to-quit/</link><description>The UK's crackdown on youth vaping may impact older adults who rely on e-cigarettes to quit smoking. Research shows over-55s use vaping for cigarette cessation but the Tobacco and Vapes Bill could hinder their access to vaping tools. In a survey, 87% of adults over 55 started vaping to quit smoking, compared to 49% in 45-54 age group and 18% among 18-24 year olds. Older vapers report improved wellbeing and health benefits post-switch, emphasizing their serious approach to quitting. Advocates call for tailored protections, not total bans, to ensure older adults can access accurate information and make informed choices. (Published on December 22, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Why Vape Flavors Matter More Than Ever? | GFN Wishes for 2026 with Garrett McGovern and Tom Miller</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/why-vape-flavors-matter-more-than-ever-gfn-wishes-for-2026-with-garrett-mcgovern-and-tom-miller/</link><description>As policymakers look ahead to 2026, experts share one clear hope for tobacco harm reduction: protect vape flavors. In this discussion, Dr. Garrett McGovern and AG Tom Miller explains why flavors are critical to keeping adults away from smoking - and why banning them could backfire, leading to higher cigarette use, including among youth. (Published on December 22, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Growing restrictions on vape sales making it harder for smokers to quit and driving others into hands of criminal dealers</title><link>https://www.independent.ie/irish-news/growing-restrictions-on-vape-sales-making-it-harder-for-smokers-to-quit-and-driving-others-into-hands-of-criminal-dealers/a1758690550.html</link><description>Proposed ban on flavored vapes by the government may hinder smoking cessation efforts for adults while failing to address underage sales concerns. Health Minister's plan could impact thousands benefiting from flavored vapes to quit smoking. Proper regulation on underage sales is suggested as a more effective approach. (Published on December 22, 2025byindependent.ie)</description></item><item><title>A Rare Case of Open Debate on Tobacco Harm Reduction</title><link>https://filtermag.org/tobacco-harm-reduction-debate/</link><description>Suely Castro raised the question of our responsibility to science and fairness in promoting safer alternatives like oral snus and nicotine pouches to reduce smoking-related deaths. Events promoting tobacco harm reduction face challenges from skeptics like Clive Bates, who debate the effectiveness of such approaches. Global debates on harm reduction policies, conference restrictions, and the importance of differential taxes on nicotine products were discussed. Experts highlighted the need for open dialogue, consumer input, and tailored approaches to reduce harm effectively. Encouraging a clash of ideas and pragmatic strategies is seen as crucial to saving lives in public health endeavors. (Published on December 22, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>One in eight of 14- to 17-year-olds in Great Britain say they have used nicotine pouches</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/dec/21/one-in-eight-teens-britain-have-used-nicotine-pouches-survey-finds</link><description>A survey revealed 1 in 8 teenagers aged 14-17 have used nicotine pouches, raising concerns about addiction. Although pouches don’t increase cancer risk, there are worries about nicotine dependence and oral health issues. Most teens obtain them from friends or stores without age restrictions. The UK plans to tighten regulations on sales to minors and decrease appeal through packaging and flavors. Notable brands include Velo, Nordic Spirit, and Zyn, leading to increased warnings from health experts about nicotine's heart and vascular toxicity. While some view pouches as less harmful than cigarettes or vapes, regulations aim to prevent youth addiction. The tobacco and vapes bill will address underage sales to safeguard public health. (Published on December 22, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item></channel></rss>