<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 01:01:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vapes more effective than other quit smoking aids, landmark Cochrane review finds</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/vapes-more-effective-than-other-quit-smoking-aids-landmark-cochrane-review-finds/</link><description>Nicotine vapes are more effective at helping people quit smoking than traditional nicotine replacement products. A scientific review analyzed 104 studies involving over 30,000 participants and found that vaping with nicotine is more successful in smoking cessation. There were no significant differences in side effects among the groups. Regulated nicotine vapes showed no evidence of serious harm; however, longer-term studies are needed for further evaluation. Public health agencies support nicotine vapes as a harm-reduction measure for adult smokers, emphasizing proper regulation and cautioning against non-smoker use, particularly by young individuals. Future research will focus on addressing gaps in evidence and ensuring safety in vaping practices. (Published on November 10, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>What’s the point in a Generational Smoking Ban?</title><link>https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/whats-the-point-in-a-generational-smoking-ban/</link><description>The text discusses the Generational Tobacco and Vapes Bill in the House of Lords and questions the need for the proposed ban on smoking among young people. Data shows a significant decline in smoking rates among the youth due to factors such as increased prices of tobacco and the popularity of vape products. The ban is deemed unnecessary as smoking rates are already decreasing, and the shift towards harm reduction products like vapes is increasing. Enforcing the ban would be costly and potentially ineffective, as evidenced by rising black market activity. Overall, the ban is criticized as unnecessary and costly, given the existing decline in smoking rates. (Published on November 10, 2025byspectator.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Q&amp;A: What to know about vaping risks for young people</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-11-qa-vaping-young-people.html</link><description>Vaping, marketed as a safer alternative to smoking, poses risks, especially for young people. Columbia doctors emphasize vaping's impact on lungs, heart, and brain, noting potential long-term consequences. The addictive nature of nicotine in e-cigarettes alters the brain's reward system, increasing susceptibility to substance abuse. Parents are advised to initiate open discussions with children about vaping, addressing the dangers and addiction potential. Monitoring subtle cues and maintaining ongoing dialogue can help prevent vaping initiation among teens. (Published on November 10, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>The "Blank Slate" Problem in Behavioral Health Research</title><link>https://arielleselyaphd.substack.com/p/the-blank-slate-problem-in-behavioral?triedRedirect=true</link><description>The concept of the "blank slate" from Stephen Pinker's book questions if human nature is determined by genetics or environment. The text critiques the overemphasis on extrinsic factors in behavioral health research, neglecting intrinsic factors like risk tolerance or personal preferences. Examples in tobacco control and health policy illustrate the bias towards modifiable external influences. The focus on extrinsic factors leads to incomplete science, ineffective public health strategies, and undermines personal agency. Acknowledging both intrinsic and extrinsic factors is crucial for a comprehensive understanding of behavior and designing successful interventions. (Published on November 10, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Expert Wall: statements on FCTC and tobacco harm reduction (2025)</title><link>https://clivebates.com/papers-and-letters/cop11experts/</link><description>This page provides statements from independent experts on tobacco science and policy. They are addressed to delegates in advance of the 11th Session of the FCTC Conference of the Parties (COP-11), held in Geneva, 17-22nd November 2025. Each statement is linked from the author’s entry in the table of contents. (Published on November 10, 2025byclivebates.com)</description></item><item><title>How Malaysia Can Finally Win The War On Smoking</title><link>https://www.businesstoday.com.my/2025/11/10/how-malaysia-can-finally-win-the-war-on-smoking/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=how-malaysia-can-finally-win-the-war-on-smoking</link><description>Despite aspirations to be smoke-free, Malaysia struggles with high smoking rates and lacks clear harm reduction strategies, unlike successful models like Sweden and the UK. Embracing proven harm reduction tools, such as vaping, could help Malaysia combat smoking-related deaths and health costs. By focusing on science-based and compassionate approaches, policymakers can lead the country towards a healthier, smoke-free future. It's crucial to shift the narrative around alternatives like vaping, enforce regulations, educate the public, and support smokers in quitting. Following successful international examples, Malaysia can make progress in reducing smoking prevalence and improving public health outcomes. (Published on November 10, 2025bybusinesstoday.com.my)</description></item></channel></rss>