<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:18:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Banning cigarette filters</title><link>https://snowdon.substack.com/p/banning-cigarette-filters?utm_source=post-email-title&amp;publication_id=977190&amp;post_id=176398081&amp;utm_campaign=email-post-title&amp;isFreemail=true&amp;r=16unn&amp;triedRedirect=true&amp;utm_medium=email</link><description>The WHO presented anti-smoking policies for discussion, including a ban on cigarette filters. Despite arguments for its harm reduction, research shows filtered cigarettes lower lung cancer risk compared to unfiltered ones. Opponents claim filters mislead smokers, suggesting a ban without considering consumer beliefs or overall health impacts. Evidence suggests filters may indeed offer some protection. Conflicting views exist within the anti-smoking lobby on tobacco regulation strategies. Ethical concerns and contradictory stances surround the debate, such as the effectiveness of low tar cigarettes and the implications of banning filters. The argument for a ban lacks a clear justification and overlooks potential consequences on smoking-related diseases. (Published on October 20, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>New science review on vape ingredients criticised for unrealistic testing</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/new-science-review-on-vape-ingredients-criticised-for-unrealistic-testing/</link><description>A recent study suggesting harmful chemicals are released when vape liquids are heated has been criticized for using unrealistic lab tests. Harm reduction experts argue that real-world vaping conditions differ. Research has shown heating propylene glycol and vegetable glycerin may create toxic byproducts, but harm is minimal when vaped as designed. Human studies found no respiratory or eye issues from propylene glycol exposure. After over 15 years of vaping, no serious harm linked to these ingredients has been found. Extreme lab tests may mislead as users would avoid inhaling burnt vapor. (Published on October 20, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Experts Advocate Swedish Model To Curb Smoking In Nigeria</title><link>https://leadership.ng/experts-advocate-swedish-model-to-curb-smoking-in-nigeria/?sfnsn=mo</link><description>Experts in Nigeria are advocating for adopting Sweden’s harm reduction model to curb smoking. Instead of total eradication, the approach promotes safer alternatives like vaping. They urge the government to implement a national framework with regulation, public education, and data-driven policies to reduce smoking-related diseases. (Published on October 20, 2025byleadership.ng)</description></item><item><title>Taiwan's first approved heated tobacco products pulled from shelves on launch day</title><link>https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/news/6223782</link><description>Taiwan's first legal heated tobacco products were briefly on sale but removed due to noncompliant packaging. Health risk assessments were prioritized before approval, requiring proper labeling. The Minister of Health confirmed the recall's completion, with fines for violations. Since 2023, Taiwan has banned e-cigarettes and regulated heated tobacco products, only allowing approved items after assessments. Products from the US and Japan were recently approved for sale. Critics argue that allowing flavored heated tobacco undermines the ban on additives, potentially impacting youth. E-cigarettes remain prohibited, and vaping releases nicotine differently than traditional cigarettes. Civil groups warn of the risks of flavored heated tobacco on the youth. (Published on October 20, 2025bytaiwannews.com.tw)</description></item></channel></rss>