<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 18:17:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>To Bring Tobacco Harm Reduction to Prisons, We Need Outside Allies</title><link>https://filtermag.org/tobacco-harm-reduction-prisons-need-allies/</link><description>Harm reduction efforts outside prison can target weak policies for positive outcomes. Advocates suggest addressing vulnerable prison policies related to smoking to save lives and costs in Washington State. Selling nicotine vapes in prisons can promote safer habits and fund essential services. However, achieving policy change requires external support due to restrictions on inmate advocacy. Involving prisoners in harm reduction initiatives is crucial, but often overlooked. Collaboration between inmates and external stakeholders, such as researchers and advocacy groups, is needed to push for vaping policies in prisons. Inclusion of prisoners in harm reduction discussions and initiatives is essential for effective and just policy change. (Published on June 10, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>EU should not copy France’s failed public health strategy</title><link>https://www.europeaninterest.eu/eu-should-not-copy-frances-failed-public-health-strategy/</link><description>France's anti-tobacco policy, with high taxes and bans on safer quitting tools, is ineffective. Around 75,000 people annually die due to tobacco, costing €150 billion. The policy lacks public trust, pushing 1 in 4 French to buy cigarettes illegally. This distrust stems from taxes seen as money grabs. France needs harm reduction programs, truthful messaging, and evaluation beyond tax gains. Hoekstra's EU-wide tax proposal risks expanding failed policies. Sensible changes are necessary to combat smoking effectively. France must shift from punitive measures to supportive strategies promoting healthier choices for smokers. (Published on June 10, 2025byeuropeaninterest.eu)</description></item><item><title>Puffs, Pods, Pouches: Which Nicotine Trend Worries Experts?</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/puffs-pods-pouches-which-nicotine-trend-worries-experts-2025a1000fhw</link><description>CHC Mont Legia welcomed Adrien Meunier, a clinical nurse tobacco specialist, on World No Tobacco Day to discuss the effectiveness of next-generation nicotine products in smoking cessation. Meunier clarified that nicotine itself is not a primary cause of fatal diseases, emphasizing the harm from toxic substances in cigarette smoke. He highlighted the drawbacks of box mod e-cigarettes and recommended pod-based e-cigarettes for smoking cessation, along with a gradual reduction strategy. Meunier also raised concerns about the popularity of puffs among youth and the risks associated with heated tobacco devices and nicotine pouches. Additionally, he warned about new addictive synthetic nicotine molecules entering the market. (Published on June 10, 2025bymedscape.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #156 | Is this the key to reducing smoking rates in Mexico?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-156/</link><description>Despite rising smoking rates Mexico still heavily restricts access to safer nicotine products, leaving few options for Mexico's. But could healthcare professionals be the key to stem Mexico's smoking dilemma? Marcela Madrazo joins us to highlight this alternative approach to THR in Mexico. (Published on June 10, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>