<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:26:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Tobacco and Vapes Bill – why we need to be careful with international comparisons</title><link>https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/politicsandpolicy/the-tobacco-and-vapes-bill-why-we-need-to-be-careful-with-international-comparisons/</link><description>The Tobacco and Vapes Bill in the UK aims to end tobacco sales to those born after 2009, with stricter regulations on nicotine products. The Bill faces criticism for misrepresenting international examples in debates. New Zealand's repeal of tobacco measures is linked to industry interference, not effectiveness issues. Australia's illicit tobacco market issues stem from weak enforcement, not regulation. Sweden's success in tobacco control is attributed to comprehensive policies, not just snus use. The UK Bill aims to regulate new nicotine products like pouches and address marketing to minors. Utilizing accurate international evidence is crucial for effective public health policy. Parliamentary debates impact global tobacco control approaches. (Published on November 03, 2025bylse.ac.uk)</description></item><item><title>OPINION: Poll on Tobacco Bill exposes its dangers to public health, jobs and security</title><link>https://www.citizen.digital/article/opinion-poll-on-tobacco-bill-exposes-its-dangers-to-public-health-jobs-and-security-n372081</link><description>In Kenya, there is high awareness of Tobacco Harm Reduction (THR) with 85% of respondents believing that promoting safer alternatives can help smokers quit traditional cigarettes. Additionally, 63% feel the government should conduct campaigns to encourage the switch to safer alternatives, recognizing the public health benefits. (Published on November 03, 2025bycitizen.digital)</description></item></channel></rss>