<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 03:08:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cambodian PM reiterates ban on investment in e-cigarette production</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/aseanplus/aseanplus-news/2025/05/14/cambodian-pm-reiterates-ban-on-investment-in-e-cigarette-production</link><description>Cambodian PM Hun Manet stated that e-cigarette production won't be allowed in Cambodia due to health concerns, reaffirming the ban on e-cigarettes and shisha since 2014. The government focuses on preventing illegal tobacco product imports, raising awareness of smoking's health risks. The Ministry of Health warns about e-cigarettes' nicotine content, leading to severe health issues like lung disease and cancer. The PM's decision comes after reports of illegal e-cigarette sales despite the existing ban. Hun Manet's stance aims to protect the public from harmful effects associated with smoking and vaping. (Published on May 14, 2025bythestar.com.my)</description></item><item><title>Lower taxes on Heated Tobacco Products are subsidising tobacco industry – new research</title><link>https://www.bath.ac.uk/announcements/lower-taxes-on-heated-tobacco-products-are-subsidising-tobacco-industry-new-research/</link><description>Research from the University of Bath and Johns Hopkins University reveals that governments lowering taxes on heated tobacco products (HTPs) to deter smokers from traditional cigarettes inadvertently subsidize the tobacco industry. This approach results in decreased tax revenues and undermines public health efforts. The study focused on Ukraine, where HTPs are taxed similarly to cigarettes. While tobacco companies promote HTPs as safer alternatives, evidence on their health impacts remains inconclusive. Tax harmonization, as seen in Ukraine, aligns with WHO recommendations to prevent market manipulation. The researchers stress the importance of taxing HTPs appropriately and urge policymakers to prioritize public health over industry profits. (Published on May 14, 2025bybath.ac.uk)</description></item><item><title>Quit Like Sweden urges SA to back harm reduction, amend Tobacco Bill</title><link>https://www.bizcommunity.com/article/quit-like-sweden-urges-sa-to-back-harm-reduction-amend-tobacco-bill-817713a</link><description>With South Africa considering new tobacco control laws, global health experts, including Quit Like Sweden, emphasize the success of harm reduction strategies in Sweden and New Zealand with low-risk alternatives like nicotine pouches and vaping. These approaches have dramatically reduced smoking rates and related deaths. Advocates urge South Africa to prioritize adult access to safer options to replicate this success and improve public health outcomes. Policymakers are encouraged to learn from successful international models and create a distinction between harmful tobacco products and safer alternatives. Ultimately, the focus is on saving lives through evidence-based approaches. (Published on May 14, 2025bybizcommunity.com)</description></item><item><title>When Cloud Chasing Becomes Clout Chasing: A Supply and Demand Problem</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/when-cloud-chasing-becomes-clout-chasing-a-supply-and-demand-problem/</link><description>Some individuals irrationally hate vaping and pouches, fueling lies about harm-reduction products. A voracious demand for negative stories about vapes exists, contrasting with the reality of zero deaths from vaping in 20 years. This phenomenon, coined Vapehausen-by-proxy syndrome, mirrors Munchausen syndrome by proxy. Manipulative tales about vaping seek attention and sympathy, spreading misinformation and unfounded claims to attract attention in the attention economy. Various examples of fabricated stories surrounding vaping illustrate the lengths some go to manipulate public opinion. It is crucial to critically assess such narratives and acknowledge the lack of substantiated evidence linking vaping to significant harm or death. (Published on May 14, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>Study finds vaping, nicotine pouches most effective quit smoking tools</title><link>https://www.westernstandard.news/news/study-finds-vaping-nicotine-pouches-most-effective-quit-smoking-tools/64730</link><description>A new policy paper from the World Vapers Alliance (WVA) urges the World Health Organization (WHO) to revise its 20-year-old tobacco control treaty. The report argues that electronic cigarettes and nicotine pouches are currently the most effective tools for reducing smoking and criticizes the WHO’s outdated stance against harm reduction. Marking the 20th anniversary of the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC), the paper claims that opposition to harm reduction has slowed progress and cost lives. It outlines 20 lessons, emphasizing the need to regulate nicotine products based on risk rather than banning them. The report cites research from Public Health England showing that vaping exposes users to at least 95% fewer toxins than traditional smoking. (Published on May 14, 2025bywesternstandard.news)</description></item></channel></rss>