<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 00:58:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>FDA’s double standard: Approves deadly opioids while banning safer smoking alternatives</title><link>http://washingtontimes.com/news/2025/aug/19/fdas-double-standard-approves-deadly-opioids-banning-safer-smoking/</link><description>The FDA portrays itself as protecting Americans from dangerous products, but its history suggests otherwise. Its approval of opioids helped cause the deadly epidemic that has killed hundreds of thousands since 2000. At the same time, the FDA restricts safer alternatives to cigarettes, applying stricter standards to harm-reduction products while effectively protecting cigarette companies. Although the dangers of smoking have been known since the 1960s, the 2009 Tobacco Control Act gave the FDA broad authority over nicotine products, requiring new ones to undergo a burdensome approval process to prove they benefit public health. (Published on August 20, 2025bywashingtontimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Young vape users three times as likely to start smoking, study finds</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/aug/19/young-vape-users-three-times-as-likely-to-start-smoking-study</link><description>Vaping among young people significantly increases the likelihood of future smoking, asthma, cough, injuries, and mental health issues. Research shows a concerning link between vaping and harmful behaviors, prompting calls for stricter regulations. While evidence is largely observational, studies indicate a threefold increase in smoking initiation among young vapers. Asthma risk rises by 20-36%. The relationship between vaping and smoking urges governments to act swiftly. Despite vaping being a less harmful alternative for adults, it poses serious risks for youth. Controversy exists on the causality of vaping leading to smoking. Urgent actions are needed to protect children from the dangers associated with vaping. (Published on August 20, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Case For Trade-proofing Australia's New Vape Laws</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/case-for-trade-proofing-australias-new-vape-laws-1518073/</link><description>Australia's tough anti-vaping laws face international challenges, per a UTS-Monash University paper. Health risks from vaping, especially among youth, prompt restrictions. With a history of industry litigations, policy decisions must align with global trade rules. Proving public health benefits is crucial to weather potential legal challenges. Transparency and ongoing justification are key. Australia must defend its laws before the WTO and set a precedent like the tobacco plain packaging. Researchers advocate for evidence-based justifications to uphold regulations. Success in reducing vaping harms could pave the way for global policy standards and protect public health internationally. (Published on August 20, 2025bymiragenews.com)</description></item><item><title>Daily Pouch Money: Does Altria Belong in Your Portfolio?</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/altria-stock-2025-nicotine-pouch-investment/</link><description>Daily Pouch Money reviews nicotine pouch makers. PMI rose 7.3% and BAT 20%. Analysts explore Altria, up 23.6%, predicting its future amid smoke-free ambitions and regulatory risks. Altria’s on! pouches surge 18%, aiming for $5 billion yearly by 2028. Market share decline suggests Marlboro loyalty. Despite downsides like US regulation and stiff competition, Altria's dividends and potential gains from NJOY vapes provide buying incentives. Investing in Altria balances risk and reward, and while short-term projections are positive, long-term growth may be modest due to industry shifts. Ultimately, Altria's performance depends on innovation and market dynamics, setting expectations for single-digit growth in 2025. (Published on August 20, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #7 | Why communication is the heart of science?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-7-why-communication-is-the-heart-of-science/</link><description>In this episode of GFN Voices, Gabriel Oke explores one of the most overlooked yet vital aspects of scientific work: communication. He explains that no matter how important or innovative research may be, its true impact depends on how clearly and effectively it is shared with the world. From researchers and academics to policymakers, advocates, and the public, communication is the bridge that turns data into action and science into progress. (Published on August 20, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>‘Vaping is safer than cigarettes,’ Kgosi Letlape blasts health department advert</title><link>https://sundayworld.co.za/politics/vaping-is-safer-than-cigarettes-kgosi-letlape-blasts-health-department-advert/</link><description>ActionSA MP Dr. Letlape defended vaping against Health Department claims, stating it's less harmful than smoking. He criticized false radio ads equating vaping to smoking and accused the department of spreading propaganda. Letlape lodged a complaint and called for the ads' withdrawal, arguing they mislead the public and undermine Parliament's authority. Letlape urged Health Minister Motsoaledi to clarify the misinformation and emphasized vaping's potential for smoking cessation. While e-cigarettes are deemed less harmful by Cancer Research UK, they are not risk-free and should only be used for smoking cessation. The Health Department's misleading ads are criticized for interfering with legislative processes. (Published on August 20, 2025bysundayworld.co.za)</description></item></channel></rss>