<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 18:18:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fifth of vapers will return to smoking due to UK disposables ban, new survey finds</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/fifth-of-vapers-will-return-to-smoking-due-to-uk-disposables-ban-new-survey-finds/</link><description>A poll shows 18% of disposable vape users may return to smoking after the ban. Yorkshire Cancer Research urges the government to keep vapes accessible for smoking cessation, especially for disadvantaged communities. Evidence supports vaping for quitting, with vaping alone helping 79% quit, surpassing other methods. Public misconceptions about vaping's harm may hinder progress against smoking-related cancers. Despite the ban, many vapers plan to switch to refillables or other nicotine products. Yorkshire Cancer Research supports regulating vape product displays in stores to protect children but emphasizes the need for accurate public messaging on vaping's lower risks compared to smoking. (Published on June 09, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>The Center for Tobacco Products: What It Has Done and What It Should Do Next</title><link>https://www.rstreet.org/commentary/the-center-for-tobacco-products-what-it-has-done-and-what-it-should-do-next/</link><description>The U.S. FDA's Center for Tobacco Products (CTP) has reduced smoking rates, focusing on youth and harm reduction. It regulates tobacco products through various pathways, contributing to decreased smoking. However, criticism surrounds its limited approval rate of alternatives through PMTA, resulting in accusations of fueling illicit markets. Stricter regulations like flavor bans have drawn debate as well, impacting adult smokers' access to safer options. Adapting policies to balance youth protection with harm reduction could enhance the CTP's impact, improving public health outcomes related to smoking. (Published on June 09, 2025byrstreet.org)</description></item><item><title>Expert raises alarm over increasing deaths linked to tobacco use</title><link>https://guardian.ng/news/nigeria/metro/expert-raises-alarm-over-increasing-deaths-linked-to-tobacco-use/#google_vignette</link><description>Dr. Rita Opene, a health expert in Delta State, Nigeria, raises alarm on the increasing tobacco-related deaths, stressing global preventable death concerns. Opene, also a coordinator for the Nigerian Cancer Society, highlights World Health Organization data revealing over seven million annual tobacco-related deaths worldwide. She addresses statistics from the Global Adult Tobacco Survey, showing 4.7 million Nigerian adults using tobacco, with a rising trend in newer tobacco products. Opene warns about the health risks, including lung cancer and heart disease, associated with tobacco use, emphasizing the need for urgent action and awareness to combat the epidemic. (Published on June 09, 2025byguardian.ng)</description></item><item><title>Switzerland to ban single-use e-cigarettes</title><link>https://lenews.ch/2025/06/06/switzerland-to-ban-single-use-e-cigarettes/</link><description>Switzerland's upper house voted to ban disposable e-cigarettes, or vapes, due to health concerns and their appeal to young people. Despite initial opposition, the ban aims to combat rising nicotine consumption and environmental impact. Switzerland follows other European countries and Swiss cantons in regulating vape sales. Critics warn of potential loopholes with reusable vapes becoming the next trend. (Published on June 09, 2025bylenews.ch)</description></item></channel></rss>