<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 06:22:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Will "Third of UK Teenagers Who Vape... Go On to Start Smoking"?</title><link>https://arielleselyaphd.substack.com/p/will-third-of-uk-teenagers-who-vape</link><description>A new study suggests youth vapers in 2018 share risk factors with teen smokers in 1974, but doesn’t prove vaping causes smoking. Actual smoking rates keep falling. The media overstated findings, ignoring that the study used estimated—not real—smoking rates, which may be inflated and misleading. (Published on August 04, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Environmental Impact of Vaping Devices: A Global Approach to Sustainability</title><link>https://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=5287029</link><description>The research explores the types of waste generated by vaping devices, including plastics that are difficult to degrade and potentially dangerous lithium batteries. It also analyzes the negative effects of this waste on nature and life, from soil and water pollution to impacts on flora and fauna. (Published on August 04, 2025byssrn.com)</description></item><item><title>When Good Intentions Go Wrong: How The UK’s Hardline Vape Measures are Backfiring</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/08/01/when-good-intentions-go-wrong-how-the-uks-hardline-vape-measures-are-backfiring/#:~:text=In%20the%20weeks%20following%20the,into%20effect%20on%20June%201st</link><description>As a result of the recent UK ban, we now have more evidence of how harsh vape restrictions risk backfiring, fueling black markets and misinformation—ultimately undermining harm reduction and making safer alternatives harder to access. (Published on August 04, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>France Moves Toward Balanced Regulation of Nicotine Pouches</title><link>https://www.ginn.global/france-moves-toward-balanced-regulation-of-nicotine-pouches</link><description>France is at a pivotal moment in determining the future of nicotine pouches, a tobacco-free oral product increasingly used by adult smokers as a lower-risk alternative to cigarettes. In 2024, the French government took a prohibitionist stance, notifying a draft decree that aimed to ban nicotine pouches entirely, including their production, sale, possession, and use. Framed as a youth protection measure, the proposal triggered immediate backlash from scientists, harm reduction advocates, and members of Parliament who viewed the move as excessive and counterproductive. (Published on August 04, 2025byginn.global)</description></item><item><title>Altria: Oral Nicotine Pouches Continue to Drive Growth</title><link>https://www.convenience.org/Media/Daily/2025/August/1/1_Altria-Oral-Pouches-Drive-Growth__Finance</link><description>In a recent earnings report, Altria said the category ‘grew to 52.0% of its U.S. oral tobacco category.’ In its earnings call this week, Altria Group Inc. reported total net revenues decreased (...) (Published on August 04, 2025byconvenience.org)</description></item><item><title>Flavoured Vaping Products in Tobacco Harm Reduction: A Comprehensive Review</title><link>https://www.cureus.com/articles/382895-flavoured-vaping-products-in-tobacco-harm-reduction-a-regulatory-perspective</link><description>Peer‑reviewed review concludes that flavored electronic vaping products help smokers switch and do not add significant toxicological risk versus tobacco‑flavored vapes. Authors warn that flavor bans may increase smoking or illicit trade, and urge regulators to keep flavor diversity while limiting youth access (Published on August 05, 2025bycureus.com)</description></item><item><title>Vape Group: So We Followed the Rules… and Now You Want to Ban Us?</title><link>https://www.scoop.my/news/266561/vape-group-so-we-followed-the-rules-and-now-you-want-to-ban-us</link><description>KUALA LUMPUR — The Health Ministry’s push to ban vape products while simultaneously approving them for market registration sends a contradictory and confusing signal to both the public and industry players, says Malaysian Organisation of Vape Entity (MOVE) president Samsul Kamal Ariffin. (Published on August 05, 2025byscoop.my)</description></item><item><title>Eliquid Base Launches Compliant Prefilled Pod Kit as Legal Alternative to Banned Disposable Vapes in the UK</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/news-release/2025/08/03/3126243/0/en/Eliquid-Base-Launches-Compliant-Prefilled-Pod-Kit-as-Legal-Alternative-to-Banned-Disposable-Vapes-in-the-UK.html</link><description>With the UK government's 2025 disposable vape ban now in effect to tackle environmental concerns and reduce health risks, millions of vapers are left seeking legal and reliable alternatives. Eliquid Base, one of the UK's leading online vape retailers, has stepped up with a robust solution; the launch of compliant prefilled pod kits that align with UK TPD regulations, offering the same convenience and flavour experience as disposables without breaching the new rules. (Published on August 05, 2025byglobenewswire.com)</description></item><item><title>Japan’s Sharp Smoking Decline Tied to Rise in Heated Tobacco Use</title><link>https://www.24shareupdates.com/2025/08/01/japans-sharp-smoking-decline-tied-to-rise-in-heated-tobacco-use</link><description>According to a study published in October 2024 in the international peer-reviewed journal Tobacco Control, “Transformation of the Tobacco Product Market in Japan, 2011–2023,” per capita and total cigarette sales in Japan decreased by more than 50 percent between 2011 and 2023. This trend remained relatively flat until 2015, when HTPs were introduced to the Japanese market, after which the rate of decline accelerated markedly. (Published on August 05, 2025by24shareupdates.com)</description></item><item><title>What’s So Bad About Nicotine?</title><link>https://www.theatlantic.com/health/archive/2025/08/nicotine-risks-zyn-vapes/683730</link><description>For the better part of the past century, the case against nicotine was simple: Smoking a cigarette might feel nice, but it will eventually kill you. Nearly one in five deaths in the United States is caused by complications from cigarette smoke. But in 2025, nicotine isn’t so straightforward. Smoking is so deadly not because of nicotine (...) (Published on August 05, 2025bytheatlantic.com)</description></item></channel></rss>