<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 01:00:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What I Saw at the FCTC COP11 on Tobacco Control</title><link>https://www.thefirebreak.org/p/what-i-saw-at-the-fctc-cop11-on-tobacco</link><description>Maria Papaioannoy, a Canadian advocate for safer nicotine products, exposes the FCTC's closed-door decision-making at COP11, resembling a belief-driven system. GATC enforces FCTC policies aggressively. Concerns arise as policies seem to protect tobacco, hindering harm reduction. Canada is being used as a testing ground, shifting focus to nicotine control. Provinces like British Columbia and Quebec are influenced, impacting public health. Advocates call for transparency, evidence-based choices, and respect for experiences with safer nicotine products. The push for dialogue, advocacy, and empowerment against restrictive policies marks the beginning of a movement for safer choices worldwide. (Published on November 26, 2025bythefirebreak.org)</description></item><item><title>25 attorneys general demand Shopify crack down on illegal e-cigarette sales to kids</title><link>https://www.consumeraffairs.com/news/25-attorneys-general-demand-shopify-crack-down-on-illegal-e-cigarette-sales-to-kids-112625.html</link><description>Over 28 illegal e-cigarette websites and 200 selling illegal tobacco products are on Shopify. Federal law bans e-cigarette sales to under-21s and requires FDA approval. Attorneys general demand Shopify stop violations. Parents should monitor teens' online activity, educate on risks, and use parental controls. Nationwide actions target e-commerce platforms avoiding regulations. Vigilance is crucial to combat illegal vaping sales and protect youth. (Published on November 26, 2025byconsumeraffairs.com)</description></item><item><title>How Trump can fix the illicit vaping crisis</title><link>https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2025/nov/25/trump-fix-illicit-vaping-crisis/</link><description>Less than a year into his second term, President Trump is facing the consequences of decisions made during the Biden years, especially visible in the crisis of the illicit nicotine market. Currently, up to 85% of vaping devices sold in the U.S. are illegal because they have not received FDA authorization. Around 9 in 10 products have never undergone full FDA review, have not been approved for sale, or are stuck in the agency’s backlog. The ingredients and manufacturing processes of devices that avoid FDA oversight remain unknown. (Published on November 26, 2025bywashingtontimes.com)</description></item><item><title>COP11: dysfunction over harm reduction reveals WHO ‘in crisis’</title><link>https://snusforumet.se/en/cop11-dysfunction-over-harm-reduction-reveals-who-in-crisis/</link><description>Following the WHO COP11 meetings, discussions around banning nicotine pouches amid failed agreements highlight issues within tobacco regulation. Patrik Strömer criticizes the FCTC's focus on ideology over successful harm reduction tactics like New Zealand's, while Sweden's progress is understated. COP11's recognition of countries without significant harm reduction success raises concerns about future tobacco policies. Strömer expresses doubts about COP12's efficacy in curbing smoking rates, citing disconnect between FCTC's discussions and practical outcomes. Although leaving room for EU regulatory updates, bans on nicotine pouches in UN facilities lack substantial impact. Strömer questions the effectiveness of the FCTC, emphasizing the need for tangible results in reducing smoking worldwide. (Published on November 26, 2025bysnusforumet.se)</description></item><item><title>WHO chief urges clampdown on nicotine products aimed at kids</title><link>https://www.nst.com.my/lifestyle/heal/2025/11/1323031/who-chief-urges-clampdown-nicotine-products-aimed-kids?source=widget</link><description>The WHO warns that sleek disposable e-cigarettes and candy-flavored nicotine pouches are targeting youth, driving a new wave of nicotine addiction. WHO chief Tedros Ghebreyesus highlighted schools as a frontline where companies recruit young users. Nearly 15 million teens worldwide now use e-cigarettes. While global tobacco use among youth has declined by a third over 20 years, tobacco companies are creating new products to attract customers, and over eight million people still die annually from tobacco-related diseases. (Published on November 26, 2025bynst.com.my)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #18 | How Moral Panic Is Killing Harm Reduction?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-18-how-moral-panic-is-killing-harm-reduction/</link><description>This GFN Voices 2025 episode brings together advocates, scientists and campaigners from around the world to share why the Global Forum on Nicotine matters, how tobacco harm reduction is being misunderstood, and why honest communication, access to safer products and open debate are essential for helping people move away from smoking. (Published on November 26, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>