<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 01:07:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Millions more using marijuana, nicotine vapes after legalization, study finds</title><link>https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2025/jul/11/millions-using-marijuana-nicotine-vapes-legalization-study-finds/</link><description>A new study published in JAMA Network Open on Friday analyzed data from 55,406 U.S. adults between 2013 and 2022. It found that in states where recreational marijuana was legalized, monthly marijuana use increased by 3.28% and tobacco e-cigarette use rose by 1.39%. These increases accelerated after marijuana dispensaries opened. However, there was no significant change in the number of people smoking traditional cigarettes. Experts express concern over the rising use of vapes and cannabis, especially as today’s marijuana is more potent and potentially more harmful than in the past. (Published on July 14, 2025bywashingtontimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches responsible for growing number of poisonings of young children, study finds</title><link>https://edition.cnn.com/2025/07/14/health/nicotine-pouches-exposure-children</link><description>A recent study highlights a concerning rise in nicotine poisoning among children due to nicotine pouches, with a 760% increase from 2020 to 2023. These pouches, popular for their high nicotine concentration and appealing taste, pose a serious risk, especially to young ones. Public health experts worry about their popularity among teens, despite a small overall user base. Ingesting even small amounts of nicotine from these pouches can lead to severe symptoms. Parents are advised to keep such products out of reach of children and seek immediate help from Poison Control if ingestion is suspected. Ultimately, avoiding exposure and educating caregivers on the dangers are crucial preventive measures. (Published on July 14, 2025bycnn.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #2 | Building effective communication in THR</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-2-building-effective-communication-in-thr/</link><description>In the second episode of #GFN25 Voices, we've invited this year's in-person conference attendees to share their thoughts on the best ways to fix misperceptions about THR! (Published on July 14, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>