<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:18:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Two decades of global tobacco control: time for a rethink</title><link>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11739-025-04131-x</link><description>Cigarette smoking remains a major health issue despite tobacco control efforts. Harm reduction strategies like using safer nicotine alternatives are crucial. Current tobacco control methods have limitations, leading to slow decline in smoking rates globally. Successful implementation of MPOWER measures has not significantly reduced smoking prevalence. Policy reform, accepting harm reduction, can accelerate reduction in smoking-related harm. Clinicians should support patients in using less harmful alternatives to combat smoking. Policymakers should focus on reducing smoking rather than banning safer alternatives. Adopting harm reduction in tobacco control strategies is vital for the next phase of the Framework Convention on Tobacco Control to achieve faster declines in smoking-related diseases and deaths. (Published on November 11, 2025byspringer.com)</description></item><item><title>Public health versus the public</title><link>https://thecritic.co.uk/public-health-versus-the-public/</link><description>As mentioned back in June, the European Commission has been preparing a plan to introduce EU-wide taxes on e-cigarettes and nicotine pouches. Consumers became aware of this and responded en masse to the mandatory public consultation, with the vast majority opposing the proposal. Public health NGOs were outraged that the public actively took part in the consultation and struck back through one of their favourite outlets — Politico. The outlet noted that there were 18,480 responses — nine times the average for EU consultations — and ran the story under the headline: “EU tobacco tax hike plan swamped with pro-industry feedback.” (Published on November 11, 2025bythecritic.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Expert Wall: statements on FCTC and tobacco harm reduction (2025)</title><link>https://clivebates.com/papers-and-letters/cop11experts/</link><description>This page provides statements from independent experts on tobacco science and policy. They are addressed to delegates in advance of the 11th Session of the FCTC Conference of the Parties (COP-11), held in Geneva, 17-22nd November 2025. Each statement is linked from the author’s entry in the table of contents. (Published on November 11, 2025byclivebates.com)</description></item></channel></rss>