<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:20:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>8 reasons the government should not introduce oral nicotine pouches to NZ</title><link>https://theconversation.com/8-reasons-the-government-should-not-introduce-oral-nicotine-pouches-to-nz-271604</link><description>The New Zealand government failed to achieve the smokefree goal, with 6.8% of adults smoking daily. Tobacco remains available with disparities, especially among Māori smokers at 15%. Vaping is popular among youth, with 13.6% of 15-17-year-olds vaping daily, raising addiction concerns. Oral nicotine pouches are proposed, but health officials doubt their effectiveness as cessation aids and warn of health risks, addiction, and youth appeal. Introduction of such products may worsen nicotine addiction issues, contradicting public health goals. Evidence is lacking on their benefits, safety, and impact on youth. The government’s focus should be on reducing smoking and addiction, not introducing potentially harmful alternatives. (Published on December 10, 2025bytheconversation.com)</description></item><item><title>Dual use of cigarettes and vapes can reduce risks of smoking and help smokers quit, study finds</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-12-dual-cigarettes-vapes-smokers.html</link><description>A study by Queen Mary University London reveals that smokers who dual-use cigarettes and e-cigarettes might reduce harmful chemical intake and increase chances of quitting. Dual-users who didn't quit entirely managed to reduce smoking rates and toxic intake. Results suggest e-cigarettes lower smoking urges compared to nicotine replacement therapy. Participants shifting to nicotine-free e-liquids highlights a gradual quitting approach. Tobacco-flavored e-liquids were less popular for quitting. The study emphasizes the harm-reduction potential of dual use. Ultimately, quitting smoking significantly benefits health. The study's findings emphasize the positive impact of dual-use patterns on smoking cessation. (Published on December 10, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item></channel></rss>