<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 12:24:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Daily Pouch Money: Does Altria Belong in Your Portfolio?</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/altria-stock-2025-nicotine-pouch-investment/</link><description>Daily Pouch Money reviews nicotine pouch makers. PMI rose 7.3% and BAT 20%. Analysts explore Altria, up 23.6%, predicting its future amid smoke-free ambitions and regulatory risks. Altria’s on! pouches surge 18%, aiming for $5 billion yearly by 2028. Market share decline suggests Marlboro loyalty. Despite downsides like US regulation and stiff competition, Altria's dividends and potential gains from NJOY vapes provide buying incentives. Investing in Altria balances risk and reward, and while short-term projections are positive, long-term growth may be modest due to industry shifts. Ultimately, Altria's performance depends on innovation and market dynamics, setting expectations for single-digit growth in 2025. (Published on August 20, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #7 | Why communication is the heart of science?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-7-why-communication-is-the-heart-of-science/</link><description>In this episode of GFN Voices, Gabriel Oke explores one of the most overlooked yet vital aspects of scientific work: communication. He explains that no matter how important or innovative research may be, its true impact depends on how clearly and effectively it is shared with the world. From researchers and academics to policymakers, advocates, and the public, communication is the bridge that turns data into action and science into progress. (Published on August 20, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>‘Vaping is safer than cigarettes,’ Kgosi Letlape blasts health department advert</title><link>https://sundayworld.co.za/politics/vaping-is-safer-than-cigarettes-kgosi-letlape-blasts-health-department-advert/</link><description>ActionSA MP Dr. Letlape defended vaping against Health Department claims, stating it's less harmful than smoking. He criticized false radio ads equating vaping to smoking and accused the department of spreading propaganda. Letlape lodged a complaint and called for the ads' withdrawal, arguing they mislead the public and undermine Parliament's authority. Letlape urged Health Minister Motsoaledi to clarify the misinformation and emphasized vaping's potential for smoking cessation. While e-cigarettes are deemed less harmful by Cancer Research UK, they are not risk-free and should only be used for smoking cessation. The Health Department's misleading ads are criticized for interfering with legislative processes. (Published on August 20, 2025bysundayworld.co.za)</description></item></channel></rss>