<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 06:21:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Young adults commonly mix cannabis with nicotine and tobacco</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-12-young-adults-commonly-cannabis-nicotine.html</link><description>A study from Columbia University Mailman School of Public Health reveals increasing cannabis use and co-use with nicotine products among young adults in New York City. Different forms of cannabis, including vapes and edibles, are popular. The research emphasizes the need to understand health effects and patterns of cannabis use, which have been largely overlooked. The study, published in Tobacco Induced Diseases, calls for increased public health education on the risks of cannabis and nicotine co-use. Findings suggest a growing trend of cannabis consumption, urging further investigation due to evolving social norms and availability of cannabis products. (Published on December 16, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>The FDA Might Be Thawing to THR: Here’s How It Could Move Faster</title><link>https://filtermag.org/fda-tobacco-harm-reduction-thaw/</link><description>In a slow shift towards tobacco harm reduction, the FDA took steps in 2025 by authorizing some nicotine pouches and Juul vapes. Despite past obstacles and misinformation, the agency acknowledged the benefits of safer nicotine products. A pilot program was launched to streamline the authorization process, with hopes to increase efficiency and offer more choices to help smokers quit. However, to achieve significant public health gains like countries such as Sweden, experts urge the FDA to authorize a wider range of safer nicotine products and implement practical reforms. Supporters emphasize the need for clear communication and education to combat smoking-related illnesses effectively. (Published on December 16, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>New study: Swedish snus pouch innovation reduces local irritation</title><link>https://snusforumet.se/en/new-study-swedish-snus-pouch-innovation-reduces-local-irritation/</link><description>In a breakthrough study published in Acta Odontologica Scandinavica, researchers reveal that innovative snus pouch designs can prevent mouth sores and irritation. This finding, involving Swedish dentists, highlights how minor changes in snus products can significantly reduce oral mucosa damage. Entrepreneur Bengt Wiberg's startup, Stingfree AB, developed technology to protect snus users' gums after he experienced irritation. The research counters misconceptions about snus, positioning it as a safer alternative to smoking. It refutes EU opposition based on oral health concerns, emphasizing that technical advancements can enhance the safety profile of nicotine products and promote a more balanced approach to risk assessment. (Published on December 16, 2025bysnusforumet.se)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #168 | INSIDE TOBACCO HARM REDUCTION IN 2025</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-168-inside-tobacco-harm-reduction-in-2025/</link><description>Join us for a fast-moving roundup of the most significant tobacco harm reduction developments of 2025. From FCTC COP11 controversies and global bans to new scientific insights, advocacy efforts, and major policy shifts, Will Godfrey breaks down the year’s biggest stories. Discover where progress is being made, where setbacks continue, and how real-world consumers are shaping the future of safer nicotine. (Published on December 16, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Azerbaijan to ban electronic cigarettes</title><link>https://news.az/news/azerbaijan-to-ban-electronic-cigarettes</link><description>Azerbaijan plans to ban electronic cigarettes and their components, reclassifying them as tobacco products under new amendments. The ban covers import, export, production, and sale, aiming to tighten regulations and clarify definitions for better control. Related changes to tax laws and advertising regulations are also proposed, including restricting advertising of non-nicotine e-cigarettes. The move follows discussions in parliamentary committees to align legislation with the updated classifications. (Published on December 16, 2025bynews.az)</description></item></channel></rss>