<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 01:05:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New phase of ‘Give Up For Good’ campaign launches to help Australians quit smoking and vaping</title><link>https://www.health.gov.au/news/new-phase-of-give-up-for-good-campaign-launches-to-help-australians-quit-smoking-and-vaping</link><description>The ‘Give Up For Good’ campaign is helping Australians live healthier, nicotine-free lives by empowering them to quit smoking and vaping for good - or to never start. Designed to help protect people of all ages from the harms of tobacco and nicotine addiction, this new phase of the campaign responds to recent research showing most Australians who smoke or vape are open to, or trying to quit, and are seeking information to help them take the next step. (Published on January 19, 2026byhealth.gov.au)</description></item><item><title>Taiwan to allow travelers to bring in heated tobacco products duty-free</title><link>https://focustaiwan.tw/society/202601190016</link><description>Starting from Feb. 1, travelers entering Taiwan can bring 200 duty-free heated tobacco sticks, bought in Taiwan airports, due to health approval rules. Only approved products can be brought in to comply with the Tobacco Hazards Prevention Act. Those found with unapproved items may face fines. The Ministry of Health and Welfare has designated two companies with approved heated tobacco products for sale in Taiwan. Travelers are advised to buy these products in duty-free shops to prevent violations. The Health Promotion Administration will educate the public on these regulations. (Published on January 19, 2026byfocustaiwan.tw)</description></item><item><title>CAPHRA Warns Australian Senate: Prohibition Has Failed, Regulation Is The Only Way Forward</title><link>https://www.scoop.co.nz/stories/WO2601/S00163/caphra-warns-australian-senate-prohibition-has-failed-regulation-is-the-only-way-forward.htm</link><description>The Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA) delivered a clear message to the Australian Senate: Australia’s illegal tobacco crisis is the result of failed policy, not weak enforcement, and no amount of additional resources will fix a problem created by prohibition. In its submission to the Senate Legal and Constitutional Affairs Committee’s inquiry into the illegal tobacco market, CAPHRA warned that organised crime has taken control of a black market worth around A$4 billion. This market has been driven by policies that removed legal access to safer nicotine products while consumer demand remained unchanged. (Published on January 19, 2026byscoop.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>Compromise proposal on tobacco ‘is opposite of harm reduction’</title><link>https://brusselssignal.eu/2026/01/compromise-proposal-on-tobacco-is-opposite-of-harm-reduction/</link><description>A leaked compromise proposal from the Cypriot presidency on the EU's Tobacco Excise Directive has faced criticism for undermining harm reduction by discouraging switching to less harmful alternatives. Despite lowering tax rates on vaping and heated tobacco compared to the European Commission’s plan, critics argue the proposal maintains a structure that favors fiscal goals over public health. [...] The World Vapers’ Alliance opposes the proposal, urging member states to reject it and opt for taxation that strongly promotes switching to lower-risk options. (Published on January 19, 2026bybrusselssignal.eu)</description></item><item><title>Vapes Improve Quit Chances</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2026-01-19_argie-bargy.html</link><description>A new report, Tale of Two Nations: Argentina v Sweden, shows that safer nicotine alternatives such as vapes and oral nicotine pouches significantly improve smokers’ chances of quitting, particularly as part of a New Year’s attempt. The report contrasts Argentina’s rising smoking rates with Sweden’s success in reducing smoking through regulated access to smoke-free alternatives such as vapes. (Published on January 19, 2026byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>