<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:56:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dutch doctors file complaint against Snapchat over illegal vape sales</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/dutch-doctors-file-complaint-against-snapchat-over-illegal-vape-sales/</link><description>Dutch doctors have filed a complaint against Snapchat's parent company, Snap, for not preventing illegal vape sales to teenagers in the Netherlands. The complaint alleges that Snapchat violates the EU's Digital Services Act by allowing dealers to use the app for selling nicotine products. Despite promised safeguards, investigations show teenagers can still access vape dealers on the platform easily. Doctors argue that Snap's measures have failed, leading to a vape epidemic among young people. The doctors urge regulators to take stronger action to protect minors from online risks. Snapchat has responded by enhancing safeguards, but concerns persist about the platform's role in youth nicotine addiction. (Published on September 04, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Teen vapers are getting e-cigs on black market despite worrying link to strokes</title><link>https://www.mirror.co.uk/news/health/teen-vapers-getting-e-cigs-35842597</link><description>Teenagers are obtaining e-cigarettes from the black market, increasing addiction risks despite a study linking vaping to strokes. A survey found that most underage vapers get their devices online, with concerns raised about weak age verification methods in shops. The growth of this unregulated market poses dangers to youth health. Research has shown vaping's association with various health risks, with experts urging stricter age checks and regulation. Despite e-cigarettes being promoted for smoking cessation, there are worries about non-smoking youths taking up vaping. Enhancing age verification measures and regulation are crucial to combat youth vaping and its potential health harms. (Published on September 04, 2025bymirror.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>The Five Stupidest Arguments from the City of Baltimore vs ZYN Lawsuit</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/baltimore-zyn-lawsuit-five-worst-arguments/</link><description>The City of Baltimore is suing Philip Morris and Swedish Match for allegedly targeting youth with Zyn nicotine pouches through flavors, social media, rewards programs, and marketing them as tobacco-free. The complaint lacks solid evidence and makes questionable claims, such as linking adult products to youth targeting. The lawsuit is criticized for misconstruing basic marketing strategies and lacking substantial proof of deliberate youth targeting. The City seeks fines and remedies despite weak arguments, suggesting a lack of substance in the case. The lawsuit is seen as a frivolous attempt based on weak reasoning and misconceptions about marketing tactics. (Published on September 04, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>