<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 12:26:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Want to quit cigarettes? Vaping is far from a go-to, Canadian guideline says</title><link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/health/smoking-quit-cmaj-1.7616258</link><description>A new Canadian guideline advises against using e-cigarettes or vapes as a first choice to quit smoking, recommending proven methods like medications and counseling instead. Despite declining smoking rates, tobacco remains a top cause of preventable cancer deaths. The guideline highlights the risks of vaping, citing lack of long-term safety data and stresses the effectiveness of nicotine replacements like patches. It discourages alternative treatments and notes the need for further research, including on the efficacy of AI-based therapy. Overall, quitting smoking is challenging but achievable with the right support and strategies. (Published on August 25, 2025bycbc.ca)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #68 | SWEDEN’S SECRET | Nicotine Innovation Challenging the Norms</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-68/</link><description>Sweden’s success with snus and now nicotine pouches proves tobacco harm reduction is a model for helping millions quit smoking. But there’s a secret behind this success. Shot on location at GFN 2025 in Warsaw, Poland, we speak with Anna Franzén and Tomas Hammargren of Emplicure about the big questions surrounding nicotine policy and the realities of recreational use. (Published on August 25, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>New guideline offers menu of options to help people quit smoking tobacco</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-08-guideline-menu-options-people-tobacco.html</link><description>A new guideline published in CMAJ provides effective options for quitting tobacco smoking, a leading cause of preventable disease and death in Canada. The guideline includes behavioral and medication choices as well as a natural health product, tailored to personal preferences. It aims to address the challenges of quitting smoking, which is highly addictive and increases the risk of various diseases. Clinicians are advised to assess patients' smoking status and offer recommended cessation options through shared decision-making. The guideline recommends against certain smoking cessation methods and suggests using e-cigarettes only as a last resort. Overall, the guideline supports efforts to reduce smoking prevalence and offers practical tools for clinicians to assist patients in quitting smoking effectively. (Published on August 25, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Rethink plan to ban vaping, says PSM chief</title><link>https://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2025/08/25/rethink-plan-to-ban-vaping-says-psm-chief</link><description>PSM criticizes the Malaysian government's plan to ban vaping, calling it an overreach in personal habits. The chairman stresses that while vaping is harmful, criminalizing it is not the solution and suggests regulating it instead. He warns that prohibition can lead to a black market and hinder health monitoring. Comparisons are made to bans on alcohol and other unhealthy habits. The former MP advises against coercive legislation and warns of potential negative societal impacts akin to Orwell's "1984." Despite state actions, the government delays a nationwide ban to avoid legal repercussions from the vape industry. (Published on August 25, 2025byfreemalaysiatoday.com)</description></item><item><title>Media, Researchers Fuel More Vape Misperceptions</title><link>https://filtermag.org/media-researchers-vape-misperceptions/</link><description>Media often sensationalize tobacco harm reduction, misinterpreting incomplete studies. A Guardian article claimed a study showed a third of UK teen vapers might start smoking, implying a gateway effect. Criticisms, including by Dr. Arielle Selya, questioned the study's methods and conclusions. Selya suggested a neutral approach to interpreting the results. The academic study warned of a potential link between vaping and smoking, while ASH UK reported concerns about vaping misconceptions among adults and youth. Selya attributed these misconceptions to sensationalist media coverage influencing public perception. The complex issue involves conflicting interpretations of data and potential biases. (Published on August 26, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>How Australia Is Failing People With Mental Illness Who Smoke</title><link>https://www.thr101.org/post/how-australia-is-failing-people-with-mental-illness-who-smoke</link><description>Anew study published inHealth Expectationsis providing important insight into smoking cessation among people diagnosed with mental illness. The researchers set out to explore how individuals with mental health conditions experience tobacco use and quitting, why they smoke, what motivates them to stop, and what forms of support they find helpful or lacking. Using in-depth, semi-structured interviews with 17 adults in Queensland – all of whom had a mental health diagnosis and at least one quit attempt in the past five years – the study highlights the complex interplay between tobacco use, mental health, and recovery. (Published on August 26, 2025bythr101.org)</description></item></channel></rss>