<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 18:19:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #6 | Interview with Ian Fearon</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-6-interview-with-ian-fearon</link><description>Flavors can play a key role in helping smokers switch. Many start with tobacco flavor but move to others over time — distancing themselves from the reminder of smoking. As adults, we enjoy sweets, drinks, and treats — why should quitting be any different? (Published on August 12, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Vapes and HTPs Reduce Toxin Exposure by More than 90%, Lithuanian Study Finds</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/vapes-and-htps-reduce-toxin-exposure-by-more-than-90-lithuanian-study-finds</link><description>Heated tobacco products (HTPs) and vapes reduce exposure to harmful chemicals by more than 90 per cent compared to cigarettes, according to a major new study. (Published on August 12, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>WHO Backs Thailand’s E-Cigarette Ban: Ignoring Evidence and Silencing Consumers</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/who-backs-thailands-e-cigarette-ban-ignoring-evidence-and-silencing-consumers</link><description>Thailand’s ongoing ban on e-cigarettes, supported by the World Health Organization (WHO), is a policy deeply disconnected from real-world evidence and the voices of those it most affects: the consumers seeking safer alternatives to smoking. (Published on August 12, 2025byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Barbados Has a Unique Opportunity to Champion Harm Reduction at COP11</title><link>https://nationnews.com/2025/08/11/barbados-has-a-unique-opportunity-to-champion-harm-reduction-at-cop11</link><description>This year, the world’s eyes will turn to Geneva as leaders gather for COP11, the World Health Organization’s critical conference on tobacco control. As decisions are made that will impact global health for years to come, Barbados finds itself at a crossroads. Will the country simply follow the crowd, or will it seize the chance to be a bold voice for pragmatic, science-driven solutions like harm reduction? (Published on August 12, 2025bynationnews.com)</description></item><item><title>Flavoured Vaping Products in Tobacco Harm Reduction: A Regulatory Perspective</title><link>https://www.cureus.com/articles/382895-flavoured-vaping-products-in-tobacco-harm-reduction-a-regulatory-perspective</link><description>Reducing the harms associated with cigarette smoking is a global public health priority. Both the individual‑ and population‑level health impacts of smoking can be reduced by novel products which deliver nicotine, but the use of which decreases user exposure to the harmful chemical toxicants responsible for smoking‑related disease. Electronic vaping products (...) (Published on August 12, 2025bycureus.com)</description></item></channel></rss>