<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 12:24:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Panama Implements Comprehensive New Vaping Regulations</title><link>https://ecigator.com/news/panama-vaping-regulations-ban</link><description>Panama’s Ministry of Health (MINSA) has announced that new, comprehensive regulations governing the use, sale, and promotion of all e-cigarettes and vaping devices are now in effect. The rules apply to all electronic and non-electronic nicotine delivery systems (ENDS and ENNDS) and are designed to protect public health, with a strong emphasis on safeguarding children and adolescents from the documented risks of these products. (Published on August 15, 2025byecigator.com)</description></item><item><title>Belgium Extends Plain Packaging to All Tobacco Products from 2026</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/08/13/belgium-extends-plain-packaging-to-all-tobacco-products-from-2026</link><description>Belgium will require cigars, cigarillos, cigarette papers, filters, tubes, and all other “herbal products intended for smoking” to adopt standardized green-brown packaging with uniform fonts and health warnings, Health Minister Frank Vandenbroucke announced. Effective June 1, 2026, the measure expands existing (...) (Published on August 15, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Senegal's Prime Minister Moves to Increase Tobacco Taxes to Save Lives, Stimulate Economic Growth</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/senegals-prime-minister-moves-to-increase-tobacco-taxes-to-save-lives-stimulate-economic-growth-302528264.html</link><description>The Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids applauds Senegalese Prime Minister Ousmane Sonko's announcement that the country will raise taxes on tobacco products to save lives and stimulate the economy. Increasing taxes on tobacco products is a smart move, a huge win for public health and a popular policy initiative. (Published on August 15, 2025byprnewswire.com)</description></item><item><title>Online Vape Sales in Malaysia Thrive Despite Ban</title><link>https://www.straitstimes.com/asia/se-asia/online-vape-sales-in-malaysia-thrive-despite-ban</link><description>The law in Malaysia bans the sale of vape-related products online, yet they remain widely available through Internet search engines. (Published on August 15, 2025bystraitstimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Vanished Report: Australia’s Smoking Reversal and the Quiet Cover-Up</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/08/04/vanished-report-australias-smoking-reversal-and-the-quiet-cover-up</link><description>Last month, behind-the-scenes pressure, not faulty data, led to the quiet removal of inconvenient research findings that contradict the Australia government's narrative. (Published on August 15, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item></channel></rss>