<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 12:25:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tobacco-funded research continues to appear in leading medical journals</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250601/Tobacco-funded-research-continues-to-appear-in-leading-medical-journals.aspx</link><description>Despite efforts to sever ties, tobacco-funded research still appears in top medical journals, complicating efforts to distance from the industry. The Investigative Desk and The BMJ's investigation found that only 20% of leading medical journals have policies against tobacco-funded studies. Identifying funding sources is challenging due to tobacco companies' involvement in various fields. The revised BMJ policy now excludes research funded by the industry and work with authors' financial ties to tobacco companies, aiming to publish more independent and reliable content. Experts emphasize the importance of rejecting industry money to protect public health and integrity in research. (Published on June 03, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>E-cigarette liquids legal but strictly regulated, says Health Ministry</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/news/nation/2025/06/02/e-cigarette-liquids-legal-but-strictly-regulated-says-health-ministry#goog_rewarded</link><description>E-cigarette liquids in Malaysia are regulated under Act 852 by multiple government agencies, including MITI and the Health Ministry. A recent statement clarified that manufacturing licenses for these liquids fall under MITI, while the Health Ministry monitors contents and emissions to protect public health. The Customs Department controls raw material imports, and SIRIM tests safety standards. Regulations define e-cigarette liquid as a smoking substance including nicotine and glycols. Stringent oversight aims to uphold public health and safety in accordance with Madani values. (Published on June 03, 2025bythestar.com.my)</description></item><item><title>New Alabama vape law bans flavored e-cigarettes in stores</title><link>https://www.alreporter.com/2025/06/02/new-alabama-vape-law-bans-flavored-e-cigarettes-in-stores/</link><description>A new law in Alabama, effective June 1, will change how retailers sell vape products, banning flavored e-cigarettes in convenience stores. It introduces two permits: the ABC Tobacco Permit for traditional tobacco and approved e-nicotine products, and the ABC Specialty Permit for vape-focused stores. Only FDA-approved tobacco and mint e-cigarettes can be sold in convenience stores, with fruit and candy flavors restricted to specialty shops. Aimed at curbing youth vaping, the law impacts retailer revenue with fines for violations. The industry braces for financial strain, while health advocates support the move to protect youth from vaping risks. (Published on June 03, 2025byalreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>PH eyes Swedish model to reduce smoking harm</title><link>https://manilastandard.net/business/314597306/ph-eyes-swedish-model-to-reduce-smoking-harm.html</link><description>Sweden is hailed as a leading example in tobacco harm reduction, with low smoking rates attributed to snus and nicotine pouches. JTI Sweden showcases its oral nicotine products and cutting-edge technologies. The company's Nordic Snus brand competes in the market, while JTI Philippines prioritizes harm reduction with products like Nordic Spirit. The country's success in reducing smoking rates is noted, with nicotine pouches seen as effective alternatives for quitting smoking. Sweden's low smoking prevalence and health outcomes compared to the EU average are highlighted. The Philippines, with high smoking rates, presents a promising market for reduced-risk products like nicotine pouches, showing a growing demand for alternatives. (Published on June 03, 2025bymanilastandard.net)</description></item><item><title>Concern ahead of vape ban</title><link>https://www.westminsterextra.co.uk/article/concern-ahead-of-vape-ban</link><description>A ban on single-use disposable vaping devices in the UK has led to panic-buying and discounts on products. This legislation aims to reduce nicotine addiction and fire hazards. However, concerns remain about enforcement and potential loopholes. Groups suggest licensing vape sellers to ensure compliance. There are worries about a return to smoking and the attractiveness of new vape products. Despite efforts to crack down on illegal sales, shops in Westminster have been found with suspected counterfeit and stolen goods. Authorities are increasing checks on vape sales to uphold the ban and protect consumers. (Published on June 03, 2025bywestminsterextra.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Mexico’s crackdown on safer nicotine alternatives is costing thousands of lives, says global report</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/mexicos-crackdown-on-safer-nicotine-alternatives-is-costing-thousands-of-lives-says-global-report/</link><description>A new report highlights Mexico's high smoking-related death toll due to strict anti-nicotine product policies, contrasting with Sweden's success in reducing smoking rates through harm reduction strategies. Mexico's smoking rate has increased, causing 65,000 deaths yearly, while Sweden's rate has dropped significantly. Legal, affordable access to alternatives like snus and vapes has aided Sweden's success. Bans in Mexico have led to a black market and failed to curtail smoking. The report advocates for harm reduction policies, emphasizing the safety of alternatives compared to cigarettes. It suggests that legalizing and regulating these products can help smokers transition away from harmful smoking. (Published on June 03, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>TobaccoIntelligence Exclusive for GFN25</title><link>https://gfn.events/media/2024/tobaccointelligence-exclusive-for-gfn25/</link><description>Proposed legislation in Poland aims to ban flavoured nicotine pouches and disposable vapes to reduce youth access to nicotine. Similar moves in France and potential restrictions in Luxembourg, Ireland, and Spain indicate a trend towards stricter regulations on such products in Europe. Critics argue that bans could fuel black market sales, while supporters emphasize public health benefits. Sweden, with its harm reduction approach allowing snus sales, contrasts with Poland's stance. The ongoing debate raises questions about the future direction of nicotine policy across European countries. (Published on June 04, 2025bytobaccointelligence.com)</description></item></channel></rss>