<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 06:22:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nicotine a Heart Threat, Per “Expert Consensus Report.” Experts Disagree.</title><link>https://filtermag.org/nicotine-cardiovascular-health-experts/</link><description>Recent expert consensus calls nicotine a potent cardiovascular toxin, urging the EU to act. The narrative of safer nicotine is challenged, emphasizing all forms are harmful. Recommendations include flavor bans and taxation proportional to nicotine content. Critics question the validity of the report's findings and policy goals. They argue for harm reduction, citing examples like Swedish snus. The report's stance against safer nicotine products is viewed suspiciously by advocates. It aligns with EU debates on tobacco regulations. Supporters of harm reduction stress its role in reducing smoking rates. The report's timing coincides with EU health plans, raising concerns about its influence. (Published on January 15, 2026byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>2Firsts Interview | Bengt Wiberg: Why the Oral Health Risks of Nicotine Pouches Merit Further Study</title><link>https://www.2firsts.com/news/2firsts-interview--bengt-wiberg-why-the-oral-health-risks-of-nicotine-pouches-merit-further-study</link><description>In 2025, nicotine pouches have become one of the most closely watched categories in the global novel tobacco market, seeing rapid growth across manufacturing, branding, distribution, and retail. Just before Christmas, the U.S. FDA granted marketing authorization to six products under Altria’s on! PLUS brand, highlighting their recognition as tobacco harm reduction tools. Despite this, experts note that nicotine pouches are still relatively new and require longer-term, more detailed studies on safety. Concerns about oral health have grown, particularly regarding gum irritation, oral lesions, and potential long-term changes to oral tissues. As the market expands, ongoing research will be key to understanding both the benefits and risks of these products. (Published on January 15, 2026by2firsts.com)</description></item></channel></rss>