<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 12:28:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Only Country In The World Where 'Smoking Is Banned': Huge Fines For Vaping; Not New Zealand, Sri Lanka, But…</title><link>https://zeenews.india.com/photos/world/only-country-in-the-world-where-smoking-is-banned-huge-fines-for-vaping-not-new-zealand-sri-lanka-but-2990620</link><description>President Mohamed Muizzu introduced new measures to cultivate a capable, ethical, and hardworking population in the country. Maldives has become the first country in the world to introduce a “generational ban” on smoking. From November 1, 2025, anyone born after January 1, 2007, cannot legally buy or use tobacco products. The ban also covers e-cigarettes and vaping devices, with import, sale, possession, and use prohibited. The law applies to both residents and tourists, and violations can result in fines. The government’s goal is to create a “tobacco-free generation” and protect public health. (Published on December 01, 2025byindia.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches: solution or smokescreen?</title><link>https://www.spectator.co.uk/podcast/nicotine-pouches-solution-or-smokescreen/</link><description>In Europe, there is a growing focus on reducing tobacco use through generational smoking bans and stricter regulations. Philip Morris International aims for most of its revenue to come from smoke-free products like Zyn by 2030. A discussion sponsored by PMI explores how nicotine pouches can aid the shift to a smoke-free future, featuring perspectives from their chief communications officer and a Swedish MEP. The conversation delves into whether PMI's motives are genuine or business-driven, lessons from Sweden's smoke-free goals, and the scientific aspects. The Spectator maintains editorial independence in this sponsored podcast. (Published on December 01, 2025byspectator.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #165 | WHY NEW ZEALAND WAS SHAMED FOR REDUCING SMOKING?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-165-why-new-zealand-was-shamed-for-reducing-smoking/</link><description>In this exclusive GFN News interview, Joanna Junak speaks with Nancy Loucas, CAPHRA Executive Coordinator, about the fallout from COP11 in Geneva and the controversial Dirty Ashtray Award given to New Zealand. (Published on December 01, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>The WHO’s Campaign Against Safe Nicotine</title><link>https://brownstone.org/articles/the-whos-campaign-against-safe-nicotine/</link><description>Every two years, the 183 Parties to the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control meet at the Conference of the Parties (COP), the treaty’s governing body. It is a closed-door diplomatic forum where global tobacco policies, regulations, and political direction are decided. Civil society and journalists are largely excluded, with outsiders allowed only in limited public sessions while real negotiations take place behind closed doors. The meetings are heavily influenced by the FCTC Secretariat and a small group of Bloomberg-funded NGOs whose positions often shape the agenda. This power structure forms the essential context for understanding what happened at COP11. (Published on December 01, 2025bybrownstone.org)</description></item><item><title>Fruit and mint flavours dominate vape sales after disposable ban, new data shows</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/fruit-and-mint-flavours-dominate-vape-sales-after-disposable-ban-new-data-shows/</link><description>Fruit and mint flavors dominate vape sales post-ban, with fruit leading at 30.4%, followed by fruit/mint at 24.2% and mint at 20.7%. Preferences differ by age, with fruit favored by 18-54-year-olds and mint by those 55 and older. Haypp emphasizes the importance of flavor variety in supporting smokers switching to reduced risk options. The UK sees more adults vaping than smoking for the first time, with vaping identified as a major driver in smoking reduction. Industry calls for clearer communication on vaping's lower risks and warns against misconceptions. The government introduces QR-tag measures to combat illegal vape sales, safeguarding public health. (Published on December 01, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Here’s How BC Can Help People Quit Smoking</title><link>https://thetyee.ca/Opinion/2025/12/01/How-BC-Can-Help-People-Quit-Smoking/</link><description>Quitting smoking is a challenging process that often requires appropriate support and effective tools. A recent recommendation from the legislature’s budget committee advises the government to consider expanding access to Health Canada–approved nicotine pouches as a smoking cessation aid. This recommendation appears in the committee’s report based on 16 public meetings and online submissions. The proposal would address last year’s policy change that placed Zonnic, the only approved nicotine pouch, behind the pharmacy counter. The hope is that the B.C. government will move forward with implementing this adjustment. (Published on December 01, 2025bythetyee.ca)</description></item><item><title>Youth vaping halves in New Zealand</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/youth-vaping-halves-in-new-zealand/</link><description>Youth vaping in New Zealand has drastically decreased, halving in two years. The ASH Year 10 Snapshot Survey found that regular use among 14 to 15-year-olds dropped significantly, attributed to targeted regulations instead of bans. While daily vaping fell, smoking among teens is nearly eliminated. NZ's harm-reduction strategy focuses on curtailing youth access while aiding smokers to quit. Despite progress, Māori youth vaping rates are high, requiring specific support. This success model is being watched globally, with policymakers interested in New Zealand's approach of reducing harm without prohibiting alternatives. (Published on December 02, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item></channel></rss>