<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 18:20:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vaping Ban Exists Only On Paper</title><link>https://www.freepressjournal.in/analysis/vaping-ban-exists-only-on-paper</link><description>The vaping ban, ineffective in practice, has led to a surge in smuggling of e-cigarettes into India, contributing to health risks and substance abuse concerns among youths. The ban, aiming to protect teenagers, has inadvertently made vapes more accessible, with loopholes exploited by smugglers. Experts note the dangers of unregulated vaping, highlighting risks of addiction and health issues. While vaping is considered less harmful than smoking in some countries, its uncontrolled spread in India raises alarms. Despite regulations, vaping products are openly sold online, fueling a growing market worth $2.2 billion. Addressing these issues through public awareness campaigns is crucial, given the lax enforcement and the significant number of cigarette smokers in the country. (Published on January 06, 2026byfreepressjournal.in)</description></item><item><title>COP11 insider speaks out: censorship, influence, and lost trust</title><link>https://worldvapersalliance.com/cop11-insider-speaks-out-censorship-influence-and-lost-trust/</link><description>Respected public health expert Jindřich Vobořil criticizes the WHO's tobacco control agenda for prioritizing ideology over evidence at the COP11 meeting. He highlights the hypocrisy of countries like China pushing for extreme measures while profiting from tobacco at home. Vobořil notes the exclusion of harm reduction and consumer voices in favor of well-funded NGOs linked to major donors, leading to a one-sided discussion. The focus on debunked myths instead of successful harm reduction strategies is alarming. He emphasizes the importance of evidence-based policies to save lives and warns of the consequences of ignoring science. The WHO must prioritize innovation and transparency to regain public trust and prevent unnecessary deaths. (Published on January 06, 2026byworldvapersalliance.com)</description></item><item><title>Africa’s nicotine moment: What to watch in 2026</title><link>https://www.environewsnigeria.com/africas-nicotine-moment-what-to-watch-in-2026/</link><description>In 2026, Africa faces a critical decision on tobacco harm reduction policies. Despite strengthening tobacco control measures, smoking remains dominant. African governments must choose to enable safer alternatives or regulate all nicotine equally. The tension between traditional control and harm reduction approaches is growing. Countries like South Africa, Kenya, Nigeria, and Zambia face key decisions on regulating novel nicotine products. Risk-proportionate regulation could lead to decreased smoking rates and healthcare costs. The continent's public health narrative now focuses on accelerating harm reduction alongside tobacco control efforts to combat smoking effectively. (Published on January 06, 2026byenvironewsnigeria.com)</description></item><item><title>Pouches safer than smoking but nicotine levels a concern, says government</title><link>https://www.talkingretail.com/news/industry-news/pouches-safer-than-smoking-but-nicotine-levels-a-concern-says-government-05-01-2026/</link><description>Health Secretary's office recognized nicotine pouches as lower-risk than cigarettes and advocates a 20mg cap to protect adults. They highlight pouches as separate from tobacco in regulation, aiming to avoid unintended consequences like increased smoking rates. The government commits to evidence-based and proportionate policies, consulting on regulations for flavors, ingredients, and display. Efforts include research on vaping and nicotine products, with plans for consultations and engagement with industry. Government acknowledges nicotine pouches as harm reduction tools but warns against youth use due to addiction risks. Focus is on protecting adults' rights while supporting smokers in quitting, ultimately aiming for stricter enforcement and age limits. (Published on January 06, 2026bytalkingretail.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotinic acid protects the liver from ischemia-reperfusion injury</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20260105/Nicotinic-acid-protects-the-liver-from-ischemia-reperfusion-injury.aspx</link><description>A recent study in Liver Research by Chinese researchers reveals that nicotinic acid, a form of vitamin B3, effectively reduces liver damage from hepatic ischemia-reperfusion injury. This type of injury is common in liver surgery and transplants, leading to oxidative stress and inflammation. Nicotinic acid's protective effects surpass N-acetylcysteine by targeting damaged mitochondria, as shown in experiments on mice and hepatocytes. The treatment not only reduces liver injury markers and inflammation but also enhances mitochondrial quality by promoting mitophagy and mitochondrial biogenesis. With its safety, affordability, and availability, nicotinic acid shows promise for improving outcomes in liver surgery, prompting upcoming human trials. (Published on January 06, 2026bynews-medical.net)</description></item></channel></rss>