<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 12:25:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Is vaping less harmful than smoking, and does it help people quit?</title><link>https://ourworldindata.org/vaping-vs-smoking-health-risks</link><description>Vaping is viewed more negatively than before, with concerns raised about its risks. Vapes are less harmful than cigarettes, containing fewer toxins. While not risk-free, vaping helps smokers quit, with research showing its effectiveness. Concerns exist about vaping during pregnancy, but it appears safer than smoking. Vaping is not a significant gateway to smoking among young people. Public health advice recommends vaping for smokers but discourages it for non-smokers. Misconceptions persist, with smokers mostly unaware of vaping benefits. Young people's use of vapes is a concern, but data does not strongly support it as a gateway to smoking. Balancing public health benefits and risks is crucial. (Published on November 04, 2025byourworldindata.org)</description></item><item><title>Brussels’ War on Tobacco Masks an Assault on National Power</title><link>https://europeanconservative.com/articles/news/brussels-war-on-tobacco-assault-on-national-power/</link><description>The European Commission advocates a ban on cigarette filters and e-cigarettes, aligning with WHO directives. This move extends centralized power and fiscal control, overshadowing Member States' sovereignty. The proposal, driven by environmental and health concerns, masks a fiscal control agenda, enabling Brussels to appropriate national tax revenues. NGOs, funded by the Commission, amplify WHO policies, tightening the grip on EU legislation. The regulation would detrimentally impact European tobacco producers and erode subsidiarity principles. It contrasts with successful national policies like Sweden's. The push for global regulations contradicts von der Leyen's promises of economic freedom. Upholding health and freedom necessitates independent legislative decision-making and transparency in NGO funding. (Published on November 04, 2025byeuropeanconservative.com)</description></item></channel></rss>