<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 13:31:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Trump tariffs could lead to surge of cheap Chinese vapes in UK, experts say</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/may/19/uk-vapes-e-cigarettes-chinese-imports-tariffs-trade</link><description>China plans to flood the UK with affordable vapes due to the US-China trade tensions. The US imposed a 60% tariff on Chinese vapes, prompting Chinese manufacturers to target the UK market. With the UK banning disposable vapes, concerns arise about the influx of Chinese alternatives. Industry experts warn of challenges in regulating these new products and ensuring they are not mistaken for disposables. Manufacturers are adapting by introducing rechargeable vape kits, but refill availability remains a concern. Amid environmental worries, efforts are needed to facilitate vape recycling. The Chinese vaping industry is adapting swiftly to navigate these challenges and explore alternative markets to survive. (Published on May 19, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Flawed Science, Fatal Consequences: Unpacking the Misinformation War on Vaping</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/05/16/flawed-science-fatal-consequences-unpacking-the-misinformation-war-on-vaping/</link><description>Scientific evidence challenges old views on tobacco control, particularly regarding safer nicotine alternatives like e-cigarettes and nicotine pouches. The debate questions if these alternatives aid smoking cessation or create new nicotine users. Critiques reveal major flaws in prominent anti-vaping research, casting doubt on its credibility and impact on policy-making. Encouraging harm reduction, groups advocate for evidence-based regulation instead of moral panic. Success stories in countries like Sweden demonstrate reduced smoking rates through harm reduction strategies. Despite mounting evidence, some nations persist in restrictive regulations, risking progress in smoking cessation. It's time for public health leaders to embrace harm reduction and dismiss flawed research hindering societal health gains. (Published on May 19, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>Young men, former smokers most likely to try nicotine pouches, new study shows</title><link>https://www.westernstandard.news/canadian/young-men-former-smokers-most-likely-to-try-nicotine-pouches-new-study-shows/64834</link><description>A study led by epidemiologist Amanda Palmer shows that young men and current tobacco users are most likely to use nicotine pouches, a new product in the tobacco industry. The research, based on data from 2022-23 Population Assessment of Tobacco and Health Survey, found this trend among almost 23,000 participants. Published in JAMA Network Open, this is one of the first studies to measure the popularity of nicotine pouches, starting with Wave 7 of the survey which began tracking tobacco use in 2013. (Published on May 19, 2025bywesternstandard.news)</description></item><item><title>WVA Urges WHO to Embrace Nicotine Pouches as Lifesaving Tools</title><link>https://consideratepouchers.org/wva-urges-who-to-embrace-nicotine-pouches-and-vaping-as-lifesaving-tools/</link><description>A recent policy paper by the World Vapers Alliance challenges the WHO's approach to tobacco control, promoting nicotine pouches and vaping as effective tools to combat smoking. The paper criticizes the outdated "quit or die" strategy and advocates for a risk-proportionate regulatory model based on scientific evidence. Nicotine pouches, deemed safer, are gaining traction in harm reduction efforts. Successful implementations in Sweden contrast with Canada's restrictive policies, leading to a black market. The paper proposes policy reforms to prioritize harm reduction and urges global action towards safer alternatives. The Considerate Pouchers community supports this initiative, emphasizing the role of nicotine pouches in smoking cessation and improved public health. (Published on May 19, 2025byconsideratepouchers.org)</description></item></channel></rss>