<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:19:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>7-Eleven among stores banned from selling popular item that comes in multiple flavors from September 1 or face $1k fines</title><link>https://www.the-sun.com/money/14987225/7-eleven-stores-ban-nicotine-sale-unflavored-pouches/?utm_source=chatgpt.com</link><description>Starting September 1, popular items like nicotine pouches will be banned in Southborough, Massachusetts, affecting stores like 7-Eleven, with fines for violators increased to $1,000. The decision aims to prevent sales appealing to children due to flavored varieties. Despite protests from industry groups citing FDA approval and low youth usage, officials emphasize the products' risks to teens and difficulty in detection by parents. The unanimous board decision follows concerns over teens turning to pouches after a decline in youth vaping. Adult-only stores are the only remaining option for purchasing these products post-ban. (Published on August 18, 2025bythe-sun.com)</description></item><item><title>Ban of single-use vapes a failure as makers replaced outlawed devices with lookalike reusables - that get binned anyway</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-15007461/Ban-single-use-vapes-failure-binned-reusable-binned.html</link><description>The ban on disposable vapes failed as manufacturers replaced them with reusable replicas, still leading to disposal. Despite the ban due to underage vaping, 5.3 million copycat vapes were sold in the first month, but only 1.4 million refills. A survey revealed users buy new devices every 16 days. Environmental concerns were raised, with many discarding vapes instead of refilling. Scott Butler warned of a potential environmental crisis. Tory MP Jack Rankin criticized the ban, suggesting it hindered adult smoking cessation efforts. (Published on August 18, 2025bydailymail.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Evidence, not fear, should guide the FDA’s vaping policies</title><link>https://reason.org/commentary/evidence-not-fear-should-guide-the-fdas-vaping-policies/</link><description>FDA Commissioner Makary emphasized stakeholder consensus and evidence-based decisions on policy issues in a podcast, raising concerns about a "child vaping epidemic" but overlooking adult smokers' needs. Makary should prioritize alternatives for adult smokers, as evidence supports e-cigarettes as a less harmful option than combustible cigarettes. Emphasizing public education to correct misconceptions and authorizing a broader range of appealing alternatives could lead to better health outcomes. Restrictive measures, such as flavor bans, risk driving consumers to the unregulated market and increasing tobacco sales. To improve public health, FDA policies should align with evidence-based approaches and address adult smokers' needs to reduce illicit products and promote safer choices. (Published on August 18, 2025byreason.org)</description></item><item><title>Heated herbal product delivers nicotine with fewer toxins</title><link>https://www.news-medical.net/news/20250818/Heated-herbal-product-delivers-nicotine-with-fewer-toxins.aspx?utm_source=chatgpt.com</link><description>Researchers tested the iSENZIA™ heated herbal system as a potential safer alternative for smokers, delivering nicotine with fewer harmful chemicals than cigarettes. The study found that the system produced aerosols with significantly lower levels of harmful compounds compared to cigarette smoke, supporting reduced exposure and potential harm reduction. Clinical findings showed lower nicotine delivery and satisfaction compared to cigarettes, suggesting lower abuse liability. However, long-term health impact and switching effectiveness require further study. Study limitations include a small sample size and lack of long-term outcomes. (Published on August 18, 2025bynews-medical.net)</description></item><item><title>The State of Academic Research on Nicotine, Part 1</title><link>https://arielleselyaphd.substack.com/p/the-state-of-academic-research-on?utm_source=post-email-title&amp;publication_id=5676531&amp;post_id=169897077&amp;utm_campaign=email-post-title&amp;isFreemail=true&amp;r=11832o&amp;triedRedirect=true&amp;utm_medium=email</link><description>This text, based on a presentation at a conference, highlights flaws in nicotine/tobacco research, discusses harm reduction, and critiques common research flaws. It emphasizes the divisive nature of tobacco harm reduction (THR) research, industry involvement, and bias in interpreting data. Common flaws include disregarding harm continuum, misinterpreting causation, and making inappropriate policy recommendations. The author proposes that confirmation bias and peer reviewer alignment contribute to the field's polarization and declining research integrity. The complexity of nicotine/tobacco research, industry influence, and the need for critical evaluation of scientific studies are discussed. (Published on August 18, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #67 | BANNED IN INDIA | Vape Prohibition and the Fight for Harm Reduction</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-67/</link><description>In India, hundreds of millions of tobacco users are kept in the dark about safer nicotine products, while the government bans popular alternatives like vaping and stays silent on even basic NRTs. Shot on location at GFN 2025 in Warsaw, Poland, Jagannath Sarangapani exposes how prohibition and the absence of relative risk messaging have shaped the country’s tobacco control strategy. (Published on August 18, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>