<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 15:19:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ahead of World No Tobacco Day, Knesset votes to require graphic images on smoking products</title><link>https://www.timesofisrael.com/ahead-of-world-no-tobacco-day-knesset-votes-to-require-graphic-images-on-smoking-products/</link><description>Israel’s Knesset has approved a new bill requiring graphic health warnings not only on cigarette packs but also on e-cigarettes, heated tobacco products, rolling papers, and loose tobacco. This makes Israel one of the first countries to extend such regulations to all tobacco and nicotine products. The decision comes just days before World No Tobacco Day, as the Israel Cancer Association revealed alarming data: 31% of Israeli smokers began or resumed smoking due to stress and anxiety related to the war that started on October 7, 2023. (Published on May 29, 2025bytimesofisrael.com)</description></item><item><title>EU Health Commissioner Under Fire for Spouting Vape Misinformation</title><link>https://filtermag.org/eu-health-commissioner-vape-misinformation/</link><description>European Commissioner Varhelyi's misleading statements on vaping's health risks have sparked criticism. Advocates urge him to consult experts, as anti-vape policies unfold in the EU. Varhelyi's claims of vaping being as harmful as smoking and causing "popcorn lung" are refuted by scientific evidence. The European Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates express concerns over misinformation influencing regulations that restrict safer nicotine products. They emphasize the need for policy decisions based on facts, not myths. Varhelyi's role includes spearheading initiatives to reduce cancer rates linked to smoking in the EU, despite vaping's proven role in smoking cessation. Requests for a meeting to address misinformation have been made, aiming to safeguard public health decisions. (Published on May 29, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Global Experts Warn WHO's Anti-Harm Reduction Stance Undermines World No Tobacco Day</title><link>https://www.prnewswire.com/in/news-releases/global-experts-warn-whos-anti-harm-reduction-stance-undermines-world-no-tobacco-day-302467661.html</link><description>Global tobacco harm reduction experts criticized the WHO and FCTC for hindering World No Tobacco Day goals by ignoring harm-reducing tools like vaping. They believe the WHO's approach fuels black markets and smoking-related deaths, dismissing evidence supporting harm reduction as effective. Panelists highlighted the importance of embracing innovation and consumer input to combat the global smoking epidemic. The WHO's prohibitionist stance was deemed counterproductive, with calls to prioritize saving lives over endorsing failed policies. Despite evidence showing harm reduction methods help smokers quit, the WHO's resistance to such tools was seen as detrimental to public health. (Published on May 29, 2025byprnewswire.com)</description></item><item><title>FDA boss under fire for exaggerated teen vaping claim</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/fda-boss-under-fire-for-exaggerated-teen-vaping-claim/</link><description>Dr. Martin Makary, the new head of the FDA, faces criticism for stating that half of high school students are addicted to vaping. Concerned about Chinese-made vaping products designed to lure kids, Makary urged stricter measures. However, data shows lower youth vaping rates than claimed. While advocating against teen nicotine addiction, experts caution against sensationalized claims. (Published on May 29, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item></channel></rss>