<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:18:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Global Health Experts Examined WHO's Tobacco Control Approach</title><link>https://www.aninews.in/news/business/global-health-experts-examined-whos-tobacco-control-approach20251006113311/?amp=1</link><description>The Consumer Choice Center held a briefing in the Philippines on harm reduction and tobacco control, urging open discussion on effective strategies. Economist Dr. Christopher Cabuay revealed that tobacco-related illnesses cost the country $9.8 billion yearly, and shifting smokers to harm reduction methods could save up to $3.4 billion annually. (Published on October 06, 2025byaninews.in)</description></item><item><title>The EU’s crackdown on safer nicotine alternatives risks driving smokers back to cigarettes</title><link>https://www.brusselstimes.com/1775919/the-eus-crackdown-on-safer-nicotine-alternatives-risks-driving-smokers-back-to-cigarettes</link><description>The sponsored opinion article discusses the ineffective bans and restrictions on nicotine pouches in some EU countries, leading to an increase in smoking and illicit markets. It emphasizes the importance of harm reduction strategies over prohibition, citing Sweden as a successful example. The text advocates for regulating nicotine products instead of banning them and highlights the negative consequences of prohibition, such as loss of tax revenue and public health risks. It calls for evidence-based policies in the EU to promote safer alternatives to smoking and urges the European Parliament and Commission to prioritize harm reduction over ideology. (Published on October 06, 2025bybrusselstimes.com)</description></item><item><title>How Australia Got the Story of Tobacco Harm Reduction So Wrong</title><link>https://www.aliveadvocacymovement.com/post/how-australia-got-the-story-of-tobacco-harm-reduction-so-wrong</link><description>In Australia, tobacco harm reduction faces obstacles due to government policies and academic biases. Despite evidence supporting harm reduction, Australia bans regulated vaping products, leading to increased smoking rates. Academic advisors focus on fear campaigns, ignoring harm reduction benefits for smokers. The government's vaping ban causes chaos, pushing smokers towards black-market products. Australia's hypocritical stance penalizes adults trying to quit smoking, while profiting from tobacco sales. The closed-loop public health network disregards international research supporting harm reduction. To save lives, Australia needs transparency, evidence-based policies, and a shift towards harm reduction. Failure to change risks continued harm and moral victories at the expense of people's lives. (Published on October 06, 2025byaliveadvocacymovement.com)</description></item><item><title>Alarming number of people now vape, says WHO</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1kwxjzeez3o</link><description>WHO warns over 100 million people, 15 million children, vape, leading to a surge in nicotine addiction. Children are nine times more likely to vape than adults. E-cigarettes, perceived as harm reduction, actually hook kids on nicotine early, reversing progress. The tobacco industry aggressively targets youth with new nicotine products, hindering global tobacco control efforts. Despite estimates, data gaps in 109 countries exist. 86 million adult e-cigarette users are mainly in high-income countries, while 15 million teens vape. Many nations are implementing regulations, yet 62 countries lack policies and 74 have no minimum vaping age. WHO urges swift action to curb child vaping. (Published on October 06, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>What Is Nicotine—And How Does Big Tobacco Weaponize It?</title><link>https://exposetobacco.org/news/what-is-nicotine/</link><description>Nicotine, a stimulant found in tobacco and e-cigarettes, has immediate effects on heart rate and blood pressure, with long-term risks including heart issues. Research hints at a potential role in cancer progression. Even handling tobacco can cause symptoms. In children, nicotine ingestion can lead to confusion, vomiting, and, in high doses, be fatal. Adolescent exposure can harm brain development, affecting attention and mood regulation. Nicotine's popularity among young people has led to a rise in ingestion incidents. Protecting children and adolescents from nicotine exposure is crucial due to its harmful effects on health and brain development. (Published on October 06, 2025byexposetobacco.org)</description></item><item><title>OP-ED: Big Tobacco calls it harm reduction, Caribbean youth calls it profiting from addiction</title><link>https://dominicanewsonline.com/news/homepage/homepage-carousel/op-ed-big-tobacco-calls-it-harm-reduction-caribbean-youth-calls-it-profiting-from-addiction/</link><description>The Caribbean is being targeted by groups like the World Vapers’ Alliance and Smoke Free Sweden as part of an industry push to weaken tobacco control ahead of the WHO FCTC COP11 meeting. Recent articles and campaigns in Barbados and Trinidad promote industry narratives disguised as “harm reduction,” claiming e-cigarettes and similar products are safer alternatives. In reality, these products are addictive, heavily marketed to youth, and linked to higher risks of cigarette smoking, with unclear long-term health effects. (Published on October 06, 2025bydominicanewsonline.com)</description></item></channel></rss>