<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 18:17:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australia: Black Market Vape Sales Outpace Legal Products 1,700 to 1</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/8417/australia-black-market-vape-sales-outpace-legal-products/</link><description>The Australian government's mandate to sell vapes only in pharmacies has led to the destruction of the legal vape market, creating a booming illicit market. Government documents show that only 1 out of 1,700 vape transactions are legal. Illicit sales dominate, with over 10 million vapes sold illegally monthly. Legal vapes are limited to certain flavors in plain packaging. Australia's vape bans and restrictive laws have failed since 2008. Efforts to eliminate the black market have backfired, leading to increased organized crime involvement and violence. To solve the issue, vapes should be legalized and regulated as consumer products, but the government needs to acknowledge the failure of its current pharmacy-only approach. (Published on June 20, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>UAE legalizes tobacco-free nicotine pouches to help smokers quit cigarettes</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/world/middle-east/uae-legalizes-tobacco-free-nicotine-pouches-to-help-smokers-quit-cigarettes/articleshow/121910813.cms</link><description>The UAE approved the sale of tobacco-free nicotine pouches from July 29, offering smokers an alternative to cigarettes. Nicotine pouches contain nicotine but no tobacco, reducing lung damage risks. Dr. Mallick explained the pouches release nicotine without smoke, aiding in quitting smoking due to reduced cravings. However, they can be addictive, and long-term health effects are still being studied. Nicotine pouches work through oral mucosal absorption, unlike patches. While they may help some smokers quit, their effectiveness compared to traditional nicotine replacement therapies remains uncertain. The UAE regulates nicotine product sales, with warnings and age restrictions required. Despite health risks, the UAE is dedicated to supporting tobacco cessation through counseling and psychological aid. (Published on June 20, 2025byindiatimes.com)</description></item></channel></rss>