<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 01:17:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Interview: David Zaruk, The Risk Monger</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/interview-david-zaruk-the-risk-monger/</link><description>David Zaruk, known as the Risk Monger, investigates Michael Bloomberg's influence on tobacco control policy, where Bloomberg funds organizations that align with his views. Bloomberg's philanthropic approach involves setting up groups under various names to control messaging and influence policy. Zaruk critiques the EU's precautionary principle, which hinders safer nicotine products regulation. The principle shifts the burden of proof onto proving absolute safety, causing challenges in various scientific fields. Regulatory actions based on this principle have led to removing products from the market, negatively impacting farmers. The tension between different definitions of precaution complicates decision-making in policy and science. (Published on February 05, 2026byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Parents warned as sales of £8.50 caffeine pouches, in vape-style flavours, soar in the UK - and children can buy them</title><link>https://www.dailymail.co.uk/lifestyle/article-15524405/Parents-warned-sales-8-50-caffeine-pouches-vape-style-flavours-soar-UK-children-buy-them.html</link><description>UK sales of caffeine pouches, doubling in a year, are attributed to Brits seeking quick energy boosts over coffee. Marketed on social media and available in various flavors, the pouches pose risks with high caffeine levels targeted at teens. Health professionals warn of potential addiction, health issues, and cognitive problems, especially among the youth. Easily accessible online and in stores, the pouches are less harmful than nicotine alternatives but raise concerns due to the direct bloodstream impact. Moderation of caffeine intake is essential for health benefits, unlike the larger doses the pouches may deliver. Vigilance is urged over the increasing popularity and potential dangers of these trendy alternatives. (Published on February 05, 2026bydailymail.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>While Europe dithers, US moves closer to seeing nicotine pouches as less harmful</title><link>https://snusforumet.se/en/while-europe-dithers-us-moves-closer-to-seeing-nicotine-pouches-as-less-harmful/</link><description>U.S. regulators are close to approving Zyn nicotine pouches as safer than cigarettes. Experts at a FDA hearing support the claim that Zyn reduces risks, with minimal youth use. In contrast, Europe is restricting similar products due to youth concerns. The Association of Swedish Snus Manufacturers praises U.S. openness to harm reduction. FDA granted pre-market approval to Zyn last year, recognizing it as less harmful. The public can comment until March 4, 2026, before the FDA's final decision. Previously, FDA approved Swedish Match USA's tobacco snus as a reduced-risk product in 2019. (Published on February 05, 2026bysnusforumet.se)</description></item><item><title>Opinion: Health Canada ghosts the science on smoking cessation aids</title><link>https://financialpost.com/opinion/opinion-health-canada-ghosts-science-smoking-cessation-aids</link><description>Bureaucracy’s primary instinct is self-preservation. Across government, non-profit, and private sectors, bureaucratic institutions work to present themselves as essential, celebrate their own past achievements, and deflect blame for failures onto those lower in the hierarchy. A recent example is a 15-page publication by federal health officials titled Delivering Results: Advancing Canada’s Tobacco Strategy, which reads largely as self-promotion. The document highlights standard talking points such as respect for Indigenous peoples and the distribution of large amounts of public funding to other agencies. It also congratulates itself for declining smoking rates and portrays Ottawa’s health bureaucracy as heroically improving Canadians’ lives. (Published on February 05, 2026byfinancialpost.com)</description></item><item><title>The WHO Is Attempting to Sabotage Life-Saving Products</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/who-sabotaging-harm-reduction-nicotine/</link><description>The World Health Organization (WHO) presents itself as a global health guardian but promotes policies that may increase disease and death, as reflected in the European Code Against Cancer. Despite scientific consensus on the reduced harm of non-combustible nicotine products compared to smoking, WHO's insistence on taxing them similarly to cigarettes discourages switching and perpetuates smoking, especially among marginalized populations. This approach prioritizes institutional interests over public health benefits, contradicting harm reduction principles, and risking lives. Embracing harm reduction instead of impeding it is crucial for genuine health progress. (Published on February 05, 2026bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>