<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 18:44:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why are more young Irish people using nicotine pouches?</title><link>https://www.rte.ie/brainstorm/2026/0216/1558091-nicotine-pouches-snus-ecigarettes-tobacco-vapes-health-risks/</link><description>Health surveys indicate a rise in nicotine pouch and vape usage, especially among non-cigarette smokers. While vaping has been a concern for youth, the surge in nicotine pouch use has been less acknowledged. These pouches, introduced in 2019, are popular among young adults and adolescents, sometimes replacing e-cigarettes. Concerns about health impacts and limited research exist. Marketing strategies have boosted sales, leading to calls for tighter regulations. The Irish government seeks to ban sales to under 18s. Addressing the dual use of pouches and vapes is crucial, prompting the need for innovative responses from health authorities. Further research is necessary to inform prevention strategies, especially targeting young users. (Published on February 17, 2026byrte.ie)</description></item><item><title>How $40-a-Pack Cigarettes Pushed Australians to the Black Market</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2026/02/15/world/asia/how-40-a-pack-cigarettes-pushed-australians-to-the-black-market.html</link><description>Australia has the most expensive cigarettes in the world, a pack of midmarket cigarettes costing on average about 55 Australian dollars, or almost $40, nearly double what it will set you back in New York City. A series of steep tax hikes — eight in 10 years — were put in place to reduce the rate of smoking, which has steadily declined. But the high prices have also given rise to a thriving black market now estimated to be a multibillion-dollar industry that accounts for as much as half of all tobacco sales in the country. (Published on February 17, 2026bynytimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Harm reduction, not prohibition, right approach to nicotine</title><link>https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2026/feb/16/harm-reduction-prohibition-right-approach-nicotine/</link><description>As a retired police lieutenant, I’ve seen firsthand how well-intentioned policies often backfire when they ignore basic truths about human behavior. Whether it’s drugs or other public health concerns, the lesson has been the same: When we try to control people’s choices through punishment or sweeping mandates, we often create new harms while failing to address the old ones. That’s why the Food and Drug Administration’s recently announced pilot program to streamline review of nicotine pouch products is a welcome step forward. It reflects a balanced, science-based understanding of the role nicotine pouches play in smoking cessation and public safety. (Published on February 17, 2026bywashingtontimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Mexico bans vape sales and warns tourists to leave e-cigarettes at home</title><link>https://traveltomorrow.com/mexico-bans-vape-sales-and-warns-tourists-to-leave-e-cigarettes-at-home/</link><description>Mexico has implemented a comprehensive ban on vaping products since January 16, 2022. The law prohibits the import, distribution, and sale of e-cigarettes, extending to tourists entering the country. This law closes the gap in previous restrictions and strengthens enforcement. Penalties for violating the ban range from fines to imprisonment, with additional restrictions on public smoking. The initiative aligns with global efforts to curb smoking and vaping, as seen in other countries like France, the Maldives, Belgium, and Spain. Travelers, including cruise passengers, are advised to leave vaping devices at home to avoid legal consequences. (Published on February 17, 2026bytraveltomorrow.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches: an aid in smoking cessation, or a new public health hazard?</title><link>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s11739-026-04278-1</link><description>Tobacco harm reduction strategies are designed to lessen the enormous health burden caused by smoking by offering lower-risk alternatives to people who are unable or unwilling to stop using combustible cigarettes. In recent years, nicotine pouches have emerged as a new category of tobacco-free oral products. Although they are conceptually derived from Swedish snus, they differ by completely eliminating the tobacco leaf, which distinguishes them from traditional smokeless tobacco products. (Published on February 17, 2026byspringer.com)</description></item></channel></rss>