<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 06:21:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Authorities seize 80,000 flavored vapes from warehouse near Schiphol</title><link>https://nltimes.nl/2025/07/13/authorities-seize-80000-flavored-vapes-warehouse-near-schiphol</link><description>Around 80,000 illegal sweet-flavored electronic cigarettes were seized at a Schiphol warehouse by the NVWA. The vapes had flavors like Lemonade, strawberry, and gummy bear, banned according to Dutch law. Another 70,000 refill bottles were found in a past case. The importer, previously caught, faced severe consequences. Only tobacco-flavored vapes are permitted in the Netherlands to prevent nicotine addiction in young people. The NVWA enforces this measure to support the National Prevention Agreement's goal for a smoke-free generation by 2040. In total, 265,000 illegal vapes have been confiscated since the ban was implemented last year. (Published on July 13, 2025bynltimes.nl)</description></item><item><title>New products, same addiction</title><link>https://www.thestar.com.my/news/focus/2025/07/13/new-products-same-addiction#goog_rewarded</link><description>HEATED Tobacco Products and nicotine pouches are marketed towards women and children as alternatives to traditional cigarettes. The Tobacco Control Research Group at the University of Bath warns about the addictive nature and appealing packaging of these products, with concerns over online marketing and youth exposure. Studies suggest that these products may act as a gateway to cigarette smoking. Regulatory measures are needed to reduce promotion and protect public health. The widespread availability of various addictive products poses risks, especially for non-smokers. Users may increase tobacco and nicotine consumption, leading to potential health consequences. Vigilance is vital to address the growing use of these products. (Published on July 13, 2025bythestar.com.my)</description></item></channel></rss>