<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 01:00:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Targeting three United States priority populations of people who smoke with educational nicotine messages using curiosity-eliciting strategies</title><link>https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-025-04050-z</link><description>The text describes the SNAC study focusing on developing nicotine educational messages for specific populations. Participants were recruited through Prodege's panel and assigned to different study conditions. Study 1 involved exposure to various messages with different presentation styles. Study 2 compared brief nicotine messages with and without curiosity-eliciting components. Measures included assessing nicotine false beliefs and perceived message effectiveness. Analysis involved ANOVAs for Study 1 and planned comparisons for Study 2. The aim was to understand the impact of different message types on participants' knowledge and perceptions related to nicotine. (Published on July 04, 2025bynature.com)</description></item><item><title>Strengthen borders, ban vape nationwide, urges Sultan Abdullah</title><link>https://www.thevibes.com/articles/news/110053/strengthen-borders-ban-vape-nationwide-urges-sultan-abdullah</link><description>Sultan of Pahang urges Malaysia to strengthen borders against drug trafficking and supports a nationwide ban on vaping. Emphasizing the need for stricter controls at entry points, he highlighted the key role of borders in curbing drug smuggling. Concerned about rising drug abuse among youths, he called for enhanced enforcement measures. The Sultan also backed Pahang's decision to ban vaping, citing health risks, with plans to formalize the ban through legislation. Noting drug smuggling through fishing vessels in east coast states, he emphasized the urgency of addressing the issue. The Pahang State Government had previously announced the vape ban based on a fatwa. (Published on July 04, 2025bythevibes.com)</description></item><item><title>Global health officials urge countries to raise ‘sin taxes’ on tobacco, alcohol, and sugary drinks</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/health/2025/07/04/global-health-officials-urge-countries-to-raise-sin-taxes-on-tobacco-alcohol-and-sugary-dr</link><description>Global health officials recommend implementing higher taxes on tobacco, alcohol, and sugary drinks to combat chronic diseases and bolster healthcare funding. The World Health Organization suggests a 50% price increase over the next decade, aiming to prevent millions of premature deaths and generate trillions in public revenue. These products contribute significantly to heart disease, cancer, and diabetes. The WHO emphasizes the effectiveness of health taxes in reducing consumption and funding healthcare, education, and social programs. Despite some challenges like cross-border shopping post-tax hikes, such measures have shown positive impacts in reducing smoking rates and children's sugar intake. These taxes could help lower-income countries offset reduced aid and strained healthcare systems worldwide. (Published on July 04, 2025byeuronews.com)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco-free future: Should Luxembourg expand smoking bans like France?</title><link>https://today.rtl.lu/news/luxembourg/a/2318440.html</link><description>France has expanded its smoking ban to include beaches, parks, and areas near schools to deter youth smoking. This has sparked a debate on whether Luxembourg should implement similar measures. The stricter ban in France aims to protect young people by prohibiting smoking in public spaces frequented by children. While Luxembourg has no beaches, discussions on extending smoking restrictions to places where children gather are ongoing. The push for anti-tobacco measures in Luxembourg continues, with initiatives focusing on raising awareness, supporting smokers to quit, and creating smoke-free zones. The goal is to reduce Luxembourg's smoking rate to below 5% by 2040. (Published on July 04, 2025byrtl.lu)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouch use rising among teens, public health expert sounds alarm</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-07-nicotine-pouch-teens-health-expert.html</link><description>Teens are increasingly drawn to discreet oral nicotine pouches, fueling public health concerns due to their high nicotine content and addictiveness. Sales have surged, with marketing through influencers and social media playing a significant role. Despite some health benefits over cigarettes, pouches pose risks like addiction and cognitive impairment. Challenges in regulation exist, especially online, where misinformation spreads. Parents and educators are urged to engage teens in open conversations. Addressing the mental health crisis among youth and providing accurate education are crucial. Efforts are needed to bridge the gap between public health messaging and teen behavior, emphasizing the importance of relatable and nuanced information dissemination. (Published on July 04, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Vapes Ban and the Legal Alternatives in the UK</title><link>https://london-post.co.uk/vapes-ban-and-the-legal-alternatives-in-the-uk/</link><description>Vaping has surged in the UK, with increasing regulations targeting illegal products. The country supports vaping as a smoking cessation aid but cracks down on non-compliant items. Legal alternatives include TPD-compliant disposables, pod systems, and open system kits. Options like the Hayati Pro Max and IVG 2400 pods provide satisfying, eco-friendly choices. Consumers and retailers are urged to prioritize legality and safety. Future trends may involve stricter regulations, emphasizing the importance of compliant products. Choosing legal vapes supports sustainability and long-term satisfaction while avoiding risks associated with illegal products. (Published on July 04, 2025bylondon-post.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Greece passes law to jail people for selling alcohol or tobacco to children</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/health/2025/07/04/greece-passes-law-to-jail-people-for-selling-alcohol-or-tobacco-to-children</link><description>The Greek parliament has passed a new law to protect minors from smoking and alcohol. The legislation includes strict age verification for sales, bans smoking in certain public areas, and limits advertising. Violations—such as selling tobacco or alcohol to minors or employing them in bars—can result in fines up to €10,000 and up to three years in prison. The law is broad in scope and introduces strong penalties to ensure compliance. (Published on July 04, 2025byeuronews.com)</description></item></channel></rss>