<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 06:19:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Smoke-free brand rethinks nicotine, harm reduction</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/06/25/entertainment-lifestyle/life-times/smoke-free-brand-rethinks-nicotine-harm-reduction/2138428</link><description>Nicotine isn't the main smoking risk; tobacco combustion is. Philip Morris' Iqos warms, not burns, tobacco to reduce harmful chemicals. In the Philippines, awareness is growing through education and the "Forever Curious" campaign. Launched in 2014, Iqos focuses on engaging consumers and promoting better alternatives to traditional smoking. With close to 150,000 users in the Philippines, understanding the product is crucial. The brand's global event in Milan highlights its innovative approach and commitment to transformation. (Published on June 24, 2025bymanilatimes.net)</description></item><item><title>Why is Harm Reduction such a Hard Sell?</title><link>https://www.thefirebreak.org/p/why-is-harm-reduction-such-a-hard?r=5t47ie&amp;triedRedirect=true</link><description>Harm reduction is a pragmatic health approach aiming to minimize harm from risky behaviors. Challenges arise due to opposition from health campaigners, criticizing harm reduction for potentially promoting risky behavior. Examples include distributing free needles for drug users. Misinformation campaigns against vaping and reduced harm alternatives to smoking are a concern, hindering public health progress. Concerns about harm reduction strategies influencing youth behavior exist but may be overstated. The WHO spreads misinformation on nicotine products, while activist NGOs align with anti-vaping rhetoric. Genuine public health leaders include passionate vaping advocates advocating for reduced harm alternatives. Issues arise from misinformation, corporate interests, and lack of support for harm reduction efforts. (Published on June 25, 2025bythefirebreak.org)</description></item><item><title>Mónica García Wants to Ban What Works. Literally.</title><link>https://consideratepouchers.org/monica-garcia-wants-to-ban-what-works-literally/</link><description>Spain's Ministry of Health's proposed regulation to ban flavored nicotine pouches and cap nicotine levels may unintentionally drive former smokers back to cigarettes. A survey shows most users switched to pouches to quit smoking and strongly oppose the ban. Many fear a return to cigarettes if the regulation is enforced. Instead of blanket bans, age verification and vendor penalties could better prevent youth access. The current approach risks fueling a black market and increasing smoking rates. Effective public health policies should focus on education and responsible sales rather than punishing consumers. Protecting the vulnerable means regulating with evidence, not fear. (Published on June 25, 2025byconsideratepouchers.org)</description></item><item><title>Global elites think you’re too stupid for soda and beer</title><link>https://www.theblaze.com/columns/opinion/global-elites-think-youre-too-stupid-for-soda-and-beer</link><description>Global public health elites propose a 50% tax increase on tobacco, alcohol, sugary drinks, and processed foods to raise $3.7 trillion, seen as governmental theft. These "health taxes" aim to expand state control rather than combat illness. The burden falls heavily on working-class individuals. The strategy is viewed as economic punishment, not health promotion. Taxing small pleasures disproportionately affects the most vulnerable. Prohibitive pricing can lead to black markets and overlooks personal freedoms and informed choices. Public health should focus on harm reduction and education, not coercive taxation. Respecting individual autonomy and promoting innovation yields better outcomes than punitive measures. (Published on June 25, 2025bytheblaze.com)</description></item></channel></rss>