<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 18:18:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Missouri health professionals worry about vaping access in young people</title><link>https://missouriindependent.com/2025/10/13/missouri-health-professionals-worry-about-vaping-access-in-young-people/</link><description>Originally meant to help smokers quit, e-cigarettes and vaping products have become a new form of addiction, especially among young people. While designed for adult smokers, many young users now vape without ever having smoked. In Missouri, surveys show record-high use — 21% of college students vape and 28% use nicotine overall. Experts warn that easy access to vape shops and high-nicotine products has made this generation more addicted than ever before. (Published on October 14, 2025bymissouriindependent.com)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco: Why won’t Brussels follow Sweden’s ‘smoke free’ policy?</title><link>https://brusselssignal.eu/2025/10/tobacco-why-wont-brussels-follow-swedens-smoke-free-policy/</link><description>Sweden's successful anti-smoking approach, with low smoking-related cancer deaths and snus use, contrasts Brussels' upcoming Tobacco Plan. The EU targets a total ban on tobacco products, including harm-reduction items like e-cigarettes and snus, going against industry trends. Philip Morris bought Swedish Match for €14.62 billion, reflecting a shift towards safer nicotine products. Despite Sweden's model reducing cancer rates, Brussels rejects this, proposing updated tobacco taxes and regulations. The EU aims to modernize tobacco taxation laws, considering new products like e-cigarettes in the revised directive effective from 2028. Sweden's opposition to these changes highlights the ongoing tension between national approaches and EU policies. (Published on October 14, 2025bybrusselssignal.eu)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #160 | WHO's FCTC COP11 Challenges &amp; Lack of Consumer Impact Explained | GFN News</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-160/</link><description>Get an in-depth look at the upcoming 11th session of the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (FCTC) Conference, scheduled for November 2025 in Geneva. This video explores the registration process for attending the conference, the challenges faced by harm reduction groups, and the importance of consumer representation in tobacco and nicotine policy discussions. (Published on October 14, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>