<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:18:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Less smokers worldwide, but e-cigarettes fuel new addictions - WHO</title><link>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/national/575245/less-smokers-worldwide-but-e-cigarettes-fuel-new-addictions-who</link><description>Global smoking rates are decreasing, but e-cigarettes are causing a rise in nicotine addiction, says the World Health Organization. While smokers have reduced from 1.38 billion (2000) to 1.2 billion (2024), one in five adults still use tobacco. Over 100 million people are vaping globally, with 15 million being children aged 13 to 15. Children are nine times more likely to vape than adults in countries with data available. WHO urges countries to intensify tobacco control efforts to combat the increasing e-cigarette use targeting youth. Women show a larger decline in tobacco use compared to men, emphasizing the need for stronger tobacco control policies. (Published on October 07, 2025byrnz.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>WHO global report on trends in prevalence of tobacco use 2000–2024 and projections 2025–2030</title><link>https://www.who.int/publications/i/item/9789240116276</link><description>The new WHO report presents updated estimates of tobacco use among people aged 15 and older from 2000 to 2024, with projections to 2030. It tracks global, regional, and country-level trends and serves as a key measure of progress in implementing the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control. The estimates, updated every two years, represent WHO’s official data for Sustainable Development Goal indicator 3.a.1 and also support monitoring of the Global Action Plan for the Prevention and Control of Noncommunicable Diseases 2013–2020 and the WHO Fourteenth General Programme of Work. (Published on October 07, 2025bywho.int)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #14 | WHY TOBACCO HARM REDUCTION MATTERS?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-14/</link><description>Toxicologist Autumn Bernal explains why harm reduction keeps her in the fight: reducing disease burden for adult smokers through better product design, rigorous toxicology, and clear science communication. She highlights the core engineering challenge for ENDS: optimizing heating to minimize emissions while effectively delivering nicotine - without the harmful constituents found in cigarettes. (Published on October 07, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Exclusive: EU Commission Leak Points to Full Crackdown on Nicotine Pouches</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/exclusive-eu-commission-leak-points-to-full-crackdown-on-nicotine-pouches/</link><description>The European Commission is considering proposals on nicotine pouches that could impact tobacco harm reduction in the EU. Plans include a potential ban on pouches, flavor restrictions, and legal liabilities for manufacturers. These measures risk reversing progress in reducing smoking rates and harming public health. Nicotine pouches have played a crucial role in harm reduction, as seen in Sweden. The proposed regulations might push individuals back to smoking, fueling illicit trade. The Commission's rush in regulation lacks solid evidence and is poised for adoption at COP-11 in November, urging member states to prioritize evidence-based policymaking for public health. (Published on October 07, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Malaysia’s Impending Vape Ban Poses Multiple Threats</title><link>https://filtermag.org/malaysia-vape-ban/</link><description>Malaysia plans to ban vaping products by mid-2026, citing concerns about unregulated sales. Dr. Wan Puteh highlights risks of illegal markets and potential harm to smokers. Banning vapes may increase illicit trade and harm public health, as seen in neighboring countries. Advocates suggest legalizing and regulating to ensure consumer safety. The ban could impact over 30,000 workers and a billion-dollar industry. They urge the government to consider a balanced regulatory approach that supports harm reduction. The move aims to protect public health and prevent the proliferation of unsafe products in the market. (Published on October 07, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Scientists to Track Health Effects of Vaping After Quitting</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/scientists-track-health-effects-vaping-after-quitting-2025a1000qzf?st=fpf_login&amp;scode=msp&amp;socialSite=google&amp;form=login&amp;icd=login_success_gg_match_fpf</link><description>The University of Birmingham is conducting the EVALUATE study, led by Dr. Aaron Scott, to investigate the long-term health effects of vaping as a smoking cessation aid. The £1.46 million project funded by the MRC will monitor 200 participants over a year, comparing their lung health to non-smokers. Researchers will analyze gene expression, toxic substance accumulation, and lung cell changes to understand vaping's impact on health. This study is crucial given the WHO's concerns about rising global vaping rates. The aim is to provide evidence for individuals to make informed decisions about quitting smoking with e-cigarettes. (Published on October 07, 2025bymedscape.com)</description></item></channel></rss>