<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:29:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Fragmented nicotine laws leave Europe's youth vulnerable despite policy aims</title><link>https://www.brusselstimes.com/1898870/fragmented-nicotine-laws-leave-europes-youth-vulnerable-despite-policy-aims</link><description>The European Commission's Safe Hearts Plan aims to protect youth from nicotine harms. Harmonizing regulations on online sales can prevent minors' access. Different EU countries have varying rules on nicotine products, leading to price and availability differences. A ban on cross-border online sales of nicotine products is crucial to uphold tobacco policy goals, prevent illicit trade, secure tax revenues, and support compliant domestic businesses. Norway's upcoming ban sets an example for the EU to follow in the revised Tobacco Products Directive. By implementing this ban, the EU can better protect public health and prevent underage sales effectively. (Published on January 05, 2026bybrusselstimes.com)</description></item><item><title>How Much Nicotine Is in a Cigarette?</title><link>https://vaping360.com/learn/nicotine-in-a-cigarette/</link><description>Many vapers ask how much nicotine is in a cigarette to estimate the nicotine strength they need in e-liquids and replicate the sensation of smoking. However, nicotine intake from cigarettes doesn’t directly translate to vaping because the delivery methods are very different. Even similar nicotine amounts can feel stronger in cigarettes than in vapes. Since most vapers are former smokers and many smokers seek less harmful alternatives, understanding nicotine in all its forms is important. This topic may become even more relevant if the FDA successfully reduces nicotine levels in cigarettes below addictive thresholds. (Published on January 05, 2026byvaping360.com)</description></item></channel></rss>