<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 06:18:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Belgian drug chief warns illegal vapes could hook children on opioids</title><link>https://www.euronews.com/my-europe/2025/12/05/belgian-drug-chief-warns-illegal-vapes-could-hook-children-on-opioids</link><description>Belgium’s drug commissioner warned that most illegal refillable vape capsules seized in the country contain synthetic opioids. This means children using illegal vapes may unknowingly become addicted from a very young age. She explained that over 80% of seized capsules include these hidden drugs, which have no distinct smell or color. Experts worry that this could harm brain development and worsen addiction risks among teens. (Published on December 05, 2025byeuronews.com)</description></item><item><title>Canada’s nicotine pouch paradox</title><link>https://www.canadianaffairs.news/2025/12/04/canadas-nicotine-pouch-paradox/</link><description>Health Canada's regulations have pushed nicotine pouches behind pharmacy counters, leading consumers like Kaden Desmarais to find alternative sources. Desmarais criticizes the confusing rules and prefers online sellers or Indigenous reserves for purchases. Health Canada's restrictions aim to control nicotine pouch sales and access, with only Zonnic approved for sale. The agency's move to require sales through pharmacies has sparked debate on the accessibility of cessation products. Imperial Tobacco Canada stresses the importance of pouches as a therapy, yet some public health groups raise concerns. The rules have prompted Canadians to seek pouches through various channels, raising concerns about organized crime involvement. (Published on December 05, 2025bycanadianaffairs.news)</description></item></channel></rss>