<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 06:19:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Importing Panic | U.S. Influence Drives Global War On Nicotine | RegWatch</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/importing-panic-u-s-influence-drives-global-war-on-nicotine-regwatch/</link><description>With all the trade tensions and tariff spats, there’s one U.S. export Europe could do without: the moral panic over vaping. Inexplicably, American-inspired fearmongering over safer nicotine products is reshaping EU policy and threatening tobacco harm reduction the world over. In this episode of RegWatch, filmed on location at the 2025 Global Forum on Nicotine in Warsaw, we sit down with Bill Wirtz, senior policy analyst at the Consumer Choice Center and creator of The Fun Police podcast. Wirtz explains how Bloomberg-funded NGOs, WHO-orchestrated pressure campaigns, and “Save the Children” messaging are fueling a crackdown on vaping in Europe and jeopardizing the rights of millions who’ve already quit smoking. (Published on June 30, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>New data reveals the UK’s vaping boom</title><link>https://www.swlondoner.co.uk/news/30062025-new-data-reveals-the-uks-vaping-boom</link><description>Vaping's popularity in the UK has soared, with users reaching 5.6 million in 2024. Concerns are rising due to health risks, e-waste, and fires, exemplified by Donna King's experience. The Tobacco and Vapes Bill aims to create a smoke-free generation by 2027, as vaping and smoking cost billions. While vaping is seen as less harmful than smoking, the long-term impacts are still under scrutiny. Public awareness and safety measures, like charging precautions, are crucial. Ongoing research will shed light on vaping's full effects on health, safety, and the environment. (Published on June 30, 2025byswlondoner.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco harm reduction must have 'a balanced and informative approach'</title><link>https://www.sowetanlive.co.za/s-mag/wellness/2025-06-30-tobacco-harm-reduction-must-have-a-balanced-and-informative-approach/</link><description>The tobacco industry and experts say perceptions on harm reduction need to be challenged and barriers tackled. Global Forum on Nicotine Ltd director Paddy Costall said the forum chose this year’s theme, “Challenging perceptions – effective communication for tobacco harm reduction”, because they believed tobacco harm reduction has the potential to play a major role in combating non-communicable diseases. (Published on June 30, 2025bysowetanlive.co.za)</description></item><item><title>Sweden Shows What Happens When the Market is Allowed to Meet Demand</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/sweden-shows-what-happens-when-the-market-is-allowed-to-meet-demand/</link><description>Nicotine pouches, often misunderstood by the media, play a crucial role in harm reduction in Sweden, particularly helping women quit smoking. Despite higher usage by men, tobacco-free pouches have significantly decreased smoking rates among Swedish women. The product's cleanliness and convenience have made it more appealing to women. In contrast, Jacinda Ardern's opposition to non-tobacco nicotine pouches in New Zealand contradicts her liberal image. The success of such harm reduction methods, as seen in Sweden, highlights the importance of offering products that cater to individuals' needs for a smoke-free future. (Published on June 30, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>Why Have Health Leaders Rejected Vaping?</title><link>https://www.thefirebreak.org/p/why-have-health-leaders-rejected</link><description>Health leaders have ignored tobacco harm reduction strategies, stigmatizing vaping and other alternatives. The anti-tobacco lobby's bias against reduced harm strategies is tied to industry perceptions. Activists push for proscriptive regulations, endorsing a 100% safe approach that impedes harm reduction efforts. Addiction fears and absolutist policies hinder rational harm reduction approaches, despite public understanding of relative risks. The text warns against moralistic regulation reminiscent of Prohibition, highlighting the need for balanced policies to prevent negative health outcomes. Stigmatizing vaping and misconceptions around addiction impede harm reduction efforts, urging for a more nuanced and evidence-based approach to public health policies. (Published on June 30, 2025bythefirebreak.org)</description></item><item><title>Butler open to pharmacy vaping reforms</title><link>https://ajp.com.au/news/butler-open-to-pharmacy-vaping-reforms/</link><description>Efforts to limit access to nicotine vaping products are showing positive outcomes, according to Australia’s Minister for Health, Mark Butler. Speaking in a Pharmacy Guild of Australia webinar, he said that reforms aimed at reducing youth vaping are working, highlighting the success of new sales restrictions. (Published on June 30, 2025byajp.com.au)</description></item></channel></rss>