<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 17:16:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>HSE warns people to stop using three vapes which are mislabelled as having no nicotine</title><link>https://www.irishexaminer.com/news/arid-41630893.html</link><description>The HSE warns against three vapes falsely labeled as "no nicotine," containing high nicotine levels. Products include Crystal Bling 6000+, McKesse MK Bar 7000, and JNR Crystal Pro Max 5000+. Consumers feeling unwell should contact a GP and notify HSE via[email protected]. The vapes exceed permitted nicotine concentrations and liquid volumes, risking consumer safety. HSE emphasizes retailers' responsibility in verifying product compliance to prevent harm and legal breaches. Distributors and importers are advised to ensure proper safety, quality, and labeling of e-cigarettes. Retailers importing from non-EU countries must comply with regulations. Vigilance in product checks is crucial to protect public health, HSE emphasizes. (Published on May 13, 2025byirishexaminer.com)</description></item><item><title>EXCLUSIVE: EU vape and pouch tax by Summer, Commissioner tells Parliament.</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/exclusive-eu-vape-and-pouch-tax-by-summer-commissioner-tells-parliament/</link><description>European Commissioner Hoekstra plans to propose higher taxes on safer nicotine products, aiming for implementation by summer. The proposal includes raising prices on nicotine pouches by over 50% and adding €3 to a 10ml bottle of vaping liquid. Hoekstra is reaching out to national officials for support, targeting countries resistant to the tax hike. While some Commission members question the economic timing, Hoekstra remains adamant against nicotine products, claiming vapes are as harmful as cigarettes. Climate change policy also falls under Hoekstra's jurisdiction, sparking criticism for prioritizing vaping taxes over environmental issues. Resistance from Member States and skepticism within the Commission may hinder the tax plan approval. (Published on May 13, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Cameroon’s opportunity to advance public health through Tobacco harm reduction – Cameroon News Agency</title><link>https://cameroonnewsagency.com/cameroons-opportunity-to-advance-public-health-through-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>Cameroon faces a public health crisis with 8.9% smoking prevalence leading to significant deaths and healthcare costs. Tobacco Harm Reduction (THR), including e-cigarettes and heated tobacco products, offers a safer alternative. However, lack of awareness and regulation hinders progress. Local research and educational campaigns are needed to promote THR and develop effective policies. Integrating THR into national tobacco control is crucial for long-term health outcomes. With the new Tobacco Control Law in place, Cameroon has the opportunity to lead in tobacco control through evidence-based, innovative strategies. Action is imperative to reduce smoking-related harm and improve public health. (Published on May 13, 2025bycameroonnewsagency.com)</description></item></channel></rss>