<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 12:35:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Unintended Consequences of Banning Flavored Vapes</title><link>https://www.cato.org/blog/unintended-consequences-banning-flavored-vapes</link><description>When governments ban products, they don’t eliminate demand—they redirect it. That basic economic fact is especially important in nicotine policy, where people don’t simply stop using nicotine because a preferred product disappears. Flavored vaping bans are a case in point. Many states and some cities have enacted bans on in-store and/​or online sales of flavored vapes. However, adults also enjoy these flavored products, and many trying to quit smoking find it easier with flavored options. (Published on January 29, 2026bycato.org)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #80 | POLICY CAPTURE | Bloomberg, the WHO, and Suppression of THR</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-80-policy-capture-bloomberg-the-who-and-suppression-of-thr/</link><description>Public health often warns about tobacco industry interference—but what happens when tobacco control itself is captured by benevolent donors and non-profit organizations? In this GFN interview, economist Roger Bate explains why the World Health Organization’s Framework Convention on Tobacco Control is uniquely vulnerable to outside influence, how Bloomberg-funded NGOs shape policy agendas upstream, and why this system consistently excludes tobacco harm reduction despite strong evidence. (Published on January 29, 2026bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Anti-Vax Levels Of Science Denial</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2026-01-28_anti-vax-levels-of-science-denial.html</link><description>The European Commission is engaging in “anti-vaccine-style science denial” according to leading health experts after it rejected overwhelming evidence supporting reduced harm products such as vapes, nicotine pouches and heated tobacco products. Smoke Free Sweden says that the evidence showing the vaping reduces smoking and smoking-related disease is “overwhelming”. (Published on January 29, 2026byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>EU Commission suspects ‘coordinated’ interference in tobacco tax feedback</title><link>https://www.politico.eu/article/eu-commission-suspects-coordinated-interference-in-tobacco-tax-feedback/</link><description>The tobacco industry is facing significant lobbying efforts in Europe, with concerns raised about fraudulent responses in public consultations. The European Commission aims to raise tobacco taxes, but some countries find the proposed increase too steep. Additionally, there are plans to regulate e-cigarettes and other nicotine products more strictly in 2026. Boublil highlighted the intense lobbying surrounding tobacco legislation at an event in Brussels, emphasizing the need for vigilance in the face of suspicious activities. (Published on January 29, 2026bypolitico.eu)</description></item><item><title>Follow Japan’s strategy to reduce harm on smokers, govt urged</title><link>https://www.freemalaysiatoday.com/category/nation/2026/01/29/follow-japans-strategy-to-reduce-harm-on-smokers-govt-urged</link><description>The managing director of a tobacco company in Malaysia has urged the government to follow Japan’s example by reducing the harmful effects of smoking instead of banning e-cigarettes and vapes outright. Naeem Shahab Khan of Philip Morris Malaysia and Singapore noted that Japan legally ensures access to heated tobacco products and other alternatives for smokers. He called this a “pragmatic harm-reduction approach.” In Malaysia, e-cigarettes and vapes will be banned by the end of this year, starting with pod system vapes. Khan also highlighted that Japan uses a separate tax structure for heated tobacco products. (Published on January 30, 2026byfreemalaysiatoday.com)</description></item></channel></rss>