<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 12:26:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Over 600 Telegram groups in Singapore selling, advertising vapes removed by HSA</title><link>https://www.straitstimes.com/singapore/over-600-telegram-groups-in-singapore-selling-advertising-vapes-removed-by-hsa</link><description>Health Sciences Authority (HSA) removed over 600 Telegram groups selling vapes to Singaporeans. More than 6,800 online vape listings were removed, with double the listings taken down in 2023. HSA actively enforces the ban on vape sales and advertisements online and offline. The agency intensified operations, collaborated with authorities, and increased monitoring efforts. The Health Promotion Board's I Quit program helped over 116,800 participants quit smoking and vaping. Vaping poses health risks, including heart and lung diseases, especially among young users. Vapes contain harmful substances like etomidate, which can lead to severe health issues when inhaled. (Published on July 16, 2025bystraitstimes.com)</description></item><item><title>My Dad Quit Cigarettes in 1984. To Doctors, He Was Always a “Smoker.”</title><link>https://filtermag.org/father-quit-cigarettes-stigma-smoker/</link><description>The text recounts the author's father's life, battling smoking-related stigma and health issues. Despite tobacco control efforts leading to reduced smoking rates in Canada, stigma towards smokers remains. The father's health issues were wrongly attributed to his smoking history until a tumor was found and treated successfully. The author advocates for ending the stigma, promoting harm reduction, and providing dignity to current and former smokers. The focus is on healthcare equity, empathy, and honest harm reduction discussions. The narrative stresses the importance of not stigmatizing nicotine users and calls for tobacco control leaders to support harm reduction initiatives without repeating past mistakes. (Published on July 16, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item></channel></rss>