<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 18:17:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New App Boosts Smoking Cessation in Low-Income Adults</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/new-app-boosts-smoking-cessation-low-income-adults-2025a1000m36</link><description>A study found that low-income adults who used the Smart-T smartphone app for smoking cessation were 1.81 times more likely to quit smoking at 26 weeks than those using the QuitGuide app. Smart-T users accessed quit tips more, used the call counselor feature, and requested nicotine replacement therapy frequently. They also felt more aware of their behaviors and found the intervention useful. The researchers suggest that Smart-T could be a cost-effective tool to help reduce smoking-related health disparities. The study, led by Emily T. Hébert, was published in JAMA Network Open. Limitations included the need for a specific quit date and Smart-T's availability only on Android devices. (Published on August 22, 2025bymedscape.com)</description></item><item><title>Young people and nicotine: Five things to know</title><link>https://med.stanford.edu/news/insights/2025/08/young-people-and-nicotine--five-things-to-know.html</link><description>The text warns about the dangers of high nicotine levels in alternative tobacco products for young brains. Trends show most youth start with e-cigarettes, not to quit smoking. Nicotine pouch use is rising, with Zyn being popular among youth. Nicotine impacts young brains differently, making them more vulnerable to addiction. The tobacco industry targets young people, knowing they're more likely to get addicted. Teaching kids to see through industry manipulation is vital. Education, not shaming, is key in tobacco prevention. Parents must be aware and listen to kids using nicotine for stress. Understanding the risks and effects of nicotine is crucial for youth health and prevention efforts. (Published on August 22, 2025bystanford.edu)</description></item><item><title>EU Plan to Heavily Tax Safer Substitutes for Cigarettes Draws Fire</title><link>https://filtermag.org/eu-tax-safer-nicotine-products/</link><description>The European Union is considering imposing high taxes on safer nicotine products, sparking opposition from tobacco harm reduction advocates and scientists. The plan includes minimum taxes of 40-55% on vaping e-liquids, nicotine pouches, and heated tobacco products, which critics argue will hinder efforts to reduce smoking rates. Some EU member states, including Portugal, have raised objections to the tax proposal, stating that taxing less harmful smoking alternatives may discourage smokers from switching. Unanimous agreement from all 27 EU nations is needed for the proposal to become law. Critics emphasize the importance of promoting safer nicotine products to achieve the EU's smoke-free goal and warn against the potential negative impact of the tax plan. (Published on August 22, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>One year in, Canada’s nicotine pouch ban still defies public health logic</title><link>https://www.hilltimes.com/story/2025/08/21/one-year-in-canadas-nicotine-pouch-ban-still-defies-public-health-logic/470824/</link><description>It has now been a year since then–Health Minister Mark Holland introduced a federal order that limited the sale of nicotine pouches—used as smoking-cessation aids—to behind-the-counter access in pharmacies. The measure removed them from convenience stores nationwide in Canada and restricted permitted flavours in pharmacies to only mint and menthol. (Published on August 22, 2025byhilltimes.com)</description></item></channel></rss>