<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:59:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Research Reveals Teen Use</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-11-17_research-reveals-teen-use.html</link><description>Young people in Scotland are experimenting with nicotine pouches and experiencing negative effects such as nausea and fainting, according to new research from ScotCen published in Addiction. Nicotine pouches, introduced to the UK in 2019, are unregulated and can still be legally sold to under-18s, though upcoming legislation may change this. ScotCen conducted the UK’s first qualitative study on how 14–16-year-olds perceive and use these products, involving focus groups with 77 pupils and interviews with 13 school staff across four Scottish schools. (Published on November 19, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Personal Attacks on THR Proponents Ramp Up Amid COP11</title><link>https://filtermag.org/tobacco-harm-reduction-attacks-cop11/</link><description>Tobacco harm reductionists face attacks while advocating for safer nicotine products. Personal attacks and intimidation are common tactics by opponents trying to discredit them. Recent attacks targeted Dr. Farsalinos and THR advocate Bates ahead of COP11. Glantz's anti-vape stance led him to attack Bates for advocating THR. Siegel criticized Glantz for misrepresenting the scientific evidence. The misleading claims aim to distort the benefits of safer nicotine products compared to smoking. The attacks within the tobacco control movement hinder progress in reducing tobacco-related diseases. Calling out such smearing is crucial to combat unjustified criticisms and uphold the integrity of the debate on tobacco harm reduction. (Published on November 19, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Health minister plans major vape flavour ban to protect young people</title><link>https://www.belganewsagency.eu/belgium-plans-major-vape-flavour-ban-to-protect-young-people</link><description>Belgian Health minister Vandenbroucke aims to ban flavored vapes, except tobacco, to curb youth nicotine addiction. The move follows advice from the Superior Health Council and aims to reduce the appeal of vaping to children. The Netherlands already allows only tobacco flavor, resulting in decreased vaping and smoking rates. While some argue for certain flavors to help smokers quit, prioritizing youth protection is key. Vaping among students has surged, prompting the need for stricter enforcement. Despite opposition from industry groups, Vandenbroucke pushes for the ban's prompt implementation, building on previous measures to reduce youth smoking and vaping. (Published on November 19, 2025bybelganewsagency.eu)</description></item><item><title>New Zealand receives 'Dirty Ashtray' award for poor progress in tobacco control</title><link>https://www.rnz.co.nz/news/national/579370/new-zealand-receives-dirty-ashtray-award-for-poor-progress-in-tobacco-control</link><description>New Zealand received the 'Dirty Ashtray' award at a tobacco control meeting, criticized for reversing reforms, high vaping rates among youth, and industry interference. Once a leader, NZ now faces international shame and fell to 53rd on the Tobacco Industry Interference Index. Experts warn that repealing tobacco control measures could hinder smoking prevalence reduction. (Published on November 19, 2025byrnz.co.nz)</description></item><item><title>GOOD COP 2.0 | Day 3 of 5 | RegWatch (Live)</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/good-cop-2-0-day-3-of-5-regwatch-live/</link><description>DAY #3 | Live from Geneva, Switzerland – RegWatch special coverage of the Taxpayers Protection Alliance’s Good COP 2.0, the tobacco harm reduction counter-conference to the World Health Organization’s COP 11. (Published on November 19, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>WHO chief urges clampdown on nicotine products aimed at kids</title><link>https://www.canadianaffairs.news/2025/11/19/who-chief-urges-clampdown-on-nicotine-products-aimed-at-kids/</link><description>The WHO warns about new tobacco products targeting youth, leading to addiction. Despite progress, eight million still die from tobacco-related diseases yearly. Marketing e-cigarettes and nicotine products to teens is concerning, with usage nine times higher in adolescents than adults in 63 countries. Companies prioritize profits over public health. The WHO urges countries to regulate these products like traditional tobacco, with bans in some nations and strict controls recommended globally. (Published on November 19, 2025bycanadianaffairs.news)</description></item></channel></rss>