<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 01:22:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to Dispose of the Environmental Argument Against Vapes?</title><link>https://filtermag.org/environmental-argument-vapes/</link><description>One of the major controversies surrounding vaping nicotine is its environmental impact, especially regarding disposable, single-use vapes. Arguments for banning vapes on this basis are often seen as a pretext. We live in a world full of disposable products, from paperboard coffee cups and plastic fast-food containers to balloons. Yet, bans citing environmental harm, such as those in Belgium and the United Kingdom, tend to target vapes specifically. This approach restricts smokers’ access to effective alternatives to deadly cigarettes, which themselves cause significant environmental damage but remain widely available. (Published on February 11, 2026byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Estonian Groups Want Disposable Vapes Banned by 2027</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2026/02/10/estonian-groups-want-disposable-vapes-banned-by-2027/</link><description>A coalition, led by the Estonian Green Movement, comprising 50 organizations and school leaders, urged Estonian government ministries to implement a nationwide ban on disposable e-cigarettes by 2027. The appeal, submitted to multiple ministries, warns about the health risks to youth, nicotine addiction, and environmental waste linked to single-use vapes. It emphasizes public support, with over 2,000 signatures collected for a similar initiative by 2025, and advocates for banning disposable devices while controlling reusable options more strictly. (Published on February 11, 2026bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Vaping ban up in smoke</title><link>https://www.financialexpress.com/life/lifestyle/vapingnbspbannbspup-in-smoke/4134774/</link><description>Despite the ban, vaping products are widely available in local markets and online. Vapes are seen as a 'cool' choice by many, particularly the younger generation. The ban, ineffective and circumvented, led to a flourishing black market. The ban lacks robust enforcement and is criticized by experts, who suggest a UK-like model. Vapes are considered a safer alternative to traditional tobacco, but health risks remain. The ban's impact on reducing tobacco consumption in India has been questioned. Enforcement of the ban is inconsistent, leading to widespread availability of vapes, particularly through the black market. (Published on February 10, 2026byfinancialexpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Exclusive: India sticks to e-cigarette ban in snub for Philip Morris</title><link>https://www.reuters.com/business/healthcare-pharmaceuticals/india-sticks-e-cigarette-ban-snub-philip-morris-2026-02-11/</link><description>India has decided not to ease its ban on e-cigarettes, including heat-not-burn tobacco products, rejecting a long-standing lobbying effort by Philip Morris International to allow such devices. The country implemented this ban in 2019. India is the seventh-largest cigarette market in the world, selling over 100 billion cigarettes annually, and tobacco use causes more than a million deaths each year. Philip Morris, the world's most valuable tobacco company, had aimed to make India a significant market for its IQOS heated tobacco device, which the company claims is less harmful than traditional smoking. (Published on February 11, 2026byreuters.com)</description></item></channel></rss>