<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 18:17:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>WHO Defends Malaysia’s Anti-Tobacco Award Despite Nicotine Vape Manufacturing Licence</title><link>https://codeblue.galencentre.org/2025/06/who-defends-malaysias-anti-tobacco-award-despite-nicotine-vape-manufacturing-licence/</link><description>WHO defended awarding Health Minister Dzulkefly Ahmad despite Malaysia granting a nicotine vape license, citing achievements up to a certain point. The award acknowledged efforts in tobacco control legislation and commitments. The WHO highlighted the importance of protecting public health policies from tobacco industry interference and monitoring new tobacco products like vapes. Malaysia achieved best-practice levels in four out of six WHO MPOWER tobacco control measures. These measures include monitoring tobacco use, protecting from smoke, warning about dangers, and raising taxes on tobacco. Malaysia reached moderate levels in offering help to quit and enforcing bans on tobacco advertising. Other countries are close to full MPOWER package implementation. (Published on June 27, 2025bygalencentre.org)</description></item><item><title>Illinois to start taxing nicotine pouches Tuesday under amended bill</title><link>https://www.cspdailynews.com/tobacco/illinois-start-taxing-nicotine-pouches-tuesday-under-amended-bill</link><description>Illinois residents will face higher taxes on tobacco products starting July 1. The changes include nicotine pouches being taxed at 45% of the wholesale price and vapor products shifting from 36% to 45%. Moist snuff will also see an increase in taxes. The state budget bill includes these tax adjustments, aiming to generate more revenue. The American Lung Association supports the tax hike to reduce tobacco use. Indiana is also increasing its cigarette tax by $2 per pack, putting financial pressure on consumers. Retailers are concerned about tax compliance and hope for better enforcement rather than further tax increases. (Published on June 27, 2025bycspdailynews.com)</description></item><item><title>Use of Tobacco and Nicotine Products On The Rise In The Czech Republic</title><link>https://brnodaily.com/2025/06/27/news/use-of-tobacco-and-nicotine-products-on-the-rise-in-the-czech-republic/</link><description>The Czech Republic has seen a rise in tobacco and nicotine product use, with 27% using them daily in 2024, up from 23% in 2023. Conventional cigarette smoking is decreasing while e-cigarettes and alternative products are gaining popularity, especially among young people aged 15-24. Smoking-related deaths account for about a fifth of all fatalities, with 16,000-18,000 deaths annually and significant economic costs. Availability and marketing strategies contribute to high usage rates, with smoking shortening life expectancy by 10-14 years. The government is discussing addiction policy coordination in response to the changing trends. (Published on June 27, 2025bybrnodaily.com)</description></item><item><title>Changing patterns of nicotine product use and nicotine dependence among United States high-school students: The National Youth Tobacco Survey, 2014–2023</title><link>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/add.70120</link><description>Concerns have been raised that e-cigarettes have created a new generation of people addicted to nicotine. This study aimed to measure changes in the proportion of US high-school students reporting symptoms of nicotine dependence over the past decade, in the context of changing patterns of nicotine product use. (Published on June 27, 2025bywiley.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #1 | Tackling the biggest barriers to tobacco harm reduction</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-1/</link><description>Tobacco harm reduction experts from across the globe recently gathered for this year's #GFN25 conference in Warsaw, so in this special series we've put together some of THR's leading experts to highlight the communication barriers that we need to overcome to share the real science behind safer nicotine products. Joining us on the conference floor today are Clive Bates, Fiona Patten and Mark Tyndall to highlight their biggest concerns facing the THR movement, and their hopes for the future. (Published on June 27, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>The EU Case for Innovative Nicotine Products [Briefing Paper]</title><link>https://www.weareinnovation.global/the-eu-case-for-innovative-nicotine-products-briefing-paper/</link><description>The European Union is off track to meet its 2040 smoke-free goal by over 60 years, with only a 1% decline in smoking rates since 2020. Three EU countries – Sweden, Czechia, and Greece – have shown remarkable success in reducing smoking through innovative nicotine products. Sweden leads as a smoke-free pioneer with a 5.4% smoking rate. Czechia achieved the fastest smoking decline in Europe, while Greece reversed high smoking rates. These success stories highlight the effectiveness of differentiated regulation and harm reduction policies. Embracing alternative nicotine products alongside traditional measures can accelerate progress towards smoke-free societies. (Published on June 27, 2025byweareinnovation.global)</description></item></channel></rss>