<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 18:17:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Are Disposable Vapes Hiding a Sweet Trap?</title><link>https://www.medscape.com/viewarticle/are-disposable-vapes-hiding-sweet-trap-2025a1000g7m?form=fpf</link><description>A study by Yale and Duke Universities found neotame, a very sweet artificial sweetener, in many popular disposable e-cigarettes in the US and EU. While safe in food, its inhalation effects are unknown. Neotame is used to enhance flavors like cherry lemonade in e-cigarettes, appealing to young users but unregulated. Neotame was detected in 78% of e-cigarette samples, especially in disposable and nicotine-free products. Concerns include potential addiction and lack of data on its health effects when inhaled. Researchers suggest stricter regulation of sweeteners in e-cigarettes due to their appeal. Comprehensive studies on the toxic effects and addictive potential of neotame are urged for future regulatory decisions. (Published on June 18, 2025bymedscape.com)</description></item><item><title>Global Panel Urges Rapid Reform of WHO and FCTC to Embrace Science, Transparency, and Consumer Voices</title><link>https://www.newswire.ca/news-releases/global-panel-urges-rapid-reform-of-who-and-fctc-to-embrace-science-transparency-and-consumer-voices-896267708.html</link><description>The Taxpayers Protection Alliance leads a call for reform within the WHO's tobacco control arm, citing politicized policymaking and lack of consumer input. Amid criticism of the WHO's pandemic response, advocates push for evidence-based changes at the Framework Convention on Tobacco Control. Consumer voices stress the need for transparency and science-based policymaking for effective reform. The panel urges the WHO and FCTC to prioritize pragmatic strategies over prohibitionist approaches to combat smoking rates and health inequities. The key message is to prioritize scientific integrity and consumer inclusion for meaningful reform in international health institutions. (Published on June 18, 2025bynewswire.ca)</description></item><item><title>Quit or Die Is Failing, Yet Hong Kong Plans Sweeping Vape Ban</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/06/18/quit-or-die-is-failing-yet-hong-kong-plans-sweeping-vape-ban/</link><description>Hong Kong is considering stricter tobacco regulations, but a study shows peer pressure and stress as key drivers of nicotine use, highlighting the importance of harm reduction strategies. Current policies risk pushing users to more harmful options by banning safer alternatives. Global experiences, like the Maldives' vape ban leading to increased illicit tobacco activity, caution against overly restrictive measures. Advocates urge for inclusive policies at COP11, calling for innovation and consumer voices in tobacco control. Differentiated tax regimes, as seen in Japan and New Zealand, can reduce smoking rates. Hong Kong's tobacco policy should prioritize harm reduction to achieve effective public health outcomes instead of solely focusing on control and punishment. (Published on June 19, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item></channel></rss>