<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:19:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The opposition to tackling cigarette smoking</title><link>https://skipscorner.substack.com/p/the-opposition-to-tackling-cigarette</link><description>David T. Sweanor discusses the historical opposition faced in efforts to combat cigarette smoking and improve public health. He highlights ongoing barriers hindering the adoption of safer alternatives to smoking, such as misinformation campaigns and regulatory obstacles. Sweanor emphasizes missed opportunities for a potential market transformation away from lethal cigarettes, despite the clear health benefits. He also criticizes the resistance from various anti-tobacco groups towards embracing advances in tobacco harm reduction. Sweanor concludes by underscoring the immense potential for positive change in public health outcomes if these barriers were overcome. (Published on October 08, 2025bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Malaysian Health Ministry Proposes Vape Liquid Tax Increase</title><link>https://tobaccoreporter.com/2025/10/08/malaysian-health-ministry-proposes-vape-liquid-tax-increase/</link><description>The Malaysian Ministry of Health plans to raise excise duty on vape liquids tenfold, proposing MYR4 per mL, ahead of a complete ban on e-cigarettes. The Ministry seeks to align vape taxes with those on cigarettes to discourage vaping. Industry representatives push back, suggesting a maximum tax of 80 sen per milliliter to prevent increased illicit trade. The government aims to implement the ban gradually through education and enforcement, pending Cabinet approval. (Published on October 08, 2025bytobaccoreporter.com)</description></item><item><title>Times Of War | Trump’s FDA Escalates the Fight Against Vaping | RegWatch (Live)</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/times-of-war-trumps-fda-escalates-the-fight-against-vaping-regwatch-live/</link><description>Donald Trump campaigned on saving vaping. But under his watch, the FDA has seized more products than any previous administration and doubled down on the very anti-nicotine crusade he once promised to stop. In our ten years covering the U.S. Vaping industry never has the future looked so bleak. Joining us today to unpack the mounting contradictions of Trump’s FDA is Lindsey Stroud, THR policy expert and founder of Tobacco Harm Reduction 101 at thr101.org. (Published on October 08, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #159 | VAPING ER “SURGE”: What The Data Really Shows?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-159/</link><description>GFN News speaks with Filter’s Will Godfrey about reports of dramatic increases in vaping-related emergency department visits across several US states, especially among youth, and examines what those numbers truly represent beyond the headlines. The conversation highlights how headlines like “teen ER visits surge” can obscure distinctions between acute nicotine toxicity and far more subjective “e‑cigarette dependence” admissions that have driven much of the increase in reported cases. The discussion also explores how clinicians may mark visits as vape-related simply because a patient discloses vaping, even when it’s incidental to the medical issue, potentially inflating counts without reflecting actual vaping-caused harm. (Published on October 08, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>