<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:21:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Total ban on vape not the right solution, says Teresa Kok</title><link>https://www.thevibes.com/articles/news/114160/total-ban-on-vape-not-the-right-solution-says-teresa-kok</link><description>MP Teresa Kok questioned why there is no tax on vape products in Budget 2026 when taxes on tobacco have increased. She highlighted the growing vape industry in Malaysia and the need for regulations rather than a total ban to avoid black market activity. Kok suggested only allowing 'closed system' vapes for sale, controlled by registered companies. She emphasized that a total ban would not deter vape use but could lead to smuggling. Strict controls were recommended before considering a ban to safeguard industry operators and tax revenue. - In summary, MP Teresa Kok raised concerns about the absence of a vape tax in Budget 2026, advocating for regulation over prohibition to manage the industry effectively. (Published on October 17, 2025bythevibes.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #15 | HOW CANADA IS FIGHTING FOR TOBACCO HARM REDUCTION?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-15/</link><description>Maria Papaioannoy-Duic, founder and spokesperson of Rights for Vapers, speaks with Joanna Junak about the challenges Canadian vapers face in being heard in public health debates. Maria shares how her organization has worked tirelessly to educate consumers on safer nicotine alternatives, fight misinformation, and give a voice to those seeking harm reduction over prohibition. (Published on October 17, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Experts urge UK to ban cigarette filters to protect health and environment</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/16/experts-urge-uk-to-ban-cigarette-filters-to-protect-health-and-environment</link><description>Experts argue that cigarette filters are ineffective, worsen plastic pollution, and should be banned by the UK government to protect public health and the environment. Filters don't reduce harm, mislead users, and contribute to plastic waste. Despite a declining number of smokers, misconceptions about filter benefits persist. An upcoming bill aims to raise the legal smoking age, offering a chance to further regulate tobacco products. Emphasizing the need for public education to debunk filter myths, the call is to ban filters due to their harmful effects and deceptive tactics by the tobacco industry. (Published on October 17, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>WHO’s harm reduction stance ‘contradicts science,’ says former agency director</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/whos-harm-reduction-stance-contradicts-science-says-former-agency-director/</link><description>A former WHO director criticizes the agency for neglecting science on tobacco harm reduction, impacting efforts to reduce smoking in the Asia-Pacific. Despite evidence supporting safer alternatives, WHO maintains an anti-harm reduction stance, citing vape and heated tobacco products as harmful. With the Asia-Pacific region having a high smoking rate, advocates push for evidence-driven coalitions to promote harm reduction. Ahead of COP11, calls intensify for WHO to prioritize harm reduction to aid smokers switching from cigarettes. The focus is on the need for factual communication, proportional regulation, and acknowledging vaping's role in reducing harm and helping smokers quit. (Published on October 17, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item></channel></rss>