<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:21:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nicotine pouch rise is driven by young men, study finds</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c075j3ezvrgo</link><description>A study found that young men are driving the increasing popularity of nicotine pouches in the UK, with 7.5% of 16 to 24-year-old men using them compared to 1.9% of young women. Many users also smoke or vape, and some are using pouches to quit smoking. Nicotine pouch sales have significantly risen in recent years, particularly among young men due to aggressive marketing tactics. The pouches contain synthetic nicotine and are marketed in colorful tins. Researchers call for more research on their effectiveness in smoking cessation. The study surveyed 127,000 people from 2020 to 2025. Recommendations include banning sales to under 18s. (Published on December 17, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>Punishing safer nicotine alternatives backfires on public health</title><link>https://reason.org/commentary/punishing-safer-nicotine-alternatives-backfires-on-public-health/</link><description>Washington state implements harm reduction policies for opioids and HIV prevention but contradicts this approach by imposing a 95% wholesale tax on nicotine pouches, potentially hindering smokers from switching to a safer alternative to cigarettes. The tax may lead to unintended consequences such as continued cigarette use. Unlike tobacco, nicotine itself is not carcinogenic, thus taxing all tobacco products equally, including safer options, may not be beneficial for public health. Evidence from Sweden demonstrates the effectiveness of low-risk nicotine alternatives in reducing smoking rates. Taxing nicotine products indiscriminately could impede smoking cessation efforts, particularly for low-income individuals. Washington's taxation strategy contrasts with successful harm reduction practices, raising concerns about its effectiveness. (Published on December 17, 2025byreason.org)</description></item><item><title>Cheered On by the WHO, Vietnam Tightens Total Vape Ban</title><link>https://filtermag.org/vietnam-world-health-organization-vape-ban/</link><description>Vietnam recently amended its Investment Law to extend the ban on nicotine vapes and heated tobacco products. The move strengthens the existing prohibition, including personal use. The World Health Organization supported Vietnam's decision, claiming benefits such as reduced youth usage. However, experts question the evidence behind the ban's alleged positive effects. With a high smoking rate, Vietnam’s tobacco regulations face challenges. Critics highlight conflicts of interest, as the state-owned tobacco company dominates the market. The ban may fuel an illicit market, impacting neighboring countries like Laos and Thailand. Overall, the policy is seen as prioritizing economic interests over harm reduction and evidence-based policymaking. (Published on December 17, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Expert calls for science-led approach to tobacco harm reduction in adult smokers</title><link>https://guardian.ng/news/expert-calls-for-science-led-approach-to-tobacco-harm-reduction-in-adult-smokers/</link><description>BAT West &amp; Central Africa emphasizes Tobacco Harm Reduction (THR) as vital for adult smokers, offering science-based alternatives like heated tobacco systems and nicotine pouches. Although quitting entirely is ideal, many struggle to do so, making harm reduction a practical approach to reduce exposure to harmful toxins from smoking. Dr. Puddicombe stresses the importance of responsibly implementing THR to protect minors and advocates for evidence-based policies and collaboration across stakeholders. THR can lower smoking-related diseases and costs, benefitting public health. Puddicombe calls for regulatory environments aligned with global health practices to support harm reduction and minimize risks associated with tobacco use. (Published on December 17, 2025byguardian.ng)</description></item><item><title>E-cigarettes banned under law; no NCB cases of drug-laced vapes: Nityanand Rai in Rajya Sabha</title><link>https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/news/india/e-cigarettes-banned-under-law-no-ncb-cases-of-drug-laced-vapes-govt/articleshow/126037432.cms?from=mdr</link><description>The Indian government clarified in Parliament that electronic cigarettes remain banned, with no cases related to vape devices with narcotic substances investigated by the Narcotics Control Bureau. Measures to prevent smuggling include vigilance at airports and ports, passenger profiling, and use of detection dogs. The government also highlighted initiatives to combat substance abuse, such as a national narcotics helpline and de-addiction services. E-cigarettes gained attention after a complaint was filed against a Trinamool Congress member for allegedly smoking one in the Lok Sabha. No amendments to the NDPS Act are currently proposed. (Published on December 17, 2025byindiatimes.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches: Do they work, are they safe and are they better than vaping?</title><link>https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/health-and-families/nicotine-pouches-side-effects-zyn-how-b2885993.html</link><description>Nicotine pouches, a new smoking cessation trend, are tobacco-free sachets with nicotine. Marketed as a healthier alternative to smoking and vaping, they aren't as regulated as nicotine replacement therapies (NRTs) and can be easily bought. Despite being less addictive than cigarettes, some pouches contain high nicotine levels and other chemicals. They have side effects like nausea and headaches, impacting oral health in the long term. Not regulated as medicines, they lack strict testing for safety and efficacy. The UK plans to regulate pouch sales to over-18s only, banning ads. While popular, their potential risks warrant caution, suggesting regulated NRTs may be a safer choice for quitting smoking. (Published on December 17, 2025byindependent.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Less Ideology, More Science | GFN Wishes for 2026 with Fiona Patten and Fernando Bueno</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/less-ideology-more-science-gfn-wishes-for-2026-with-fiona-patten-and-fernando-bueno/</link><description>As 2026 approaches, policymakers face a critical choice: continue repeating failed tobacco strategies or finally listen to science, consumers, and real-world evidence. In this discussion, Fiona Patten and Fernando Bueno examine why Australia’s tobacco tax revenue has collapsed, how harm reduction products like vaping are being wrongly regulated, and what countries like Sweden and New Zealand have done differently to dramatically cut smoking rates. The message is clear: less ideology, more evidence and a smarter, risk-based approach to public health. (Published on December 17, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>