<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 18:18:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Colourful vapes in fun flavours might be a bigger problem in Pakistan than you think</title><link>https://images.dawn.com/news/1193598</link><description>The text discusses the rise of vaping in Pakistan, with shops selling e-cigarettes targeted at adults but attracting young users with fruity flavors. Despite claims of being safer than cigarettes, health experts remain cautious due to unknown long-term effects. The tobacco industry is pivoting towards nicotine products, leading to concerns about addiction and access to underage users. Weak regulations in Pakistan allow for a thriving market, while global concerns about the environmental impact of disposable vapes are also highlighted. The narrative questions the true safety of vaping, emphasizing the need for stricter regulations and public awareness campaigns to prevent a potential health crisis. (Published on June 16, 2025bydawn.com)</description></item><item><title>WHO’s prohibitionist stance costs lives, harm reduction experts say</title><link>https://manilastandard.net/business/biz-plus/314602616/whos-prohibitionist-stance-costs-lives-harm-reduction-experts-say.html</link><description>Public health advocates criticize the WHO's restrictive stance on innovative nicotine products, stating it endangers smokers who could benefit from safer alternatives. They argue the WHO ignores evidence of harm reduction tools like vapes and heated tobacco being effective in helping smokers quit. Advocates stress the importance of embracing innovation and harm reduction strategies, pointing to successful examples in countries like the UK and Sweden. They highlight the contrast between the WHO's mission to reduce tobacco-related deaths and its resistance to proven cessation methods. The group calls for a shift towards harm reduction policies and consumer engagement to combat the global smoking epidemic effectively. (Published on June 16, 2025bymanilastandard.net)</description></item><item><title>Vapes could have age-test so they don't work unless you are over 18</title><link>https://www.express.co.uk/news/politics/2068380/vapes-could-have-age-test-they</link><description>Proposals to tighten regulations on vaping and smoking include age verification technology for e-cigarettes and banning tobacco sales to those born after Jan 1, 2009. The Tobacco and Vapes Bill faces criticism for potential risks to shop staff and black-market sales. Amendments suggested in the House of Lords aim to introduce a tobacco ban by 2040, set a minimum price for vapes, and enhance health warnings. Lord Lansley's idea involves fitting vapes with age-gating technology. The legislation, backed by both Conservatives and Labour, will be reviewed by the Lords and then the Commons. However, concerns exist that restricting vape flavors might hinder smoking cessation efforts. Vaping is recognized by the NHS as a safer alternative to smoking. (Published on June 16, 2025byexpress.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Netherlands, Spain, France, Germany, Ireland Thailand India, Singapore, Australia and New Zealand Unleash Strict Vaping Bans and Powerful Travel Crackdowns to Protect Public Health</title><link>https://www.travelandtourworld.com/news/article/netherlands-spain-france-germany-ireland-thailand-india-singapore-australia-and-new-zealand-unleash-strict-vaping-bans-and-powerful-travel-crackdowns-to-protect-public-health/</link><description>Several countries, including Netherlands, Spain, France, Germany, Ireland, Thailand, India, Singapore, Australia, and New Zealand, have implemented strict vaping bans to protect public health. These bans include prohibiting flavored e-liquids, restricting vaping in public spaces like beaches, and imposing legal penalties. Tourists are advised to research and comply with vaping laws when traveling to avoid fines and legal issues. Countries in Europe, the Middle East, Asia, and Oceania are enforcing stringent restrictions on vaping, with some, like Thailand, India, and Singapore, having comprehensive bans. It is crucial for travelers to be aware of these laws to prevent potential trouble while abroad. (Published on June 16, 2025bytravelandtourworld.com)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco companies want tighter age rules on sale of nicotine pouches</title><link>https://www.irishtimes.com/business/2025/06/16/tobacco-companies-called-on-government-to-age-restrict-nicotine-pouches/</link><description>Vaping and tobacco companies in Ireland called for regulations on nicotine pouches and e-vapour products due to concerns about appealing to young people. Japan Tobacco International and British American Tobacco urged for age restrictions and health warnings on packaging. The companies emphasized the need to prevent underage sales and reduce nicotine concentrations. Meanwhile, a vaping retailer criticized proposed strict regulations on vaping products and suggested alternative measures, including better enforcement and a deposit scheme for disposable devices. The companies' concerns were acknowledged by the Minister for Health. (Published on June 16, 2025byirishtimes.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #66 | NEW PROHIBITION | Jacob Grier on Tobacco Control’s Dangerous Turn</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-66/</link><description>Jacob Grier offers a sneak peek of his #GFN25 keynote on how the media misrepresents tobacco harm reduction. He unpacks the narratives driving public fear, the criminalization of safer nicotine products, and the explosive growth of the illicit vape trade. As millions turn to vaping despite the headlines, is tobacco control losing its grip on the narrative? (Published on June 16, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>