<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 12:25:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Quit or Die Is Failing, Yet Hong Kong Plans Sweeping Vape Ban</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/06/18/quit-or-die-is-failing-yet-hong-kong-plans-sweeping-vape-ban/</link><description>Hong Kong is considering stricter tobacco regulations, but a study shows peer pressure and stress as key drivers of nicotine use, highlighting the importance of harm reduction strategies. Current policies risk pushing users to more harmful options by banning safer alternatives. Global experiences, like the Maldives' vape ban leading to increased illicit tobacco activity, caution against overly restrictive measures. Advocates urge for inclusive policies at COP11, calling for innovation and consumer voices in tobacco control. Differentiated tax regimes, as seen in Japan and New Zealand, can reduce smoking rates. Hong Kong's tobacco policy should prioritize harm reduction to achieve effective public health outcomes instead of solely focusing on control and punishment. (Published on June 19, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>Australia: Black Market Vape Sales Outpace Legal Products 1,700 to 1</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/8417/australia-black-market-vape-sales-outpace-legal-products/</link><description>The Australian government's mandate to sell vapes only in pharmacies has led to the destruction of the legal vape market, creating a booming illicit market. Government documents show that only 1 out of 1,700 vape transactions are legal. Illicit sales dominate, with over 10 million vapes sold illegally monthly. Legal vapes are limited to certain flavors in plain packaging. Australia's vape bans and restrictive laws have failed since 2008. Efforts to eliminate the black market have backfired, leading to increased organized crime involvement and violence. To solve the issue, vapes should be legalized and regulated as consumer products, but the government needs to acknowledge the failure of its current pharmacy-only approach. (Published on June 20, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item></channel></rss>