<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:21:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Health Canada admits half of those who quit smoking used nicotine replacements</title><link>https://www.junonews.com/p/health-canada-admits-half-of-those</link><description>Even though new data show that alternatives such as vaping are helping thousands of Canadians stop smoking, the Liberal government continues to maintain strict restrictions on these nicotine replacement products. In 2024, around 300,000 Canadians successfully quit smoking, yet federal rules on many nicotine replacement options remain unchanged. (Published on January 23, 2026byjunonews.com)</description></item><item><title>Calls to bring back hard-hitting anti-smoking campaigns to warn off gen Z</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/calls-to-bring-back-hard-hitting-anti-smoking-campaigns/106076928</link><description>Although smoking rates have dropped to their lowest levels since their peak in the 1960s and 1970s, worries are rising about a possible resurgence as tobacco companies target younger people via social media. Data from the Australian National University show that 24,000 Australians die each year from smoking-related causes, and experts caution that the country now faces the danger of complacency. (Published on January 23, 2026byabc.net.au)</description></item><item><title>What to know about FDA’s review of new Zyn advertising proposal</title><link>https://apnews.com/article/zyn-fda-nicotine-pouches-tobacco-smoking-cancer-d2bb42e4aa70b09c90d969845327bce9</link><description>The FDA is considering approving Phillip Morris International's Zyn pouches as a less harmful alternative for smokers. FDA experts are inclined towards approval, though concerns about underage use and marketing efficacy remain. Zyn, with various flavors, is a fast-growing product in the tobacco industry. Phillip Morris aims to promote Zyn as reducing risks associated with smoking-related diseases. Evidence supports Zyn's potential health benefits, but long-term studies and impact on smokers switching are lacking. FDA must also assess potential harm to young people despite low teenage use of nicotine pouches. (Published on January 23, 2026byapnews.com)</description></item></channel></rss>