<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:56:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The war on nicotine will fail but could kill millions</title><link>https://clivebates.com/the-war-on-nicotine-will-fail-but-could-kill-millions/</link><description>The global goal to cut non-communicable diseases by one-third by 2030 is being undermined by tobacco control ideologues. Activists, officials, and academics are shifting the focus from smoking-related harm to nicotine itself, aiming for nicotine eradication and framing the tobacco and nicotine industries as inherently harmful. This ideological approach to nicotine, the author argues, hinders progress in reducing smoking-related diseases. (Published on September 25, 2025byclivebates.com)</description></item><item><title>Regulating vaping with a deadlier habit in mind</title><link>https://news.harvard.edu/gazette/story/2025/09/regulating-vaping-with-a-deadlier-habit-in-mind/</link><description>Approximately 34 million U.S. adults smoke cigarettes, resulting in over 480,000 deaths yearly. Vaping, seen as a safer alternative for smokers, has gained popularity among teens. Balancing the need to deter youth vaping while allowing adult smokers access was discussed in a panel by the Petrie-Flom Center and others. Policies have shown some success in reducing youth e-cigarette use, but may increase adult tobacco use. E-cigarettes, with fewer harmful chemicals, are considered effective for smoking cessation. Regulatory gaps and weak FDA authority have hindered efforts to control e-cigarette sales, with financial penalties limited. Stricter age restrictions and penalties could help enforce regulations and prevent a shift from e-cigarettes to traditional cigarettes. (Published on September 25, 2025byharvard.edu)</description></item><item><title>Indonesia Finance Minister cracks down on illegal cigarettes</title><link>https://asianews.network/indonesia-finance-minister-cracks-down-on-illegal-cigarettes/</link><description>The Finance Minister of Indonesia announced strict measures against illegal cigarette sales impacting state revenue, targeting smugglers and sellers. Random checks will target travelers, e-commerce platforms, and suppliers. Customs and excise authorities are monitoring tobacco products to prevent underpriced sales. Raids in several regions have seized millions of illegal cigarettes. With excise rates at 57%, efforts aim to address the issue of illegal cigarettes. Minimizing excise losses and deterring the illicit cigarette trade are top priorities for the government. (Published on September 25, 2025byasianews.network)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouch restriction makes quitting harder for workers</title><link>https://nbmediacoop.org/2025/09/23/nicotine-pouch-restriction-makes-quitting-harder-for-workers/</link><description>Michael, a 32-year-old construction worker from Saint John, struggled with smoking until finding success with nicotine pouches. Despite their effectiveness, Canadian regulations restricting access to them caused inconvenience and hindered efforts to quit smoking. Michael argues that limiting safer alternatives like pouches disproportionately affects working-class individuals and perpetuates addiction rather than promoting public health. He highlights the importance of supporting harm reduction strategies in reducing smoking-related health issues. Michael calls on MPs to overturn the ban on nicotine pouches, emphasizing the need for sensible health policies that prioritize people's well-being over moral judgments. (Published on September 25, 2025bynbmediacoop.org)</description></item><item><title>UKVIA Responds to Plain Packaging Demand</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-09-24_ukvia-responds-to-plain-packaging-demand.html</link><description>UKVIA Director General John Dunne warned that putting vapes in plain, cigarette-style packaging could drive ex-smokers back to cigarettes. He argued that while studies claim plain packaging reduces youth appeal, it risks reinforcing myths that vaping is as harmful as smoking. Dunne stressed that vaping is far less risky and the most effective way to quit smoking. He also pointed to evidence from the UK, Canada, and the US showing plain packaging reduces adult appeal and can increase smoking rates. Citing that 14% of former smokers have already returned to cigarettes after the disposable vape ban, he cautioned against further restrictive laws. (Published on September 25, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #11 | BREAKING THE NOISE | How Consumers Fight Vaping Misinformation in New Zealand?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-11/</link><description>In this interview, tobacco harm reduction advocate Nancy Loucas unpacks how consumer voices are pushing back against vaping misinformation in New Zealand, why education matters in a “post-truth” world, and how Asia-Pacific communities win by doing it “their way". (Published on September 25, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>