<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:56:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Nigeria’s health financing: Lessons From Canada’s $32.5bn tobacco settlement</title><link>https://pmnewsnigeria.com/2025/09/22/nigerias-health-financing-lessons-from-canadas-32-5bn-tobacco-settlement/?amp=1</link><description>Nigeria’s decision to allocate SIN taxes—levies on alcohol, tobacco, and sugary drinks—to health financing demonstrates a strong commitment to protecting public health and reflects long-standing demands from local advocates and the World Health Organisation (WHO). The move comes at a critical time. A recent investigation found Nigerians spend around N1.92 trillion ($1.26 billion) annually on treatment for non-communicable diseases (NCDs). Nearly 30% of all deaths in the country are linked to NCDs, with tobacco, alcohol, and sugary drinks identified as major contributors. (Published on September 23, 2025bypmnewsnigeria.com)</description></item><item><title>To quit smoking you have to sincerely want to, and I’m not sure I do</title><link>https://www.irishtimes.com/life-style/people/2025/09/22/to-quit-smoking-you-have-to-sincerely-want-to-and-im-not-sure-i-do/</link><description>A person reflects on their smoking habits, acknowledging the desire to cut down but not quit entirely. They describe the initial allure of smoking as a form of rebellion and self-discovery, as well as its social aspects and perceived glamor from movies. Despite being aware of the health risks and the need for change, the addiction's grip remains strong. The author contemplates the complex reasons behind smoking, acknowledging the challenges of truly wanting to quit versus finding comfort in the habit. They express a mix of resignation and enjoyment in smoking, despite recognizing its negative impact. (Published on September 23, 2025byirishtimes.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #72 | OPTIONS MATTER | Lisbon’s Vaping Project for Marginalized Groups</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-72/</link><description>Portugal is celebrated for its progressive drug policy, yet tobacco harm reduction remains sidelined. At GFN 2025 in Warsaw, Adriana Curado of GAT in Lisbon shows how nicotine became “the forgotten substance.” From her own move away from smoking to a pioneering vaping project with people who use drugs and those experiencing homelessness, Curado exposes public health contradictions, the persistence of stigma, and why safer nicotine options matter—especially for marginalized groups. (Published on September 23, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Vape use among UAE university students highest in Arab states, study suggests</title><link>https://www.thenationalnews.com/news/uae/2025/09/22/vape-use-among-uae-university-students-highest-in-arab-states-study-suggests/</link><description>Almost 40% of university students in the UAE use vapes, the highest among Arab countries studied. Factors like availability, various flavors, and online promotion contribute to the popularity. While vaping is seen as less harmful than smoking tobacco, health risks remain. Doctors recommend stricter controls on access to these products. In the UAE, 23% of students had vaped in the past month, indicating a growing trend. Flavors attract many users, but doctors suggest vapes for smokers aiming to quit. Concerns arise over the high prevalence among young adults. UAE authorities are urged to adapt regulations as the nicotine market evolves rapidly. (Published on September 23, 2025bythenationalnews.com)</description></item><item><title>Ireland’s delayed vape tax set to take effect by end of year</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/irelands-delayed-vape-tax-set-to-take-effect-by-end-of-year/</link><description>Ireland is set to introduce a tax on vape liquid, with a levy of 50c per milliliter planned to start by the end of the year. Measures to implement the tax, aimed at curbing youth vaping, are in advanced stages. The government is also increasing restrictions on vaping, including bans on sales to those under 18 and plans to prohibit disposable vapes along with stricter rules on flavors and advertising. Enforcement of regulations is crucial, with concerns raised about retail compliance and the need for effective prosecution of offenders. (Published on September 23, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Banning vaping in public? What is Labour smoking?</title><link>https://www.spiked-online.com/2025/09/23/banning-vaping-in-public-what-is-labour-smoking/</link><description>The UK government plans to ban vaping in public places, claiming health risks without scientific evidence. Public Health England emphasized the negligible harm of secondhand vaping in 2015 and 2018. Recent research also supports this, finding minimal health risks for bystanders. The proposed ban lacks evidence of significant risks, potentially hindering smokers from switching to safer alternatives. Critics argue it's a disproportionate restriction that harms harm-reduction efforts and reinforces negative perceptions of vaping. Public health policies should be evidence-based. Banning vaping without proven risks undermines harm reduction and individual freedoms, contrary to the government's successful smoking cessation programs. This overcautious approach may perpetuate smoking and stigmatize vaping. (Published on September 23, 2025byspiked-online.com)</description></item></channel></rss>