<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 01:03:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Don’t Let Tobacco Prevention Programs Go Up In Smoke</title><link>https://www.civilbeat.org/2025/07/dont-let-tobacco-prevention-programs-go-up-in-smoke/</link><description>The tobacco industry targets young users with new products. Programs assisting people like a sixth-grade vaper in Hawaii show promise in quitting nicotine addiction. Despite progress, youth vaping remains a concern, with flavored products masking nicotine harshness. Health disparities are evident among Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander populations. Tobacco prevention programs in Hawaii are successful but face funding threats. Urgent actions include protecting funding, banning flavored tobacco, and supporting front-line workers. Continued efforts are crucial to safeguard youth, reduce diseases, and address health inequalities. By investing in proven strategies, we can prevent another generation from falling victim to tobacco addiction. (Published on July 01, 2025bycivilbeat.org)</description></item><item><title>‘Vapes are safe alternatives to smoking’ — and other lies they tell us</title><link>https://mg.co.za/health/2025-07-01-vapes-are-safe-alternatives-to-smoking-and-other-lies-they-tell-us/</link><description>Lekan Ayo-Yusuf discussed the 2025 WHO Report on the Global Tobacco Epidemic and the Tobacco Bill, emphasizing the industry's shift towards electronic devices like vapes and heated tobacco products. The report reveals how tobacco companies manipulate regulations, funding biased research, and promoting new products as harm-reduction tools. Ayo-Yusuf highlighted the ineffectiveness of these products in reducing harm and the industry's violation of tobacco laws. The Tobacco Bill aims to control the marketing and use of these products, especially among youth. Despite the rising popularity of vapes and heated tobacco in South Africa, Ayo-Yusuf expressed concerns about the increasing number of smokers and emphasized the need for stricter regulations. (Published on July 01, 2025bymg.co.za)</description></item><item><title>The WHO's Attack on Reduced Harm</title><link>https://www.thefirebreak.org/p/the-whos-attack-on-reduced-harm</link><description>The text discusses the WHO's opposition to harm reduction products like e-cigarettes, misinforming against vaping and failing to support smokers trying to quit tobacco. It highlights the WHO's reliance on activists and foundations funding biased research, impacting their policies. The lack of transparency, refusal to consider scientific evidence, and questionable decision-making regarding a potential nicotine-based vaccine during the COVID-19 pandemic are also addressed. The text emphasizes the need for the WHO to reform, address conflicts of interest, prioritize public health over political agendas, and promote responsible behavior. (Published on July 01, 2025bythefirebreak.org)</description></item><item><title>Michael Russell Oration 2025 | The State of Academic Research on Nicotine</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/michael-russell-oration-2025-the-state-of-academic-research-on-nicotine/</link><description>GFN 2025 Michael Russell Oration - delivered by Arielle Selya - titled "The State of Academic Research on Nicotine". (Published on July 01, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Leading US Nicotine-Consumer Voice Falls Silent</title><link>https://filtermag.org/nicotine-consumer-voice-silent-casaa/</link><description>The CASAA, a leading US tobacco harm reduction organization with 250,000 members, will cease active advocacy in August due to financial constraints. The group aimed to educate about vaping and tobacco harm reduction, impacting legislation and public discourse. Despite industry funding challenges, CASAA prioritized consumer advocacy over donors' interests, leaving a legacy in THR. Its closure is mourned by advocates globally. Former members like Phillip Kirschberg emphasize the organization's crucial role in empowering consumer voices. CASAA's evolution signifies a continuing fight for safer nicotine products. The future of THR advocacy rests on consumer experiences shaping research, policy, and product development toward a healthier future. (Published on July 01, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco tax hikes: A costly gamble for Europe’s health and fiscal stability</title><link>https://www.eureporter.co/health/2025/07/01/tobacco-tax-hikes-a-costly-gamble-for-europes-health-and-fiscal-stability/</link><description>A leaked internal report from the European Commission reveals serious concerns about proposed major tobacco tax hikes across the EU. While the reforms aim to improve public health and raise revenue, the Commission’s own analysis warns of unintended and potentially harmful consequences. The leaked impact assessment, reported by Bild on 12 June 2025, outlines steep excise duty increases—139% on cigarettes, 258% on rolling tobacco, and 1,092% on cigars. Vaping and heated tobacco products would also be taxed for the first time at the EU level. Though expected to generate €15.1 billion annually, the report raises doubts about the overall effectiveness and impact of the plan. (Published on July 01, 2025byeureporter.co)</description></item></channel></rss>