<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 18:17:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Harm Reduction Explained | Dr. Mark Tyndall</title><link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PKfzFW2tRjc</link><description>Join us for a thought-provoking conversation with Dr. Mark Tyndall, a leading physician, researcher, and global voice in harm reduction. With decades of experience in public health, Dr. Tyndall has been at the forefront of efforts to reduce the harms of substance use, improve access to life-saving interventions, and challenge stigma through evidence-based solutions. (Published on September 22, 2025byyoutube.com)</description></item><item><title>Health officials trying to tackle massive and 'tragic' use of vapes among teens</title><link>https://www.cbc.ca/news/canada/london/health-officials-trying-to-tackle-massive-and-tragic-use-of-vapes-among-teens-1.7638534</link><description>Local health officials are concerned about the increasing trend of teen vaping, with some young people even turning to cigarettes to curb their high-potency nicotine addiction. Issues of vaping on school premises are widespread, with many students facing warnings and fines. The deceptive marketing of vapes, coupled with the high nicotine content, poses risks of addiction and health problems. Efforts are being made to combat youth vaping rates through education, enforcement, and regulation. It is crucial for parents to educate their children early on the dangers of vaping. The complex intervention approach involves multiple strategies to address the issue effectively. Despite regulations, online sales of vapes and discreet product designs remain challenges for enforcement. (Published on September 22, 2025bycbc.ca)</description></item><item><title>Telford and Wrekin: More smokers need to set quit date</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn762e20re0o?app-referrer=deep-link</link><description>Health officials in Telford and Wrekin aim to reduce smoking rates, with 21,580 adult smokers, especially in deprived areas. Efforts include a "smoke-free alliance" and investing in anti-vaping campaigns. The council is allocating funds for smoking cessation services. Despite a decrease in quitters, vaping among teens is rising. Aiming for a smoke-free future, authorities are inspired by success in other regions. Discussions are ongoing to expand the alliance beyond Telford and Wrekin. The initiative seeks to combat smoking and vaping among adults and youth. (Published on September 22, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>Calls for changes to how vapes are sold to curb appeal to teens</title><link>https://www.independent.co.uk/news/health/vapes-law-uk-plain-packaging-b2830899.html</link><description>Research suggests selling vapes in plain packaging could deter children while still serving as a tool for adult smokers to quit. A study by UCL and King’s College London showed standardised packs with limited flavor descriptions reduced youth appeal by 15%. Interest among adults remained steady. The Tobacco and Vapes Bill aims to regulate vape marketing to protect children while supporting smokers trying to quit. The study emphasized finding a balance to discourage youth vaping without hindering adult cessation efforts. Standardized packaging could be effective in reducing youth interest without impacting adults' perception of harm. The findings highlight the importance of regulating vape packaging to strike a balance. (Published on September 22, 2025byindependent.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>WHO Disenfranchises the Public from Tobacco Control Conference as Registration Barriers Reach "Insane" Levels</title><link>https://www.manilatimes.net/2025/09/22/tmt-newswire/globenewswire/who-disenfranchises-the-public-from-tobacco-control-conference-as-registration-barriers-reach-insane-levels/2187916</link><description>The Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA) has condemned the World Health Organisation’s Framework Convention on Tobacco Control (WHO FCTC) for deliberately blocking public participation in the upcoming COP11, set for November in Geneva. CAPHRA’s Executive Coordinator, Nancy Loucas, criticised the WHO FCTC for creating an “insane system” of registration, designed to exclude legitimate stakeholders. [...] Such requirements make it impossible for consumer advocates to register, as their advocacy is separate from their professional careers. According to CAPHRA, these barriers reflect a long-standing pattern of exclusion built into the WHO FCTC process. (Published on September 22, 2025bymanilatimes.net)</description></item><item><title>Mexico Mulls 30% Tobacco Tax Hike from 2026; Industry Warns of Illicit Market Growth and Revenue Losses</title><link>https://www.2firsts.com/news/mexico-proposes-cigarette-tax-hike-of-at-least-20-pesos-per-pack-concerns-raised-about-impact-on-consumption-and-revenue-increase-in-illegal-market</link><description>Mexico's National Tobacco Industry Council (Conainta) is concerned about a proposed more than 30% increase in Special Tax on cigarettes and nicotine products, with up to 200% tax on alternative products starting in 2026. The Mexican Confederation of Industrial Chambers estimates a potential 50% boost in illicit consumption, leading to annual fiscal losses of MXN 13–15 billion. Conainta argues that previous tax hikes did not reduce consumption or boost revenue, citing a 7% drop in IEPS receipts for manufactured tobacco in 2024. Illicit trade poses a significant risk, with reports showing a 240% surge in illicit cigarettes from 2017–2023. The industry calls for a balanced fiscal reform to promote public health and combat illicit trade while maintaining sustainable revenues. (Published on September 22, 2025by2firsts.com)</description></item></channel></rss>