<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:25:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #75 | EMINENCE-BASED | How Misinformation About Nicotine Took Hold</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-75/</link><description>Public health’s war on nicotine has spiraled into hysteria—untethered from science and reason. In this hard-hitting GFN Interviews, addiction specialist Dr. Garrett McGovern exposes how ideology, fear, and institutional ego are driving the misinformation crisis around vaping and safer nicotine products—and why it’s time to bring smoking harms back to the center of the debate. (Published on October 27, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Denver’s Flavor Ban a Poor Solution Looking for a Problem</title><link>https://i2i.org/denvers-flavor-ban-a-poor-solution-looking-for-a-problem/</link><description>Denver voters face Referendum 310, deciding on a ban on flavored nicotine products. Proponents aim to curb youth access, but opponents argue it's unnecessary due to declining underage vaping rates. The ban overlooks harm-reducing alternatives like e-cigarettes and nicotine pouches. Similar bans in other places led to revenue loss and thriving black markets. Advocates suggest focusing on education and enforcement, not prohibition. The ban could push consumers to neighboring areas, causing economic losses. Critics warn of repeating past policy failures and urge for a balanced approach. Ultimately, the ban might do more harm than good, impacting public health, freedom, and the economy. (Published on October 27, 2025byi2i.org)</description></item><item><title>Over a thousand profiles offer drugs on social media</title><link>https://cphpost.dk/2025-10-27/news/round-up/over-a-thousand-profiles-offer-drugs-on-social-media/</link><description>A study by Analyse &amp; Tal for netstof.dk found 1,341 profiles on Snapchat, TikTok, and Reddit selling illegal nicotine products and drugs such as cannabis and cocaine. This sale is accompanied by effective communication strategies, with young people encountering attractive ads and profiles selling puff bars and drugs. Snapchat claims to monitor and remove such accounts, while Reddit and TikTok have not responded. (Published on October 27, 2025bycphpost.dk)</description></item></channel></rss>