<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 01:08:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Free vape schemes drive smoking rates to record lows</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/free-vape-schemes-drive-smoking-rates-to-record-lows/</link><description>Government-backed schemes promoting vaping have led to a significant drop in smoking rates across UK, with places like Richmond-upon-Thames achieving a 5.3% smoking rate, close to the national "smoke-free" goal. Richmond's successful Stop Smoking Service, offering free vape kits and assistance, has helped over 178 residents quit smoking in a year. This approach is supported by evidence of vaping being less harmful than cigarettes and an effective quitting aid. Similar successful initiatives, like Swap to Stop in Dorset, have helped thousands switch to vaping, showing health and financial benefits. Quitting smoking can save individuals around £285 monthly. (Published on January 22, 2026byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Big Tobacco is turning into Big Nicotine</title><link>https://www.ft.com/content/701f58d2-66f8-4dfb-91de-f49dadecc24e</link><description>British American Tobacco shocked investors two years ago with a £27bn writedown of its US cigarette brands, causing its shares to fall amid declining cigarette sales and political pressure on vaping. Contrary to expectations, the company’s shares have since risen nearly 90%, lifting its market value to £92bn and making it the UK’s sixth most valuable company. This performance has outpaced even Nvidia over the past year, while rival Imperial Brands has also grown to a £24bn market capitalisation. (Published on January 22, 2026byft.com)</description></item><item><title>NSW looks to stamp out illicit tobacco</title><link>https://www.medicalrepublic.com.au/nsw-looks-to-stamp-out-illicit-tobacco/122646</link><description>The AMA NSW submitted strategies to reduce nicotine consumption, focusing on tackling illegal tobacco trade, tightening tobacco regulations, enhancing educational campaigns, and assisting individuals to quit. The submission emphasizes the ineffectiveness of reducing tobacco excise in combating illegal trade, calling for evidence-based solutions. Measures include limiting tobacco shopfronts, banning specific nicotine products, and improving youth education on vaping risks. The AMA stresses the importance of prevention through educating minors and vulnerable groups. Initiatives aim to inform individuals about the implications of nicotine use and discourage smoking, reflecting a comprehensive approach to addressing smoking rates and illegal trade concerns. (Published on January 22, 2026bymedicalrepublic.com.au)</description></item></channel></rss>