<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 18:14:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Banning Flavored E-Cigarettes Increases Traditional Cigarette Use Among Young Adults</title><link>https://www.profolus.com/topics/banning-flavored-e-cigarettes-may-increase-traditional-cigarette-use-among-young-adults/</link><description>A study in Health Economics revealed that state bans on flavored e-cigarettes may lead young adults to increase traditional cigarette use. Led by Henry Saffer, the research used survey data to analyze the unintended consequences of these bans. Among 18-24-year-olds, there was a 2-3% decrease in e-cigarette use alongside a similar rise in cigarette smoking, indicating a substitution effect. Evidence also suggested a potential increase in smoking among minors. Older adults were less affected. Similar studies show bans reduce vaping but increase smoking, indicating the need for nuanced public health policies to address unintended outcomes. (Published on September 09, 2025byprofolus.com)</description></item><item><title>Spain plans smoking ban at bar terraces, beaches, stadiums</title><link>https://cyprus-mail.com/2025/09/09/spain-plans-smoking-ban-at-bar-terraces-beaches-stadiums</link><description>Spain's leftist government proposed a bill to ban smoking at outdoor venues, including beaches and terraces, along with vapes. The Health Minister emphasized public health over private interests. The hospitality sector is concerned about the impact on popular outdoor smoking areas. The legislation is similar to France's ban, but Spain's exempts cafes and e-cigarettes. The bill aims to reduce smoking-related deaths, which average 137 per day in Spain. Plain tobacco packaging was not included in the final bill, despite being implemented in 25 countries. The parliament still needs to approve the bill in a country with high smoking rates. (Published on September 09, 2025bycyprus-mail.com)</description></item><item><title>Prohibition Does Not Work</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-09-08_prohibition-does-not-work.html</link><description>Last week marked the launch of Prohibition Does Not Work, an international coalition backed by think tanks and aimed at promoting evidence-based harm reduction policies over prohibitionist approaches. The group argues that prohibition has failed, fueling crime, black markets, and public health risks, while blocking access to safer alternatives. Partners such as the Tholos Foundation and the Australian Taxpayers’ Alliance stress that governments should follow the science, adopt harm reduction strategies, and curb the unintended consequences of restrictive tobacco and nicotine laws. (Published on September 09, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Anti-tobacco groups hail France's decision to ban nicotine pouches in 2026</title><link>https://www.rfi.fr/en/france/20250906-anti-tobacco-groups-hail-france-s-decision-to-ban-nicotine-pouches-in-2026</link><description>France will ban nicotine sachets, balls, and gum due to toxicity concerns and addiction risks, effective from March 2026. The ban follows the prohibition of disposable e-cigarettes and aims to protect young people from nicotine-related dangers. The government's decision has been praised by anti-tobacco associations as a crucial measure. Critics argue the ban may deprive adult smokers of regulated alternatives and fuel illegal drug trafficking. Nicotine pouches are said to cause poisonings, especially among children and adolescents, leading to severe health issues. The move reflects a shift in tobacco regulation to tackle addiction and public health concerns. (Published on September 09, 2025byrfi.fr)</description></item><item><title>Don’t Ignore the People: The WHO and EU Must Listen to Consumers on Tobacco Harm Reduction</title><link>https://www.republicworld.com/initiatives/dont-ignore-the-people-the-who-and-eu-must-listen-to-consumers-on-tobacco-harm-reduction</link><description>Policymakers and health officials convening in Dublin overlook consumer perspectives on tobacco regulation, focusing on prohibitive measures influenced by powerful stakeholders. This ignores evidence supporting harm reduction strategies and excludes those benefiting from safer alternatives in countries like Sweden and the UK. Proposed EU regulations, aligning with the WHO's strict abstinence model, risk hindering public health by restricting access to less harmful nicotine products. Amidst global policy debates, it is crucial for decision-makers to prioritize evidence-based approaches and engage with consumer voices to ensure effective and inclusive tobacco control strategies at COP11 and beyond. (Published on September 09, 2025byrepublicworld.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches may offer path to reduced tobacco harm</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-09-nicotine-pouches-path-tobacco.html</link><description>Adults in the U.S. are turning to nicotine pouches as a potential step down from more harmful nicotine products. A study by Rutgers Health found that most users have a history of tobacco use, with some using pouches to quit. Despite low overall usage rates, concerns about the long-term health effects, addiction, and youth uptake persist. Researchers emphasize the need for monitoring and regulation to prevent uncontrolled proliferation. While potentially beneficial for established tobacco users seeking harm reduction, caution is advised for non-users. Understanding usage patterns is crucial as these products gain popularity. The study provides valuable insights into current trends around nicotine pouch use. (Published on September 09, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item></channel></rss>