<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 12:33:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Beyond Nicotine Replacement Therapy: Smoking Cessation for Older Americans</title><link>https://www.rstreet.org/research/beyond-nicotine-replacement-therapy-smoking-cessation-for-older-americans/</link><description>Smoking is a major issue among older Americans, with higher rates of smoking and lower quit attempts compared to younger individuals. Nicotine Replacement Therapy (NRT) is effective in aiding smoking cessation, but older smokers face barriers such as cost and access. Combining NRT with Cognitive Behavioral Therapy (CBT) and social support can enhance quitting success. Additionally, promoting non-combustible nicotine products like e-cigarettes can offer alternative quitting methods. To support smoking cessation among older Americans, tailored education, accessible resources, and policy interventions are crucial to increase awareness and decrease environmental triggers. Providing a variety of cessation options is essential for improving the health outcomes of older smokers. (Published on May 16, 2025byrstreet.org)</description></item><item><title>A Health Philosopher’s Views on Tobacco Harm Reduction</title><link>https://filtermag.org/health-philosophy-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>The tobacco harm reduction (THR) debate raises ethical questions about misinformation, youth rights, and health equity. Dr. Sridhar Venkatapuram explores these issues, advocating for harm reduction strategies over bans and discussing the societal factors influencing smoking. He emphasizes providing accurate information, supporting marginalized populations, and balancing individual freedoms with public health concerns. Venkatapuram addresses misconceptions around safer nicotine products, highlighting the complexities of regulating disposables and flavored vapes. He debates the role of tobacco companies in harm reduction efforts and advocates for individual autonomy in drug usage while acknowledging societal responsibilities. Venkatapuram advocates for a nuanced approach to addressing drug use and health disparities. (Published on May 16, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item></channel></rss>