<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 01:01:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dutch doctors threaten legal action against snapchat over illegal vape sales</title><link>https://nltimes.nl/2025/06/10/dutch-doctors-threaten-legal-action-snapchat-illegal-vape-sales</link><description>Doctors from LUMC, the Antoni van Leeuwenhoek Hospital, and Rookpreventie Jeugd are threatening legal action against Snapchat over the illegal sale of flavored vapes. The lawyers demand that Snapchat block vape-related content within two weeks, citing European regulations. The sale of flavored vapes is illegal in the Netherlands, but their circulation, especially among minors, persists. Snapchat responded by stating their prohibition of illegal activities and use of detection technology. The doctors aim to protect children and may escalate the issue to authorities if demands are not met. Discussions continue on the platform's responsibilities and potential solutions to combat illegal vape sales. (Published on June 11, 2025bynltimes.nl)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco excise has passed a ‘tipping point’ and is fuelling black market, economists warn</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/jun/11/tobacco-excise-isnt-making-australians-smoke-less-and-should-be-frozen-to-curb-black-market-economists-say?CMP=share_btn_url</link><description>Economists suggest freezing or reducing the tobacco excise to tackle Australia's booming illegal cigarette market, as raising the excise further has failed to curb smoking rates. However, public health advocates warn against drastic tax cuts. The excise, which has tripled in the past decade, comprises a major portion of cigarette prices. Despite successful past policies reducing smoking rates, current measures are ineffective. Border seizures of illegal tobacco have surged, prompting calls for stronger enforcement over tax decreases. Experts argue that the excise level has become counterproductive, suggesting a temporary radical cut. The excise rate, now heavily indexed and escalating annually, needs revision to combat illicit tobacco trade. (Published on June 11, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item></channel></rss>