<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 01:01:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vapers overtake smokers for first time in Britain</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ceq0z9e2wwwo</link><description>Vaping surpasses smoking in the UK, with 5.4 million adults using vapes compared to 4.9 million smoking cigarettes in 2024. Daily vape use is popular among 25-49-year-olds and rising among women. The NHS states vaping poses fewer risks than smoking due to fewer harmful chemicals. Currently, 10% of UK adults use e-cigarettes, slightly more than smokers. Efforts to reduce smoking include bans on indoor smoking, smoking in cars with children, plain cigarette packaging, and future legislation prohibiting tobacco sales to those born after 2009. Concerns about vapes appealing to children have led to plans for stricter packaging rules. Usage among 16-24-year-olds has slightly decreased from 2023. (Published on November 04, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>Tax hike that will more than double price of vapes will hit smokers trying to quit, warns GP</title><link>https://m.independent.ie/irish-news/tax-hike-that-will-more-than-double-price-of-vapes-will-hit-smokers-trying-to-quit-warns-gp/a556632228.html</link><description>Tax hikes in Ireland, doubling vape prices, concern addicts quitting cigarettes and impact smokers. The Department of Health targets youth vaping but faces backlash. Irish Heart Foundation supports tax due to rising youth vaping rates. Vape shop owners fear black market growth and loss of adult customers. UK plans similar vape tax next year. Responsible Vaping Ireland backs the tax for public health. Enforcement and restrictions on flavors and sales are proposed. Vape shops foresee challenges in compliance and business sustainability amid rising prices. (Published on November 04, 2025byindependent.ie)</description></item><item><title>Is vaping less harmful than smoking, and does it help people quit?</title><link>https://ourworldindata.org/vaping-vs-smoking-health-risks</link><description>Vaping is viewed more negatively than before, with concerns raised about its risks. Vapes are less harmful than cigarettes, containing fewer toxins. While not risk-free, vaping helps smokers quit, with research showing its effectiveness. Concerns exist about vaping during pregnancy, but it appears safer than smoking. Vaping is not a significant gateway to smoking among young people. Public health advice recommends vaping for smokers but discourages it for non-smokers. Misconceptions persist, with smokers mostly unaware of vaping benefits. Young people's use of vapes is a concern, but data does not strongly support it as a gateway to smoking. Balancing public health benefits and risks is crucial. (Published on November 04, 2025byourworldindata.org)</description></item><item><title>Brussels’ War on Tobacco Masks an Assault on National Power</title><link>https://europeanconservative.com/articles/news/brussels-war-on-tobacco-assault-on-national-power/</link><description>The European Commission advocates a ban on cigarette filters and e-cigarettes, aligning with WHO directives. This move extends centralized power and fiscal control, overshadowing Member States' sovereignty. The proposal, driven by environmental and health concerns, masks a fiscal control agenda, enabling Brussels to appropriate national tax revenues. NGOs, funded by the Commission, amplify WHO policies, tightening the grip on EU legislation. The regulation would detrimentally impact European tobacco producers and erode subsidiarity principles. It contrasts with successful national policies like Sweden's. The push for global regulations contradicts von der Leyen's promises of economic freedom. Upholding health and freedom necessitates independent legislative decision-making and transparency in NGO funding. (Published on November 04, 2025byeuropeanconservative.com)</description></item></channel></rss>