<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 14:19:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What is popcorn lung? The serious and irreversible disease linked to vaping</title><link>https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/health-and-families/vape-what-is-popcorn-lung-vaping-symptoms-b2751522.html</link><description>Vaping can lead to serious lung damage, like "popcorn lung," caused by chemicals inhaled into the lungs, particularly harmful to young users. The condition, reminiscent of a case involving a US teenager, stems from chemicals like diacetyl, present in e-cigarettes and linked to irreversible lung issues. Vaping's rise among youth poses a significant health risk, with various flavorings containing harmful compounds. To address this growing concern, regulations and awareness campaigns are crucial to safeguard public health and prevent long-term damage. The story underscores the necessity of scrutinizing vaping products to protect future generations from enduring similar health consequences. (Published on May 15, 2025byindependent.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Vaping banned in WA workplaces</title><link>https://www.yourlocalexaminer.com.au/vaping-banned-in-wa-workplaces/</link><description>Vapes and e-cigarettes are now banned in enclosed workplaces in Western Australia under updated safety laws. The regulations aim to protect workers from harmful vapours, treating vaping like tobacco smoking. The rules, covering general and mining workplaces, include heated tobacco products. Employers must have clear policies, designated outdoor areas, and consider specific risks, such as children's presence. The change reflects growing health concerns around vaping's dangers, including life-threatening illnesses and cancer from hazardous substances in e-cigarettes. The government's focus on worker safety is highlighted through these new laws. (Published on May 15, 2025byyourlocalexaminer.com.au)</description></item><item><title>Smoking Is More Common Than Previously Thought — So Naturally, the UK Plans to Ban the Solution</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/smoking-is-more-common-than-previously-thought-so-naturally-the-uk-plans-to-ban-the-solution/</link><description>New research shows the UK significantly underestimates smoking rates by not including vulnerable groups in surveys. Including hidden populations like those in care facilities and homelessness increases smoking prevalence from 12.9% to 14.5-14.8%. Despite this, government policies hinder harm reduction efforts, such as banning ads for safer alternatives and imposing high vape taxes. Such measures can prevent smokers, especially in marginalized communities, from switching to less harmful options. The UK's goal of being smoke-free by 2030 seems unattainable with current restrictions. Increasing access to safer alternatives and building trust through regulation is crucial for effective smoking cessation strategies. (Published on May 15, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item></channel></rss>