<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 06:47:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Aotearoa’s first medically approved quit-vaping product</title><link>https://waateanews.com/2026/02/03/letitia-harding-health-organisation-welcomes-first-medically-approved-quit-vaping-product-calls-for-stronger-laws-a-health-organisation-has-welcomed-the-approval-of-aotearoas-first-medical/</link><description>Medsafe approved Aotearoa's first medically endorsed quit-vaping product, recognizing vaping addiction as a health issue. The product targets high-frequency nicotine exposure associated with vaping and facilitates controlled nicotine reduction. The Foundation highlights accessibility concerns, urging wider availability and affordability, especially for youth. They emphasize the product as part of a holistic approach to public health, underscoring the need for education, regulation, and prevention. (Published on February 04, 2026bywaateanews.com)</description></item><item><title>Conflict of Interest - Redefined to Mean Only Industry</title><link>https://09algor.substack.com/p/conflict-of-interest-redefined-to</link><description>In tobacco control, “conflict of interest” has quietly undergone a semantic narrowing so severe that it now means almost one thing and one thing only: proximity to industry. Not proximity to power, not proximity to government, not proximity to advocacy organisations, not proximity to one’s own past statements or professional brand, just industry. Funding from a tobacco or nicotine company is treated not merely as a potential source of bias, but as a moral contaminant that disqualifies arguments in advance. Meanwhile, other forms of interest, ideological, reputational, institutional, and career-based, are waved through as if they were morally neutral, or worse, invisible. (Published on February 04, 2026bysubstack.com)</description></item><item><title>Revised Tobacco Business Act takes effect April 24, strengthens regulations on e-cigarettes</title><link>https://koreajoongangdaily.joins.com/news/2026-02-03/national/socialAffairs/Revised-Tobacco-Business-Act-takes-effect-April-24-strengthens-regulations-on-ecigarettes/2515133</link><description>Starting April 24, e-cigarettes containing synthetic nicotine will be regulated in the same way as conventional combustible cigarettes, following an amendment to the Tobacco Business Act that broadens the legal definition of tobacco. The Ministry of Health and Welfare announced on Tuesday that the revision, which was approved by the National Assembly late last year, will require tobacco manufacturers, importers, retailers, and users to adhere to the new rules once the law comes into effect. (Published on February 04, 2026byjoins.com)</description></item><item><title>Shameful Changes in the WHO’s European Code Against Cancer</title><link>https://filtermag.org/who-world-cancer-day-nicotine/</link><description>Cancer has deeply impacted my family, with members suffering from various types. Smoking was common among them, a significant risk factor. World Cancer Day has personal significance, but conflicting messaging from organizations like the WHO on smoking and nicotine adds frustration. The WHO's updated European Code Against Cancer blurs distinctions, falsely equating smoking with vaping. The failure to acknowledge harm reduction poses risks, especially since nicotine is wrongly believed to cause cancer. The WHO should prioritize clear risk communication, acknowledging the benefits of harm reduction and the experiences of those who have switched to safer alternatives, rather than pushing misleading narratives. (Published on February 04, 2026byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>French watchdog flags heart, lung and cancer risks as vape use grows</title><link>https://www.rfi.fr/en/france/20260204-french-watchdog-flags-heart-lung-and-cancer-risks-as-vaping-use-grows</link><description>France's health agencies warn about the risks of vaping, including heart, lung, and cancer dangers, especially among teenagers. Anses cautions that vaping is not risk-free and can have long-term health effects. While vaping is seen as an alternative to smoking, it is not without risks, with concerns over exposure to toxic substances like aldehydes. Nicotine-containing products may impact cardiovascular health, respiratory systems, and potentially cancer development. The agency advises that vaping, while potentially aiding smoking cessation, should be temporary. An increase in long-term vaping among users is noted, especially among former smokers. Teens are drawn to vaping for various reasons, posing unique challenges. Long-term cancer risks are still being studied, particularly among non-smokers. (Published on February 04, 2026byrfi.fr)</description></item></channel></rss>