<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 12:24:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>International public health experts warn about high nicotine taxation</title><link>https://www.eureporter.co/health/tobacco-2/2025/09/01/international-public-health-experts-warn-about-high-nicotine-taxation/</link><description>A group of 83 leading public health experts has written to European Commission President Ursula von der Leyen, criticizing plans to tax smoke-free alternatives like e-cigarettes, heated tobacco, and nicotine pouches at the same level as cigarettes. They argue this contradicts scientific evidence, misinforms the public, and protects the cigarette trade. The experts point to successful harm reduction examples in Sweden, the UK, and New Zealand to support their case. (Published on September 01, 2025byeureporter.co)</description></item><item><title>GFN.TV Interviews #69 | SHIFTING FIREPOWER | Tobacco Control’s Self-Serving Reinvention</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfntv-interviews-69/</link><description>Institutions like WHO, regulators, and NGOs are hostile to harm reduction and have shifted their firepower from smoking to safer nicotine alternatives, says Clive Bates, international tobacco control policy expert. Shot on location at GFN 2025 in Warsaw, Bates describes public health’s “war on nicotine” as a misguided, ideological crusade that betrays its original mission of reducing smoking-related disease and death. (Published on September 01, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Could Vapers Be Denied NHS IVF</title><link>https://daily-pouch.com/nhs-ivf-vaping-ban-cheshire-merseyside/</link><description>NHS services in Merseyside and Cheshire have imposed restrictions on publicly-funded IVF, including denying treatment to vapers. While lifestyle factors like smoking and BMI impact IVF success rates, the effects of vaping are less clear. Publicly-funded IVF faces funding limitations, leading to restrictions based on proven impacts. However, research on vaping's independent effects is inconclusive. Restrictions targeting vapers may be unjustified, as switching from smoking to vaping can improve fertility. The proposal aims to save money but could unfairly penalize vapers. A call for evidence-based policies is essential to ensure equitable access to IVF treatment. It remains crucial for the NHS to prioritize fair and evidence-based healthcare decisions. (Published on September 02, 2025bydaily-pouch.com)</description></item><item><title>UAE smokers turn to nicotine pouches as harm-reduction debate grows</title><link>https://www.arabianbusiness.com/abnews/uae-smokers-turn-to-nicotine-pouches-as-harm-reduction-debate-grows</link><description>Nicotine pouches, recently legalized in the UAE, offer a "smoke-free" alternative but still pose addiction risks, cautioned by experts. The Ministry of Industry authorized their sale under strict regulations to reduce health risks. Although pouches decrease respiratory issues linked to smoking, they can impact cardiovascular health. While helpful in transitioning from cigarettes, doctors advise they are not a complete solution and stress the importance of proper usage and monitoring. Concerns include potential appeal to youth and lack of long-term safety studies. Regulations aim to ensure quality and safety, emphasizing the need for structured quitting plans. The effectiveness of nicotine pouches in reducing smoking prevalence in the UAE remains to be seen. (Published on September 02, 2025byarabianbusiness.com)</description></item></channel></rss>