<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:55:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>UK disposable vape ban failing to protect environment, says waste boss</title><link>https://clearingtheair.eu/en/post/uk-disposable-vape-ban-failing-to-protect-environment-says-waste-boss/</link><description>The UK ban on disposable vapes to reduce environmental impact and waste issues has backfired, with more vapes found in general recycling post-ban. Biffa reports a 3% increase with around a million vapes entering recycling monthly, despite the ban aiming to reduce them. The rise is partly attributed to cheap reusable vapes being treated as disposables. Improper disposal poses risks due to lithium battery fires and remains a challenge for waste management. The ban has failed to meet its goals of safeguarding health and the environment, as the disposal problem persists. (Published on September 16, 2025byclearingtheair.eu)</description></item><item><title>Tobacco kills 13.5L Indians yearly, costs nation ₹1.8L crore</title><link>https://www.newsbytesapp.com/news/science/tobacco-crisis-in-india-1-35m-deaths-annually-massive-healthcare-costs/story</link><description>Tobacco is a major health issue in India, causing 1.35 million deaths annually. Treating tobacco-related diseases costs over ₹1.77 lakh crore each year. Only 7% of smokers quit without assistance. Healthcare experts recommend smoke-free nicotine alternatives to reduce harm, with studies showing they are significantly safer than cigarettes. Nicotine pouches, now available in 34 countries, including India, could help smokers switch from cigarettes. Public Health England states these alternatives are up to 95% less harmful than smoking. Dr. Soni from AIIMS-CAPFIMS suggests regulating these products to aid smokers in transitioning away from traditional cigarettes. (Published on September 16, 2025bynewsbytesapp.com)</description></item><item><title>Fed Up with the FDA, Big Tobacco Goes Nuclear</title><link>https://vaping360.com/vape-news/big-tobacco-is-fed-up-with-the-fda/</link><description>NJOY, an Altria Group vape subsidiary, has filed a lawsuit against the FDA, claiming delays in deciding on NJOY vape products violate the Tobacco Control Act. On the same day, Altria announced plans to launch a new nicotine pouch brand without FDA authorization. R.J. Reynolds also launched flavored disposable vapes without FDA approval. NJOY argues that the FDA's delayed decisions may suggest a de facto ban on flavored products. Despite providing scientific evidence, NJOY's supervisory appeal has not been resolved after almost three years. Altria and Reynolds are pushing boundaries by introducing new products without FDA consent, citing reasons such as exceeding review timelines and legal loophole interpretations. (Published on September 16, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item></channel></rss>