<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 01:00:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From cigarettes to snuff to nicotine pouches: the unusual Icelandic model for tobacco harm reduction</title><link>https://gsthr.org/resources/briefing-papers/from-cigarettes-to-snuff-to-nicotine-pouches-the-unusual-icelandic-model-for-tobacco-harm-reduction/</link><description>The new Briefing Paper,“From cigarettes to snuff to nicotine pouches: the unusual Icelandic model for tobacco harm reduction”, is now available. The paper provides an overview of how Iceland has transitioned from high smoking rates to becoming one of the world’s leading examples of tobacco harm reduction. It explains how strict tobacco control measures, combined with the growing availability of lower-risk nicotine products such as snuff, vapes, and especially nicotine pouches, have led to a significant decline in cigarette use. The briefing explains how these products are regulated, how their use has been changing, and what this means for public health. You can read the full document here:gsthr.org. (Published on November 20, 2025bygsthr.org)</description></item><item><title>Vaping: Irish government approves plans to ban disposable vapes</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c15p5g7p1n5o</link><description>The Irish government approved banning disposable vapes and imposing restrictions on nicotine products to protect children. The move follows Northern Ireland's ban on single-use vapes. Retailers face fines and jail time for selling single-use e-cigarettes. Legislation will also regulate the sale of other nicotine products and restrict advertising, with new laws under consideration. Health Minister Jennifer Carroll MacNeill supports the measures to safeguard youth from nicotine harm. (Published on November 20, 2025bybbc.com)</description></item><item><title>People With COPD, Like My Husband, Are Being Failed</title><link>https://filtermag.org/copd-smoking-stigma/</link><description>A wife rushes her husband to the ER for breathing problems, where he's diagnosed with COPD. Stigma surrounds his smoking history, affecting his treatment. The healthcare system offers little support, leaving the wife to research COPD herself. Despite quitting smoking, proper tests weren't done initially. COPD changes their lives drastically, limiting his activities. Stigma persists in healthcare, with misconceptions about nicotine and its relation to diseases like COPD. The couple advocates for better understanding and care for COPD patients. As World COPD Day approaches, the focus shifts to combating stigma, misinformation, and improving care for those affected by COPD. (Published on November 20, 2025byfiltermag.org)</description></item><item><title>Good COP 2.0 | Day 4 of 5 | RegWatch (LIVE)</title><link>https://regulatorwatch.com/brent_stafford/good-cop-2-0-day-4-of-5-regwatch-live/</link><description>DAY #4 | Live from Geneva, Switzerland – RegWatch special coverage of the Taxpayers Protection Alliance’s Good COP 2.0, the tobacco harm reduction counter-conference to the World Health Organization’s COP 11. Good COP 2.0 unites 37 experts from 22 countries to separate fact from fiction and confront the misinformation shaping global health policy. (Published on November 20, 2025byregulatorwatch.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN News #164 | WHAT'S THE TRUTH ABOUT HARM REDUCTION IN NIGERIA?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-news-164-whats-the-truth-about-harm-reduction-in-nigeria/</link><description>Nigeria is experiencing increasing health impacts from smoking, and experts argue that harm reduction—not prohibition—is key to saving lives. In this GFN News episode, Joanna Junak interviews Uche Olatunji and Yusuf Adebisi on the major barriers to tobacco harm reduction in Nigeria, including widespread misinformation about nicotine and a lack of educational resources. They discuss community outreach, science-based alternatives, and the critical roles of universities and the media in shifting public perception. Learn how evidence-based harm-reduction strategies can help Nigerians make safer, informed decisions. (Published on November 20, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item><item><title>Billowing smoke from regulations clouding tobacco firms’ outlook</title><link>https://theedgemalaysia.com/node/779268</link><description>The Malaysian tobacco and e-cigarette industry faces increasing regulations and taxes, with bans on vape products in several states, and discussions about a nationwide vape ban. Tobacco companies are adjusting to the changes, with British American Tobacco withdrawing a vaping product. The Ministry of Health proposed a vape liquid tax increase, while Japan Tobacco is focusing on heated tobacco products as part of a global shift towards reduced-risk products. Malaysia's illicit cigarette trade is declining, but potential revenue from properly taxing vape products remains untapped. Japan Tobacco plans significant investments in reducing risky products, like heated tobacco sticks, expecting a shift towards smoke-free alternatives. (Published on November 20, 2025bytheedgemalaysia.com)</description></item><item><title>Opinion: The WHO wants nine times more money to control tobacco. Don’t pay!</title><link>https://financialpost.com/opinion/opinion-who-wants-more-money-control-tobacco</link><description>As COP30 on climate change wraps up in Brazil, the WHO has opened COP11 in Geneva, its conference focused on nicotine and tobacco, with a Canadian delegation in attendance. For months, the WHO has been preparing new anti-nicotine measures for delegates to approve. Delegates are now tasked with deciding how strict global nicotine policy should become. The WHO’s tobacco-control budget is just over US$1 billion — largely funded by Michael Bloomberg — but the organization says it actually needs US$9 billion to effectively pursue its goal of eliminating nicotine use, an 800% increase. (Published on November 20, 2025byfinancialpost.com)</description></item></channel></rss>