<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:19:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Tobacco and Vapes Bill – why we need to be careful with international comparisons</title><link>https://blogs.lse.ac.uk/politicsandpolicy/the-tobacco-and-vapes-bill-why-we-need-to-be-careful-with-international-comparisons/</link><description>The Tobacco and Vapes Bill in the UK aims to end tobacco sales to those born after 2009, with stricter regulations on nicotine products. The Bill faces criticism for misrepresenting international examples in debates. New Zealand's repeal of tobacco measures is linked to industry interference, not effectiveness issues. Australia's illicit tobacco market issues stem from weak enforcement, not regulation. Sweden's success in tobacco control is attributed to comprehensive policies, not just snus use. The UK Bill aims to regulate new nicotine products like pouches and address marketing to minors. Utilizing accurate international evidence is crucial for effective public health policy. Parliamentary debates impact global tobacco control approaches. (Published on November 03, 2025bylse.ac.uk)</description></item><item><title>OPINION: Poll on Tobacco Bill exposes its dangers to public health, jobs and security</title><link>https://www.citizen.digital/article/opinion-poll-on-tobacco-bill-exposes-its-dangers-to-public-health-jobs-and-security-n372081</link><description>In Kenya, there is high awareness of Tobacco Harm Reduction (THR) with 85% of respondents believing that promoting safer alternatives can help smokers quit traditional cigarettes. Additionally, 63% feel the government should conduct campaigns to encourage the switch to safer alternatives, recognizing the public health benefits. (Published on November 03, 2025bycitizen.digital)</description></item><item><title>The Second Life of Juul: Why the Brand’s Return Matters for Public Health</title><link>https://www.vapingpost.com/2025/11/02/the-second-life-of-juul-why-the-brands-return-matters-for-public-health/</link><description>Juul Labs is undergoing a strategic reset in response to underage vaping concerns in the US, including settlements and regulatory challenges. They are focusing on the Juul2 platform with enhanced features and age verification checks to deter underage use. Despite criticism, Juul remains committed to harm reduction for adult smokers. The tobacco industry has historically faced hurdles in innovation due to regulatory and communication barriers, hindering harm reduction alternatives. This cycle of demonization has impeded progress in reducing harm from smoking. Restricting safer options while allowing conventional cigarettes to dominate perpetuates harm and limits consumer choice. The need for a shift towards harm reduction and policies supporting innovation is crucial in public health efforts. (Published on November 03, 2025byvapingpost.com)</description></item><item><title>London smoking rate rise ‘concerning’: Five boroughs among twenty worst in England</title><link>https://london-tv.co.uk/london-smoking-rate-rise-concerning-five-boroughs-among-twenty-worst-in-england/</link><description>Five London boroughs, including Ealing, Croydon, Barking, Harrow, and Camden, show high smoking rates per ONS data. Ealing stands out with a 22% rate, 92% above the national average. Harrow and Bromley have doubled rates in a year. Despite concerns, Redbridge, Waltham Forest, and Richmond upon Thames feature the lowest rates. Nationally, smoking remains at 11.9%, the lowest since 2011. Vaping is noted as a safer quitting tool, but negative perceptions may hinder progress. Education on vaping risks versus benefits is urged to address rising smoking rates in specific areas as per Vape Club’s findings. (Published on November 03, 2025bylondon-tv.co.uk)</description></item><item><title>Maldives becomes the only country with generational smoking ban</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/nov/01/maldives-becomes-the-only-country-with-generational-smoking-ban</link><description>The Maldives has introduced a unique smoking ban for individuals born after January 2007, making it the only country with such a generational prohibition on tobacco. The measure took effect on 1 November to safeguard public health and create a tobacco-free generation. The ban encompasses all tobacco products and applies to residents and visitors alike. Violators face fines, with retailers required to verify age before selling. The Maldives also prohibits e-cigarettes and vaping products. In comparison, the UK is still considering a similar ban, while New Zealand repealed theirs just under a year after its introduction in November 2023. (Published on November 03, 2025bytheguardian.com)</description></item><item><title>Prominent Anti-Vaping Advocate is Misrepresenting Scientific Evidence and Being Unnecessarily Divisive, Polarizing, and Disrespectful</title><link>https://tobaccoanalysis.blogspot.com/2025/10/prominent-anti-vaping-advocate-is.html</link><description>There are three disturbing things about Dr. Glantz's presentation. Dr. Glantz misrepresents the scientific evidence, as extensive clinical research shows that switching from smoking to vaping leads to significant health improvements, including better respiratory symptoms and lung function; millions of people have experienced these benefits, and while dual use offers fewer gains than complete switching, there is no credible evidence that it increases harm, making claims that e-cigarettes worsen health scientifically unfounded and irresponsible. (Published on November 03, 2025byblogspot.com)</description></item><item><title>GFN Voices 2025 #17 | CAN TOBACCO HARM REDUCTION IMPROVE PUBLIC HEALTH IN LATIN AMERICA?</title><link>https://gfn.tv/vids/gfn-voices-2025-17-can-tobacco-harm-reduction-improve-public-health-in-latin-america/</link><description>Social worker and health policy advocate Angelica Cabrera discusses the growing movement for tobacco harm reduction across Latin America. She shares regional experiences, challenges, and success stories that highlight how alternative nicotine products could transform public health outcomes — if supported by science-based policies. (Published on November 03, 2025bygfn.tv)</description></item></channel></rss>