<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 18:19:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why People Are Swapping Vapes For Cigarettes Despite The Risks</title><link>https://www.refinery29.com/en-gb/vaping-addiction-cigarettes-quitting-smoking</link><description>In the UK, suspicion around vapes grew when disposable vapes were banned. Despite the ban, ex-smoker Lewis switched back to cigarettes to quit altogether. He found it easier to resist smoking in social settings while vaping. Although aware of cigarette risks, Lewis prefers vaping for its taste and convenience. Concerned about unknown long-term effects, he limits smoking and monitors his habits. Lewis believes vaping is a healthier alternative to smoking but remains cautious due to potential risks associated with vaping products. Considered switching to snus but faced adverse reactions. (Published on July 24, 2025byrefinery29.com)</description></item><item><title>It’s Time to Clear the Air on Juul</title><link>https://www.thefp.com/p/time-to-clear-the-air-on-juul</link><description>The FDA recently authorized Juul's e-cigarettes after a long delay, with minimal public outcry despite concerns from groups like the Campaign for Tobacco-Free Kids and the American Lung Association. Senator Durbin criticized the decision, but overall, there was little opposition. The decrease in youth vaping rates and Juul's declining popularity could explain this lack of outrage. In 2019, 27.5% of high-school students vaped, mostly using Juul, but in 2020, only 5.9% vaped, with less than 1% using Juul products. (Published on July 24, 2025bythefp.com)</description></item></channel></rss>