<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:19:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Study shows ads for prescription smoking cessation drugs help reduce smoking rates, but OTC ads fall short</title><link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-ads-prescription-cessation-drugs-otc.html</link><description>A peer-reviewed study in Marketing Science shows that direct-to-consumer ads for prescription smoking-cessation drugs reduce cigarette use, while ads for over-the-counter products do not. The research emphasizes the impact of advertising on public health goals for smoking cessation. Insurance coverage influences how ads affect behavior, with strong coverage leading to larger declines in cigarette sales. Ads for prescription products also boosted demand for alternative methods. The study highlights how the effectiveness of advertising depends on therapy accessibility and affordability. Policymakers should consider these findings when regulating pharmaceutical advertising. The research analyzed advertising effects on cigarette consumption, showing that a 10% reduction in ads leads to increased cigarette sales. (Published on October 22, 2025bymedicalxpress.com)</description></item><item><title>Stronger Laws Tackling Illicit Tobacco And Vapes</title><link>https://www.miragenews.com/stronger-laws-tackling-illicit-tobacco-and-vapes-1555525/</link><description>The ACT Government will increase enforcement against illegal smoking products through the Tobacco and Other Smoking Products Amendment Bill 2025. This bill aims to combat illicit tobacco and e-cigarettes by granting authorities new inspection and penalty powers. The reforms also enhance seizure provisions and officer safety measures. This initiative follows the alignment of vaping laws with federal regulations. Additionally, the government plans to provide substantial funding for smoking and vaping cessation support services. These measures signal a strong stance against illicit tobacco trading, emphasizing collaboration with other jurisdictions. (Published on October 22, 2025bymiragenews.com)</description></item><item><title>Italian PM Giorgia Meloni jokes she’d ‘kill someone’ if she was forced to quit smoking: ‘Impossible’</title><link>https://nypost.com/2025/10/14/world-news/italian-pm-giorgia-meloni-jokes-shed-kill-someone-if-she-had-to-quit-smoking/</link><description>Italian Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni joked about potentially "killing someone" if she had to quit smoking during the Gaza peace summit in Egypt. She bantered with world leaders like Turkish President Erdogan, who urged her to quit. Meloni revealed she restarted smoking after 13 years. Despite President Trump's compliments on her appearance, Meloni has gained respect for her political success. As Italy's first female prime minister, she plays a crucial role in mediating between the EU and the US, notably during Ukraine war negotiations. (Published on October 22, 2025bynypost.com)</description></item><item><title>NGOs accuse company of flouting nicotine-label rule on heated tobacco</title><link>https://focustaiwan.tw/society/202510220019</link><description>NGOs in Taiwan condemn a tobacco company for not labeling nicotine content on heated tobacco products, leading to their removal from shelves. Despite violating the law, the company opted for a fine over compliance. Authorities are investigating why the products differed from the approved samples. A study found high nicotine levels, surpassing legal limits. NGOs call for stricter enforcement, highlighting the company's power and profit in Taiwan's tobacco market. Health authorities clarify that heated tobacco's health risks are equivalent to regular cigarettes if nicotine levels exceed 1 milligram per stick. Tests are conducted on the products to verify compliance with regulations. (Published on October 22, 2025byfocustaiwan.tw)</description></item><item><title>WHO faces questions on donor-linked funding</title><link>https://www.philstar.com/world/2025/10/21/2449290/who-faces-questions-donor-linked-funding</link><description>A recent report questions the World Health Organization's independence due to significant donations by Bloomberg Philanthropies and undisclosed "dark money". The report highlights concerns over global health policies being influenced by donor-driven agendas, outlining instances where powerful financial interests, like Bloomberg, have shaped WHO's strategies, particularly in tobacco control. Transparency issues arise from the acceptance of undisclosed corporate funds by the WHO Foundation. Allegations point to Bloomberg's influence on public policy globally, bypassing democratic processes. The report urges reforms for accountability, inclusion of diverse voices, and respect for national sovereignty within the WHO's framework to prevent outside influences on health policies. (Published on October 22, 2025byphilstar.com)</description></item><item><title>Philippines Vape Ban Slammed</title><link>https://www.planetofthevapes.co.uk/news/vaping-news/2025-10-21_philippines-vape-ban-slammed.html</link><description>The Coalition of Asia Pacific Tobacco Harm Reduction Advocates (CAPHRA) has strongly criticized the Philippines’ new vape ban, calling it a “reckless policy” that removes safer alternatives for adult smokers. The ban on open pod systems and uncertified e-liquids has already closed compliant shops and limited consumer choices. Nancy Loucas, CAPHRA’s Executive Coordinator, argued that the government fails to distinguish between different vaping systems, demonstrating a lack of understanding that harms the public. CAPHRA also condemned the Department of Trade and Industry (DTI) for not consulting consumers, leading to policies that undermine effective public health measures. (Published on October 22, 2025byplanetofthevapes.co.uk)</description></item></channel></rss>