<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Nicotine Science and Policy</title><link>https://nicotinepolicy.net/</link><description>Daily digest of views, debates and discussions on nicotine science, policy, regulation and advocacy.</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:04:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Vaping Taxes in the United States and Around the</title><link>https://vaping360.com/learn/tax-rates-on-vaping-products/</link><description>As vaping becomes more popular, governments see it as a new source of tax revenue. Because many vapers are current or former smokers, money spent on e-cigarettes often replaces spending on traditional tobacco, reducing tobacco tax income. Governments have long relied on tobacco taxes and want to recover this lost revenue. Whether vaping should be taxed like tobacco is less important to policymakers than the financial impact. Since vaping resembles smoking and faces public health criticism, politicians find it easy to justify taxing it, often using debatable health arguments. (Published on December 29, 2025byvaping360.com)</description></item><item><title>Nicotine pouches offer huge promise—so long as the U.S. doesn’t repeat its mistake with vaping</title><link>https://www.aol.com/finance/nicotine-pouches-offer-huge-promise-141400732.html</link><description>Smoking and vaping are public health challenges. Despite anti-smoking efforts in the US, new cigarette users are rising, partly due to celebrities' influence. Vapes were meant to help smokers but turned into a new epidemic with counterfeit products. Nicotine pouches offer a tobacco-free alternative, showing promise. The US should learn from the UK's stricter regulations, raising the legal age for tobacco and proposing a ban on nicotine products for youth. Industry and government collaboration is crucial to prevent youth nicotine use. The focus should be on aiding adult smokers and avoiding creating a new generation of nicotine users. Achieving a tobacco-free world is possible. (Published on December 29, 2025byaol.com)</description></item><item><title>Republika Srpska: From now on, coffee without cigarettes</title><link>https://en.vijesti.me/world-a/balkan/789512/Republic-of-Srpska-from-now-on-coffee-without-cigarettes</link><description>Banja Luka has implemented a strict smoking ban in public spaces with fines up to 6.000 marks. The law aims to reduce secondhand smoke exposure and protect health. Supporters highlight health benefits and tourism appeal, while opponents argue it infringes on individual rights and hurts businesses. The law covers traditional cigarettes, e-cigarettes, and tobacco products, with penalties for non-compliance. The ban aligns with European clean air directives and aims to curb smoking-related diseases. Public opinion is divided, but the majority supports the new regulations. Republika Srpska joins the Federation of BiH in becoming smoke-free, with RS enforcing stricter penalties than the Federation. (Published on December 29, 2025byvijesti.me)</description></item></channel></rss>